THE PRIMAL HUNTER 10

©2024 ZOGARTH

This book is protected under the copyright laws of the United States of America. No part of this publication may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted, in any form or by any means, without the prior permission in writing of the publisher, nor be otherwise circulated in any form of binding or cover other than that in which it is published and without a similar condition including this condition being imposed on the subsequent purchaser. Any reproduction or unauthorized use of the material or artwork contained herein is prohibited without the express written permission of the authors.

Aethon Books supports the right to free expression and the value of copyright. The purpose of copyright is to encourage writers and artists to produce the creative works that enrich our culture.

The scanning, uploading, and distribution of this book without permission is a theft of the author’s intellectual property. If you would like to use material from the book (other than for review purposes), please contact editor@aethonbooks.com. Thank you for your support of the author’s rights.

Aethon Books

www.aethonbooks.com

Print and eBook design and formatting by Josh Hayes. Artwork provided by Antti Hakosaari.

Published by Aethon Books LLC.

Aethon Books is not responsible for websites (or their content) that are not owned by the publisher.

This book is a work of fiction. Names, characters, places, and incidents are the product of the author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any resemblance to actual events, locales, or persons, living or dead is coincidental.

All rights reserved.

Chapter 1

First Floor

Jake didn’t know how long they fell. It felt like minutes, yet also hours. No notification ever popped up, and no prompt asked them to enter. They did not have to register or do anything to confirm they were a party, as the system handled all that. All they had to do was enter together and fall together.

Then, suddenly, Jake felt solid ground beneath his feet, and his sphere spread out to reveal the world around him. He also opened his eyes and was nearly blinded by the bright sunlight beaming down on him from above.

He and the others found themselves standing on a large rock in the middle of a giant desert-like landscape. Sand stretched infinitely in all directions, and the wind was utterly still. Aside from his party members, Jake did not see a single living being anywhere.

“So, this is Nevermore,” the Sword Saint spoke.

“It’s—”

Jake was about to say something when he was cut off by a notification.

You have entered Nevermore.

Welcome to the first floor of the C-grade portion of Nevermore: the Sunlight Dunes. In order to progress to the next floor, the main objective of this floor must be completed, and the entrance to the next floor must be entered together with all surviving party members.

Completing events, achievements, and objectives rewards points that count towards the leaderboards and final rewards.

Main objective: Defeat the Lord of the Dunes.

Bonus objectives: Gather at least 1000 Sunlight Fragments of the Dunes to open the Lord’s Treasury.

Current progress: Lord of the Dunes (0/1), Sunlight Fragments of the Dunes (0/1000)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Godspeed, Chosen of Vilastromoz; I look forward to your performance. Do not expect any assistance.

Current Nevermore Points: 0

Jake read the notification and smirked a bit at it getting personal towards the end. While this was indeed a mega-dungeon and a World Wonder, it was also the domain of the Wyrmgod. Even now, Jake felt an odd presence observing him. It felt different than when Villy looked at him, and more passive in nature. Rather than an individual, it was more like a trained AI kept an eye on things.

“Lord of the Dunes, huh?” the Sword Saint said. “And a thousand of these Sunlight Fragments?”

“Ree,” Sylphie complained loudly.

“The wind is oddly silent, huh?” Jake commented. The lack of wind-affinity energy in the air was an issue for Sylphie, and when he looked at the Sword Saint, the old man simply nodded.

“I do feel this environment is less beneficial than it could be,” he said. “However, it is not truly an obstacle. Besides, this is not one of the difficult floors, now, is it?” He then turned to Dina, who looked to be in thought. “How about you, Dina?”

“There aren’t that many here,” she said in a sad tone. “This land is… dead.”

Not good for her either, huh? Jake thought. He suspected she was talking about plants, so the environment was also bad for her.

“I am unbothered,” the Fallen King said. “How about you, Hunter?”

“All good here,” Jake said, smiling. “Now, let’s not delay and get going right away.”

Though the environment may have been shit, they still had one thing going for them. Jake smiled as he closed his eyes and released a Pulse of Perception. Seven.

Instantly, he spotted seven identical shard-like items hidden in the sand, all about ten to a hundred meters down in the sand.

“Two secs,” Jake said as he quickly teleported over to the closest one and, with a blast of mana, blew up the sand and sent the shard flying into the air. With a string, he quickly caught the orange crystal. The moment he did, it disappeared.

Current progress: Sunlight Fragments of the Dunes (1/1000)

Jake grinned even more as he quickly made his way back to the others. “Aight, the shards appear hidden beneath the sand and are pretty much indestructible. Should be easy enough.”

Once more, his Perception build proved supreme.

“Was the shard that orange thing?” Dina asked curiously.

“Yep.” Jake smiled, happy she was even talking to him. Progress!

Dina nodded. “Okay.”

She took out a small pouch that she could somehow put her entire hand into, then pulled out a handful of seeds and threw them onto the sand below. The moment they landed, she sent out a green blast of energy that soaked the hundreds of seeds she had just thrown out.

Within seconds, each seed sprouted a stalk, then a flower at the head, and finally, a wellspring of vines popped out everywhere. This happened to every single one, and soon there were several hundred. Jake curiously used Identify on one of them, not expecting it to work, and was surprised when it did.

[Vine Seed Soldier – lvl 194]

He saw it had a level, but he also felt like it was summoned and not a “true” creature. Closer to an ectognamorph drone than a truly living being.

“Go find the Sunlight Fragments,” Dina told the many Vine Seed Soldiers. Without any indication they even understood her, the many plants began wandering off into the large dune.

“Sure that will work?” Jake asked.

“They know what to do,” Dina said with confidence.

“Alright, then.” Jake nodded, seeing no reason to question her. He did wonder how they would bring the shards, but he had no idea how long they would spend there, so it wasn’t a problem.

“Stop dallying; let’s get this area cleared out and move on to the next floor rather quickly,” the Fallen King said.

“I would lean towards agreeing,” the Sword Saint said. “Attempting to fully complete this floor would be a waste when all subsequent floors give more points.”

“Fair enough,” Jake said. “Let’s get this show on the road, then. First, we need to find the end boss, and I do still think we need to collect these thousand fragments, so finding this Lord’s Treasury is also a priority. That sounds good?” he asked the group.

He got three nods and a ree in confirmation. “Great. Aight, Fallen King, do your thing.”

The Fallen King nodded and held out his ivory claw. Four golden orbs condensed and took on a solid, physical form before flying out to each of them. Once they touched the orb, they simply allowed it to be absorbed into their bodies. Small golden, tattoo-like drawings appeared for a moment before quickly fading.

“Testing, testing,” Jake said, reaching out. “We good?”

“Loud and clear,” the Sword Saint said in a rather joking tone.

A major issue many parties faced in Nevermore was communication over vast distances. Jake had initially just wanted to bring in some walkie-talkies made by Arnold, but he’d come to learn that items like that were either not allowed or significantly weakened within the mega-dungeon. The same was true for many other supporting items, formation discs, and pretty much anything that one didn’t create themselves. Well, themselves, or someone in the party.

Luckily for them, the King was capable of condensing these golden orbs that people could infuse into themselves and then communicate over pretty much unlimited distances due to soul magic stuff. This was one of the kingly abilities the King had, and as the Unique Lifeform had explained, the skill had originally been created to keep in contact with his servants, and each orb could also be used for tracking. The entire thing functioned by using the King as the focal point of their telepathy… which did have the slight drawback of everyone hearing everything anyone said through the orb unless the King purposefully blocked it. A small drawback, all things considered, as many other groups simply relied on something akin to signal flares by shooting magic into the air.

Oh, and on the topic of them being lucky… One thing many groups needed more than a proper method of communication in dungeons was consumables. More specifically, they needed that good shit Jake chugged down with reckless abandon: potions.

That’s right—even potions were restricted within Nevermore if they weren’t created by one of the individuals in the party. Their effects would be “capped,” making them far worse and below what an average alchemist could make at their levels. All this was naturally an attempt by the system and the Wyrmgod to introduce some level of fairness for those who weren’t swimming in wealth or enjoying huge backings. It was naturally impossible to truly curb all advantages people with deep pockets and solid backings would have, but at least it was an attempt.

With communication established, Jake did one of the jobs he had been assigned: scouting. Jumping, Jake took to the air as Sylphie threw a gust of green wind his way, propelling him up faster than he could possibly fly on his own. The others spread out in the immediate area where Jake had pointed out seeing Sunlight Fragments with his sphere. As he took off, he also saw Dina take out more seeds to bolster her army of vine soldiers.

Jake kept flying upwards, and the higher he went, the more he felt the oppressive sun bearing down on him. As far as Jake could tell, it wasn’t even a false sun either, like what he had encountered in so many other dungeons’ sub-dimensions. No, this was a true star.

A true star that served as a limiter on how far people were allowed to fly up. Jake felt his skin begin to hurt a bit from the sheer heat, and he identified some other concept mixed into the rays. Scoffing, he covered his body in scales, and the pressure instantly disappeared.

He kept going for several more minutes, but soon he had to stop. Using his stable arcane mana, he condensed a parasol to cover himself, then turned to look down at the desert below.

“We’re on a small planet,” Jake told the others through the soul walkie-talkie. “Got a diameter of around nine to ten thousand kilometers, based on my estimates. Can’t spot any boss quite yet, but there are quite a few elementals spread throughout.”

“Go look for the Lord and this hidden treasury?” the Sword Saint sent.

“That’s the plan,” Jake replied, smirking.

He scanned the planet beneath him one more time before he began flying. Down below, the others got to work collecting fragments, with Dina covering a huge area with summoned vine soldiers while Sylphie kicked up tornadoes to send anything and everything hiding under the sand flying up into the air. The King and Sword Saint were not particularly helpful for this part, so they instead made sure no elementals or other creatures bothered them.

Not like that job was hard… Jake had not seen a single creature above level 205.

After flying for an hour while scouting the ground below, he finally noticed the environment truly begin to change in the distance. It wasn’t that it was no longer a desert, but rather, a huge shadow stretched across the horizon.

Jake had moved to the other side of the planet. Seeing as the shadow seemed to get closer faster than he flew, he had also correctly flown counter to the planet’s rotation. The sunlight energy had been slowly weakening for a while now, and looking ahead, he felt a different kind of energy. Upon squinting, he spotted something interesting.

Ice elementals.

The energy he felt was dense ice-affinity mana that dominated the other side of the planet. Jake informed his party as he kept flying into the darkness, and soon after, it was as if he had passed some threshold. The warmth of the sun was gone, and rime began to form on his body and even his parasol. Seeing no need for it anymore, Jake dispelled the magical construct and picked up his pace even more.

Cold energy began to condense in the air in front of him, and finally, Jake faced his first enemy. A floating, ghost-like creature slithered towards him in the sky, and he quickly Identified it.

[Ice Wraith – lvl 202]

He didn’t even bother stopping. Instead, he simply summoned two spears of destructive arcane mana and blew it up. The creature’s form was dispersed, but it managed to reform itself behind him. Luckily for it, Jake was long gone, and he had no interest in finishing it off.

The cold intensified, but Jake easily handled it. He did begin flying a bit closer to the ground, as the constant drain on his resources to fight off the unfriendly environment was an annoyance, but he still had an easy time spotting anything of note on the planet below.

Jake noticed more creatures gathered towards the north pole, and Sylphie also confirmed this was the case during her southern scouting. This made him question if this was also where this Lord of the Dunes was. However, not long after, this theory was dispelled when he saw something on the horizon. A large mountain of some kind of limestone-looking rock appeared, the entire thing covered in dense ice. At the peak of this mountain, on its spire-like tip, was a large, six-legged, chameleon-looking creature. Its entire body had a bluish hue, and Jake quickly Identified it.

[Lord of the Dunes – lvl 205]

“Boss spotted on the dark side of the planet,” Jake said after reaching out to the others. “How about you guys?”

What he got in return was a mixture of images from Sylphie. It seemed that while he had flown around the planet, she had reached the southern pole and found a huge mountain, far larger than the one Jake was at. Inside the mountain, she had then found a ritual circle requiring a thousand fragments. Likely the treasury.

As for fragments…

Current progress: Sunlight Fragments of the Dunes (654/1000)

It turned out that having an army of vine soldiers scouting was pretty damn overpowered.

“Can you slay the Lord of the Dunes on your lonesome?” the Fallen King asked Jake. “Travelling to you would be a wasted effort.”

Jake just grinned. “I’ll be done in a jiffy.”

Still flying far up in the air, Jake pulled out his bow and retrieved a well-poisoned arrow from his quiver. He nocked it and activated Arcane Awakening at the stable 30%, then began charging his Arcane Powershot. Below, the creature seemed to be in some kind of hibernation with its eyes closed, and it didn’t react before it was too late.

An arrow tore through the sky and descended upon the unsuspecting dungeon boss. The chameleon was slammed right in the head, its eyes opening in a panic as it was blasted off the mountain. While still in mid-air, it was struck by a barrage of arrows, sending it tumbling toward the ground.

It hit the frozen sand and sent it flying everywhere, but it didn’t even have time to stabilize before even more arrows stuck it, slamming it deeper into the sand. The boss let out a loud screech as ice magic condensed around it, and hundreds of ice elementals rose from the sand all around it, but its opponent was simply too far away. Though the chameleon struggled and tried to defend itself, every barrier was broken, and every attempt to dodge stopped.

Jake had to admit it took longer than expected, but the takedown never even turned into a fight.

*You have slain [Lord of the Dunes – lvl 205] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Achievement earned: Slay the Lord of the Dunes before it ever sees the sunlight. 3 Nevermore Points gained.

Achievement earned: Slay the Lord of the Dunes within 24 hours of entering the first floor. 1 Nevermore Point gained.

As Jake watched the notifications come in, he got a ping from the others.

“I see you are done on your end,” the Fallen King sent him.

“I take it you all got the achievements too?”

“Yes,” the Sword Saint confirmed. “We are all moving towards the south pole as we gather the rest of the fragments. Can you check out the northern one?”

“Sure thing,” Jake answered.

It seemed like everything was going smoothly. He flew down and quickly stored the corpse of the large boss monster while also checking if it had dropped anything. The answer to that was a big no, so he took to the air once more and flew towards the northern pole. On the way, he also checked a new part of his interface.

Nevermore Points: 4

Four points. Yay. Jake did find the name Nevermore Points a bit lame, but hey, it was descriptive and easy to remember, so who really cares?

His flight towards the north was uneventful, but once he got closer, he did spot something interesting. Not unlike what Sylphie had shown him and the Lord of the Dunes’ former perch, a large mountain appeared, and Jake flew closer to investigate. On this one, he also found a large cave to enter. Just as he walked into the cave, he got another round of notifications.

Bonus Objective Completed: Unlock the Lord’s Treasury. 5 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Unlock the Lord’s Treasury within 12 hours of entering the first floor. 2 Nevermore Points earned.

Jake had netted himself another seven points, bringing him to 11 total.

“Anything good in there?” Jake sent to the others.

“I do not find myself impressed,” the Fallen King answered. “Nevertheless, we shall bring what is here. Now, all we need is to find our way to the next floor.”

“See, funny you should mention that,” Jake said with a grin, having made his way into the mountain’s depths.

Chapter 2

The Dina Show

Just after Jake was contacted and told his teammates were done, he just happened to find himself standing in front of a large gateway that he didn’t doubt led to the next floor. One thing did confuse him a bit, though. There was another smaller teleportation circle of some kind near the wall of the cavern, but it was slightly damaged.

“Pretty sure I found it, but there is also this other teleportation circle. It looks like a short-range one, though.” Jake passed along a mental image to the party.

“Peculiar,” the Sword Saint answered, sending back the mental image of an identical magic circle down at the south pole. This one wasn’t broken, though. “Is yours operational?”

“Nope, is yours?”

“Appears to be, but with yours broken… we shall begin making our way north now.”

“Eh, gimme a minute,” Jake said, looking at the magic circle a bit. He tilted his head and went closer. Touching the circle, he closed his eyes and studied it for a minute or so while comparing it to the one at the southern pole.

“Pretty low-level one, huh?” Jake muttered as he infused his energy. Analyzing it and finding the flaws had been easy enough, and soon enough, the broken lines were restored. The entire magic circle hummed to life.

“Ours just seemed to activate,” the Sword Saint said, surprised. “Did you do something?”

Jake grinned. “What can I say? I know a bit about formations.”

A minute later, the party of five appeared in the cave on the north pole. The second the last person was there, the large archway that served as a gate activated, and a portal appeared.

First floor completed. 10 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the first floor before the light of the sun could reach the Lord of the Dunes. 5 Nevermore Points earned.

Nevermore Points: 26

“That’s one floor down.” Jake smiled as he turned to the others. “Anyway, what did you get from that treasury?”

The Sword Saint proceeded to take out two rare items and a bunch of stuff clearly meant to help battle the Floor Boss and the environment, such as crystals that gave resistance to the sunlight and what looked like a grenade. These items would disappear upon entering the next floor, so, honestly, the only reason to even do the bonus objective was the points.

Without further ado, the five of them entered the portal to the next floor. Upon entering it, the party found themselves in a large square room about fifteen meters on each side with one gateway in front of them, another behind them, and a third off to the side. The walls were dark gray stone, and Jake’s sphere informed him that there was nothing beyond them but an empty void.

Jake instantly understood what this room was. The gate in front of them had a sign saying “second floor,” while the gateway off to the side was an exit. Mind you, if one exited Nevermore before one reached a city, they would have to go through the first floor once more to progress. And not “go through” as in do the boss again and whatnot, but literally travel through the already-completed dungeon, making it a waste of time.

Anyway, in the middle of this new in-between-floors room was a small platform with a lockbox on it. The loot from the first floor.

“I must say, it is a bit underwhelming,” the Sword Saint said as he looked at the lockbox. “Though we must consider that this is simply the first floor, and it only took us a few hours to clear it all.”

“True, true,” Jake said as he walked over and unceremoniously opened the lockbox. Within was a rare-rarity sword, and Jake could only act teasingly as he went over and handed it to the Sword Saint in an overly formal way, even going down on one knee as he held it up. “For you, our resident swordsman. It is only proper you receive this bounty. I hope there are no complaints?”

“Will… Will he use it?” Dina questioned, looking confused.

“No, no, he won’t.” Jake grinned as he stood up.

“Then… why?”

“Exactly.” Jake nodded. “Let’s move on to the next floor?”

Dina was still confused as they all moved through the gateway leading onwards.

Walking through the gate was like stepping into an entirely new world. Probably because they did step into an entirely new world. Jake’s sphere spread out, and he saw a familiar-looking environment filled with greenery and trees as far as the eye could see. At least in front of them. Behind was an endless wasteland.

They had appeared on top of a large cliff overlooking an utterly massive valley filled with trees, its greenery stretching thousands of kilometers. When the others came through the gateway, they also just appeared standing beside him with no indication of an actual gate, making it clear there was no way back. The only way to proceed was to clear the floor… or wait for the full fifty years and get thrown out.

Welcome to the second floor of Nevermore: The Evergreen Valley.

Main objective: Defeat the Lord of the Valley.

Bonus objectives: Find 10 Illusory Lotuses hidden throughout the forest.

Current progress: Lord of the Valley (0/1), Illusory Lotuses (0/10)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 26

Jake read the message and nodded. Only ten lotuses this time, but going by their description, these lotuses would be a bit harder to find than the Sunlight Fragments, as their name indicated an ability to create illusions. The Lord of the Valley was pretty straightforward, though Jake was a bit disappointed at the name of the boss.

Maybe these first few floors are just low-effort creations by the Wyrmgod, as most good parties just rush through, Jake considered.

“This seems nicer than the desert,” the Sword Saint said with a smile, looking down at the valley.

“Definitely.” Jake nodded as he looked at the King. “Sad this floor isn’t called the Evergreen Forest. Then we could have had a Floor Boss called the Lord of the Forest.”

“Your humor is far from as funny as you believe it to be,” the Fallen King answered.

“Now that is just mean,” Jake commented.

“The joke is only made worse by requiring inside knowledge only you and I are aware of, as no one else here has known me as anything other than the Fallen King.”

“I get it, I get it,” Jake said defensively. “Geez. Anyway, let’s just use the same tactic as last time. Find the ten lotuses, find and kill the end boss, and move on to the next floor. I can handle finding the lotuses while you all search for the boss. Sounds like a plan?”

“The boss is over there.” Dina pointed northeast into the nearly endless forest beneath them. Jake was about to question her when she looked down at all the trees and spoke again. “And… oh, okay. Okay. That would be nice, thank you.”

Dina looked like she was just talking to herself, but suddenly the forest rumbled. Large vines extended upwards all throughout the valley, creating lines of giant pillars reaching to the horizon. Then Jake saw the vines begin moving. A few kilometers away, an entire patch of land around five meters across was being carried by vines that simply handed the patch off to one another. After a few minutes, the patch was dumped on the ground just beneath them in the valley, and looking down, Jake noted that the small landmass had an odd rock on it. After squinting at it, the illusion fell away, revealing a lotus.

“Did… Did you just…?” Jake asked Dina.

The dryad seemed confused and tilted her head. “I just asked if the trees wanted to help, and they agreed. They were very nice and even offered to bring the lotuses to us, so we didn’t have to go through the forest and potentially ruin anything. Oh, and they asked if we could kill the Lord of the Valley, as it isn’t very nice to the trees and is hurting the natural balance.”

Jake nodded slowly as he stared at tens of thousands of vines extending endlessly into the valley, all working to gradually carry lotuses toward them. This was… kind of overpowered, wasn’t it? Like, pure cheese of an entire floor. Would the Wyrmgod penalize them for shit like this?

“Good job, Dina.” The Sword Saint smiled and gave the dryad a proud nod.

“Quite a display of power, indeed,” the Fallen King said. “Is it your Bloodline that allows this?”

“Ye—yeah, I just asked… so…” Dina said, looking shy. Her green skin turned a slightly darker shade of green—the dryad way of blushing, which did make Jake wonder what color the blood of dryads was. It wasn’t important, but he was a bit curious. Anyway.

“Definitely does make life easier.” Jake smiled and gave her a thumbs-up. Even Sylphie gave a happy screech.

“Did the forest also tell you where the exit is?” the Sword Saint asked.

Dina nodded and pointed in the same direction as the Floor Boss.

“So, we will pass the boss if we go for the exit?” Jake asked.

“It moves around… but if we hurry, yeah,” Dina explained.

“Then let’s get a move on,” Jake said. “Can you somehow handle collecting the lotuses on the way?”

While they had been brought one lotus, it wasn’t like the many vines were fast. They were pretty damn slow, actually, so it would likely take them a few hours at least to bring all the lotuses to their group, and while waiting for them at the entrance to the floor would be quicker than searching themselves, it would be even faster to just get them along the way.

“Oh, okay.” Dina nodded as she looked out at the forest. Jake didn’t feel energetic movements or any indication whatsoever that she was doing anything, yet a few seconds later, she nodded again. “Okay, they will help.”

Jake smiled. “Then let’s go.”

What followed was something Jake could only call cheating. Along their way to the boss monster, they encountered raised patches of land with lotuses on them, and by the time they reached the boss, they had six of the ten. Killing the boss took less than thirty seconds from the moment the five of them descended on the poor level 208 beaver-like monster, which was just trying to enjoy a good meal by eating one of the trees.

The fight had started with roots shooting up from the ground and entrapping the beast. Pure pressure from the King had kept it utterly fixed as Jake released a barrage of Powershots, with Sylphie and the Sword Saint cutting it apart using wind and water blades, respectively. It had never even had a chance to fight, and the only reason it had stayed alive as long as it did was its high health pool. On that note, after encountering it for the second time, Jake was pretty sure these Floor Bosses had artificially inflated health pools. Not that it mattered in a case like this.

Achievement earned: Slay the Lord of the Valley before it manages to return to its lair. 5 Nevermore Points gained.

Achievement earned: Slay the Lord of the Valley within 12 hours of entering the second floor. 2 Nevermore Points gained.

After the boss was dead, it was just a relaxed flight to the end of the second floor while collecting “hidden” lotuses on a silver platter along the way. As mentioned… it was pretty much cheating.

The second-floor exit had also been intended as a challenge, as they’d first encountered a hidden pit in the ground covered by vines, but a slight nudge from Dina made them move out of the way. Right in front of this pit was the final lotus.

Bonus Objective Completed: Collect 10 Illusory Lotuses. 10 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Collect 10 illusionary Lotuses without using any of the provided tools to assist in their discovery. 4 Nevermore Points gained.

Seeing that there were tools to help find the lotuses nearly made Jake choke at how unfair Dina’s ability was. He did have to admit that their illusion was quite good, forcing him to squint a bit to see through it. While that didn’t seem like a lot, one had to remember that Jake had more Perception than pretty much any other C-grade at his level in existence. Because he was smart and knew what the best stat was, of course.

“Dina,” Jake said once they jumped into the pit and walked through the small tunnel leading to another gateway, “you are awesome. You know that, right?”

The dryad blushed again. “I… I just did what I should…”

“If that is only what you feel like you should do, then you should definitely keep being awesome.” Jake grinned, happy with Nature’s Attendant for introducing her to the group.

Just that brief interaction with the boss monster also made Jake aware she was no slouch when it came to combat. Her support capabilities were still unknown, but if anything she had shown so far was an indication of her skills in that department, they were indeed in for a fantastic time.

The Sword Saint also praised Dina, making her even shyer than before. No one had really had a chance to show off any of their skills on this floor, and in the end, the entire thing ended up taking only a bit over an hour and a half. Most of their time had been spent flying at a semi-leisurely pace, as they’d still had to wait in a few places for the vines to bring a lotus. Quite a bit smaller than the first floor, but far more densely packed. Even then, they only explored a few percentages of the forest as the trees did all the work.

When it came to the setting of the floor, Jake learned that a war of sorts had been going on between the forest and invading beaver-like monsters that were pretty much just smaller variants of the Lord of the Valley. Their group of five had not gotten involved in any of this fighting, instead making a beeline for the boss and getting their lotuses. It wasn’t like the wanton slaughter of the beavers would help any of them, and the trees were nice and helpful, so there was no way they would fight them either. The trees even told Dina to avoid killing anything besides the boss, so they saw no reason not to follow that advice.

Anyway, after only a bit of walking, they reached the floor’s exit.

“Ree,” Sylphie said as they reached the gateway proper.

Jake smiled. “Yep, a lot easier and faster than the first floor.”

In the room with the gateway, they also found a small pond with a sealed treasure chest in the center. It was ringed by ten small rock formations with holes, each perfectly shaped to hold a lotus. After placing all the lotuses, they opened the lockbox and got an epic-rarity lotus crown that they decided to give Dina. No one else needed it, and she had done everything on this floor, so it was only fair.

Without any reason to stay longer, the overpowered party moved through the gateway and completed their second floor of the day.

Second floor completed. 20 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the second floor within 12 hours while collecting all ten lotuses. 8 Nevermore Points gained.

Achievement earned: Traverse the Evergreen Valley and complete the second floor while collecting all ten lotuses without killing any living creatures other than the Lord of the Valley. 15 Nevermore Points gained.

Nevermore Points: 90

The points just kept rolling in. Jake wondered if the points would keep doubling, considering they’d gotten 20 for this floor, but he had a feeling they wouldn’t. Exponential growth like that tended not to end super well. Oh, well. He would find out once they did the third floor.

Leaving the local wildlife and ecosystem alone also proved to be a good idea, as it had netted them an extra 15 Nevermore Points. Taking the advice of trees was definitely a lesson to remember.

As for loot… well, it was shit again. Two pieces of rare equipment they also gave to Dina.

Let’s hope the third floor is fun, Jake thought to himself as their party continued.

Spoiler alert: It wouldn’t be fun.

It was the exact opposite.

A fucking water level.

Chapter 3

The Worst Floor

The Wyrmgod of Nevermore. One of twelve Primordials, and a being often viewed as the greatest of all the dragons. The Draconian Accords had been overseen by the Wyrmgod, and all dragons in existence viewed him as the most powerful. While the Malefic Viper had also been a dragon before godhood, his chosen name made it clear he identified more as a snake than a dragon. Hence why the Wyrmgod got the title.

When the Wyrmgod had managed to directly work with the system and create the World Wonder known as Nevermore—the most famous in all of the multiverse—the skill of this Primordial had only become more widespread. He was not only the most powerful dragon, but also the apex of all dungeon masters.

No one could discount the achievements of the Wyrmgod… but on this fateful day, Jake did feel like he could question the title of apex dungeon master. Or perhaps even the greatest of dungeon masters fell victim to the folly of trying to do the impossible:

Make a fun water level.

And a folly it was. The third floor was complete shit compared to the two before it. Their group of five appeared on the dry ground within a cave, but soon it became clear it was but a temporary refuge.

The only way out of this cavern was diving into a large pool of water extending into a vast ocean. Once they’d all appeared in the cavern, the system issued the message for this floor.

Welcome to the third floor of Nevermore: Deep Coral Ocean

Main objective: Defeat the Coral Ocean Lord.

Bonus objectives: Collect at least 500 Deepsea Pearls to open the Ancient Clam.

Current progress: Coral Ocean Lord (0/1), Deepsea Pearls (0/500)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 90

Jake hated the place from the very moment they appeared there, and the description of the place sure didn’t help. Defeat a boss? Sure. But collect five hundred fucking pearls? That sounded like suffering. To make matters worse, his one hope was dispelled when he looked at the Sword Saint shortly after they all realized what they were dealing with.

“I delve into the concept of rain, not water as a whole,” the old man said, shaking his head. “While my understanding does assist me, I too find myself heavily impeded while underwater.”

Jake then looked to the King with hope.

“Water is an obstacle, but it is manageable. It weakens all but my soul magic, and while my force magic still has significant potency, I have to fight the environment itself.”

Dina?

“Water plants… are rare,” Dina said, sounding a bit sad. “I don’t hear anyone nearby, either. I can do okay in water, though. Grandpa made sure I was prepared.”

So, at least they had one combatant. Their support. Jake looked at Sylphie, who he estimated to be the weakest of their group. As a bird primarily using the wind affinity, she was naturally unable to fly while in water, and would thus rely solely on her magic. Her speed would also be reduced, her maneuverability nil… Jake honestly considered if it was best for her to just take up the role of ranged fighter for this floor.

“Sylphie, want me to help carry you?” Jake asked.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked as she tilted her small head in confusion.

“The water,” Jake said, pointing. Then he had a realization. Had Sylphie ever really encountered deep water? The thought struck him, and he prepared to explain what Sylphie would face and how she’d probably need to acclimate herself to the pressure, but then she screeched again.

“Ree, ree.”

“No, you can’t fly in the water.” Jake shook his head. “There is no wind there. The pressure and density of the water will also make every action harder. You can’t even properly flap your wings.”

“Ree.”

“I said you can’t.”

“Ree.”

“It doesn’t work like that!”

“Ree.”

“Yes, we can bet on it!”

“Ree.”

Jake had mixed feelings about what happened next. They had all rushed into the water at Jake’s ushering, with Sylphie being the last one to enter. He’d goaded the bird to please go ahead and show him how she could “totally just fly in water like normal,” and he’d already had his “I told you so” ready on his lips when the bird dove into the water.

And… yeah.

“I have difficulty comprehending how that works,” the Fallen King said.

“She is indeed a peculiar creature,” the Sword Saint echoed through telepathy.

Even Dina agreed. “Yeah…”

Jake was floating there, surrounded by water and passively fighting off the pressure with the four others, while the hawk was just zooming around them, flying as if in normal air. She wasn’t even slower than before. Straining himself, Jake tried to see what Sylphie was doing, but no matter what he did, it just looked like Sylphie was flying as usual. As if the pressure didn’t really matter.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched, not even using telepathy.

“That makes even less sense!” Jake complained. You couldn’t fucking talk underwater.

“Ree.”

“I… I give up. You win.” Once Jake surrendered, Sylphie happily flew over to him and perched on his shoulder while he swam just outside the small alcove leading into the vast ocean.

Perhaps he had been foolish to believe Sylphie cared about things such as logic, and he was now paying for his mistake by owing Sylphie “all the scratchies.” The hawk cashed in right away by forcing Jake to rub her stomach.

Either way… Sylphie’s unexpected prowess proved to be incredibly valuable. They all agreed on not wasting more time than necessary in the damn water level, resolving to find the boss and the exit as fast as possible. Because of Sylphie, they could explore things a lot more easily, and Dina could also summon some aquatic plants to help scout, albeit in fewer numbers than above ground. Even if she could have made more, they encountered an issue on that front.

While the prior floors had been relatively absent of enemies, this one was filled to the brim. Sharks, squids, fish, coral monsters, elementals, giant floating crabs, and even a few undead creatures. While none were a challenge for Jake and the others, as they were all weak variants below level 210, they were more than strong enough to kill Dina’s summons, reducing their ability to gather information. This meant they had to explore the ocean as a group. Sylphie was the best scout by far, as she was several times faster than anyone else.

Besides water, there were also giant rock formations floating in different areas, their buoyancy somehow allowing them to just float there without being attached to anything. Some of these were utterly huge and allowed their party to enter and find dry land within, and it soon became clear they’d appeared on this floor inside one of these floating rocks. They were actually needed, because compared to all prior floors… this one was not a speedrun.

Instead, it was a long and arduous journey of trying to explore an ocean that even Jake didn’t have good visibility in. Finding their target was a huge challenge, and Jake sent out Pulses of Perception so often that he got a headache just attempting to find something—anything—of note. Sylphie also took the initiative to fly upwards and find the surface while the others tried traveling downwards to the sea floor, but after quite a while, they reached another slightly horrifying conclusion.

The “ocean” had no bottom and no surface. It was just a huge bubble of water floating within a massive goddamn fishbowl. They did eventually find some kind of barrier that sealed in all the water, but their hope of discovering some clue as to the location of the final boss was shattered.

Their entire first day was spent trying to simply figure out the environment and find clues to locate the final boss. They did find a few pearls, all of which were carried by flying clam monsters, but they had no expectations of collecting all five hundred.

Combat was still piss-easy even when they got ganged up on, meaning the only real challenge was figuring out where the hell to go. Ultimately, they decided to split up and explore different areas of the huge fishbowl while using the King’s markers to stay in communication. Meanwhile, the King kept track of their locations and made sure they didn’t have any overlap in the areas they covered.

This was how the first week of the dungeon passed by.

For some reason, the Wyrmgod had decided that making the water floor larger than the preceding two was a great idea. Based on what the King said, the spherical ocean they were in had to be at least twenty thousand kilometers across, making it far larger than the entire planet on the first floor. Considering everyone besides Sylphie was also far slower in this environment… it was hell.

Two weeks into the water level, the Sword Saint found the giant clam they were supposed to give the pearls to for the bonus objective—not that it was any help. Meanwhile, Sylphie had located the gateway leading to the next floor, but before it would unlock, they had to find the final boss and kill it. Something none of them had managed to do yet.

Now, Jake liked to find positives wherever he could. While it was undeniable this floor was complete shit, and everyone hated it, it did force them all to take the time to properly adapt to an underwater environment. If one compared their speeds from the day they’d entered the ocean to now, they had all gotten significantly faster. Well, besides Sylphie, who’d never been bothered to begin with. The Sword Saint had managed to leverage the concept of rain to propel himself forward and nearly merge with the water, while the Fallen King used his force magic to more aggressively move around, even shaping a barrier around himself to give his entire form better fluid dynamics.

Dina had slightly morphed her own body to almost resemble some ocean plant, helping her to adapt to the pressure and swim far faster. Finally, there was Jake.

Jake had not spent this period of time learning to swim faster, but instead working to adapt one skill: One Step, Thousand Miles. Space magic shouldn’t care that much about being underwater or above ground, and the environment should at most lead to increased energy consumption. His primary issue with the skill wasn’t actually the space magic part, but the activation of the skill. The act of taking a step.

Without any solid ground in the water, taking a step seemed impossible. Even if Jake condensed stable arcane platforms to step on, it was still damn slow. It was unnatural. While the entire concept of One Step was rooted in the natural movement of taking a step, one simply couldn’t walk underwater naturally. However, given that they were stuck in a damn ocean without much else to do, Jake had time to properly explore the skill.

He considered dozens of ways to improve his use of the skill, such as condensing the water itself to harden it, then trying to step on the water itself with stomping motions to force himself forward, relying on constant platforms beneath his feet. He even had one crazy idea of making some spring-like system so that whenever he forced his foot downwards, the springs would collapse and make a stable arcane platform hit the sole of his boots. All of these ideas ended up being shit, but the experience alone did allow him to realize some things.

It was all about making it natural. It couldn’t function using forced movements that Jake would never make if not for the skill. That was how he had his breakthrough on the sixteenth day. He slowly moved away from the concept of stepping down normally and turned towards what he considered a “step” while in the water. If he didn’t have a seafloor to walk on, how would he normally move around?

Well… Jake would swim. So, rather than trying to force his movements to fit with the skill, Jake changed his perspective to make the skill fit his movements. He also began to break away from some other usual assumptions. Normally, a step would be taken from a horizontal position, but Jake had walked on several vertical surfaces and used the skill like that before, so why would that be an issue while in the water?

This was a true three-dimensional space, and while some odd kind of gravity allowed them to know what was up and down, it wasn’t that impactful. With all his insights and realizations coming together, he finally managed to form a far more effective way of getting through the water.

Swimming forward, Jake naturally moved his legs up and down to propel himself, but rather than simply pushing against the water to move forward, he “stepped” on it. Every stroke teleported him several hundred meters in the direction he was facing. Coupled with Unblemished Arrows, the use of his Wings of the Malefic Viper to swim even faster, and his increased adaptation over time, Jake became far more potent in the water. He estimated he could still fight with nearly seventy-five percent effectiveness while in the water. He could also still do a normal “step” while in combat, but his new swimming-stepping was far faster for moving around the vast ocean.

Sadly, or perhaps luckily, he didn’t need these new capabilities much, as he did not do anything of note on this floor.

On the twenty-second day, Sylphie finally encountered the Floor Boss. Their group had been under the assumption that something called the Coral Ocean Lord was stationary, given the nature of coral, but they found that to be an entirely wrong assumption. The boss was instead a huge floating rock filled with corals that traveled around the ocean at an impressive speed. This was how they had somehow kept missing it despite feeling like they had explored everywhere.

Sylphie had only found it due to the whispers of the wind. While the wind was far quieter under the water, Sylphie eventually managed to hear it. The whispers told her of the environment, and after the Fallen King found a rock formation filled with seaweed that Dina then spoke to, they managed to narrow down the area the boss was in.

While everyone would have loved to let out some pent-up frustration by teaming up and tearing up the Floor Boss together, Sylphie did it alone, as that was just faster. Meanwhile, the rest of the group headed toward the exit.

On the dawn of the twenty-third day, they all promptly entered the gate and finished the god-awful water level.

Third floor completed. 30 Nevermore Points earned.

Nevermore Points: 120

Jake noted that the floor gave 30 Nevermore Points upon completion, which made him believe that each floor’s points were simply the floor level multiplied by ten. They also didn’t get a single achievement, yet no one cared. They were just happy to be done with the third floor.

Sitting in the small in-between room before the fourth floor, they were all regrouped for the first time in weeks, and all relaxed as they reflected a bit on the third floor.

“Even if this particular experience was less than pleasant, I do believe it was a valuable one,” the Sword Saint said. “If we find ourselves in a similar environment on a later floor, we are not entirely powerless, and I almost have a feeling the Wyrmgod placed a level such as this early on to prepare us.”

Wise words, yet Jake’s were even wiser.

“Doesn’t make water levels like this less shit.”

“While I do agree with that assessment, the Sword Saint is also correct,” the Fallen King chimed in. “It is a potentially lethal weakness for our group that only the Sylphian can act unimpeded in the water. Improvements are needed.”

Jake nodded. “Yeah, we did all get better at dealing with water, and this will definitely prove beneficial if we encounter a water floor later on. Also, if some monster is capable of summoning a water domain or something, we won’t find ourselves as limited.”

Dina also seemed in agreement. She looked deep in thought after the water level, having also not enjoyed it much.

“Ree,” Sylphie said with a shrug, not understanding why they all cared so much. Jake seriously wanted to figure out how the hell Sylphie did it, but alas.

He sighed and looked towards the next gate as the others went through the lockbox with loot. Once more, the reward was useless, and Jake was more determined than ever to get a move on. They had just wasted over three weeks, so now it was time to pick up the pace and rapidly clear their way to the first city layer.

Chapter 4

Monarch of the Skies

The fourth floor. When Jake and his party entered, they were all met by a very different environment than the one they had just been in. Pure darkness roamed, and the air smelled of soil and death. The environmental mana affinity matched this, as it was an odd mix of earth, death, and dark. Shortly after they were all there, the dungeon informed them of their objectives for this floor.

Welcome to the fourth floor of Nevermore: Darkrock Caverns.

Main objective: Defeat the Darkrock Revenant Lord.

Bonus objectives: Smelt and create at least 200 Darkrock Ingots using Darkrock Ore.

Current progress: Darkrock Revenant Lord (0/1), Darkrock Ingots (0/200)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 120

Instantly, they encountered one pretty major issue:

Jake was the only one who could see properly.

The dark mana was intense, and it appeared that Jake was the only one who possessed a natural affinity to work with it. Even the Fallen King was significantly affected by the dark mana, which reminded Jake of how well his dark mana had also worked on the King back when he was known as the King of the Forest. He had managed to blind the Unique Lifeform using his formerly mild dark-affinity mana, so it made sense that the energy was a weakness of his.

Sylphie still managed to adapt by using a domain of wind that was barely detectable. It was as if a slight breeze appeared all around them, but it allowed the bird to know everything going on in the area. Dina adapted by quickly growing some odd flower on top of her head, which could apparently see for her without any problems and warn her of dangers.

This still left the Sword Saint and the Fallen King as the most affected individuals. The Sword Saint lacked good tools to see in the darkness, but he did have skills that allowed him to fight quite effectively regardless. The same was true for the King, who did have a skill to sense souls in his vicinity even through the darkness, but this wasn’t very useful when it came to the primary challenge of this floor:

Navigating the caverns. Oh, and avoiding the traps that were placed bloody everywhere. It really took Jake back to his Forgotten Sewers days in the tutorial, except the enemies here were not rats, but a mix of earth-affinity creatures and—as indicated by the death mana in the air—a whole lot of undead.

If the second floor had been Dina’s time to shine and the third Sylphie’s, then this floor was Jake’s. Collect ores to form ingots for the bonus objective? Sphere of Perception. Avoid traps and find their way through the labyrinthian cavern network? Sphere of Perception. Locate hidden “vaults” of sorts hidden deep beneath the earth? Well, okay, the sphere wasn’t quite big enough to reach these in its passive state, but the occasional Pulse of Perception had that covered.

The Darkrock Ore was quite easy to discern from the surrounding rock due to its increased mana density, so Jake spent quite a lot of time directing the others where to blast cavern walls apart or where to dig. His party members did slowly adapt more to the environment as time went by, but it honestly wasn’t even needed.

There was only one problem Jake encountered, and that was how to change the ore into ingots. He considered if he could melt it himself using Alchemical Flame, or maybe even try to summon an actual fire-affinity flame, but that turned out to be a non-issue. In one of the secret vaults, they found an entire damn forge that one just had to pour the ore into, and ingots would be spat out shortly after. By the time they found this vault, they had more than enough ore to quickly make the two hundred ingots and move on.

Less than half an hour later, Jake spotted a large being that seemed to be made of pure energy through his sphere. It was also in a large cavern surrounded by other, smaller variants of itself, and it didn’t take much brainpower to know this was the boss. After getting there, Jake finally saw this Darkrock Revenant Lord. It looked like hundreds of corpses fused into stone, mixed with a shitload of dark-affinity mana. It was a mix of an elemental and a ghost, making it quite an interesting opponent. Not that any of them cared, as this abomination was rapidly ripped apart. After that, they found a large smelter pot to throw all the ingots they had formed into, with the result being an epic-rarity breastplate and a pair of legguards that none of them needed.

From there, they moved on to quickly locate the exit and reach the next floor, having finished this one in less than a day.

Current Nevermore Points: 234

114 Nevermore Points earned on the fourth floor. 40 from just completing the floor, 74 from the bonus objective, and then a bunch of achievements. These achievements included finding more than half of the hidden vaults, killing the boss fast, no one taking any damage from any traps, and of course, swiftly completing the dungeon.

The loot from the in-between room was once more useless, so they moved on to the fifth floor.

Upon entering the fifth floor, a theory they had discussed was pretty much confirmed. The moment they stepped out of the gateway, they were met with vast, open skies. They stood on a floating island that was surrounded by other floating islands, their sizes ranging from a few meters across to several kilometers.

The environmental mana was dense with wind-, water-, and lightning-affinity energy, and Jake even saw a few cloud islands in the distance, reminiscent of those he had seen on Earth. The theory they had confirmed was that the first five floors of Nevermore all served a simple function: making sure the challengers could at least handle different environments.

They had gone from a desert of extreme heat and cold to a nature-filled forest of life. From there, they had entered an ocean of pure water, followed by a dark cavern with death, with the final floor in the sky surrounded by wind mana. Each floor had a theme. Perhaps this was why the design felt so lazy at times… They were meant to be relatively simple and test the basics of those who dared attempt to explore Nevermore.

Though Jake called the design lazy… upon reading the description of the fifth floor, it did appear there was more to this one.

Welcome to the fifth floor of Nevermore: Cloudspring Archipelagos.

Main objective: Defeat the Lord of Winds, the Lord of Clouds, and the Lord of Lightning.

Bonus objectives: Catch at least 24 Cloudspring Spirits before they escape the archipelagos.

Current progress: Lord of Wind, Lord of Clouds, Lord of Lightning (0/3). Caught Cloudspring Spirits (0/24)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 234

Rather than having only a single boss to kill, this floor had three. Perhaps it was because this was the final floor before they entered their first city. After every fifth floor, there would be an intervening floor that counted as neither a true floor nor a dungeon. Even if Jake admittedly didn’t know much about these city floors, he planned on getting there fast.

This floor was also different in one other way. Each of the prior floors had been an unfavorable environment for one or more members of the party, or, at the very least, not a beneficial one. Dina had been advantaged in the second floor, and Jake in the fourth, sure, but this floor… This one was different.

Wind. Clouds. Open area. Sylphie, the Sword Saint, and Jake all felt in their element. Due to their advantage, they all knew that this level was theirs to utterly dominate. It wasn’t like the King and Dina were disadvantaged either. They set out with great gusto, and it quickly became clear just how ridiculous their advantage was.

The wind whispered far louder than on any other floor, allowing Sylphie to know where everything was. Within a minute, she already had a rough idea of where the three Lords were. The bonus objective of capturing at least 24 Cloudspring Spirits was also one they wanted to tackle, and it didn’t take them long to find their first spirit. These spirits were small, fairy-like creatures that moved incredibly fast and were quite elusive. Their group discussed how to capture them and even laid out plans that included the King creating small cages and Jake weaving stable arcane mana nets, which made their first encounter with one incredibly anticlimactic.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched loudly the second they saw this first spirit.

The spirit stopped dozens of kilometers away and turned around. Then, like an arrow, it flew straight towards them before circling around Sylphie and eventually settling on her back, rubbing its head against the hawk’s feathers.

Current progress: Capture Cloudspring Spirits (1/24)

It turned out that these Cloudspring Spirits really liked Sylphie. As in, after the first one was “captured,” they kind of all just came flying in while the party traveled toward the three bosses. They weren’t even a quarter of the way when they passively completed the bonus objective.

Bonus Objective Completed: Capture at least 24 Cloudspring Spirits. 20 Nevermore Points earned.

After completing the bonus objective, they learned that the three bosses were all in roughly the same area on three massive cloud islands. It turned out that a reward for collecting the spirits—outside of the points—was information, and damn, were the spirits all chatterboxes. They told them all about the secrets they could find on different islands and warned them of what the three bosses were capable of. Once they had captured all twenty-four, they were also told where the three bosses were. Something they already knew, but hey, it was something.

When it came to opponents on this floor, they took the form of birds, elementals, and even some pterodactyl-looking monsters that breathed lightning. None were a problem and all were killed before they even had a chance to attack, though most foes actively avoided their group.

A bit less than halfway to the bosses, Sylphie was practically surrounded by Cloudspring Spirits, and they got an achievement.

Achievement earned: Capture more than 50 Cloudspring Spirits. 25 Nevermore Points earned.

With the achievement came more information. They were informed that if they crushed the orbs dropped from all three Lords instead of bringing them to the exit of the dungeon for an extra reward, they would be able to summon an optional and even harder boss. So that was definitely cool.

By the time Jake spotted the first large island with one of the Floor Bosses, Sylphie was drowned in spirits, and when just one more joined them, a second achievement popped up.

Achievement earned: Capture all 100 Cloudspring Spirits. 30 Nevermore Points earned.

The reward for getting every single spirit wasn’t information. Instead, all of the one hundred Cloudspring Spirits merged together and formed one Cloudspring Spirit Queen. The Cloudspring Spirit Queen was only slightly larger than the smaller spirits, and Jake wondered what her function was. Something he would never come to know.

Shortly after she appeared, Sylphie let out a few screeches. The Spirit Queen seemed ecstatic as her body began to fade and turn into a small marble, which Sylphie then inhaled before burping and looking happy.

No one bothered to question the hawk. Instead, they split up to take down the three bosses. The Lords were all relatively close together, but there were still around a thousand kilometers between each island.

Contrary to the other floors, this one was not as much about finding the end goal. The islands were all placed in a long strip that grew larger as one traveled, with the final four Islands being the largest by far. It was one massive island in the middle, surrounded by three large islands that had smaller masses in between.

Jake went for one boss, the Sword Saint another, and Sylphie a third, with the Fallen King and Dina going toward the massive central island to secure the exit Sylphie had told them was there.

The three Lords were elementals, so they divvied it up by giving Sylphie the Lord of Winds, the Sword Saint the Lord of Clouds, and Jake the Lord of Lightning.

Given that this was still only the fifth floor, what followed was not truly a fight. Jake took down the Lord of Lightning by barraging it with arrows from afar, while Sylphie demolished the Lord of Winds by, in her words, “out-winding it.” The Sword Saint took the longest, as cutting an elemental wasn’t the most effective, but it was still done within minutes.

Each of the three Lords dropped a basketball-sized orb corresponding to their affinities, and as agreed upon, the three of them instantly broke the orbs to summon the optional boss.

And summon an optional boss it did.

After he broke the orb, the island Jake had fought the Lord of Lightning on began to crumble, then released a giant arc of lightning that flew towards the central island. Shortly after, a tornado-looking beam of wind flew from another broken island. Finally, a stream of clouds was launched from the final boss island.

Event unlocked.

The three Lords of the Cloudspring Archipelagos have fallen, powerless before their foes. As the three islands crumble, the Orb of the Winds, Clouds, and Lightning all lie broken. Behold, as the Monarch of the Skies awakens.

Objective: Defeat the Monarch of the Skies.

Warning: The Monarch of the Skies is an optional objective and is significantly more powerful than any prior Floor Bosses.

“Meet up at my location,” the Fallen King sent to Jake and the others as they began flying towards the central island.

On the island, a massive pillar of wind, clouds, and lightning had appeared and begun soaring toward the sky. Far above, lightning clouds formed as the wind picked up and the occasional thunder rumbled. It truly gave off the vibes of a proper final boss being summoned.

Meeting up with the Fallen King, Jake saw that Sylphie had already returned, and they waited only for the Sword Saint to make his way back as they observed the pillar slowly fade to reveal the form of the final boss.

Jake wasn’t sure what he should have expected as he laid eyes on the Monarch of the Skies. Considering the three Lords had all been elementals, Jake had assumed that this Monarch of the Skies would be an elemental too, but what he saw instead was a humanoid creature that stood nearly ten meters tall. Feathers crackling with lightning covered the creature’s entire form, only hidden by silvery armor that protected the Monarch’s chest area. Two large white wings sprang from its back. The Monarch looked androgynous, and Jake honestly had no idea what its race was.

What he did know was that this creature was far more powerful than any other Floor Boss they had faced in Nevermore.

[Monarch of the Skies – lvl 225]

However… even if this one was stronger than anything they had faced in Nevermore, it was not stronger than anything Jake had ever faced before. Compared to the Isoptera Hive King, this Monarch of the Skies fell short by quite a margin. Moreover, Jake was not alone.

“Are you disappointed?” the Sword Saint, who had just returned, asked Jake as they both looked at the event boss.

“I don’t know,” Jake said honestly. “But I guess I had hoped for more.”

“We are barely at the starting stages of Nevermore,” the King said. “This foe already surpasses what the vast majority of parties would be capable of handling.”

“I know, I know,” Jake said with a sigh. “Anyway, let’s just get this over with.”

Jake wasn’t gonna lie. While he did find the experience of exploring the floors of Nevermore kind of interesting, and he enjoyed the company he was there with, the entire thing had been quite disappointing so far. He would have preferred to just skip to the twentieth floor or some shit. Sadly, he had to bully far weaker foes for a while longer before that was possible.

However, just as they were about to engage, the Sword Saint seemed to get an idea. He turned to Dina and asked, “Dina… how about taking on this foe alone?”

Chapter 5

Nature Magic Is Scary

The dryad didn’t seem to register the words immediately. After a second, she said with clear confusion, “Huh? I… I could… but why?”

The old man shook his head and smiled. “The four of us have either fought side by side or against each other before. We know about one another. I believe it would be pertinent to get a better idea of your skills, too, before we move on to the later floors. That way, none of us are taken by surprise.”

Dina seemed to consider the words for a moment before nodding resolutely. “Alright.”

“I take it you are all fine with this arrangement?” the Sword Saint asked Jake and the others.

“It is acceptable to me as long as she does not take too long,” the Fallen King said.

“Ree,” Sylphie said as she flew over and landed on top of Jake’s head before quickly sitting down and resting. Apparently, she would need some time to properly digest the fairy queen thing.

Jake shrugged. “Fine by me.” He didn’t really believe the Monarch of the Skies would give him a good fight, so why not share the love? Besides, he was interested in seeing how well Dina would handle the thing.

While the Monarch of the Skies wasn’t some pinnacle creature, it did feel pretty powerful for its level. Chances were it also had some of that special Floor Boss juice that Jake had noticed all the other bosses had. The extra juice came in the form of expanded resource pools—specifically, their health pools. That would likely push the Monarch up a level.

The highest-leveled bosses so far in Nevermore were the Lords they had just killed, and all three of those had been level 212. At 225, the Monarch was quite a bit above anything else… and twenty levels above Dina herself.

Moreover, the environment obviously favored the Monarch of the Skies. It would likely turn into a battle in the air, and so far, most of what Dina had shown was summoning vines from the ground, throwing out seeds and growing soldiers, and some occasional enhancement magic.

Jake looked forward to what more she had to show, and he gladly sat back as Dina made her way down towards the large central island where the Monarch of the Skies stood with its eyes closed.

Still floating in the air a good distance away, Dina threw out two small seeds that grew to become spear-like trees. Using some kind of plant telekinesis, she kept them floating there as she took aim at the Monarch below.

The second she threw them, the Monarch awakened. A whirlwind appeared around it instantly, and Jake and the others backed away to not get involved in the fight. The two trees entered the whirlwind unimpeded, but the ten-meter-tall winged creature still managed to dodge, resulting in the two trees stabbing into the ground and embedding themselves.

With lightning crackling on its wings, the Monarch prepared to take to the air, but vines suddenly exploded out of the trunks of the thrown trees, seeking to entangle its talon-like feet. It managed to avoid the roots with one of its feet, but the other was caught as Dina followed up her attack.

The ground below the Monarch erupted as hundreds of thorn-filled vines flew toward it. The Floor Boss reacted quickly and held out its hand, causing a lightning bolt to descend from the thunderclouds above. The lightning hit the Monarch and made its entire body explode, getting rid of the vines and allowing it to get airborne. Moreover, the lightning had delivered with it a large white halberd that the boss now wielded.

“It is quite powerful,” the Sword Saint commented.

“Yeah, not bad,” Jake agreed. The fact that it was effectively fighting within a giant formation that assisted it sure did wonders. However, its opponent wasn’t simple either.

Dina seemed almost annoyed at it for getting out of her attack. Rather than retreat, she chose to engage the Monarch of the Skies directly, and the two clashed in mid-air.

That was when Jake realized something he hadn’t even considered before. Dina was a druid that specialized in manipulating plants, but she was also a dryad. A part-human, part-plant lifeform. An obvious weakness of any kind of manipulation-based class was a lack of whatever they specialized in manipulating. They would try to shore up this weakness by being able to summon some of their element of choice, but this obviously came with some drawbacks, including highly increased resource consumption.

But what happened when bringing the element meant bringing your own body? Well, you would have someone like Dina.

The second before she clashed with the Monarch, a sea of vines grew from her arm and speared forward toward the boss. Surprised, the Monarch stopped in its tracks and tried to retreat out of range of the wall of spiky vines, but before it could, the vines shot out like spears, a few of them managing to stab it in its arms and legs. Sadly for Dina, the breastplate worn by the Monarch meant it avoided most of the damage, but the winner of this brief exchange was still clear.

Before the Monarch could properly recover, Dina pulled out a staff and aimed it. Jake expected to see her summon root spears or something, but instead, the staff began to glow with green light before it released what looked like an emerald bolt of lightning.

It was too fast for the Monarch to dodge, striking its shoulder. At the spot where it had been hit, the feathers began to fall off, the flesh rotting within seconds. Jake opened his eyes wide as she released several more green bolts of lightning, trying to analyze the nature of her attack.

Meanwhile, the Monarch retaliated with its own lightning. The two magics clashed in mid-air and exploded upon impact in flashes of white and green. After the Monarch failed to block a bolt and took another hit, Jake finally gained an understanding.

Willpower-based attack.

This was… rare, but Jake had read about it. What Dina did was release bolts of will-empowered life energy that, rather than nurturing life, carried with it intent to self-destruct. Which it promptly did, resulting in rot setting in and spreading to the surrounding flesh. It was an incredibly insidious type of attack, and one that was quite difficult to protect against.

However, in this instance, the Monarch of the Skies did have an advantage due to its significantly increased health pool, which resulted in the wounds healing quickly. Dina also realized this as she stopped her attack and changed her stance. The staff began to warp, sprouting a large blade at its end to transform it into a scythe.

The two of them flew towards each other once more, and it was clear this fight would transform into a melee battle, which did make Jake a bit worried, considering Dina was mostly a caster. However, it appeared he had once more underestimated her.

Now, there was someone Jake had heard mentioned quite a few times. Nature’s Attendant had mentioned this being, and so had Dina, but Jake didn’t believe they had ever seen it. Jake was naturally talking about the mysterious Bobo, the Guardian of Dina. He had hoped to see this Guardian during this fight, not realizing… Bobo had been in front of their eyes this entire time.

The large robe that usually covered Dina’s entire body was torn to shreds as four spider-like limbs of wood speared out and penetrated the breastplate of the Monarch. The halberd that had been aimed at Dina was also stopped by several branches that grew out and took the blow. This allowed Dina to properly close in. Swinging her scythe, she sent out a crescent wave of green energy that tore into the Monarch, leaving a deep cut of rotting flesh.

Jake could finally see what had been hidden beneath her thick robe. A wooden suit of armor covered her entire chest, abdomen, and thighs, stopping just above her knees. It extended nearly all the way to her neck, exposing only her head, arms, and lower legs. It wasn’t truly a piece of armor, either… It was alive.

Despite being pushed back, the Monarch of the Skies counterattacked by raising its halberd and fired a giant bolt of lightning down at Dina. Before it could even hit, a spear of wood shot out from her armor to absorb the blow, allowing Dina to pursue her foe.

By now, the Monarch seemed to realize it was in a bad position. Blood dripped from its chest from several barrel-sized holes, and a large part of its chest was rotting away from the scythe hit earlier. It tried to back away, but Dina pursued with impressive speed and continued delivering ranged attacks in the form of wooden spears. Being hit by one of these also wasn’t as simple as just taking a hit.

Every wooden spear that penetrated the Monarch’s body bloomed into more spear-like vines that dug into its flesh, and as it kept trying to retreat, Jake saw something frightening. Leaves began to sprout beneath the breastplate of the Monarch, at which point he realized that the hit from her armor—from Bobo—had done more than just stabbing; it had planted seeds.

While Jake used poison, Dina did something similar but far scarier, in his mind. With her attacks, she implanted almost microscopic seeds that took hold inside the body of her foe. Jake hadn’t even noticed it before Dina chose to activate the many seeds she had planted within the Monarch, and damn, did it look scary when thorns and vines began growing out from beneath its feathers. The giant creature howled in pain.

Still, the Monarch of the Skies refused to give up as it screeched louder than ever before. The thunderclouds above began to gather, and then a giant pillar of pure lightning descended, bathing the Monarch in energy and pushing Dina back. Once the light faded, its form was once more revealed, the vines and whatnot burned away, its entire body crackling with lightning.

Floating above the large island it had been summoned on, it didn’t notice what was about to hit it before it was too late.

Below, the entire island exploded with thousands of meter-thick vines surging upwards, grasping the form of the Monarch. The vines were instantly singed by the powerful lightning, but ten more came to take their place whenever one broke.

Seeing this, Jake realized where they had come from. Those two trees she had fired at the beginning had launched seeds into the island, and vines had slowly grown within while she fought the Monarch. Then, during the fight, she’d eventually pushed the Monarch back to float just above the island, where her trap had fully germinated and then activated.

Immobilized, the Monarch of the Skies tried to free itself by calling down a lightning storm. A whirlwind surrounded it, cutting away at the vines, but Dina rushed forward unimpeded, her armor growing wooden shields to block anything headed her way. The Monarch let out a loud screech as Dina transformed her arm into a long lance of wood that penetrated its chest. Its screech slowly turned into a scream as Dina’s body burned with energy, the vines pulsing with power.

Then a hundred vines erupted from within the Monarch of the Skies, piercing its skin and even its beaked mouth, effectively exploding it from within.

Achievement earned: Defeat the Monarch of the Skies. 50 Nevermore Points awarded.

Achievement earned: Defeat the Monarch of the Skies within half an hour of summoning. 25 Nevermore Points awarded.

“Ree,” Sylphie commented.

“Yep,” Jake agreed with a nod. “Definitely scary.”

“Nature magic is notoriously weak offensively, but I must say I find myself impressed by her ability to make use of her skills so effectively,” the Fallen King said with admiration.

Jake smiled. “Makes me wonder if her being a support type is even true.”

“I only look more forward to her support skills after seeing her personal combat prowess,” the Sword Saint said with a nod.

The dryad in question still floated in the air, looking at the dead Monarch of the Skies as the vines growing from its body began to bloom flowers of various colors. She nodded and looked proud of herself as she flew back towards them.

“I did it,” she said with a smile as she stopped in front of the Sword Saint.

“That you did,” the old man said with his grandfatherly smile. He then looked at her wooden armor with a raised eyebrow. “And am I right to assume that is Bobo?”

“Oh, yeah,” Dina said, nodding as she looked proudly at her armor. Still looking down at it, she nodded a few more times before looking up. “Bobo also says hello to you all. He is a bit shy, though.”

“I see, I see.” The Sword Saint nodded. “Well, Bobo sure also did a nice job. Tell him that for me, okay?”

Dina smiled and gently hit her armor. “Come on, Bobo… be polite.”

Jake also stood off to the side and smiled. Dina was naturally the only one who could hear her—

“Thank… you…”

A deep, rumbling voice came from Dina’s chest area as the armor moved slightly. Jake and everyone else stared, surprised for a moment, but Dina just looked incredibly proud and patted the armor gently.

“Bobo is full of surprises, it seems,” the old man said, being the first to properly collect his thoughts. “If I may ask… is he permanently attached to you, or can he also act more independently?”

“He can, but he doesn’t like to… We are best together,” Dina answered. “Grandfather gave Bobo to me when I was still small, and he has always been with me. Keeping me safe and helping me fight. He is my best friend.”

Bobo seemed to move a bit at her calling him her best friend, making Dina smile even more.

Jake also couldn’t help but smile at the girl and her scary wooden armor able to grow large thorns that torn things apart while also offering insane defense. It was like having an automatic defense system, and from how they fought, Dina’s style was fully capable of taking advantage of Bobo.

Dina’s offensive prowess was also pretty darn impressive. As the King had mentioned, nature-affinity casters tended to be quite weak offensively and in direct combat. Especially so when not in an environment beneficial to them. Dina had managed to overcome the weakness of requiring a good environment by using her own body and even Bobo. She could grow plants of all kinds from her own body, and she was the perfect conduit for her own nature mana. Further amplified by her Bloodline… she was indeed a true monster.

The dead Monarch of the Skies was definitely proof she could fend for herself and wouldn’t need babysitting, even on later floors. Jake still wondered how she would fight something like an elemental that didn’t have any life energy and didn’t care about physical attacks, but he had a feeling she had tools to handle those too. In fact, he got a feeling she had a lot more to show them over the next few years as they dove further and further into Nevermore.

For now, it was time to move on. While still partaking in small talk, they made their way to the gateway and passed through, collecting their 50 Nevermore Points for completing the floor and some extra for achievements. All in all, counting all the achievements and the extra reward from slaying the Monarch of the Skies, this floor had yielded the most Nevermore Points by far.

From one floor, they had gotten 231, which was nearly a doubling of the 234 they’d had before.

Current Nevermore Points: 465

Jake was satisfied as they stood in the in-between room, noting one more gateway than usual. One leading to the first intervening city layer of Nevermore. After opening another disappointing lockbox of loot, there was no need to delay, so they all promptly moved on and entered the first city.

Chapter 6

Dead on Arrival

Nevermore was often called the greatest dungeon in the multiverse, but it wasn’t just one dungeon. In fact, it was a multitude of dungeons stacked on top of one another, and even if Nevermore broke conventional rules, it was still classified as a dungeon. However, perhaps due to fairness from the system or the will of the Wyrmgod himself, individual floors did not count as their own independent “dungeon.”

Instead, a set number of floors in a row would as be classified together, with the five first in C-grade counting as “one dungeon.”

Why did this matter?

Well, for the title, of course.

[Dungeoneer X] – Successfully clear a Dungeon suitable for your level. +20 all stats.

Jake’s Dungeoneer title had upgraded to level 10, also known as the “cap” of D-grade. In E-grade, one could get up to level 5, 10 in D-grade, and 15 in C-grade. Jake also knew that every increase in the title from here on out would give +9 to all stats, tripling the +3 given in D-grade.

Anyway, having an upgraded title was nice but not that impactful, and honestly, not something Jake thought much about as he and the others entered the first city floor of Nevermore.

Nevermore’s city layers, or city floors, were quite peculiar. Jake had read a bit about them and knew that he shouldn’t expect overly much quite yet for one simple reason: This city layer had only existed for a few years.

Like the floors, these city layers had also been “reset” and “redone” for the new integration. One could still enter the city from the previous era if no one in the party in question was from the 93rd Universe, but if anyone was, they would end up on this layer. This was another reason why many factions had quickly taken some C-grades and pretty much forced them through these first layers of Nevermore. They wanted to establish themselves and claim space on the city floor. Not that many factions had had the time to arrive and build much of note quite yet.

Even then, it wasn’t like the city was completely empty.

Jake and the others walked out of the gateway and found themselves in the middle of a nearly completely empty square. Large stone buildings surrounded them, but they all seemed similarly empty. Jake did notice a few eyes land on them shortly after they appeared, and when he looked towards an empty-looking building, he spotted a man peeking out at them.

The man was surprised at being noticed and quickly retreated. Jake didn’t bother trying to figure out what the guy wanted, and besides, he had a system message to skim.

You have arrived on the first city floor of Nevermore. You are currently in the northern square.

All violence outside of the arenas is strictly prohibited on all city floors. Challenge Dungeon(s) can be found in the central square. If Nevermore is left and reentered, you will automatically be taken to the latest city floor unlocked.

Short and simple, yet very informative. Like Nevermore City before they’d entered the dungeon, violence was not allowed, but arenas were supplied. The message also mentioned another important aspect of Nevermore: Challenge Dungeons.

This was the individual aspect of Nevermore. Challenge Dungeons of varying natures gave Nevermore Points, just like the main floors. However, Jake had no interest in checking them out quite yet. These Challenge Dungeons could be found on every single city floor and were the same throughout. Besides, if he did ever want to go back to this first city floor, he would be able to at any point, as one could travel between all the city floors—or leave Nevermore altogether. This was because one other big difference between the other floors and a city floor was that one could exit Nevermore from a city floor and reenter again on that same city floor, just like the system message had mentioned. To summarize, city floors were pretty much save points for Nevermore.

Besides that, these city layers primarily functioned as places for parties to replace their members or fill empty group slots if someone happened to die. One could only attempt floor six onwards with people who had already done the first five, and it wasn’t possible to reenter the first five to get someone up to speed, so people really didn’t have a choice. This was one of the reasons the arenas had been established.

Another reason for these city layers was to stock up on resources without having to leave and come back again. Additionally, people could sell special items unique to Nevermore only within the city layers. While Jake and the others hadn’t found any such items, he knew one could find tokens that allowed one to travel back to the closest city layer, orbs that released pulses to create maps, and even items granting information on the specific floor one found themselves in.

Finally, factions used these floors for one more thing… time-dilation training. One was able to compound time dilation within Nevermore, and the Wyrmgod even provided these chambers for anyone interested. Needless to say, Jake and the others had no interest in these chambers, and they quite honestly didn’t make much sense for people who were actually talented. They were primarily made for people who just wanted to quickly finish their Nevermore dive and get on the Leaderboards, or maybe to sit down and do a crafting session without delaying their party too much before moving on to the next level.

That was pretty much all these city floors were for. Ah, but they did hold one more interesting thing…

Leaderboards.

“Do we have a reason to linger on this floor for longer than necessary?” the King said. “It appears deserted, and we have no need for additional resources.”

It made sense. While time dilation was still in effect, it wasn’t as powerful on the earlier floors as on the latter ones. Jake and the others had no idea how much it varied, and even the Sword Saint, who had insights into the concept of time, had no way to determine it. To him, time was not dilated at all due to the system fuckery making time appear “normal” within Nevermore.

“I want to check out the Leaderboards first,” Jake said.

“That does sound worth our time,” the Sword Saint agreed. “Though, from my understanding, the Wyrmgod is quite stingy with what information is given out.”

Jake smiled. “True, true, but it is better than nothing.”

No one else disagreed with quickly going to check out the Leaderboards, so without further ado, they began walking through the empty city streets. Quite a few buildings had been pre-constructed by the Wyrmgod, but even more empty lots were present, as factions had yet to claim any land.

The nearer they drew to the central square, which held both the Leaderboards and dungeons, the more people they began encountering. All of them were naturally C-grade, but Jake was still taken aback when he noticed something was off: their levels.

While Jake and his party members were all below level 210 and hadn’t even gained any levels from the first five floors, Jake saw a slew of people towards the end of C-grade. He quickly guessed these were people who’d been brought to this floor specifically to establish a presence for whatever faction they represented rather than actually doing floors.

Jake wondered if the Order had boosted some people to the floor yet, but then realized he didn’t actually care. Soon enough, they made their way to the central square, where they finally laid their eyes on the two Leaderboards there.

“A bit lower than I expected,” Jake commented as they looked at the first of the Leaderboards.

“It is the average, and considering the many groups that don’t aim to accomplish anything beyond the bare minimum while taking their time, it isn’t that surprising,” the Sword Saint said, with the King and Dina agreeing with him.

Jake still thought it was a bit low.

Average Nevermore Points (Floors 1-5): 226

Of these, 150 were guaranteed just for completing the floors. That meant the average group only got 76 extra points from achievements, bonus objectives, and events. Once more, it had to be noted that this only counted groups who qualified for the Leaderboards by having nobody above level 210. If one counted the groups that had rushed through with a bunch of people in late-tier C-grade, then the points would have been far higher. A bunch of people at level 300 boosting one lower-leveled native from the 93rd Universe would have demolished the floors quite easily, after all, and gotten all the bonus points for speed.

Looking at the next Leaderboard, Jake was once more surprised.

Current Nevermore Points Record (Floors 1-5): 553

“Also lower than I expected,” Jake said.

“There, I concur,” the Sword Saint agreed.

They had gotten 465 Nevermore Points, and that had been by rushing through, so to see the top group only earn 88 more points than them was honestly surprising. Then again… considering how long it had been since the integration, it was doubtful any team from the new universe had even been close to reaching the maximum threshold yet. The groups going right now consisted of those with high levels of talent and high confidence, who only cared about racking up points on the later floors.

“Are there no Leaderboards that include the Challenge Dungeons?” the Fallen King asked inquisitively. “Or one that includes bonus points gained from any level-ups?”

“Doesn’t seem like it,” Jake said, shrugging.

“As I said… stingy.” The Sword Saint smiled and shook his head.

Either way, the Leaderboards were a bit disappointing, and their party of five quickly moved on.

Being at the central square and in the vicinity of Challenge Dungeons, they decided to check out the dungeon on this city floor. Yes, dungeon, singular. It appeared there was only a single Challenge Dungeon on this floor.

Oh, well. At least there would be more on later city floors. All Challenge Dungeons that would eventually become available could be entered from all city floors they encountered, and as they also all had limited attempts, it was often advised to wait to enter them. Considering one couldn’t truly die within the Challenge Dungeon, limited attempts were pretty much a requirement to make sure one couldn’t brute-force it, and honestly, giving people more than one try was already nice. On a side note, one could leave and enter, and attempts were only considered consumed if one chose to leave in the middle of a challenge or died.

Inspecting the one available dungeon, it appeared to be some kind of arena. Exactly what it was about, they naturally couldn’t know, but Jake looked forward to checking it out later on, as some arena battling seemed fun.

Unbeknownst to Jake, he would have his hopes of arena battles fulfilled sooner rather than later as they moved toward the sixth floor.

Now, when it came to how he would feel about these arena battles… that was an entirely different story.

In Nevermore City, activity was buzzing as always. Even during normal times, it was one of the areas in the multiverse with the most traffic, but with the recent integration, it had reached a new level. A new era did not only bring with it an age of new geniuses, but the wave of Records it sent echoing through the entire multiverse also benefitted the geniuses that already existed. This was a time for countless talents to compete, and those from the ninety-two other universes gladly rose to the occasion to challenge the newly integrated fighters.

But… even these geniuses still needed someone from the new universe to go with them if they wanted to compete on the new Leaderboards, where getting titles was far easier. Finding someone who would fit in the group was hard—especially someone who could keep up with the pace of a multiversal genius. Unless they themselves were supreme geniuses, of course. Or… if they, for some reason, were specially qualified for dealing with Nevermore.

Which was the exact scenario Casper found himself in. He had been busy working on New Yalsten with the others, and had reached C-grade only a week prior. Shortly after his evolution, he had been contacted by his Patron—the Blightfather—and given a direct task for the first time since the tutorial:

Go to Nevermore and be the one party member from the new universe in a group put together by the top brass of the Risen. Casper had expected to go to Nevermore with Priscilla and others from Earth, but when the order came from the Blightfather, he had no choice.

As for who he was going there with? As far as he could tell, the best the entire Risen faction had.

That day, Casper had arrived at the Risen compound at Nevermore. There, he had promptly been escorted to his four upcoming party members, all of whom had arrived beforehand. Casper couldn’t lie to himself and say he wasn’t nervous, as he could feel an aura ahead of him that surpassed his own by quite a margin.

Nevertheless...

Casper entered the room without seeing a need to knock, and a woman sitting close to the door looked his way. She was the only one at the entrance, with the others likely in some of the many side rooms.

“The Dungeon Engineer, huh?” She smiled, showing her fangs. She was some kind of beastkin Risen.

“That’s me,” Casper said noncommittally. He wasn’t exactly enthusiastic about being there.

“Well, ain’t you a peachy one?” The woman grinned even more as she jumped off the chair she had been lounging on and came closer. “Hey, I heard that new universes don’t have native undead. Is that true? Doesn’t that mean you are a newborn?”

“No.”

“No to you being a newborn, or no to no undead exis—”

“Maltrax, leave him be,” a voice spoke as a tall man entered the room.

The moment he did, Casper felt the atmosphere of the room change, and even Lyra was alarmed within his locket. The sheer level of blight energy he emanated… Casper knew who it was instantly.

He was the party leader of their group and the youngest Ghost King within the last billion years. A genius nurtured within the Ghostlands from birth, he’d been assessed as having a high chance of reaching godhood even in D-grade. He was, based on all Casper had heard, an absolute monster.

“I was just kidding around; no need to be so serious,” the undead beastkin woman said. “Though he does feel a bit too weak to join us, doesn’t he?”

“He is an engineer, is he not?” a third voice said, and then a woman wearing what looked like a wedding dress walked in. Thin, semitransparent cloth seemed to float around her, obscuring her form entirely beyond a faintly female outline. Her body gave off intense death energy.

“I am,” Casper said, nodding.

“Still, you should be strong, too,” the beastkin complained.

“You’re right; I vote for removing me from the group and me going back home,” Casper said semi-jokingly.

“Hehe, at least you have some guts,” the Ghost King said as his abyss-like eyes stared at Casper. “Name’s Azal. A pleasure to meet you… Casper, was it?”

Casper nodded, not surprised the other party didn’t really comment on his willingness to go back home. They both knew that nobody had any say in who was in this group.

Besides, Casper had not been selected for nothing. While Casper did fall behind the usual elites when it came to pure combat prowess, this was Nevermore, not some battlefield. This was a mega-dungeon, and Casper was a dungeon engineer. To be an engineer did not simply mean he was capable of making dungeons; it also allowed him to analyze dungeons when within them. To see the “code” behind their functions, and discover things a normal person couldn’t—most of it through system assistance.

This advantage became readily apparent upon entering the first floor.

The moment they appeared, Casper didn’t hesitate to kneel down and place his palm on the hot sand. The other undead shielded themselves and him from the life-infused sunlight as Casper closed his eyes. Thirty or so seconds later, he opened them again. “Are we going for any hidden events?”

“Are there any easy ones?” the woman in her ghostly wedding dress asked.

“No, not really; they are all time-consuming. Better to just go for the boss right away.” Casper shook his head. “Although, I would collect those fragments for the bonus objective. There are far more than is needed, and while chances are we would get an achievement for collecting far more than a thousand, I don’t believe that to be worth it either.”

“Where is the boss?” Azal asked.

Casper quickly took out a small orb and infused some energy into it before throwing it to the Ghost King. “Should take you straight to it, but for reference, it is straight down and through the planet.”

“Distance?” their fifth and final party member asked. He was a three-meter-tall, lank abomination with limbs not truly fitting together, and he wore an entirely black cloak, hiding his grotesque body.

Casper did a quick scan before sending the exact distance from them to the boss. The fabric of the dungeon was so easily readable on this first floor.

The lank abomination nodded as spears of bone embedded themselves in the sand all around him. Energy surged, space seemed to warp, and then, with a nod, he stepped back to let Azal enter the formation. A black abyss opened up beneath him as his body distorted, and he disappeared into the spatial tunnel digging straight through the planet.

Meanwhile, the ghostly bride had sent out an army of specters to collect Sunlight Fragments, joined by the beastkin woman.

Not even a minute after Azal disappeared—and less than ten minutes after entering the first floor—they got the achievement telling them of the death of the Floor Boss, and within less than an hour, they were off the floor and on to the second.

Casper simply went with the flow and did his job. He had heard Jake had also entered, and he couldn’t help but wonder how his speed compared to that of his old colleague and friend. Also, he did feel a bit sorry for Jake… because he had to be bored out of his mind dealing with these early floors.

Chapter 7

Impatience & A Witch's Evolution

Floors one to five had demonstrated pretty clear goals: Determine the dungeon divers’ ability to adapt to different environments and handle different enemy types. They’d also included a good deal of exploration, with a major part of each floor being the search for the exit.

Floors six to ten, on the other hand, had none of this. There were no difficult environments to adapt to, no mysteries about where one had to go, and no doubts about the objective. These five floors were all about one thing and one thing only: combat. At least on the surface.

Jake and the four others had appeared within the entrance area to a giant colosseum. Giant, in this case, was honestly not enough to describe the sheer size of the place, as it looked more like an entire city constructed in a donut shape with a large, open area in the middle. Entering the colosseum, their party was met by a guide who introduced them to the place and, along with the system message about the floor, told them all they had to know.

In order to move on to the next floor, they simply had to win ten battles and thus advance to the next rank. Contrary to earlier floors, floors six through ten were connected, and all shared the same arena theme. In fact, the guide would remain the same as they moved on to larger arenas and colosseums on the higher floors.

This setup did make earning bonus points harder, as there weren’t as many opportunities for achievements and bonus objectives. On floor six, the bonus objective required them to collect an adequate amount of in-depth information on at least five of their opponents, which was another aspect these floors had that the others didn’t: the opportunity to prepare.

It was possible to research your foes before entering the arena with them. They could discover facts about these opponents and their abilities, and since they decided to do the bonus objective on the sixth floor, they got a good idea of the scope. It was so in-depth that they even learned one of their opponents—a giant, kraken-like land monster—had an existing injury caused by a curse that they would be able to exploit. One of the battles was also against a party of five like their own. There, the Sword Saint ended up learning two of the party members used to be in a relationship. Without the girl knowing, the guy had cheated with the other girl in the party and broke it off, so if they revealed this to them before the fight, it would likely make them fight worse during the actual bout due to relationship drama.

So… yeah. That was a thing. Anyway, Jake and the others didn’t really need any of this information; they only gathered it for the bonus objective. The floor was also made more annoying by the fact that one could only fight in the arena once a day, and before winning a fight, Jake and the others would have no idea who their next opponent was or who to collect information on. All this resulted in them taking a bit over a month to do the floor, as they had to wait for information brokers and stalk people. All in all, it wasn’t a good time. Especially when they didn’t need what they learned at all. Every single fight on the sixth floor was utterly one-sided.

The only interesting thing was the achievements. On the sixth floor, they would get a bonus of between 1 and 6 Nevermore Points for every fight based on how much the audience liked it, and from what they learned, this would be the same on floors seven, eight, nine, and ten. This meant one could double the reward for passing every floor just by being entertaining.

Jake and Co ended up earning 45 points total for audience satisfaction, which was still pretty good. It turned out that a lot of people loved overpowered people doing overpowered stuff to utterly dominate their foes.

Floors seven, eight, nine, and ten were just more of the same, with the arenas getting bigger, the audience growing, and more points on the line. Floor seven had the same bonus objective of collecting information as floor six, but this time, they didn’t bother to do the bonus objective. They just did their fights as fast as they could, meaning they completed their ten fights—and thus, the seventh floor—in only ten days. Potential bonus points per battle had gone from 6 to 7, with Jake and the others doing even better than they had on the sixth floor.

They also learned that there was an achievement that gave the exact same points as the bonus objective for fighting without gathering any information, and another for completing the floor in ten days, meaning they had lost points by doing the information gathering on the sixth floor. So, yeah, they weren’t gonna do that again.

On floor eight, they decided to test a bit and did the fights solo rather than as a group. No fight so far had been harder than the Monarch of the Skies, so they all easily swept through the battles one by one, also completing this floor in only ten days. They got 78 out of 80 points for audience satisfaction, with the Fallen King and Dina being the only ones to lose points during their solo fights.

The two were—naturally so—bullied for this as they moved on to the ninth floor. Mostly the same as before, with them once more doing the fights solo for extra entertainment value. The only fight of interest here, from Jake’s point of view, was when he faced a party that had pretty interesting synergy and used mixes of water, lightning, and earth magic to lock down and kill. Not because Jake was in any real danger, but because it was his first time trying an instantly summoned lightning bath.

It was only when they reached the tenth floor that things changed again. This was the final colosseum, and once more, they had ten battles to finish. However, once they had completed the tenth battle, they unlocked the option to attempt a final event round, the same as on the fifth floor. This final battle would be against the current “champions” of the arena: a full party of humanoids.

Given that the levels of their opponents had increased, they decided against having anyone try to solo this final challenge. Not because they doubted that any one of them could do it, but because chances were it would take a while, and nobody wanted to wait around before moving on to later floors. Hence, all five of them entered the arena and utterly demolished the poor champions before moving on.

The constant one-day waits between fights had annoyed the hell out of Jake. Sylphie and the King also weren’t happy. Dina and the Sword Saint took it in stride, however. The Sword Saint enjoyed taking his time working on his profession by painting in between fights, and Jake learned that Dina spent their downtime tending to a garden within her spatial storage.

Jake also got some alchemy in, but that still left Sylphie and the Fallen King. Neither had professions, so all they could do was meditate or work on skills if they wanted to stay productive. Sylphie especially found this downtime difficult, as at least the King had lived long enough to not be bothered by the waiting. Sylphie, meanwhile, was used to constantly having something to do. Ultimately, she ended up sleeping most of the time while digesting the natural treasures she had eaten.

On the topic of the special puzzle cube that he had gotten as a gift at the Chosen ceremony, Jake held off on playing with it, as he feared he would find it too entertaining. He was confident later floors would have even more downtime or quiet periods, considering they had fifty entire years, so he would show patience and play with it when the time was right.

After floor ten was complete, they moved on to their second city layer. Points-wise, they’d gotten quite the increase.

Nevermore Points: 1512

They had done far more achievements than on the prior floors, as the only true judgment here was how well one fought. There were far fewer hidden points to be found, which was also reflected when they reached the Leaderboards on this floor and compared their score with the current record.

Current Nevermore Points Record (Floors 1-10): 1650

While they had been 88 behind on floor five, they were now only 138 behind, which meant they’d only lost 50 more than the top team. As for how well they did in comparison to the average party… well, the gap had only widened.

Average Nevermore Points (Floors 1-10): 706

As for this second city layer, it was even less populated than the first one by quite a margin. There was simply no reason to stay there, so they quickly moved on to floor eleven and beyond.

By now, Jake and company only had one priority: reach the harder floors as fast as possible. And with that mentality, they truly picked up speed and blazed through floor after floor.

“Is it heretical to want to rip a Chosen apart?” Miranda asked Lillian as they talked within a large tent set up near the Fort.

“Probably.” Lillian shrugged. “But I would assume it can be forgiven, considering the circumstances he put you in.”

“Yeah, let’s go with that,” Miranda said, smiling. Looking at the map on the table in front of her, she felt pretty damn stressed. After returning to Earth, things had been much more hectic than she would have liked, but honestly, not more than she’d expected.

One hundred and twenty million slaves. That was what she had to deal with, but at least she had been helped along by one thing: her C-grade evolution. That’s right—after returning from the Chosen ceremony, Miranda had finally chosen to evolve, and damn, was she glad she had waited, because she had a strong feeling her patience had paid off.

Her profession, at least, seemed to indicate this.

Court Witch of the Primordial’s Chosen – It is said that behind every influential leader is a court wizard—or in your case, a court witch—offering advice. As the foremost confidante of Jake Thayne, the Chosen of the Malefic Viper and Harbinger of Primeval Origins, you have taken upon yourself the task of operating as his liaison and right hand. Be it managing his territory, exerting his will upon the world, or simply interpreting and acting out his intent, you will find yourself well-equipped with your diverse set of skills. As your Records blend together with the Chosen and you continue to walk your Path, so shall success follow as you bathe in the shadow of greatness. Be warned that should you lose the confidence of the Primordial’s Chosen, you will not escape unscathed. Stat bonuses per level: +100 Willpower, +100 Free Points.

This profession was interesting and didn’t feel like a direct upgrade for the Mistress of Haven profession she’d had in D-grade. It still had many of the same aspects and was still inherently tied to Jake, but it also mixed in more aspects of who Miranda herself was. Just the fact that it was called Court Witch meant it was truly based on her and felt more personal. It had also gone beyond simply managing cities and territory, having removed the restriction of requiring her to defend the city of Haven—something she was quite relieved about, as the entire Ell’Hakan situation had put her on edge. It was honestly a miracle—or perhaps the plan of the enemy Chosen—that the city had remained under her control.

Now, after her evolution, she was only required to keep Jake confident in her… Something she had no idea how to do, and, for some reason, barely felt she even had to do. He cared for so little of what she did as long as she acted within his moral compass and didn’t do things to piss him off… Heck, she had a feeling she could dedicate the entire budget of the World Council to constructing a base on the moon, and all he would do was shrug and say “cool,” maybe even visiting for fun.

Another interesting note about this profession was how it referred to Jake. It placed side by side his roles as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper and the “Harbinger of Primeval Origins.” That the system chose to do this truly hammered home how impactful his feat of creating the True Royal had been, and the fact that everyone knew it now made the sheer level of Records matter so much more. This detail for the description was one of the reasons she felt confident that evolving after the ceremony counted, as she doubted she would have gotten a profession offering 200 stat points per level—only 40 below the theoretical maximum—without it.

As for her class, well, she wouldn’t complain about that one either.

Verdant Witch Sister – The Verdant Lagoon lies waiting, ready to listen to your beck and call, to consume any who dare stand in your way. Recognized as part of the coven’s sisterhood, the Verdant Witches truly view you as one of their own, and your connection to the Verdant Lagoon is more powerful than ever, allowing you to pull on powers from the ethereal domain. As a Verdant Witch, you are a spellcaster focusing on magic rituals and intricate spells, making preparation your key to victory. All who dare intrude upon your domain should tread carefully lest they find themselves swallowed by the Lagoon. Beware that should you lose the trust of the Verdant Witches and be cut off from the Verdant Lagoon, the consequences will be highly unpredictable and potentially fatal. However, if you succeed in your Path, you shall one day eternally claim a part of the Lagoon as your very own. Stat bonuses per level: +60 Will, +55 Wis, +45 Int, +30 Vit, +20 Per, +50 Free Points.

This class was also far better than she had in any way expected. 260 stat points per level was considered really good, even if it wasn’t absolutely top-tier.

Miranda hadn’t had the best profession or class in F-grade, average or maybe slightly above average in E-grade, good ones in D-grade, and now pretty excellent ones in C-grade. She knew that compared to someone like Jake, she still fell behind, but with every step, she was slightly closing the gap. One could get far, far more stat points in C-grade than all the grades before it combined—and even more so in B-grade, A-grade, and S-grade. It was possible to close the gap, with earlier disadvantages—and advantages—in lower grades mattering less and less as one progressed further.

When it came to the class itself, this one had naturally come due to her connection with the Verdant Witches. The fact that they had included her in important meetings, asked for her advice on how to “keep Jake happy,” and treated her like more than just a D-grade had led to this being offered. It indicated that she was moving at least a little closer to being considered an equal of the Godqueens. She still had a long way to go, but at least it was something.

As for what the class gave her, it was a bit more complicated. During her time with the witches, Miranda had learned that the Verdant Lagoon was a bit more than simply their divine realm. True, it was also their divine realm, and they had even created it, but the place had grown to resemble something greater. A conceptual existence, almost, that one could call upon. Maybe it was because they were witches, but even if they were “only” Godqueens, they were considered borderline invincible if one dared intrude upon their realm. A verdant witch like Miranda also pulled on the Verdant Lagoon and its mystical powers, allowing her to display feats above what she should actually be capable of, and if she became a god, a part of the Lagoon would come to be within her own divine realm, independent yet linked to the same concept utilized by the Sisters of the Verdant Lagoon.

All this is to say that her class was damn good, and Miranda was already working on better securing Earth by making use of it.

Anyway, her evolution had been done after the ceremony partly because it was time, and partly because she would need it to deal with what was to come. The slaves had not yet begun arriving—not only due to Miranda and Lillian stopping it, but also because it took the many factions time to set everything up.

As for why Miranda had stopped it… Well, quite a few reasons. First of all, getting accommodations for over a hundred million people was difficult, especially when one factored in that a lot of them would be lower grades that still needed food and whatnot. Seeing as they didn’t want to treat them badly, they also needed proper housing.

Then there was convincing the World Council that having them come was fine. Arthur had been receptive so far, but convincing him that bringing over a hundred million slaves wasn’t some invasion-level event wasn’t easy. She needed him on board to avoid widespread panic.

Oh, yeah, and they would also soon host representatives from the United Tribes. Those guests would require wholly different accommodations.

Did Miranda mention the issues popping up from the Fallen King effectively abandoning his domain, and the Sky Whale being busy dealing with that?

And the growing fanaticism spread by Felix after his return?

Miranda was still staring down at the map of the camp they were constructing to receive all the slaves when Lillian pointed something out.

“I heard that quite a few races don’t get along together, so would it be a good idea to avoid mixing the beastkin, humans, elves, and whatnot? Build natural dividers?”

“Oh… Oh, yeah, that too,” Miranda said, nodding. “Lillian, why did I agree to this job, again?”

“Because you are ambitious and, even if you don’t want to admit it, greedy for power and influence, and you recognize that riding Lord Thayne’s coattails is beneficial to achieving these goals?”

Miranda nodded again. “Right, right. Silly me.”

Chapter 8

Grinding Through the Floors as Competition Tightens

Due to the inability to receive concrete information about the floors of Nevermore, no one knew how many there even were in the C-grade section. Jake and Co naturally didn’t know either, but they could infer based on how slowly the levels of enemies increased. To see the average levels of enemies go up by 1 to 3 per floor was expected, which meant the “easy” section of Nevermore they’d planned on blazing through was much longer than they had initially predicted.

Nevertheless, they went through with impressive speed and cleared floor after floor, the levels of their foes slowly increasing.

Floor fifteen had a Floor Boss at level 224, with the optional event boss at only 235.

Floor twenty, level 232 for the Floor Boss, event boss only at 240.

Floor twenty-five, Floor Boss level 238, event boss 245.

Floor thirty, Floor Boss 245, event boss 250.

This seemed like a semi-rapid increase to some, but one had to put it into perspective.

Jake, on his lonesome, had managed to take down the Hive King and Hive Queen, which had both been above level 270, so for him to face level 250s—even if they were event bosses—wasn’t too difficult, as he had also grown stronger since then. The Fallen King displayed power equal to Jake’s, the Sword Saint hadn’t needed to get serious yet, and Sylphie and Dina were easily doing their jobs.

Some of the floors they encountered could be cheesed, entirely circumventing the challenges they offered, but generally, they just had to face whatever challenge was provided head-on. Once they began encountering floors more like the first ones, in which a big part of the task was finding the Floor Boss, Jake finally bit the bullet and did his damn job as the resident hunter of the group…

He started tracking.

While sending out seed soldiers or having Jake fly really high up and scout was effective, it was far from the most efficient approach. With that in mind, Jake took out his old tracking skill and got to work.

The first thing he identified was that all Floor Bosses did indeed have unique advantages in the form of increased resources. This was important for the next part, which related to a particular… trait to their energy signature. Once Jake figured this out, things got a lot easier, as he no longer had to search broadly for powerful energy signatures, but instead for a singular aspect of a mana signature.

Jake also began to truly embrace his instinctual nature when tracking. He began to trust his intuition more, relying less on physical evidence and more on faint, nearly undetectable traces of auras left behind. His ability to recognize these auras was something he’d worked on with the Fallen King, as the Unique Lifeform could often detect “echoes” of presences yet had no way to properly differentiate them. Jake did.

By floor thirty, Jake had gone from being a shitty hunter in the tracking department to quite a proficient one, which was also reflected by his new tracking skill.

[Traditional Hunter’s Tracking (Uncommon)] - The Hunter does not sit silently in his lodge but actively hunts for his prey. Unlocks proficiency in tracking down prey based on limited clues left behind, including both magical and physical ones. Also allows the Hunter to more easily identify characteristics of the game, including mana signatures and aura. Allows the Hunter to more easily distinguish and analyze physical tracks. Adds a bonus to the effect of Perception while tracking.

-->

[Bestial Hunter’s Tracking (Epic)] – The Hunter tracks his prey with his mind; the beast tracks through instinct. You use both. Grants high proficiency in tracking down prey as long as you know their basic signatures, be they physical or magical. Makes it far easier to distinguish different kinds of tracks. Relying on your instincts, you are capable of picking up tracks and clues about your prey that others may be unable to, and while tracking, all your senses can be focused on the act. Adds a noticeable bonus to the effect of Perception while tracking.

Two skill upgrades later, the Floor Bosses could no longer hide. Not that they tried to, and even if they had, it wouldn’t have helped; Jake’s extreme Perception allowed him to track them down regardless of simplistic attempts to obscure their locations.

This ability to track down targets far quicker sped up the non-linear floors significantly, but even then, it still took them a long time to reach the city floor after floor thirty. Fourteen months and a few days, to be accurate, if one counted from when they’d first entered Nevermore.

While Jake had not gotten any levels out of the first five floors, and only a single level in his profession from the next five, doing twenty more floors with ever-increasing levels over so many months still resulted in some progress.

Jake wouldn’t have called it fast, considering how long it had taken, but it wasn’t terrible either, if one took into account the time often required to level in C-grade.

For his profession, he had ended up netting six levels since entering Nevermore—a bit more than one every four months.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 207 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 210 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

With him barely doing any alchemy outside of when they had downtime and primarily experimenting whenever he did do alchemy, it wasn’t that bad, honestly.

Between the still relatively low level of the enemies he faced, and the fact that he was doing everything with a party, there had been little to challenge them so far. Due to that, they got fewer levels. Still, he had gotten a total of six levels in his class, so it wasn’t all bad.

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 204 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 209 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

Naturally, that had also come with race levels.

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 205 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 209 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Annoyingly, despite his progress, this still put Jake below the level 210 limit… The only one in his party.

[Fallen King – lvl 214]

[Juvenile Sylphian Hawk– lvl 222]

[Dryad – lvl 212]

[Human – lvl 211]

It had rapidly become clear that Jake earned less experience than everyone else. Sylphie leveled up far faster than the others, yet Jake knew this was partly due to her still “growing,” as she was only a juvenile. That, coupled with all the treasures she had consumed throughout their exploration of the many floors, meant her progress was not too surprising.

Then there was the Fallen King, who was also a monster and could consume natural treasures to gain experience. However, compared to Sylphie, the King was far more fastidious and only consumed very specific items, and the items he did want were often ones Sylphie also wanted.

The Sword Saint and Dina outpaced Jake’s leveling speed simply due to the difference in their Paths. Dina was also part monster, and she could level her race passively, but according to her, it had no impact. As a dryad, her way of leveling passively included “taking roots” and sitting still for a few centuries. Thus, her fast levels were due to her druidic nature, and her supporting the group with different magical buffs and whatnot still had a tangible impact, even in easier fights.

When it came to the old man, his class just didn’t have the same demerits as Jake’s, even if he did express that he got more out of duels rather than group battles.

Jake was a bit miffed at finding himself the lowest-leveled individual, but it was made up for by reaching the city layer after the thirtieth floor, where they once more made their way to the Leaderboards.

One thing they had earned in spades during this descent was Nevermore Points. The growth in this department had been quite substantial, with the last twenty floors nearly increasing their total tenfold.

Nevermore Points: 14,622

Honestly, looking at the points made Jake feel a bit silly for even caring about whatever they might have missed on earlier floors. What truly mattered was completing more floors than anyone else to get high scores; the biggest achievements always seemed to come from doing the hardest challenges. The prevalence of these event bosses on every floor before a city meant that unless a group was good at fighting, they would miss out on a lot.

Putting it into perspective, just completing floors twenty-six through thirty had earned them 1400 points without any bonus objectives, achievements, or events. 1400 was nearly as many as they had earned on floors one through ten, truly hammering home how much the points from later floors mattered in contrast to earlier ones.

As for how this compared to the average? Well, quite favorably.

Average Nevermore Points (Floors 1-30): 5503

Jake wasn’t quite sure what to think about this average. It seemed so unbelievably low, but then again, the average was indeed just the average. He did wonder when they would stop seeing a true average due to a lack of participants, but clearly they hadn’t reached that quite yet.

As for why Jake felt better about his level after seeing the Leaderboards… Well, it was due to the final one. Had they taken the top spot yet? No, but they were pretty damn close.

Current Nevermore Points Record (Floors 1-30): 14,954

332 Nevermore Points. That was all that separated Jake’s party from the current record-holders. One good achievement or event away from claiming the top spot.

Jake had talked to the others, surmising that it probably wasn’t the same team who had the top score on these floors. Chances were that by floor thirty, the people who could get a high score and had also already gone so deep this early in the integration were people like Jake and his group, who wanted to rush to the later levels to get as many points as possible. Fifty years was a long time, but Jake and company had already burned through a year and three months. No one knew what kind of levels they would encounter later on, potentially including those with mandatory waiting periods like the arena. Floors eleven to thirty had all been relatively simple—just big worlds with different objectives and no big scenarios—meaning they’d finished them rather quickly. There had only been one partial water level, too…

Standing and looking at the Leaderboards, the Sword Saint noted something. “Pretty empty here, isn’t it?” the old man spoke while looking around.

They were the only ones standing in the massive square in front of the large Leaderboards, with only empty buildings surrounding them. Well, mostly empty.

“There are a few people around, but they seem to mostly be scouts or something,” Jake said, shrugging. “All of them are high level, too, so they probably don’t expect to be detected.”

The Sword Saint smiled. “I merely find it peculiar that the difference is so stark.”

The city after floor twenty-five had been surprisingly populated—far more so than even the ones after floors fifteen and twenty.

“Well… there are only so many C-grades from the new universe, right?” Dina said. “If they are good enough to bring to floor thirty, don’t you want those C-grades to keep going and not settle down?”

“I guess that is possible,” Jake said.

“It is also possible they simply travel back to floor twenty-five,” the Fallen King said. “Is it not pointless to perform major constructions and invest in every single city layer when travel between the layers is so easy?”

“They do it for the prestige.” The Sword Saint smiled again. “To be on a higher floor is a show of power.”

“Ree,” Sylphie chimed in.

“Good point,” Jake said, nodding as he translated. “Same as how the best birds get the highest nests in the trees and can look down on the worse birds while not getting pooped on.”

“That… kind of makes sense?” Dina said, a bit confused.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched, offended.

“Yeah, of course you always make sense.” Jake smiled as he rubbed her feathers.

“Sure…” Dina muttered, not entirely convinced. Overall, their group dynamic had improved over all these months, and Dina had opened up more. She was still pretty shy, but by now, Jake was certain that was pretty much just her personality.

“Let’s proceed to the next floor. Hopefully, the difficulty will begin to spike soon.” The Fallen King’s impatience had clearly grown over this period.

“Yeah, let us,” Jake agreed. Seeing as there were no complaints, the group proceeded to the next gateway leading toward the next floor. They all shared the hope that things would get harder from here and offer a proper challenge.

Little did they know that the thirty-first floor was the first major roadblock for most parties, even the extremely talented ones, and they were about to encounter something quite a bit different than any prior floors.

Since Jake and his party were busy diving further and further into Nevermore, they were unaware of the competition that had now begun arriving in Nevermore City. The records they had seen on the Leaderboards on floors five, ten, fifteen, and twenty had all been surpassed by new parties diving into the dungeons. Whether that was due to the Chosen of the Malefic Viper entering or simply the invisible hand of the system at work, no one knew. All they did know was that a time of competition had truly arrived in Nevermore, with pinnacle groups appearing from all over the multiverse one by one.

Yip of Yore’s Chosen, Ell’Hakan—the disciple of the former champion of Nevermore in the last era—entered shortly after the Chosen of the Malefic Viper.

Ghost King Azal, one of the most talented Risen ever seen, arrived shortly after.

High Justiciar Elevian entered with the Augur of Hope, Jacob, as the representative from the new universe.

Warlord Davion of Valhal entered with a party of supreme elites, including his mandatory party member from the new universe, a Runemaiden named Carmen. Since she was simply the person from the new universe they needed to enter, there were few expectations of her, yet the first thing she did after arriving in Nevermore City was enter the arena. A hundred consecutive victories later, she was dragged away by her party to enter the dungeon, albeit with little doubt remaining about her skill.

Countless other factions arrived within weeks of each other, many of them not even advertising their participation. It was suspected that nearly all major factions sent several elite groups, with the Order of the Malefic Viper sending additional parties only two weeks after the Chosen had entered, led by the Malefic Dragonkin Draskil.

Several independently powerful people also made their entrance. Three additional Unique Lifeforms after the Fallen King were spotted, two of which hailed from the new universe. The United Tribes appeared to have allied with one of these darlings of the multiverse, making many also consider them contenders for the top spot on the Leaderboards.

When the usual information brokers began to believe no more exceptional groups would appear, a surprise addition stepped out of one of the public teleporters in Nevermore City. This particular faction, despite its prominence, did not have a permanent compound in Nevermore.

A party had arrived from the Dao Sect, the organization founded by the Primordial known as the Daofather. They were a faction that rarely sent people to Nevermore, as they preferred to isolate themselves from the rest of the multiverse. They even had a philosophy contrary to most norms, viewing killing as something to be avoided unless absolutely necessary.

Yet they had shown up, and they had shown up in force. The high-level information brokers quickly gathered information on four of the individuals in the group, all of which were personal disciples of gods. Still, when it came to the apparent leader of this group, they had difficulties. They knew he had to be from the new universe, as none of the other four were.

In the few hours this group spent in Nevermore City before entering the dungeon, these information brokers learned only two things about this mysterious leader.

First, he was the Chosen of one of the twelve Daolords of the Dao Sect: the Lifesoul Daolord. A true pinnacle god.

Second, a name. Not a Daoist title, which the members of the Dao Sect liked to adopt, but an actual name:

Eron.

Chapter 9

Minaga's Labyrinth

The thirty-first floor felt different from the moment they arrived. They walked out of the gateway and into a large chamber that looked like part of some temple, with white pillars lining the walls and a large, elevated stone platform in the middle. Towards the other end of the chamber was a massive gate with a glowing rune on it, emanating impressive power. Through his sphere, Jake also felt that outside of these chamber walls, only the void existed, meaning they were definitely not meant to try and go there. Not that he even thought they could, as the walls gave him the feeling they were practically indestructible.

However, none of these things explained why this place felt different. The explanation for that came from the mana in the air… Rather than being the usual environmental mana, this was not in any way natural. After exchanging a glance with the Fallen King and feeling Sylphie shuffle a bit on his shoulder, he knew they all felt it.

This was the domain of a living being, or perhaps even the interior of some creature’s body—though that didn’t seem likely, considering the void outside the walls. No, chances were they’d entered a claimed domain akin to a world formed by a high-grade space mage.

As they all took in the environment, the introduction to the floor appeared.

Welcome to the thirty-first floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: N/A

Current progress: End reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 14,622

Staring at the message, one thing instantly occurred to Jake: This was the first floor without a bonus objective. Perhaps that meant achievements and bonus events were also limited on this floor. Seeing the name, though, Jake felt quite a bit more confident. Labyrinth… Jake was good at labyrinths.

Jake was about to speak, but he stopped himself when he faintly felt a new presence appear.

“Welcome, welcome, welcome! Oh, I am so excited to have some more visitors! Such esteemed guests, too!” The jovial voice echoed as the entire chamber lit up. A light show featuring all the colors of the rainbow played out along the walls, and on the central platform, a figure appeared as space warped.

Jake was instantly on alert once he observed the being.

Blue skin, two legs, and two arms. A generally humanoid form, making Jake almost mistake them for a blue human. Yet the creature had four eyes on its head, a large mouth, no nose, and, instead of hair, short tendrils grew out of its scalp, wriggling slightly every time the creature spoke. A loose-fitting blue robe covered its body, held in place only by a belt. This meant Jake couldn’t see if the creature had any other peculiar features hidden beneath.

“My name is Minaga, your glorious host. Truly a pleasure to make your acquaintance.” The creature flashed a big smile as he looked at Jake and the others, and then the entire light show died down.

Jake used Identify and was taken aback.

[Minaga – lvl 275]

He knew, without a shadow of a doubt, that this Minaga was more powerful than any C-grade he had ever stood before. Definitely stronger than anything in Nevermore… which did make Jake wonder why he—Jake was pretty sure the creature identified as male—had shown up at the beginning of this floor.

While Jake pondered this, he felt the Fallen King tense up at his side when the creature laid eyes on him, and as the being spoke… he understood why.

“Oh, a fellow Unique Lifeform? How fun, how fun.” Minaga looked down at the Fallen King for a few moments before shifting his gaze to Jake. “And a C-grade Chosen of the Malefic Viper? Even a Transcendent? Oh, is that a mutated version of Nature’s Attendant’s Bloodline? Interesting, interesting… but not quite as interesting as you, Sylphian Hawk! Never even heard of your race before! I know Sylphs, but… Oh, wait, too much information, right? Ha ha!”

“I am beginning to get the feeling you have not shown up before us as an opponent,” the Sword Saint spoke as he bowed. “I am Miyamoto.”

“Right on!” Minaga said with a grin. “As I said, I am your host! It is your honor and your privilege to have me let you go through the wonderful labyrinth that I have spent oh so long constructing.”

“Are you a dungeon master of some kind?” Jake asked curiously. “Do you perhaps work for the Wyrmgod and made this floor for him?”

Based on how this Unique Lifeform spoke, he obviously knew of the outside world, meaning he was likely someone who had existed on the outside before this. Perhaps someone who had just entered Nevermore around the last integration.

“I work with, not for the Wyrmgod, but otherwise, your assessment is correct… Jake, was it?”

“I never told you my name.”

“Right, you didn’t. Anyway, let’s get this show on the road!”

“Who are you?” the King asked, refusing to let the topic go.

“I am alpha and omega, the beginning and the end, but more commonly just known as Minaga. Oh, well, I guess—seeing as you are all pretty influential people—I can give a small hint. I know who you all are, and you know so little about me, so it’s only fair. I am the creator of this labyrinth, and I am more than you see before you right now. But most importantly, I like to snack on mana berries.” He ended with a grin.

“Very informative.” Jake shook his head. “Either way, you seem to know about us, and you are not particularly willing to tell us much about you, but can you at least tell us what we are meant to do here? Seeing as the gate behind you is still shut, I assume we must have you open it?”

“Straight to the point! I like it! Unlike Vilastromoz, who never likes getting to the point… unless the point is a poisoned needle he pricks you with, in which case he can be a bit too happy getting to the point…” Minaga gave an overdramatic sigh. “But you are right. See, I wanted to make this entire thing a bit more interesting, so before you enter my labyrinth, you have a choice to make!”

Opening his arms, the entire room lit up once more. Five giant pillars of light descended from nowhere, each containing a large, floating rune that corresponded to a word. Jake quickly checked them all from left to right.

Initiate – Apprentice – Adept – Mage – Archmage

“Seeing as we are all smart people, I don’t think I have to explain to you what we have there. That’s right… It is, of course, different difficulties! A floor with multiple difficulty levels from the very beginning is quite innovative, eh?” Minaga asked this rhetorically and with clear pride. “Naturally, it’s a great idea. I came up with it, after all. Alright, alright, it isn’t overly original, but you didn’t see it on any prior floors, now, did you? So, any questions?”

“When you say difficulty level, how exactly does it impact the floor?” the Sword Saint asked.

“In every way,” Minaga said, smiling. “Size, danger, enemy level, more powerful variants, the bosses, complexity of the labyrinth. It is quite an extensive makeover. Also, it isn’t just this floor. My labyrinth is kind of big, so I decided it should take up ten floors to make it more fun.”

Jake frowned upon hearing it was ten floors… Wasn’t there meant to be a city layer after floor thirty-fiv—

“You are probably thinking, ‘but isn’t there a city layer after floor thirty-five?’ And you are right that there should be, but you see, I decided to make it a part of the labyrinth! Once more, innovation at its finest. Now, which difficulty do you all want? Do note that you can only lower or increase it by one level every time you enter a new floor.”

There wasn’t really any need to discuss it, was there? Jake quickly exchanged a glance with the others and was about to answer when their “host” spoke once more.

“Actually, why do I even ask? You are, of course, going for the Archmage difficulty, right?” Minaga tilted his head while looking at them. “If you didn’t, that would be pretty darn pathetic, considering your party setup. Oh, and also, doing it all on the Archmage difficulty gives the best rewards, so I highly recommend it. Maybe there is even something special at the end if you do it all on the highest difficulty… Hint, hint.”

“Can’t see why we wouldn’t go for the Archmage difficulty.” Jake shrugged. “It isn’t like Nevermore was particularly challenging before this. Wait, unless choosing the highest difficulty means submerging the entire labyrinth underwater…”

“No worries, no worries, no water theme here,” Minaga said, shaking his head. “You know, I never even liked these water-themed floors. Yet the Wyrmgod insists on having them every damn era for some silly reason. Sure, you can argue it is unfair for aquatic lifeforms that Nevermore doesn’t really cater to them, but it isn’t like the system doesn’t go out of its way to help them deal with the harsh reality of dry land.”

“Well, great… How do we select the difficulty?” Jake asked, glad that the Unique Lifeform had at least some idea of how to design a proper dungeon floor.

“You already have.” Minaga grinned as four of the pillars disappeared, leaving only the final one in place. It lit up with intense light before exploding in a cascade of multicolored wisps, bathing the chamber. Their host looked damn proud of the display as he smiled at the group.

“With that done, good luck to you all! Ah, and Jake, don’t worry too much about all that Yip of Yore business; I am sure you got it covered! Then again, I will definitely say the exact same thing to Ell’Hakan when he appears and tell him not to worry about you, but don’t let that take away from me encouraging you right now! You dying would also make a bunch of factions sad—especially the Endless Empire—so just don’t die inside my labyrinth, alright?” In his usual jovial tone, Minaga added, “Dealing with complaints is so annoying. Now, let the challenge begin! Don’t get too lost inside, okay?”

With those words, the grand gate behind him opened. Jake stared at the creature while processing what he had just said and his clearly contemporary information. Minaga gave them a final grin and a farewell before slowly fading away.

“I’ll be watching with high expectations! Oh, and of course, remember to have fun!”

Once he was gone and the path forward was open, the Fallen King scoffed. “What an insufferable creature,” the Unique Lifeform said, complaining about… the other Unique Lifeform.

“I thought he was kind of funny…” Dina said, a bit unsure.

“This creature is clearly not some random dungeon monster or Floor Boss, and he seems fully aware of what is happening in the outside world in real time,” the Sword Saint mused. “The level of 275 is clearly not accurate either, though he did register to me as truly only at that level.”

“Maybe some kind of cloning skill?” Jake wondered aloud. “Or perhaps summoning of some kind. There could be a lot of explanations. Shit, maybe he just has an earpiece and has someone talking in his ear, telling him what to do and say.”

“I don’t,” the voice of Minaga suddenly echoed through the room.

They all stood silently for a few seconds until it became clear the damn guy had no intentions of saying anything more or otherwise reappearing.

“As I said, absolutely insufferable,” the King once more said.

“Ree?” Sylphie tilted her head.

“Yeah, I also think the comedic timing was pretty good,” Jake said. “The Fallen King is just mad this Unique Lifeform is more unique than him. But I do agree it would be fun to prove him wrong.”

“Good luck with that!”

Jake smiled at the encouraging voice as he looked towards the gate leading onwards. “Oh, we won’t need luck.”

“He, he… I think you will. Did I forget to mention one of the more interesting properties of my little labyrinth?”

Something came out of the gate leading into the labyrinth as he said this. A dense bluish mist or perhaps fog entered the room, and Jake frowned as it slowly reached them. Seeing through the fog was incredibly difficult; Jake found his vision limited to only a few hundred meters ahead of him. And he was the best off due to his high Perception stat.

The others could barely see a few dozen meters ahead, with even skills getting limited. More than that, Jake felt like the atmosphere was somehow denser. Wanting to test the environment, he tried using One Step, but rather than teleporting to the other side of the room, he only moved eight or so meters.

“Not that easy, huh?” Minaga said jokingly. “This is a special something I cooked up so this labyrinth wouldn’t be so easily passed. Space mages are damn annoying and find ways to surpass things, and scouting skills would nullify much of the challenge, so I got rid of them. Oh, and hey, seeing as none of you seem into that divination stuff, I guess I can share that I even created false flags and whatnot to make divination actively harmful. I know, I know, my genius once more shines through. Ah, but don’t worry—the rooms with fighting in them don’t have the mist present, only the hallways.”

“Are you going to narrate and keep talking throughout this entire labyrinth?” Jake asked.

“A privilege, is it not?”

“More like an added challenge through constant auditory mental attacks,” Jake said jokingly while shaking his head.

“You know, the vast majority of people really avoid saying anything negative aloud, as they are afraid I will up the difficulty or think I have some other way to screw them over. To clarify, I do. Not that I am actually offended; a bit of banter is what makes the world spin. Besides, if any of you were negatively, tangibly affected simply by my talking, then that seems more like a you-problem and less of a me-problem. In which case, I would simply view the situation as me helping you overcome your weak mentality. Or watch you die. A lot of people that weak-minded usually just die.”

“Sure, sure.” Jake nodded as he turned and looked at the others through the blue mist. “Let’s get going?”

“Let us,” the Sword Saint agreed.

None of them wanted to delay more than necessary, so they moved into Minaga’s Labyrinth through the giant gate. The hall they entered was massive, nearly twenty meters across and forty meters high, with an arched ceiling. Jake watched out for traps using his sphere as they walked through but spotted nothing.

Seeing as it was relatively safe, they picked up the pace and rushed through straight ahead. Rushed, in this case, was not actually that fast, as none of their movement-related skills worked properly. Even just running wasn’t as fast as it should be due to the mist. On their way, they encountered several side paths but kept going forward until, soon enough, they met another large magical gate. Studying it, Jake saw that it had four magic seals on it.

“Oh, what is this? A sealed gate you must pass to keep moving forward? Looks like you will need four keys to unlock it. Where could these keys be? Perhaps some of the side paths you passed earlier lead to rooms that may offer a key, or maybe they lead to dead ends or traps. I guess you will have to go check.”

Jake stared at the gate and slowly nodded. All kinds of perception-related abilities were limited. Sylphie even complained about the wind being completely silent. This place was designed to force people to slowly explore each path. Of course… there was one thing Minaga could not address.

Closing his eyes, Jake focused and took a deep breath. A Pulse of Perception echoed out of his being as he opened his eyes again and smiled.

It was time to take their dear host down a peg.

Chapter 10

The Devil is in the Details

“Lucky bunch! Found your way to the first room right off the bat without encountering any dead ends! Now to find the key… if there even is one here!” Minaga kept up his usual glee as Jake and company walked out of what looked like a wall of fog and entered a massive chamber. As their host had explained, these large chambers did not have any of the usual mist, and it felt liberating to finally be free of the restrictive environment.

On second thought, merely calling the chamber they had entered massive was a bit fallacious. It was pretty darn humongous—at least a good hundred kilometers deep, with a width of about two kilometers. This narrowness was heavily used, as what appeared in the distance was a large, derelict-looking castle with plenty of defenses.

In front of the castle, a dozen rows of ramparts went from wall to wall, and every one of these walls was filled with creatures. Taking a deep breath, Jake could practically smell the death energy emanating from the chamber—which made sense, considering the enemies he saw on the ramparts.

Using Identify, the theme was pretty damn obvious.

[Skeleton Swordsman – lvl 240]

[Skeleton Spearman– lvl 240]

[Skeleton Marksman – lvl 240]

[Skeleton Mage – lvl 240]

[Skeleton Captain – lvl 245]

“Skeletons, huh,” Jake muttered. “So original.”

He and the others waited for a few seconds, but nothing came. Jake looked at the ceiling of the chamber, wondering if their dear host had decided to leave, but he still felt them being observed. Maybe he didn’t talk while they were inside the chambers?

“I assume there is some kind of boss here,” the Sword Saint said.

“Let me check real quick,” Jake said as he jumped and summoned his wings. He flew all the way to the ceiling in little time and peered past the many ramparts towards the castle. There, standing on a large tower atop the castle, was a large skeleton in fine ivory armor surrounded by several Skeleton Captains.

[Skeleton Bonelord – lvl 250]

“Found it… Level 250 at the central castle,” Jake said through the Golden Mark left by the King. “Likely the one with the key. If not, it should be easy to find if we make it to the castle.”

Now, why was Jake so sure the key was there in the room?

Finding the room itself had been pretty simple using his Pulse of Perception. Throughout the last fifteen months in Nevermore, Jake had used far more pulses than ever before, allowing him to slowly build up more and more resistance to the point where he could now do it pretty comfortably at regular intervals without getting a headache.

On the way, they avoided dozens of dead-end paths, traps, and hallways that would make you walk in circles for a few hours, if not days, while heading straight for this large one.

However, this wasn’t the only room he saw. In fact, Jake spotted four during their run, but this was the only one he had bothered entering, which led back to the original question… Why was he so sure the key was in this room and not any of the prior ones? The answer was easy: intuition.

Jake didn’t just have his sphere in his arsenal of cheats. He also had all his other totally balanced advantages. His intuition had told him this was the room to check out, so even if Minaga tried to muddy the water by hinting that maybe the key wasn’t there, Jake didn’t listen.

Looking at the boss in the distance, Jake pulled out his bow and took aim while charging an Arcane Powershot. He saw no reason not to rush through this room and move on quickly, and on the way there, he and the others had agreed to do things fast. Jake wanted to get a good opening shot on the boss, and if they had to face every enemy on the floor at once, so be it.

After he had sufficiently charged the attack, he let go of the string, releasing an explosion of arcane energy as his arrow of destruction surged forward. He had expected it to soar toward the boss and potentially even blow it off the tower, but things did not go as expected. The second the arrow appeared above the first of the many defensive ramparts leading further into the room, a barrier sprang up, making Jake’s arrow explode. The shimmering white wall of energy hadn’t taken any damage apart from a few cracks.

Below, on the rampart, Jake saw over fifty Skeleton Mages stand and channel with their staves, led by a captain also holding a staff. The barrier extended up from the ramparts but did not cover the gate leading below, making it quite apparent you were meant to through there and not use ranged attacks from afar. In essence, Minaga wanted to force them into melee.

“Seems like we will have to go through each rampart individually,” the Sword Saint said, having seen Jake’s failed attack.

“Or continue to bombard the barrier until it breaks,” Jake offered.

“There are too many… It will be faster to just go through directly,” the old man said dismissively.

“I concur with the swordsman; trying to destroy each barrier individually is a waste of time,” the Fallen King agreed. “It isn’t like the alternative will be that much more difficult.”

Jake surrendered to their will and put away his bow, then flew downwards to join his party, which was already charging the first rampart. When they got close, the mages stopped channeling energy into the barrier and faced them in combat. Nearly a hundred melee-focused skeletons stood in defensive stances just past the gate.

The two groups clashed—one with hundreds of skeletons twenty to thirty levels above their opponents, and the other consisting of three humanoids, a bird, and a Unique Lifeform. The result was as expected.

Bones went flying everywhere as a giant golden hammer smashed sideways through a crowd of skeletons. Crescent waves of water cut bones apart and sent limbs flying. Arcane explosions bombarded all the Skeleton Mages as arrows fell from the sky and roots shot up from the ground, making them unable to dodge.

On the second rampart in the distance, nearly a hundred Skeleton Marksmen released a rain of arrows, but the attacks were all met with a green whirlwind that scattered their attack. Without even bothering to make sure they finished off all the skeletons, their party moved forward while staying close to each other to avoid getting ganged up on.

The second rampart met a similar fate, followed by the third and the fourth. At the fifth, the entire wall was torn apart when the Fallen King released a golden beam of energy to blow away all the skeletons guarding it. Jake, not wanting to be outdone, went HAM at the sixth one, using a fully charged Arcane Powershot to one-shot the captain while blowing up several more skeletons unlucky enough to stand too close. Joining in on the fun, the Sword Saint led the push on the seventh, using his Rainblade to release a torrent of slashes that killed dozens of skeletons within a minute while also taking down the captain. Sylphie and Dina didn’t get to take down a rampart solo, seeing as Jake, the King, and the Sword Saint all felt competitive while facing the remaining five, going all-out until they finally reached the castle.

With a roar, the Bonelord released its aura. All the remaining skeletons seemed to get some kind of buff. The captains around the boss also seemed to get stronger as they jumped off the tower and ran down the side of the castle walls towards Jake and company.

One of them was blasted into the wall by an arrow before it had even gotten a quarter of the way, with a second getting embedded by a substantial wave of force. The Bonelord seemed angry and jumped off the tower, too. It then pulled out a giant axe of bones and began flying at high speed directly toward Dina, who was manipulating a forest of vines to rip apart skeletons chasing them from behind.

The Bonelord never even got close. The Sword Saint met it mid-air, and after a brief exchange of blows, it was forced back with a few cuts on its otherwise pristine armor yet largely unharmed. What little injuries it had taken rapidly healed as it released a dense white aura of pure death energy. All around it, the death mana from the many slain skeletons began to gather and empower the Bonelord, which then resumed its attack on the old swordsman.

The two of them had a pretty damn ferocious battle for several minutes. All the while, the Sword Saint failed to get any substantial advantage, even after he made slight use of his boosting skill. Jake ended up joining in when the constant army of skeletons storming out from within the castle started to die down, and Dina handled all those chasing after them from the earlier ramparts. Sylphie and the Fallen King would also soon be done with the captains and join them.

Together, Jake and the Sword Saint managed to push back the Bonelord despite it constantly healing and getting empowered by every skeleton that died around them. It was burning through energy at a ludicrous pace, as Jake counted himself blowing off the Bonelord’s head at least ten times. It kept fighting with its axe and released death-affinity attacks and ranged bone spurs, occasionally forcing the two of them on the defensive.

When Sylphie joined them—the King had the remaining skeletons handled—they finally managed to get the decisive blow, and soon enough, the Bonelord stopped regenerating and died. The second it fell, the wisps of deathly fire burning within the eyes of all the skeletons were also snuffed out. The remaining soldiers collapsed like marionettes with their strings cut.

As the body of the Bonelord crumbled to dust, a magical rune floated up from its body before flashing and disappearing. Jake faintly saw that a small tattoo of the same rune had appeared on the back of his hand. Needless to say, this was one of the keys.

“Let’s go,” Jake said, and they rushed out of the room towards where the next key was. When they made it back to the hallway, the disembodied voice of Minaga once more joined them.

“You know, that was pretty damn good! Made it look easy. There was even a key for you! Three more to go, and you can open the gate and continue. You got lucky once, but I shall still wish you luck in having a repeat!”

Rushing out of the second room with the second key in hand, leaving a crumbling volcano and hundreds of dead lava and earth elementals in their wake, their dear host spoke again.

“I must say, you are quite a lucky bunch! Straight from one room holding a key into the next! Almost makes me think you found a way to circumvent all my checks and balances and aren’t just getting extremely lucky, but that can’t be, right? Nah, definitely not, so watch out for traps and find the right path to the next key… if you can!”

“See, something unlikely happening two times is a coincidence, but three times? Now, that is a pattern. Then again, some people are really just that lucky, you know? Even I cannot get around some of the more intangible aspects of this world, and I guess it is entirely possible you merely have increased luck or perhaps some kind of reality-bending skill? Though my mist would stop that… Hm… I guess there is also that… Nah, that is too much of an assumption!”

“So, by now, I think we all know this isn’t how things are supposed to work, and you clearly found a way to not only learn the layout of the labyrinth, but also correctly determine which rooms hold keys, which is honestly impressive. See, if you, my dear guests, could do one of these things, that would be one thing, but both? Really? Isn’t that a bit too much? This is why designing a perfect dungeon is impossible and why we can’t have nice things. Damn Bloodlines and Transcendents ruining everything.”

Jake and company made their way back towards the gate that required the four keys at a brisk pace while listening to Minaga complain about their group. It had to be noted that he only complained. There was no interference or even direct questions posed to any of them. It was more like he was just voicing his own thoughts while forcing the group to listen.

“Two Bloodlines and one Transcendent… Oh, yeah, and a Unique Lifeform. I guess I can’t rule out some Unique skill that I wasn’t able to account for, either, but I definitely think it is one of the other three suspects. Now, the swordsman doesn’t strike me as the kind to have a skill allowing him to find stuff easier, much less have a Transcendent skill related to it, so I will temporarily rule him out, which narrows it down to one of two Bloodlines.”

The thought that Minaga wouldn’t figure out his Bloodline did cross Jake’s mind. Even if Minaga didn’t figure it out, though, the Wyrmgod clearly would. Considering they would spend fifty years there… Shit, the Wyrmgod probably already had a good idea.

The thing was, Jake didn’t want to fuck himself over by getting fewer points than he should have. Additionally, it would feel wrong to fuck over his party members if he decided to effectively nerf himself and keep his true capabilities hidden.

“Dina is the granddaughter of Nature’s Attendant, so she is a candidate. Assuming she is also capable of communicating with plants the same way he can, I can’t really see it being her, though. Of course, it is entirely possible her Bloodline mutated, and she can now communicate with something else I hadn’t accounted for, but with her skillset and the serious lack of anything to even converse with, I am inclined to rule her out. Which leaves us with Jake.”

Jake kept quiet, as he was inclined to hear what the guy thought his Bloodline was about.

“Based on everything publicly displayed so far, it appears to be related to presences. I also have my own pet theory that your Origin manipulation is at least partly rooted in your Bloodline, so that strengthens the presence-related Bloodline theory. This initially made me guess that maybe your Bloodline allows you to also detect presences far more easily, and by using that, you would be able to locate rooms that contained presences… The thing is, how would that help you navigate the hallways? Pick the rooms with keys out from those without? Well, of course it wouldn’t, so that leaves a few possibilities. It either isn’t your Bloodline, your Bloodline is quite a bit different than anyone had estimated, or it really isn’t you, but one of your other party members.”

“What do you think the answer is?” Jake asked.

“That it is you, and that the current information of what your Bloodline is capable of is severely limited, making it far more powerful than anyone truly knows. Well, anyone besides the Malefic Viper. To make someone at a low grade their Chosen, they have to have something very special about them, and I am willing to bet your Bloodline is just that special.”

Jake was silent for a moment before wondering aloud, “Which begs the question… what will be your response?”

“Now… Oh… oh, wait! You think that I think you are cheating and unhappy with that? True, true, I am a bit miffed, but to say I am unhappy? Far from it! You break my labyrinth all you want and use any advantage you can possibly get! Go HAM; that is what you are in Nevermore for, isn’t it? To truly let loose. Don’t worry about me sharing details about your Bloodline either. I am a strict believer in confidentiality! Only me and the Wyrmgod are aware of anything happening here, and none of us are sharing.”

“I guess that is a little comforting,” Jake said, not entirely sure if he believed him.

“Besides, Jake… do you really think this is the first time I have encountered anything like this? Even if you can perfectly navigate the labyrinth, that doesn’t mean this will be a cakewalk. I made this place to challenge everyone, and to do that, I had to consider a lot of things. Many potential guests have vast skillsets, including Transcendents and Bloodlines. Can I make a perfect labyrinth? No, but I can try. The devil is in the details, and trust me, I am very detail-orientated. So keep having fun, and keep breaking stuff. I’ll be watching with glee. Okay, I might complain a bit, but don’t take it to heart!”

Jake shook his head as he and his party finally appeared before the gate leading forward. Lifting his hand, the tattoos on his hand began glowing, then peeled off and flew straight towards the gate. The four runes glowed brighter before merging together… and the second they did, the entire door turned red.

All of the runes began warping to form four words.

Demon Seal Don’t Open.

The door slammed open, and all the mist in the hallway was pushed away as a torrent of flames spewed out, forcing Jake and the others to jump back. Behind the door was a swirling portal, and while Jake tried to figure out what was going on, two large claws grabbed the sides of the now open door.

“I did tell you… the devil is in the details.”

An aura rushed out of the portal as a five-meter-tall creature pulled itself through the gate, and Jake barely had time to use Identify before it attacked.

[Demon Lord – lvl 270]

Chapter 11

Demon Lord

Jake was blasted backward as he blocked with a barrier of stable arcane mana. A torrent of flames bellowed out from the Demon Lord, obscuring its form even as it walked forward. As the one closest to the gate, Jake had taken the brunt of it, but he had reacted quickly due to his danger sense to avoid any real damage.

A wall of roots shot up from the ground just after Jake was shot back, but a blast of deep red flames removed it instantly. Everyone retreated back to Jake as the Demon Lord walked through the burning wall of vines, properly revealing its form for the first time.

As Jake had initially seen, it was about five meters tall and had rock-like outgrowths on its skin; all of them were cracked, showing off red energy pulsing beneath. It carried a large sword that looked like it was made of stone, with veins of glowing red lava running through it. Otherwise, it didn’t have any equipment. Even its bottom side was covered only by a loincloth of sorts. The demon’s entire body released a constant stream of heat energy, its form burning perpetually. Whether its skin was red due to the fire or it was just its usual skin tone, Jake didn’t know. Its head looked vaguely humanoid, with two large, curled horns like that of a goat, and it had two burning red eyes that stared down the party in front of it.

There was no doubt about it… This was the strongest foe they had faced in Nevermore so far. That difficulty-setting thing had allowed them to encounter opponents worth fighting far sooner than expected; this Demon Lord was proof of that.

Jake grinned as the Demon Lord assessed the five of them. The Demon Lord sneered and spoke in a deep voice, its words infused with Willpower.

“Kneel.”

That command became the starting shot, as their entire party moved in unison. The Demon Lord legitimately seemed taken by surprise at their immediate response, but it still managed to react. A blast of force struck it in the side, making the demon stumble slightly while blocking a blow from the Sword Saint. It roared at the water mixed into his attacks.

Jake shot an arrow toward the demon’s ankle to try and limit its movements, but it managed to shift its stance and do an upward slash, sending out a massive wave of fire that sent the Sword Saint retreating. Just as it was about to do a follow-up, a green hawk barreled into it from behind. Sylphie had previously turned herself into wind to get around the demon.

She managed to punch a hole in the demon’s backside from the impact but still found herself on the defensive when the wound released a blast of fire. The blood that dripped down the demon’s body burned like lava.

Dina also finally released a proper attack, shooting a massive spear of wood towards the Demon Lord and forcing it to block with the flat side of its large blade. The impact still sent it skirting backward and gave Jake and the King an opportunity to each land a ranged blow in the form of an arrow and a golden blast of force, respectively. As the demon stumbled, the Sword Saint got close and cut its leg, aiming to sever the tendons on its ankles. Assuming it had any.

The Demon Lord roared and slammed its sword into the ground with both hands. A massive blast of fire exploded out from its body, forcing them all to disengage. When the Demon Lord’s form was revealed again, it looked calmer. It also seemed to have truly realized it was surrounded by powerful people. It regarded them for a moment before grunting.

“Very well.”

It squeezed the handle of its sword, and the stone-like weapon cracked. Stone slowly fell away, revealing a pulsing orange blade of metal that released heat powerful enough to make Jake activate Scales of the Malefic Viper just to be on the safe side. Dina also responded quickly and sent out green waves of energy toward each of them, resulting in a faint, glowing green barrier covering their bodies. Jake instantly felt the temperature lower and gave Dina a nod as they prepared to reengage the demon.

The demon swung its empowered blade toward the people in front of it and sent out a crescent wave of flames. A golden magic barrier met the flames, and Jake jumped back as he began charging his Arcane Powershot. The Sword Saint stormed forward after the King dispelled the barrier, and together with Sylphie, the two of them engaged their opponent in melee. The Fallen King also began charging some magic of his own while Dina retreated to stand beside Jake, preparing a spell of her own.

Aware of what they were doing, the Demon Lord wanted to stop them, but the Sword Saint wouldn’t allow it. He activated his boosting skill properly for the first time since entering Nevermore, and Sylphie soon followed suit as the Demon Lord got more and more aggressive. They both needed to avoid the sword at all costs, and Jake saw that Dina’s protection spell wouldn’t last much longer against the intense fire energy.

Luckily, it didn’t have to.

Jake was ready and sent the mental go-ahead to the Fallen King. The Unique Lifeform reacted instantly. Two massive, golden chains erupted from his hands and flew straight toward the Demon Lord. The demon tried to avoid them, but just then, thorned roots shot up from the ground and entrapped its feet, allowing the chains to hit.

Less than a quarter of a second later, Jake released an Arcane Powershot that tore through the air, releasing a devastating trail of destruction and then an explosion. The Demon Lord roared as it blocked with one of its arms, not able to raise its blade in time.

Despite the power of Jake’s attack, the Demon Lord managed to partly block the hit. Its arm had a huge chunk of flesh blown off, revealing the obsidian-like bone beneath, but the Demon Lord also borrowed the momentum from the impact to retreat. The Sword Saint still managed to give chase and, using his Rainblade, delivered an upwards cut aimed straight at where Jake had also just hit. Once more, the Demon Lord was ready to respond, but the Fallen King yanked the golden chains, interrupting its dodge and allowing the Sword Saint to land a solid cut. Even then, the arm was not fully severed; the sword was stopped by the bone, only cutting halfway through.

Just as Jake feared their attack had failed, though, a green bullet swept through the hallway. The arm was hit straight on, and in an explosion of fire, blood, and bone, the Demon Lord’s limb was severed just below the elbow.

Sylphie materialized not far from Jake, a few of her feathers burned despite her ethereal form when attacking the demon. Jake had already pulled out another arrow and was prepared to continue his attack when the Demon Lord once more erupted in crimson flames. The golden chains of the Fallen King rapidly melted away, allowing the demon to retreat, but it was once more caught by Dina attempting to immobilize it. The Fallen King also didn’t take his chain being melted lightly. The Unique Lifeform flew forward, his ivory claw now glowing golden.

Jake, the Sword Saint, and Sylphie also gave chase as the Demon Lord took blow after blow. Its body was honestly ridiculously tough, its metallic bones so durable that causing any proper damage was difficult. Dina had to soon focus solely on protecting them from the extreme heat aura from the Demon Lord.

The demon’s sword was still the most dangerous thing by far. Due to overconfidence in his barrier, the Fallen King had attempted to get close and land a solid blow, only to wind up being slammed in the chest. His barrier broke, sending him flying several kilometers down the hallway. The Sword Saint also failed to respond in time when the Demon Lord used the severed bone on its hand to stab him in the shoulder, leaving a nasty, burning wound.

They all felt pressured, but the situation was still under control. Yet the Demon Lord didn’t seem afraid in any way, just annoyed. It fought valiantly, but it was slower than any one of them besides Dina and the Fallen King, so it failed to do a lot of damage that Dina couldn’t quickly handle. The Sword Saint also managed to nullify many of the major fire attacks, though it did look like his own blows utilizing the concept of rain failed to do much. Nevertheless, the wounds accumulated on the Demon Lord, and considering its missing hand, it was only a matter of time.

At least, they thought it was. Sure, they had figured the Demon Lord had some hidden tricks, but what it did next was still surprising.

It swung its blade wide to release a wave of fire, making Jake and the others momentarily retreat once more. Usually when this happened, it just gave Jake time to charge up an attack, but this time the Demon Lord changed its behavior entirely.

Rather than keep attacking, it straightened its back and scoffed. “Pathetic, this body,” the Demon Lord said, frowning deeply before turning to the five of them. “You are worthy adversaries. We will meet again.”

With its remaining hand, the Demon Lord stuck the sword into the ground, and a pentagram-shaped magic circle appeared beneath its feet. Jake reacted quickly by firing an arrow, but a red barrier covered the demon, and before anyone else could attack, a crimson flash of light stole the Demon Lord away.

What the fuck? Jake cursed internally at the fucking thing just running away. He was about to yell at their host when a system message popped up.

Achievement earned: Defeat the Demon Lord during your first encounter. 250 Nevermore Points earned.

Okay, so at least they’d gotten a bunch of points for it. Jake still didn’t feel satisfied.

“Should we have gone all-out using boosting skills and everything?” he questioned aloud.

“I… I don’t think that would work,” Dina said, shaking her head. “That was a Demon Lord, after all.”

The four of them turned to look at Dina, with even Sylphie, who had landed on Jake’s shoulder, tilting her head.

Dina seemed to grasp what they wanted, explaining, “That is a Demon Lord, a very particular subspecies of the demon race. Demon Lords are notoriously difficult to kill, and they are even able to resurrect if slain. These are not true resurrections, but more like their remnant energy regathered, and an entirely new creature with a new Truesoul is born in its place, though at a slightly lower level in most cases. Due to this, many just seal away Demon Lords instead. In the end, time kills everything that is not a god, no matter how tricky they may be.”

“Oh,” Jake said, wondering why he had never heard about them before while also thinking that sounded kind of similar to some of the fiction he’d read before the system. “Do they also have inherent knowledge like True Royals?”

“A little, but it is very limited, so for one to be able to speak is already proof it has lived for a pretty long time, and even if all Demon Lords are born C-grade at minimum, being halfway to B-grade may mean it has gained those levels itself. Demon Lords are also usually born through large-scale sacrificial rituals, which means they usually have subordinates… This one was alone and weakened after being sealed in for a long time.” Dina shook her head.

Jake nodded. “I see.” Its comment about its body being pathetic was likely genuine. They hadn’t faced the Demon Lord at full power.

“Does that mean that even if we killed this Demon Lord, it would only be temporary?” the Sword Saint asked. “That we would face it again later on?”

“Well… usually they take at least a decade or so to resurrect, so probably not?” Dina said, a bit unsure.

“Wait, if they can keep resurrecting, doesn’t that mean whenever a Demon Lord is spawned, there will always be one more in the multiverse?” Jake questioned.

“They can still die permanently, depending on the way they are killed, and the amount of times they resurrect is still limited,” Dina explained. “The problem is that you can’t really know how many resurrections a particular Demon Lord has left… Hence, most prefer to seal them.”

“Definitely going for the kill next time either way,” Jake said, getting a nod from the Sword Saint and a screech of agreement from Sylphie.

“I believe I can make its death quite a bit more permanent than usual,” the King shared. “As long as you shatter the soul enough, the regathering of energy should at least be slowed down enough for it to take millennia for any new Demon Lord to emerge, if what you explained is correct.”

“Aight,” Jake said approvingly. “Now, let’s check what was behind that damn gate.”

During the fight, they had traveled several kilometers down the hallway, as more space had helped them avoid the large, sweeping fire attacks. Now, with the Demon Lord gone, they could rush back down the hall and finally see what had been behind the gate requiring four damn keys.

Once there, they first saw that the portal was gone, and behind it was a relatively small chamber, barely wider than the normal hallway. On the other side of this small chamber was the gateway leading onto the next floor, making Jake and the others feel pretty relieved.

Jake smiled. “So, at least this was the right way.”

“No, it wasn’t,” Minaga chimed in.

“Clearly was. I see the gateway right there.” Jake shrugged.

“I guess it depends on your definition of what the right way is. This was technically one of the ways you could take, but not really the one most are expected to take, so to call it the right way isn’t entirely accurate.”

“This seemed like the most straightforward way, though. Humor me, if you will. What was the other way we could have gone?” Jake was asking partly to have the Unique Lifeform divulge more information about the labyrinth, and partly because he was genuinely curious.

“See, if you had done any of the other rooms that you so quickly avoided, you would have known that there was a second way into this room that wasn’t through the gate that would also unleash the Demon Lord. The friendlies in these mystical rooms you so adamantly avoided would have told you that through the efforts of a cult of demon worshippers, a Demon Lord has been summoned. They would then have led you to a mage who could use the four keys to instead teleport you to that central platform right there.”

A spotlight appeared in the middle of the room, highlighting a slightly elevated stone platform with several patterns carved into it.

“I am trying to tell a story here, too, you know? Not the best story, maybe, but I am trying. Granted, I care more about the mechanics of an experience over the background story, but I still put in effort, so you will learn this lore if you want to or not!”

“Fine, fine,” Jake said, not wanting to argue. “But do tell me, since you keep insisting we did it wrong… would the other way have given more Nevermore Points? Would it have been faster?”

Somehow, Jake heard Minaga’s lack of reply.

“How do you even make audible silence? That makes no sen—”

“Would you look at that? The entire first layer of the labyrinth is now collapsing after you so haphazardly released the Demon Lord! Hurry into the gateway before it is too late!”

Jake was about to respond to what he thought was an obvious joke when the ceiling cracked, and in the hallway behind them, the entire thing began to collapse in on itself.

“Fucking hell,” Jake cursed as he and the others charged forward.

“Did you find it necessary to annoy him?” the Sword Saint said as they reached the gateway.

“In my defense, I think he is genuinely enjoying this.” Jake smiled as they entered the gateway and moved on to the first in-between room of Minaga’s Labyrinth.

Chapter 12

"Seriously? Again?"

Going through the gateway leading out of the thirty-first floor, Jake wasn’t exactly sure what he had expected. Considering the uniqueness of these next ten floors and Minaga being the one in charge, it wasn’t even certain there would be an in-between room. There was one, but it wasn’t at all what Jake had predicted.

All the prior in-between rooms had consisted of three gates: one to enter, one leading to the next floor, and one to exit Nevermore. Besides that, there was a place for lockboxes to spawn... and that was it. They were barebones and functional, clearly meant to just be a room you quickly went through.

As for Minaga’s version of an in-between room?

“This is nice,” Dina said just as they arrived, looking around.

“Certainly a relaxing atmosphere,” the Sword Saint agreed.

What they had walked into looked like the lounge of a five-star hotel. There was red carpeting across the floor, a large open bar, a sitting area with lounge chairs, and an elevated platform that looked to be made out of wood—already with a lockbox on it. In general, this entire hall was a big and welcoming space. In Jake’s sphere, he even saw that there were several more rooms, including five bedrooms with attached bathrooms, and each of these bedrooms also had a “crafting room” attached. Based on the void behind those doors, Jake guessed that the room changed based on who entered. Finally, Jake saw a fucking open-air bath. Did they need an open-air bath? They didn’t, but it was there.

“Minaga is truly an evil mastermind,” Jake said with respect. “Trying to make the parties attempting the labyrinth waste time in these in-between rooms, thus having less time for the actual dungeon.”

“Now that is just mean,” Minaga said in a fake sulking tone.

“Sure, sure.” Jake smiled, but just then, the party got a bunch of system messages that made Jake smile even more.

Thirty-first floor completed. 310 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-first floor in less than a day (24 hours). 500 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-first floor without any party member taking damage from any trap. 300 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-first floor without interacting with any friendly creatures. 200 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-first floor while only entering a maximum of four challenge rooms. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

The achievements were just rolling in, netting far more points than on any floor prior. Jake did find it a bit odd there wasn’t a single mention of the fact that they had chosen the Archmage difficulty, but it was also entirely possible that the reward would come at a later point.

“Certainly a lot of points,” the Sword Saint said, satisfied.

“We may have taken the top spot if there was a Leaderboard after the thirty-first floor,” Jake said with a smile.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched as she flew over to the lockbox in the room.

“Yeah, I guess you can open it,” Jake said, sensing Sylphie’s excitement about what was inside.

Many of the earlier rewards had turned out to be natural treasures or even raw materials their party could use, and thus, most of it had also been consumed by Sylphie. It was only natural she was excited about opening each and every lockbox now.

Poking the box with her talon, it opened, and from within, a small, shield-like item floated out. It was no more than ten centimeters tall and had a heater shield design that featured a glowing flame symbol. The entire thing look to be made of gold, except for the orange flame symbol. Jake used Identify and raised an eyebrow at the description.

[Greater Firebane Talisman (Ancient)] – Infusing power into the talisman grants you and all nearby party members significantly increased resistance to all fire-affinity attacks for one hour (60 minutes). Has limited charges, and once the charges are used up, the talisman will break. This item cannot be used outside of Nevermore and will cease to exist if brought out for too long. Charges remaining: 3

“Very clearly an item offered for either a later environment or a rematch with the Demon Lord,” the Fallen King said. “Perhaps both, considering it has a total of three charges.”

“It would be good against the Demon Lord,” Dina agreed, having been the one to primarily deal with it. “The passive fire aura was quite powerful even for a level 270 Demon Lord, and if the demon is stronger the next time we encounter it, I am not sure I would be able to properly fight it off.”

“Then we will have to simply deal with it ourselves,” the Fallen King said a bit dismissively.

Jake kind of agreed. While having Dina help with it was nice, Jake still had his scales, and if he used Arcane Awakening at full power, the passive shield from that should be fine. The King was also good, leaving her only with Sylphie and the Sword Saint, but they could also take care of themselves.

“In either case, can you carry it, Dina?” Jake asked.

“Me?” she said, taken aback.

“Well, you are the support, and you seem good at judging when to use it.” Jake smiled encouragingly.

“I find it admirable,” the King said, making Jake nod approvingly before he promptly stopped at the King’s followup. “I find it admirable that Jake recognizes he would have forgotten about the item’s existence ten seconds after putting it in his spatial storage, so he gave it to someone else.”

“Hey, that ain’t fair,” Jake fought back.

“There… There was that compass on the twenty-fourth floor…” Dina muttered.

“Ree!” Sylphie said, valiantly coming to Jake’s defense.

“Yeah, Sylphie is right. We didn’t need it, so who cares?” In any event, Jake knew it was a losing battle.

“Chances are we could also proceed without this Firebane Talisman, but not using it strikes me as wasteful, seeing as it cannot even be brought out of Nevermore,” the Sword Saint piled on.

“So I gave it to Dina—case closed,” Jake said as he used the number-one strategy to get out of trouble: misdirect. “Hey, Minaga, I have a question. If you are willing to answer, that is.”

“It is pretty hard to know if I am going to answer before you ask the question,” Minaga answered with a hint of snark.

“Sorry, sorry. I do love the break room, by the way. I wanted to ask about the time-based achievement we got. More accurately, how it works. 500 points seem like a lot, but at the same time, few would have a chance to do it that fast, so is the achievement for doing it within a day the only one?”

“Well, there is one that gives 100 points for doing it in less than a week, 200 points for less than five days, 350 points for less than three days, and finally, 500 points for less than a day. Congratulations, you got the best one there, but you did miss out on other achievements!”

“I see.” Jake nodded. “Just to ask… was it possible to kill the Demon Lord during our first encounter?”

“Naturally, it was possible… just as you could have attacked me in the opening room if you so desired,” Minaga said in his usual cheerful voice. “Not saying doing either would have done you any good, but it was an option. Now, enjoy the break room and relax! At least try out the free bar.”

Minaga vanished again, and while Jake did want to move on quickly, he kind of got the feeling keeping Minaga happy would do him good. That some eccentric dungeon master was part of Nevermore, a transformed World Wonder, and that you had to keep the weird guy happy to not get fucked over was admittedly a bit weird… but what could he do about it? Seeing as Minaga had made the entire thirty-first floor collapse behind them, it was likely he could actually influence the dungeon if he wished, even if the collapse had just been a joke.

In that sense, it was also somewhat comforting that he had done nothing to mess with Jake. He could have easily scrambled the hallways, switched the locations of rooms with keys, reassigned which monsters had keys, and a slew of other things, but he had done none of it. So while Jake didn’t think Minaga would outright work against him, it seemed silly to risk it. Thus, he bit the bullet and sat down at the bar.

Looking at all the flasks on display, he extended a string of mana and picked out a few that seemed interesting. Dina and the Sword Saint walked over to join him as he began mixing stuff at random, making different drinks. He had a failure rate of about ninety percent, but he did manage to make some stuff that at least didn’t make him retch. His Sense of the Malefic Viper also allowed him to sense the general level of alcohol within each bottle. This was mainly important to make sure Sylphie didn’t have any, as she was still too young to drink. Dina also didn’t like alcohol, so they went to the section with non-alcoholic drinks.

“Why do you inferior lifeforms even consume these things?” the Fallen King asked, clearly just jealous he was the only one who couldn’t enjoy Jake’s mixing skills.

“Because we can, and some of them are tasty.” Jake smiled. “I could ask you the same about consuming natural treasures. You have eaten literal rocks.”

“They were precious gemstones containing soul—”

“Shiny rocks, then,” Jake said, grinning.

The five of them stayed in this in-between room longer than they had planned, thoroughly falling for Minaga’s trick. Then again, perhaps it was good for them to have a mental reset, and Jake had a strong feeling that was what these rooms were designed for. The five of them had dealt with the oppressive mist for less than a full day, but being within it just for a few hours was suffocating. Without something like his sphere or other things to help find the way, Jake could see others spending months just walking in a fog.

Yeah, he could see why someone would need a drink and a nice soak in the open-air bath after that.

Jake and company still only stayed for a few hours to check out the local amenities before moving on to the thirty-second floor.

Walking through the gateway, they found themselves in a room that was pretty similar to the one on the thirty-first. A few seconds after they appeared, another floor description popped up.

Welcome to the thirty-second floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth (Part 2)

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: N/A

Current progress: End reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 16,682

The first thing Jake noticed was the name of the floor. To just call it part two was honestly lazy, and he would have expected more of Minaga. Alas, Jake would let it go in an act of benevolence.

As expected, Minaga once more popped into existence on the room’s central platform, though he didn’t bother with the light show this time around.

“Hello, there! Long time, no see,” Minaga said in his usual joking tone. “I guess we all know what we are doing here. Are you going to be pathetic disappointments to all of the gods that blessed you—and the saddest excuse for a Unique Lifeform I have ever seen—or are you going to keep going at the Archmage difficulty? You can totally downgrade if you want to act like little—”

“Same difficulty,” Jake said, waving him off.

“Surprising,” Minaga said in a deadpan tone.

“Say,” the Sword Saint began, “the first time around, you mentioned that one could increase or decrease the difficulty by one at the start of every floor. Does that mean there is a difficulty above Archmage we can increase it to?”

Jake looked at the Sword Saint and gave him a mental thumbs-up. He hadn’t even considered that.

“That is a very good question,” Minaga said with a smile. “But no, there is not. I should probably change the wording in the initial briefing, huh? Well, good catch either way!”

Achievement earned: Ask Minaga a good question. 1 Nevermore Point earned.

The system announcement surprised all of them.

Jake just stared at the Unique Lifeform. “Really?”

“Are you complaining?” Minaga asked teasingly. “Can’t take them back, but I can make sure you won’t get any more.”

“Nope, definitely not complaining, just surprised,” Jake quickly backpedaled.

“Oh, then no worries, no worries.” Minaga waved him off. “Now for the second thing we have to deal with…”

As Minaga stood on the platform with his usual smile, he seemed to be waiting for something. Jake exchanged a glance with the others, but none had any idea what the hell he wanted them to do. After nearly ten seconds of awkward silence, Minaga scratched his chin.

“Nothing?”

“What did you expect?” Jake asked.

“Well, I just said it was an option to attack me, so… you know.” Minaga shrugged.

“But you also said it wouldn’t necessarily do us any good, and I have a strong feeling it would end badly if we did attack,” Jake pointed out.

“Oh, it definitely would. But you also didn’t attack because we are becoming friends, and it would feel bad to attack me, right?”

“Oh, definitely that also,” Jake agreed.

“I knew we had built a good rapport,” Minaga said with a smile. “Now, go forth and conquer the second part of my labyrinth! This one will be different; I can promise you that!”

With that, Minaga was gone again. The five of them exchanged glances as the large gate leading into the labyrinth began opening. Once it opened, the familiar fog rolled out, and without hesitation, Jake and the others made their way inside. Releasing a Pulse of Perception, Jake scanned what was ahead of them. At a cursory glance, it looked mostly the same, except he saw humanoid figures actually walking in some of the halls.

Jake also spotted one other thing. Only about a hundred meters into the hallway, a lone humanoid figure was sitting on the ground with their back against the wall. Jake shared his findings, and they quickly made their way to this lone figure.

They couldn’t see if they were human or not, as the person was fully covered in metallic armor that now had red scars all over it and several melted pieces. The moment they got close, the armored person lazily turned their head.

“You… were you the ones who released that monster?” came a strained male voice.

Jake used Identify and was kind of surprised to see his level equaling that of the Demon Lord.

[Knight of Light’s Dawn – lvl 270]

“He is dying,” Dina shared through their link. Considering she said it with such certainty, Jake saw no reason to doubt her—and thus, no reason to lie.

“If you are talking about the Demon Lord, then yes,” Jake answered. “But accidentally.”

“Curse you… Curse all of you!” the Knight said as he tried to stand up, but he stumbled and fell to the ground instantly, then stopped moving.

“Dead,” the Fallen King said.

“Not entirely.” The Sword Saint frowned as the corpse began leaking dark energy. An energy that was familiar to Jake.

A curse manifested from the corpse of the Knight. It took on a vaguely humanoid form that then lifted one of its arms and pointed at their party.

“Absolve yourselves!”

As the curse exploded outwards from the body and towards them, a bonus objective finally appeared before their eyes.

Bonus objective gained: Slay the Demonic Cultist Prime Summoner to dispel the curse.

Yet just as the curse was about to invade their bodies, Jake took out Eternal Hunger. The curse energy trying to attack instantly stopped when his katar released a pulse of energy. Without even the slightest chance to resist, every single speck of curse energy was absorbed by his weapon.

“Not bad,” Jake said, seeing that Eternal Hunger had quite liked the curse. High-quality curse, but a bit lacking in the energy department. At least none of them had been affected at all, so that was nice.

“Seriously? Again?” the exasperated voice of Minaga echoed. “I am trying to teach you about consequences here.”

Jake shrugged. “Should have had a better curse.”

Chapter 13

Ritual in the Rain

Even if they didn’t have to do the bonus objective to dispel the curse, they still wanted to kill this Prime Summoner, as it would no doubt reward extra Nevermore Points. Jake couldn’t really say he felt sorry about breaking whatever scenario Minaga had planned, though he could see what their host had been going for.

Had they done the first part without freeing the Demon Lord and instead gotten help to teleport here, they would have met this Knight, who’d been tasked with guarding the gate. He would then have told them about rumors of cultists recently appearing further into the labyrinth, urging them to slay the Prime Summoner he feared was trying to free the Demon Lord.

Jake and company had instead freed the Demon Lord themselves, and the Demon Lord had attacked and killed the Knight. Seeing them as intruders, the Knight had tried to use a curse to make Jake and the others kill this Prime Summoner instead of merely asking them to do it. Even then, the curse would only have resulted in slightly reduced resource pools and evil whispers from the dead Knight, admonishing them for their crimes and screaming at them to kill the Prime Summoner. In other words, more annoying than impactful.

Now, back in the original story where Jake and company didn’t free the Demon Lord… Upon finally reaching the Prime Summoner, they would have found her just as she was about to succeed. Luckily, they would arrive just in time—regardless of whether they’d spent an hour or a year walking the hallways—and naturally best the evil Prime Summoner. However, just as she was about to die, she would sacrifice herself to still release the Demon Lord.

One might ask why Jake knew all this. Well…

“Then, when the Demon Lord is summoned, a magical circle will appear at the entrance of the room, and the formation mage who helped you in the first part will appear together with the Knight. The Knight will engage the Demon Lord, and they will have a totally epic battle! The Knight of Light’s Dawn versus the evil Demon Lord! Sadly, the Knight is no match. He will tell you to run, and the mage will assist in teleporting you away into another part of the labyrinth. Sure, you would also be able to join the Knight and fight the Demon Lord as you did before, then have the demon teleport away again if you wanted to do that—that would give an achievement—but I definitely find the first scenario way more fun. Ah, but the Knight would still die, having overused his boosting skill during the fight. This always happens… Well, unless you knock the Knight out before he can use it. That has happened, but he stays back to protect this part of the labyrinth anyway, so it doesn’t do much in later parts… though, again, that earns an achievement.”

Minaga had decided that while their party rushed through the halls, he would narrate the entire story they had missed and really go into detail about the different scenarios they were now locked out of. Jake wouldn’t exactly call the story good or original, and Minaga did also interject to clarify that the story had been written solely to set up good challenges and not actually tell an exciting story. Though… despite saying this, Minaga also seemed overly interested in sharing his so-called “bad” story.

Besides an even more talkative Minaga, the thirty-second floor was quite similar to the thirty-first, with the biggest difference being that the hallways were no longer void of life. Patrols of cultists wandered about, which usually wouldn’t have been much of a challenge, except they now had to fight them within the fog. Perceiving one’s surroundings and moving about was made more difficult, but at least this also affected the cultists, so both sides struggled.

These cultists usually patrolled around in groups of three to seven, with their levels hovering around 240. Jake had identified three types of cultists so far.

[Demonic Cultist Flameblade – lvl 242]

These were the usual fire types, and they all acted like fanboys of the Demon Lord. They had similar skills, and their identical weapons all looked like replicas of the Demon Lord’s sword. They were pretty easy to deal with overall, as their blades all lit up and made them easily locatable, even within the fog.

[Demonic Cultist Cauterizer – lvl 241]

Fire healers. Somehow their fire was able to mend injuries, really bending the definition of cauterize to make it straight-up healing. They could also do some offensive fire magic to double as mages. Individually, they were very squishy, and Sylphie, in particular, liked breaking through their defenses and killing them.

Then there was the last enemy type.

[Demonic Cultist Bulwark – lvl 242]

These were pretty standard defensive warriors wielding large shields, though they did also partake in the fire theme by making barriers of flame. They could even release torrents of fire from their spiky shields. Usually, these Bulwarks worked hand in hand with the Cauterizers, but due to the small size of the groups, every encounter was too one-sided to truly get insight into their synergy. These patrols were clearly just made to keep explorers on their toes, but Minaga also shared some other reasons.

“Thematically, the patrols are to signify that the Demonic Cult has claimed this entire part of the labyrinth as their own. Mechanically, it is to combat a very obvious strategy many groups would have no doubt made use of on the prior floor: divide and conquer. While a lot of Perception-related abilities are blocked, blocking everything that allows party members to locate and keep track of one another is simply not feasible, and I wouldn’t want to even if I could. So, in order to make splitting up less safe, I introduced these patrols into the hallways. Sure, for a team like yours, you could still split up, but for the average party—even those capable of doing the labyrinth on Archmage difficulty—it would be incredibly dangerous, and a risk they’d avoid. It isn’t like a normal group can send their healer running around solo and expect them to return unscathed.”

“That does actually make perfect sense,” Jake said as they walked away from another patrol they had just killed.

“However, it is also to communicate to the challengers when they are closing in on this Prime Summoner,” the Sword Saint stated.

Jake had already pretty much confirmed this through his Pulses of Perception, and the Sword Saint had also easily figured it out. The patrols all came from somewhere, and by backtracking their paths, one would get closer and closer to the headquarters of these demonic summoners.

Of course, it wasn’t entirely that simple. Some groups came from other rooms not containing the Prime Summoner, and some even purposefully tried to lead Jake and company into traps, but with Jake in the lead, they kept their course straight and rapidly made progress toward their target. At the edge of his most recent Pulse of Perception, he saw a room bigger than any other they’d encountered on this floor, so he felt pretty confident it was there. Extremely confident, actually, as he also applied his improved tracking skills. Despite the fog, he vaguely got the feeling that the strongest source of demonic energy was in that direction. This was definitely helped along by his Bloodline-empowered intuition, too.

Minaga had also clearly noticed this, as he made a few snide comments here and there. Their group had already decided to replicate what they’d done on the prior floor, not bothering with all the optional rooms. The only potentially optional thing they would do was kill this Prime Summoner for the bonus points. Was it possible that skipping this step would reward some kind of achievement? Sure, but it was equally possible that it would just result in them missing out on points.

Soon enough, they reached their destination: the massive room Jake had detected. Just as on the prior floor, the haze dispersed when they walked through the fog wall to enter. As soon as they set foot inside the room, Jake’s danger sense reacted.

Several Demonic Cultist Flameblades descended upon them, but an expanded golden barrier from the King sent them all stumbling back. Jake pulled out his bow and sent one of them flying even further back as the Sword Saint, Dina, and Sylphie also released their own attacks, making quick work of their welcoming party.

Needless to say, this would not be a stealth mission. The design of this enormous room reminded Jake of an old temple, but it was so large that an actual cathedral stood in the back. Jake quickly used his tracking skill, and without the fog, it was clear as day.

“Prime Summoner is in the cathedral,” Jake shared with the party.

“Let’s make haste and quickly dispose of the trash before getting there,” the Fallen King said as he rose into the air.

The large temple hall was filled with cultists. Jake spotted at least a few thousand, though it had to be noted that the vast majority of them were truly in the trash-mob category. In fact, more than ninety percent had barely reached C-grade.

[Demonic Cultist – lvl 201]

The races of these cultists varied wildly, including beastfolk, humans, elves, dwarves, gnomes, and a bunch of other exotic humanoid races Jake didn’t recognize. All of them burned with fanaticism and gladly picked up arms against the evil invaders, spurred on by some of the higher-leveled cultists among them.

Just then, a massive projection of a masked woman appeared in the sky.

“Lord Gubrothas has already informed me of your meddling, outsiders,” the lunatic woman announced. “For daring to lift a hand against his honored lord, the only true recompense is death. Rejoice, as your souls will be used to fuel my ascension. Attack, my faithful!”

The group of fanatics was thrown into a frenzy. Jake and the others prepared to fight, but as they were about to step forward, the Sword Saint spoke.

“Would you allow me?” he asked as he walked forward. “This place seems fitting for something I have been waiting to reveal.”

“Go right ahead,” Jake said, wondering what the old man wanted to show them.

He smiled as he drew his blade, and his aura spiked. Near the ceiling of the room, rain clouds appeared out of nowhere, and a light drizzle fell upon the entire hall. The Sword Saint charged away from the party and into a crowd of Demonic Cultist Flameblades and Bulwarks.

Sylphie was about to take flight, but Jake lifted his hand and gently pushed her down on his shoulder. “Let the old man have his fun.” The Fallen King also summoned a golden barrier to cover them and block the rain, as well as any wayward attacks.

They’d had times like these on prior floors, allowing one of them to have a bit of a solo show. It was a way to avoid boredom and show off one’s skills. Jake and the others thus stood back near the entrance and observed the Sword Saint engaging an entire army of cultists in melee combat.

He had fully activated his boosting skill and expertly dodged every single attack as the rain fell down all around him, soaking the floor of the temple and creating puddles everywhere. The rain weakened the fire-affinity fighters, and after a few minutes of the Sword Saint cutting down cultist after cultist, the big boss made her appearance.

The Prime Summoner stepped out of the cathedral alongside two actual demons. Jake checked them all from afar to see if the old man could still deal with them.

[Demonic Cultist Prime Summoner – lvl 260]

[Demon Guardian – lvl 255]

It would be tight, but Jake had confidence. The Sword Saint was incredibly well-versed in dueling opponents like these. They were humanoid, they used fire-affinity abilities, and the primary foe was a caster. Jake had seen him fight large beasts and struggle, but against other humanoids, he was an absolute monster.

Yet Jake also noticed something was off. The movements of his opponents were slow… too slow. Somehow, the rain seemed to stick to them and hinder their movements. Jake considered if perhaps the Sword Saint had gotten inspiration from the underwater level or something. However, what Dina said next dispelled that thought.

“Time… Every raindrop is infused with the concept of time,” she said with astonishment.

Taken aback, Jake reassessed the situation. He always scanned the environment, but he hadn’t bothered checking out the individual raindrops. Upon doing so, he realized Dina was right. Every single raindrop contained a bit of time energy. Individually, it was meaningless, but as the rain accumulated, it would rapidly build up and have a noticeable effect. But… the energy expenditure had to be utterly insane, and while studying the Sword Saint, Jake did notice some sweat mixed in with the raindrops. He was truly straining himself just to keep up the massive, chamber-spanning domain.

Things got worse when the two Demon Guardians properly joined the brawl, and the Prime Summoner began doing some magic in the background. The regular cultists had never truly joined the fight, but they now grouped around the Summoner as she raised her hands to the sky.

“Loyal subjects… today is the day we ascend!”

She yelled this loudly as a giant magical circle appeared, spanning a huge section of the chamber. All of the regular cultists began chanting, and the energy level in the room rose in tandem with the Prime Summoner’s aura.

Jake had read enough about rituals to know what this was. He was about to tell the King to dispel the barrier and have them join the fight before the ritual was completed, but before he could, the Sword Saint spoke through their telepathic mark.

“Jake, I remember you being curious about my mythical rarity skill. Well, formerly mythical, now legendary.” Opening his eyes wide, Jake sent a mental confirmation. “I would advise you to strengthen the barrier, Fallen King. This attack is indiscriminate.”

The King reacted by infusing the barrier around them with his golden energy, and Dina also assisted, applying a green membrane to further strengthen it.

Retreating from his foes, the Sword Saint took a deep breath, shifted his stance, and knelt down while holding his weapon with the tip of the blade resting against the floor like he was about to perform an upward sweep.

Then… it happened. The raindrops falling all over the massive chamber stopped moving in mid-air and simply floated. An incredibly intense aura erupted from the Sword Saint, and Jake saw the Demonic Cultist Prime Summoner react with panic as all of the raindrops moved backward in time, the puddles on the floor slowly dripping upwards.

“What is—” the Summoner began, but she was cut off.

The Sword Saint raised his blade in one fluid motion, and the rain followed suit.

“Rain of Time: Reversal.”

Every droplet that had fallen became a small blade piercing the clouds above. The entire chamber rumbled as the ground was torn up, an area of several square kilometers seemingly lifting off the ground amid the heavenly destruction sundering the hall. Within less than a second, every single raindrop had been sent flying back to the clouds above.

Each of them individually only contained enough energy to lightly injure a peak E-grade or early D-grade… but when there were millions, the result was devastating.

Jake was taken aback by the ability, but what happened next was almost as ludicrous. The Sword Saint raised his blade, and the rainclouds above descended upon him like a whirlwind, the energy entering his body. Jake felt the old man slowly being revitalized. Not only had he reversed the raindrops—he had reclaimed a large portion of the resources spent on the skill.

Looking out at the chamber, the chaos had finally started dying down, revealing the scene of the Sword Saint’s devastation. The terrain was covered in small, pencil-sized holes, and in the center of it all knelt the Prime Summoner, blood running down her lips. The two demons at her sides had also survived.

As for the weaker cultists… not a single one remained, aside from a few heavily injured Flameblades, Cauterizers, and Guardians spread here and there.

“You… You ruined everything! I was to ascend!” the Prime Summoner screamed, her ritual having failed with the deaths of thousands of her subjects and the circle itself utterly torn apart.

“Yeah, well, tough shit,” Jake said as he walked over to join the Sword Saint, the King having long since dispelled the barrier.

“I… I will kill you all!” she screamed as her body erupted in power, and the two Demon Guardians both bulked up.

Anyway, skipping the boring part, the group walked towards the cathedral ten minutes later to check what was in there, leaving only corpses in their wake. Jake even got a level, and they all received a nice achievement when the Prime Summoner died.

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 210 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 210 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Bonus Objective Completed: Defeat the Demonic Cultist Prime Summoner. 200 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Defeat the Demonic Cultist Prime Summoner before she can carry out her ascension ritual. 250 Nevermore Points earned.

All in all, good stuff.

Upon seeing the achievement related to not allowing the ritual to happen, Jake was glad they had stopped it, though he also wanted to see what would have happened if they’d allowed her to do it. As for why they were headed towards the cathedral… well, Jake had spotted something interesting there. Or, more accurately, someone interesting.

Chapter 14

Two Old Men

The cathedral had, to Jake’s amazement, not at all been affected by the attack from the Sword Saint. Maybe it was protected by some magical barrier, or perhaps the construction was indeed durable enough to handle his weird reversal of the rain.

This meant that the interior was also spotless and bereft of damage. It was also entirely empty, save for a hidden cellar dungeon with no obvious entrance. Jake managed to sniff out how to enter through his sphere: A secret door opened by someone pulling on a lantern hanging from a pillar. Yes, Minaga was that cliche.

“Do you believe this individual will be a foe?” the Sword Saint asked as they walked down the newly revealed stairs.

“I doubt it,” Jake answered. “The dude is in chains and in a sealed room, so unless they are really shitty hosts, I would assume it is a prisoner.”

Even if he didn’t share it, Jake did have an idea about who this person might be based on the stories Minaga had shared. Upon entering the hidden prisoner dungeon, his suspicions were pretty much confirmed. A disheveled old man was chained to a wall, sealed away by a red barrier.

[Old Royal Mage – lvl 250]

Again, a very original name from Minaga. At least the Demon Lord had a unique name, based on what the Prime Summoner had said.

After they entered the room, the old mage also seemed to notice them, but he didn’t even look up.

“Just kill me already… I will never betray my comrades!” he said in a valiant tone.

Jake wanted to praise Minaga for his wonderful dialogue, but the Sword Saint spoke first. “We are not with the Demonic Cult, but those who have come to slay them.”

The old man looked up and laid his eyes on them. “Truly? I feared all was lost when the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas was released from the seal that we of the Mage Court laid down five hundred years ago. In an attempt to help the citizens, I came here to try and stop the Prime Summoner from assisting the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas regain his former strength, but I was too late and was instead captured. Tell me, did you succeed in stopping her from ascending to Prime Consort of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas?”

Who the hell just goes on a tirade like that after one reassurance we are the good guys!? Jake wanted to scream, but the old swordsman stayed in character.

“Her foul ritual was ended by my blade, and the cultists slain for their evil acts,” he said in a serious tone.

“Good, good… Did the Knight of Light’s Dawn join you? He was said to have guarded the entrance to this labyrinth, and I fear the worst if he encountered the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas. Even if the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas was weakened… tell me, is he safe?”

Does he really have to refer to the Demon Lord as “evil Demon Lord Gubrothas” every time? Jake thought, yet he kept his mouth shut.

“Sadly, the Knight valiantly fought the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas but failed to stop him,” the Sword Saint said in a comforting tone. “With his dying breath, he tasked us with stopping the Prime Summoner. That we found you here is simply a blessed happenstance. Please, allow us to free you.”

The Royal Mage nodded, and Jake and the others proceeded to dismantle the barrier and free the mage from his chains. Jake was primarily interested in the magic circle they had used for the prison. The chains served as energy-sappers that made the person too weak to use their physical strength to rip themselves free, while the formation itself drained their resource at all times, making them even weaker in all other aspects. However, Jake believed the most important function was the formation’s ability to disrupt energy movements, even within the body of the affected person. It acted almost like a neurotoxin, making Jake very curious.

As the two old men continued speaking, Jake subtly disassembled the entire prison cell and stored it away, including the chains on the wall and the floor tiles on which the magical circle had been carved.

“Thank you, thank you, oh valiant heroes,” the Royal Mage said. Adopting his usual dramatic and severe tone, he added, “Please, with the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas now freed, he must be stopped, but I fear he has already managed to reach his castle deep within the labyrinth. I… I wish we could seal him once more, but I am too weak. Heroes, do you believe yourselves capable of facing the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas? That you can bring peace and justice?”

“That is a quest we would take upon ourselves with honor,” the Sword Saint said, nodding.

“I cannot express my gratitude enough, heroes,” the old mage said with a big smile. “Allow me to assist you in your quest.”

The old man made a magical seal with his hands, then summoned a small golden stone with magical scripts on it that Jake promptly Identified.

[Anti-Demon Sword-Sealing Stone (Unique)] – A stone created by the Old Royal Mage, capable of temporarily weakening the Demon Lord by sealing in his sword. The duration of the seal is one minute (60 seconds). This item cannot be used outside of Nevermore and will cease to exist if brought out for too long. Will break upon use.

“In an attempt to assist the Knight of Light’s Dawn, I created this Sealing Stone, but sadly I could never use it… Please, would you take it instead? Use it to slay the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas?” The Old Royal Mage then held up the stone.

To Jake’s surprise, the Sword Saint shook his hand and closed the hands of the Old Royal Mage around the stone. “No, this quest is ours alone, and we shall slay the Demon Lord using our own power. We have already encountered him once, and the last time, he cravenly fled. I thank you for the offer, but your job is done, and you can rest. We will handle what remains.”

“Truly?” the old mage asked in disbelief. “The evil Demon Lord Gubrothas is not easily bested… Even if you faced him once, he will be far stronger when you face him in his domain.”

“No matter where or when, he shall fall to us. Evil shall never prevail; I swear this on my life.”

“Very well… I shall respect your conviction, and once more, I thank you, heroes.” The old man bowed deeply.

Achievement earned: Locate and free the Old Royal Mage and reject the Anti-Demon Sword-Sealing Stone. 200 Nevermore Points earned.

So that’s why he rejected it… Bonus points. Yay, Jake thought, giving a mental thumbs-up to the Sword Saint.

The old mage seemed to be deep in thought for a moment before he smiled at them. “Even without the seal, allow me to assist you in reaching the deeper parts. We have a stronghold that should still hold due to formations of old laid down by the Court. It is close to the next entryway leading further into the demon’s domain.”

Jake instantly caught on and sent a mental negative to the Sword Saint. Chances were this stronghold would be within a room, thus making them lose out on an achievement for tackling the minimum number of rooms needed to progress.

“Once more, I thank you for the offer, but we wish to scour the halls to truly wipe out the foul cultists that still wander them,” the Sword Saint said in a solemn tone.

“I understand,” the mage said with a nod. “In that case, all I can give you is my well-wishes. Go forth and be the arbiters of justice.”

“That we shall.” The Sword Saint nodded and bowed, then turned around and left the cathedral.

Jake looked at the old mage for a second before mimicking the actions of the Sword Saint, including bowing before he moved to follow. Everyone except for the Fallen King did a small bow; even Sylphie gave it a try.

Following the Sword Saint out of the cathedral and back towards the hallway, Jake gave the old man a questioning look.

“I did theater back in my school days,” the old man revealed. “It has been… Hm, must be a century since then? How time flies…”

“Old fart,” Jake snorted jokingly, the old man just smiling in response.

Once gathered back in the hallway, Jake proceeded to keep guiding the group towards the exit. With commentary, of course.

“Such a missed opportunity. You should have just teleported with the Old Royal Mage. Even if you didn’t want to wait for him to recover, Jake could have just handed him a mana potion to get him up to speed. It would have been faster by a lot, and you would have been able to see the cool stronghold and even interact with all the people who live there. There are a bunch of individuals with very interesting information, including a former member of the cult, an old nobleman, and the squire of the Knight of Light’s Dawn that died at the beginning of this floor. Who knows—maybe they would have even given you some reward for slaying the Prime Summoner? At the very least, you would have seen them all react to the Old Royal Mage reuniting with old friends. It would have been really touching. Even his granddaughter would’ve been there, handing you all these small flower crowns to wear for freeing her grandpa…”

“Or, we could get the bonus achievement points by only doing the minimum number of rooms,” Jake countered.

“Well, considering the room with the Prime Summoner was only for the bonus objective, you could have skipped that too.”

“Yeah, but seeing as it is the bonus objective, and coupled with the points for freeing the Old Royal Mage, I’m gonna bet it has at least equal or more points, especially with the two achievements we just got. Oh, yeah, and the experience was also pretty worth it.” Jake smiled lightly as he turned to the group. “Patrol ahead on the right, two-point-five kilometers.”

The Fallen King and Sylphie responded by picking up speed and moving ahead of the group to clean up the patrol.

“Why do I get the feeling you said that out loud and not through telepathy just to annoy me?” Minaga asked.

“I have no idea why you would possibly think that,” Jake said before he looked at the Sword Saint and Dina. “We should reach the end in about thirty minutes. Just got eleven left turns and eight right turns before we reach the final room.”

“You are definitely doing it on purpose.”

“All in your imagination.” Jake shrugged. The Fallen King and Sylphie soon rejoined them as they passed through the place where the two of them had utterly slaughtered the patrol.

From there on out, it was just a rush to the final room with the gateway in it. This room was also filled with cultists, including a level 255 Cultist Leader who ended up being weaker than the Prime Summoner. Maybe he would have been stronger if he had managed to finish his large-scale ritual, but they’d promptly killed him before he had a chance to. Without further ado, they entered the gateway to finish off the thirty-second floor even faster than they had the thirty-first.

Thirty-second floor completed. 320 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-second floor in less than a day (24 hours). 500 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-second floor without allowing the Demonic Cultists to perform any of their planned rituals. 400 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-second floor without receiving assistance from any friendly creatures. 350 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-second floor while only entering a maximum of two challenge rooms. 300 Nevermore Points earned.

Appearing in the in-between lounge, Jake admired all the achievements just rolling in.

“We managed to stop all the rituals?” Dina asked, a bit confused. “That seemed… too easy? There were only those two…”

“No, there were not only two—there was a total of nine rituals going on across this entire labyrinth—but setting aside the mandatory two you handled, even the slowest one would’ve taken around a full day to complete,” Minaga told Dina. “Honestly, I am questioning why I even decided it was a good idea to add an achievement for not allowing any rituals to go off while also having one to complete it in under a day. Seems a bit like an unnecessary double reward… Oh, well, what can you do about it? I guess you did interrupt two rituals, so it wasn’t like it was totally free.”

“Oh… thank you for telling me,” Dina said with a small bow.

“See, Jake? That is how you treat an all-powerful dungeon master who wields your fate in his hands.”

“Noted and ignored.” Jake smiled. “Though I have an even more important question than Dina.”

After a pause, Minaga said, “What?”

“Are the drinks in the bar different in this in-between room from the ones before?”

“Yeah, they are… why?”

“Any recommendations?” Jake asked genuinely. “I didn’t do that well last time. I reckoned you would have some good recipes.”

“Mixing Ualberry Juice and… Actually, get over there and let me guide you,” Minaga said, oddly engaged. “As an alchemist, you should be able to at least properly mix drinks. It can’t be worse than last time. That was a damn atrocity.”

“Sir, yes, sir,” Jake said as he popped over to the bar. The next two hours were spent with Minaga guiding Jake on how to mix some banger drinks, and he learned a lot about different foodstuffs of the multiverse.

Sylphie also opened the lockbox in the room while he was working at the bar, and inside was a staff suited for a mage. A fire mage, more specifically, as the staff gave off intense fire-affinity energy. This made Dina visibly upset with the thought of getting it, so they opted to just decide by random chance. The Fallen King eventually won.

They had chosen to relax in the in-between room primarily because the Sword Saint needed to fully get back in top condition after using his Rain of Time and boosting skills. That Jake got a lesson in drink mixing was just a bonus.

After resting, they entered the next floor as usual and once more appeared in a room pretty much identical to the thirty-first and thirty-second floors. And as was also customary, they got their usual welcome message.

Welcome to the thirty-third floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth (Part 3)

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: Free at least a quarter (25%) of the prisoners trapped on the thirty-third floor (0%).

Current progress: Prisoners freed (0%), end reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 19,203

Minaga appeared in all his glory, a huge grin on his face as they all read the floor’s description.

“Hello again!” Minaga said with a big smile.

“Hello again, indeed.” Jake smiled in return. “Will this floor be different from the last two?”

“Oh… this floor is truly special… because this time, your cheating skills won’t give you any big advantage; I can promise you that!” Minaga said, full of confidence. “Oh, and I already set the difficulty to Archmage again. If you have any complaints, voice them in three… two… one. Okay, it is set now.”

“No complaints about the difficulty,” Jake said with a shrug. “But not sure I believe the first part.”

“You will… Oh, you will!” Minaga said with maniacal laughter as he disappeared from the room, and his voice echoed as the door in the distance glowed red and opened.

“Do tell me… how are you going to cheat this time around, huh!?”

Chapter 15

A Different But Welcome Experience

For the first time since entering Minaga’s Labyrinth, Jake had truly met his match. Minaga had claimed Jake wouldn’t be able to “cheat” on this floor, and Jake had obviously not believed him. It wasn’t that there was no way to cheat him, just that doing it would fuck over others far too much.

Make the labyrinth randomly shuffle around to nullify Jake’s Pulse of Perception? That would make it utterly impossible to find anything and have all exploration just be pure luck—something Jake was certain Minaga didn’t want.

Make it so the rooms only revealed their contents after entering? Well, the rooms existed and weren’t generated when they entered, so this would be a huge change in how the entire dungeon worked. It would also mess with people who used more mundane skills. Minaga had even commented on Jake using tracking as a fairly legit way of finding things, so he doubted the dungeon master wanted to stop everything.

Increasing the distances to make Jake’s scanning range insufficient would also just ruin the entire labyrinth. If the only way to nerf Jake was to make things take too long, it would make all the time-based achievements useless.

Minaga did also reveal that these labyrinths were, of course, the same for everyone. Even if Minaga messed around, he still had a strong sense of fairness and cared a lot about balance. That was why he had not made any direct moves to make Jake less of a cheat, allowing him to do as he did while complaining. However, on this floor, things were different.

“Do you see now? Tell me, Jake, how are you going to ruin all sense of exploration on this floor!?” Minaga sounded like a true maniac.

He had won. Jake had to face that. Staring through the now open gate leading into the labyrinth, his Pulse of Perception made it clear that he had indeed been thoroughly countered by Minaga, who’d designed this floor in a fashion he hadn’t even imagined would make sense for a labyrinth.

“You can’t, can you!? Ha ha!”

“You are an absolute madman,” Jake muttered as he stared at his mental map of parts of the floor. “How does this even qualify as a labyrinth anymore?”

What Minaga had done was indeed ingenious. He had gotten rid of all of Jake’s usual exploration advantages with one small trick:

Not making it a labyrinth.

“That’s right! Completely linear, on-rails floor with not a single ounce of exploration! Just run straight down the middle till you reach the next floor, and you’re done!” Minaga laughed. “Of course, you can also choose to stop and save the prisoners, so maybe you think you can use your cheating skills to locate them… but they are also right there, out in the open! No secrets here!”

“I am also not certain this qualifies as a labyrinth,” the Sword Saint commented.

“Alright, so I did admittedly take some creative liberties with this design, but you only see it as a problem because you view this floor in isolation,” Minaga explained, sounding significantly less maniacal. “I see these floors as one continuous labyrinth, so even if this part is straightforward, it is only a small part of the whole.”

“That makes sense,” Dina said, nodding.

“Ree!” Sylphie chimed in.

“See, they get it! Especially the Sylphian Hawk!”

“I guess so,” Jake muttered in response to Sylphie’s apt metaphor. She’d explained that saying this floor was not a labyrinth was like saying that if a beast in the forest had a hill as their domain, then the hill wasn’t a part of the forest anymore. This, of course, wouldn’t make sense, because while hills were not forests, hills could still be in forests. Same as a straight path could not be called a labyrinth, but a labyrinth could have parts that were straightforward.

“Rather than discuss the definition of a labyrinth, shouldn’t we proceed into the floor?” the Fallen King said.

“We should,” the Sword Saint agreed.

Jake didn’t complain as they walked through the gate leading into a small hallway that was no more than twenty meters long before entering their first room. These hallways had extra-thick fog that not even Jake could see through in any way, and they limited movement so much that they had to just walk.

Entering the first room, Jake understood why the thick fog was there: One couldn’t just look through the fog and scout the next room… but also, whatever was on the floor couldn’t spot them before they entered.

They found themselves standing within a large, open room more extensive than the one the Prime Summoner had been in. Jake estimated it had to be at least fifty kilometers long and about ten kilometers wide, and it was filled to the brim with life.

Not the friendly kind, however, if their names were anything to go by.

[Demon Guard – lvl 248]

[Demon Torturer – lvl 251]

That’s right—they were all demons. The entire floor had a bunch of spread-out camps and villages, with one large tower at the back of the room. There, over forty-five kilometers away, was a figure sitting and meditating on a chair atop it, overlooking the entire room.

[Demon Warden – lvl 255]

If one hadn’t noticed yet, the names of all these demons had a theme of sorts. They were all guarding something. That something being large groups of people sealed within barriers in all of the camps and villages.

[Prisoner – lvl 175]

Jake also spotted a few C-grades, but they were mostly D-grades with a few E-grades mixed in. As he scouted the room, he also noticed that this entrance area was shrouded. Based on what Jake could see, nothing could detect them ten meters from the entryway, which was the only reason no one had spotted them yet. The reason for this magic circle was also pretty obvious.

“The second we make a move… those prisoners will be in deep shit,” Jake muttered to the group.

“They appear to be kept as potential sacrifices,” the Sword Saint said.

“Which means that when we are discovered, a good portion of them will be sacrificed relatively quickly,” the Fallen King said. “So we will have to decide whether we want to save as many as possible or rush this entire floor. If we split up and secure a camp each, we should be able to ensure the twenty-five percent for the bonus objective. However, we will also need to be cautious. Any accidental attack could kill a significant portion of them, and while we may be careful, I doubt the demons care.”

“Ree,” Sylphie said with a low screech.

“Stealth is an option… but how many of us are good at it?” Jake asked. “I can do some stealth, but…” He looked at the others beside him.

“Ree!” Sylphie said proudly.

“I think we already talked about how being hidden by giant tornadoes doesn’t count as being invisible,” Jake pointed out.

“Ree?”

“Yes, even if the tornado prevents them from seeing anything,” Jake said with mild exasperation.

“Ree…” Sylphie seemed a bit sad.

Jake felt somewhat bad about ruining her plan, but someone had to say it. As they were trying to figure out what to do, Dina knelt on the ground and felt the soil. That was when Jake noticed that the ground was indeed different here. Rather than the hard rock of the chamber floor, it was more like normal soil found on the outside. Looking at Dina, he realized what she was trying to find out.

“Dina, what are you looking for?” the Sword Saint asked curiously.

“There are a total of fourteen barriers sealing away prisoners, right?” Dina asked.

Jake released another Pulse of Perception to scout the room and nodded. “Yeah, fourteen.”

Dina nodded along. “Give me ten minutes, and I will make sure they are safe.”

“You’re going to go through the ground, aren’t you?” Jake asked.

“Yeah, I will create protection for them by summoning vines.” She nodded and began to infuse energy into the ground.

Jake noticed that the formation hiding their presence slowly faded as she did this, and he responded by creating a barrier of stable arcane energy all around them, colored the same as the background. Was this perfect stealth? No, but it appeared to be good enough, as Dina’s actions were not very flashy to begin with.

While Dina prepared, Jake and the three others also made plans for where to strike. Their main problem was the size of the room, so they needed someone to get to the back fast, preferably before the Warden had time to make a move. Jake ended up taking this upon himself. He opened a small hole in the stable arcane barrier and snuck out, activating his stealth skill for the first time in a good while. With it, he also used something else he hadn’t really used before: his new cloak. It allowed him to better hide while in the shadows, and as luck would have it, these demons weren’t a big fan of having a lot of light around. They just used open fires everywhere, which cast plenty of shadows for Jake to stick to.

He quite easily made it to the back of the room undetected, helped along by none of the demons really being on guard, despite being called literal Guards. The Enforcers were mainly inside buildings chilling, with the Guards just lazily patrolling about and the Torturers seemingly working on their torture tools, which none of them seemed to even use. All the prisoners just stood catatonically within their sealed-off confines, waiting to be rescued. It was some real NPC behavior.

Either way, once he got to the back of the room, Jake sent a mental confirmation to the rest of the party members, all of whom had prepared to launch their own attacks. Jake had been tasked with dealing with the Warden as quickly as possible, and he had more than gladly taken that task upon himself.

Finding a good position in the shadows, Jake took out the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter he had prepared on his way there and began charging his Arcane Powershot. He remained undetected, as the cloak hid not only his person, but even his actions and energies, as per the description:

“Allows the wearer to meld into the shadows when they stand still or move slowly, masking their presence and all of their actions, including energies. Improved further if already dwelling in the shadows.”

Jake had been a bit skeptical of how well it would work and was fully prepared to be discovered instantly, but the Demon Warden remained oblivious even as someone charged an attack a few hundred meters behind him. Once Jake had fully charged the Arcane Powershot, it was time.

“Go!” Jake sent through their link as he let go of the string and unleashed his attack. The second he did so, the cloak failed to suppress his energies any longer. His body exploded with arcane energy, lighting up the entire back part of the room with a pink-purple light.

At that very moment, they all made their moves at once. In every single village or camp with prisoners, vines erupted from the ground and embraced the barriers sealing in the prisoners. Bark began to grow all over the vines to protect them further. Smaller vines also tore up the ritual circle, deactivating it and ensuring the demons could not harm any of the people within.

A giant beam of pure golden energy exploded from the entrance area of the room and struck one of the camps without any prisoners in it, resulting in a giant explosion that leveled the entire thing. A green tornado shot across the terrain towards the middle of the room, then towards one of the villages with a high prisoner population. Rain began to fall across the room’s left side as a swordsman stormed forward.

The Demon Warden—Jake’s target and the boss of this room—leapt up, alarmed at the sight of roots shooting up all over the place. He had barely managed to stand and turn before he, with wide eyes, raised a hand to try and block the arrow coming his way.

Red shards flew everywhere as the crystalline barrier shattered. The arrow sank into his chest, sending him flying backward. In mid-air, the Demon Warden managed to stabilize himself. A fist-sized hole now marred his chest, but he didn’t even have to orient himself before another shot hit him from above, launching him down toward the ground.

Jake had instantly jumped into the air after releasing the initial arrow to launch one at a downwards angle, grounding the Demon Warden. He proceeded to unleash a rain of arrows upon the Demon Warden, but a giant red disc blocked it and launched itself up towards Jake.

Dodging, Jake refused to let up and shot another rain of arrows. The demon once more blocked with a barrier, but all of the arrows suddenly bent and flew around it the moment they got close, hitting the boss anyway.

With a roar, the Demon Warden flew up from below, his body filled with wounds. An inferno erupted around him as burning crystals materialized. He stared at Jake with hatred but didn’t speak as he flew forward, wanting to face Jake in melee.

Jake humored him as they clashed in mid-air, and it quickly became clear what he was dealing with. A pugilist.

The demon covered his hands in crystal-like skin and even used the floating crystals around him to further empower his attacks or launch strikes. Sadly for the guy, Jake had fought far better… and he was not at all the same melee fighter as he had been back then.

Less skilled than Carmen…

Jake proceeded to dodge under the hand of the demon and punch him in the stomach with a katar. He reacted by trying to kick Jake, but Jake raised his own leg to block and stabbed the demon in his already-outstretched arm. The Warden tried to pull away, but Jake gave chase and refused to let up.

He knew he was on a bit of a timer. The death of the Warden would hopefully lead to some level of panic amongst the guards, so for the first time since entering Nevermore, Jake activated his boosting skill and got serious.

Every hit by the demon was countered as Jake focused on destroying his hands first. The crystals were strong, yes, but against his Blackpoint Nanoblade, they still faltered. The indestructible nature of Eternal Hunger also allowed him to not care about the tip breaking as he met the demon punch for punch, coming out on top every time.

Desperation from the demon began to set in. The Warden had failed to meaningfully land any blows on Jake, and the assistance he had expected to come was occupied elsewhere. Realizing this, the Demon Warden went on one last offensive, knowing that if he managed to significantly injure Jake, he would have a chance to regroup with his allies.

That was never going to happen.

The Demon Warden exploded forward, his entire body temporarily covered in deep red spiked crystals. Jake flew to meet him, but just before they clashed, reality split.

Gaze of the Apex Hunter momentarily froze the Demon Warden. Jake slammed two Descending Dark Fangs into his chest just before he was capable of moving again or using his full power on the hunter that had entered melee with him.

The Warden slammed his fists together in a giant explosion of crystals and flames, but rather than crushing the human, his fists met the shadowy curse energy of Eternal Shadow.

Still confused, the Demon Warden had no time to react before an arrow pierced his eye and embedded itself deep within his skull—fired by the real Jake, who had jumped back as he used his mythical skill.

The arrow had included all the Hunting Momentum Jake had built up during the fight, and it resulted in the arrow only stopping when it reached the back of the demon’s skull. The Warden stumbled as Jake switched the balance of the arrow, making it explode within his head.

Somehow he still lived, but Jake followed up with an Arcane Powershot, shooting the head straight off the Warden.

*You have slain [Demon Warden – lvl 255] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

From there on out, it was just a cleanup of the entire room, as they decided to kill every single demon there. Hey, it had to give an achievement, right? Of course, Jake didn’t expect to get that achievement quite yet, because they had far more rooms ahead in this on-rails portion of Minaga’s Labyrinth.

Not that Jake was complaining. Also, finally getting in some pure combat was a good reprieve from just walking through hallways, and something Jake got a feeling they all enjoyed—even Dina. Surprisingly enough, there was one more person who also enjoyed it.

“See, this is how things are supposed to be! Through pure skill and power, you manage to overcome the floor and conquer! I knew you could do it! Definitely giving Dina MVP for this one, by the way.”

“I thought you couldn’t speak while within the rooms, only the hallways?” Jake asked, still not done with the demon cleanup.

“Oh, yeah, got a bit too excited there. Act like I didn’t say anything, alright? Good not-a-talk. Minaga out!”

Chapter 16

An Expansive Spectrum of Emotions

After Jake killed the Warden, the demons more or less fell apart, and it was just a cleanup from there. A few of them had tried to get to the prisoners during the attack, but Dina’s bark-covered roots had completely stopped all their attempts.

Jake joined the others in killing, and in the end, they finished off every demon without a single prisoner dying. To make things even better, Jake got an unexpected level upon killing one of the last Torturers.

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 211 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

As for the progress of saved prisoners, it turned out that despite saving everyone, they had not yet completed the bonus objective of saving at least 25% of the prisoners.

Current progress: Prisoners freed (20%)

This was honestly expected, as Jake saw far more rooms ahead of them in this linear part of the labyrinth. In fact, he had a strong feeling there were more than five in total, which he sure wouldn’t complain about. Nevermore had thus far not really been that interesting in the combat department, outside of maybe the bout with the Demon Lord, but the Warden had been decent in Jake’s mind, and even the average demon enemy on this floor could pose a danger if he let his guard down. It was a great change of pace from walking through hallways with no real danger… outside of the traps that Jake easily led them around.

Of course, some parts of Minaga’s Labyrinth remained the same, such as their host’s commentary and the utterly outrageous “people” they could meet and talk to. The leader of the saved prisoners in this room was a prime example.

“Thank you, heroes, for saving us from the demons,” the old man that looked a bit too much like the Old Royal Mage said as he bowed to them. “After we heard of the return of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas, we feared all was lost and had resigned ourselves to our fates. Now that you have shown up, we have hope once more. Please do your utmost to bring justice to us all and continue on your honorable quest. We shall stay here and rebuild that which was lost.”

Jake and company had gathered all the prisoners they had saved after Dina laid down her vines, and one of the only C-grades among them suddenly came alive to tell them this. To the cheers of exactly two hundred prisoners, they moved towards the next room.

Before they even entered it, Minaga spoke up, clearly not caring that much about his earlier ruse of never talking while they were inside rooms.

“Managing to free all the prisoners so easily while not truly facing any difficulties dealing with your foes… Impressive, indeed! Now, the difficulty will increase slightly with each coming room, so do not be so sure you will be able to use the same strategy twice in a row!”

Upon entering the second room and scouting it, Jake turned to Dina. “We are using the exact same strategy two times in a row.”

The room was nearly identical to the first one except for a change in layout, a few higher-leveled demons around, and a Warden one level higher than the last one. They did an exact repeat of the strategy from the last room, and it went off just like before. Almost a bit too much like before, considering the words of the second old man representing the saved prisoners.

“Thank you, brave heroes, for saving us from the demons. After the return of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas, we all feared that we were doomed and had resigned ourselves to our fates. Now that you have shown up, we can hope for a better future once more. Please do your utmost to restore justice and continue on your valiant quest. We shall stay here and rebuild.”

Bonus Objective Completed: Save at least 25% of the prisoners. 200 Nevermore Points earned.

Current progress: Prisoners freed (40%)

Walking to the next hallway, Jake failed to resist a comment. “Minaga… please tell me you outsourced whatever bloody dialogue these people use.”

“I am not the one who decides what they say! It is entirely caused by you, and I am sure they are genuinely just showing their appreciation and—”

“Bullshit,” Jake said, calling him out.

“Alright, fair, I made them, but that doesn’t mean I just decided what they say. Now, this may get a bit philosophical, but hear me out. Normal creatures in the multiverse are born without purpose—even those we usually say have one. Many would argue something like a True Royal is born with the purpose of ruling their Lineage, but that is strictly incorrect. It is just the most obvious Path to them. If they so wished, they could choose to break that Path entirely and actively go against it. Their Records allow it, and they have the ability to do whatever they want. In the eyes of the system, their purpose is their own to find.”

Jake slowly nodded along, kind of understanding what Minaga was talking about. The system cared a lot about freedom and allowing everyone to find their own Paths. However, these creatures in dungeons were different, which Minaga expanded on as he continued.

“Meanwhile, creatures like these prisoners have no Paths. They were truly born with just one purpose, and it isn’t possible for them to break it. As I am sure you all know, in natural dungeons, it is possible to actually bring out the creatures, though only one version can exist in the real world. However, that isn’t true for many dungeons created by dungeon engineers, as the dungeon is inherently tied to them. Unless the creature in question was brought from the outside and into the dungeon, that is, but in most cases, only an Image of the creature is made while doing this, with the true version persisting in the world outside. Ah, by the way, funny fact… If you take the Image of a creature that is already dead in the real world outside of a dungeon, it will instantly die. Actually, not that funny of a fact, on second thought… Anyway, my point is that nearly all the creatures you encounter within Nevermore are made entirely for Nevermore, never existed in the real world, and are all purpose-built for the dungeon. Anything they say or do is done with a purpose, but that purpose is never their own, only the wish of their creator. In summary, even if they do possess free will and have free thoughts, it is useless to them, so their way of speaking is only made with purpose, not with any intent or actual emotion behind it.”

“That got… deeper than I had expected,” Jake muttered as he and the others stopped before the hallway leading into the third room, waiting for Minaga’s ramble to finish. “Are they sapient?”

“Oh, they are, which may make this seem a bit darker. You see, there have been parties in the past convincing these creatures that they can become true living beings like everyone else, with their own futures and Paths. Naturally, that isn’t the case, but it is technically a possibility to convince all the survivors on prior floors to follow you here by making contracts with them and such. They will still be unable to enter the city layer and continue onwards after the thirty-fifth floor. However, if they are under the illusion of free will till then, they would be quite handy helpers, especially the Knight of Light’s Dawn and Old Royal Mage. Oh, you just reminded me… There was also an interesting demon prince that entered with a party and ended up with the Demon Lord joining him, so I had to adapt the scenario quite a bit moving forward… Nothing for you guys to worry about, though. You are experiencing the vanilla quest. Well, if we ignore the fact that you bypass my storytelling and just brute-force through everything while cheesing every floor, that is.”

“I see.” Jake nodded, trying not to think too much about it as they entered the third room, where they would use the same strategy once more.

However, he couldn’t help but think about a certain someone really good at manipulating people.

This brought up a scary thought… Ell’Hakan could manipulate emotions, and seeing as Minaga already seemed friendly towards everyone who entered the dungeon and was nearly omnipotent when it came to shaping the dungeon as desired, could Ell’Hakan convince Minaga to help? Could he make Minaga tell him everything there was to know while assisting them directly through different means?

No matter how powerful Minaga was, Ell’Hakan had a Bloodline, so his ability would still work. Minaga seemed aware of what was happening even in other versions of the floors, so Jake considered… should he warn him? Finally, he spoke up.

“Hey… would it be possible for someone with a Bloodline to influence you?”

“Considering you have a Bloodline and influenced me quite a lot already by infuriatingly ruining all exploration aspects of my labyrinth, then I would say the answer is yes,” the dungeon master answered.

The Sword Saint seemed to catch on to what Jake was asking and followed up. “I think Jake is asking if someone with a Bloodline focused on manipulating others would be able to influence you. Especially given the fact that you show up in front of us at the beginning of every floor.”

“While I won’t answer that with a definite no… I must say it is funny that you would ask. If you are worried about what I think you are worried about, then don’t be. You are talking to Minaga here; who the hell do you think I am?”

“A powerful yet utterly insane and unstable Unique Lifeform who likes to create dungeons while constantly complaining to the people actually doing said dungeons?” Jake asked rhetorically.

“You’re goddamn right.”

Ell’Hakan stepped onto the thirty-first floor, followed closely by the carefully curated party members Yip of Yore had introduced to him. While he was generally satisfied with them, especially the Saintess from the Holy Church, he still had a gnawing feeling. In all honesty, neither he nor Yip had expected the Chosen of the Malefic Viper to get a good party, given the relative uncertainty around him. Most factions would hesitate to send their top talent with him, so it was regrettable that he had managed to gather quite the group, and even more so that he had convinced the Unique Lifeform to join him.

The Ashen Phantom Devourer was someone Ell’Hakan had tried and failed to make a permanent ally, but the innate pride of a Unique Lifeform was not something even his Bloodline could overcome. He had managed to convince it to work with them, but in the end, the Devourer had always seen itself as superior, which was also why Ell’Hakan had been fine with sacrificing it, even if it would’ve been preferable to have it as a permanent fixture in his faction.

Dispelling the thought, Ell’Hakan focused on the task at hand. Shortly after entering the floor, the usual prompt was presented.

Welcome to the thirty-first floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: N/A

Current progress: End reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 14,930

Reading it over, Ell’Hakan nodded at their luck. A labyrinth. The Priestess from the Holy Church was an expert in divination, and with their tracker also on the team, this level should be a breeze. Their entire party was designed to handle Nevermore, after all—an advantage they did have over the Malefic’s Chosen’s party.

As he considered this advantage, something slightly unexpected happened.

“Welcome, welcome, welcome! Ah, some interesting visitors this time around, eh!?” The voice suddenly echoed throughout the entire room as lights flashed, marking the appearance of a creature. Ell’Hakan’s party was on high alert, but he raised a hand, not detecting a single aggressive emotion from the creature that had just appeared. In fact, the mix he felt was oddly upbeat… but a touch too complex to easily read intent from. That there was no intent to attack was at least lucky, considering the level and power of the being.

[Minaga – lvl 275]

“My name is Minaga, your incredible host,” the creature said with a smile. “You are indeed one interesting bunch, I must say!”

Ell’Hakan was already at work reading the creature when it looked at him.

“Ell’Hakan, right? From what I heard, your Bloodline allows you to read and influence emotions, which seems pretty accurate. However, I gotta warn you, using your ability on me won’t do much…” Minaga shrugged.

“I see that my efforts were in vain,” Ell’Hakan said, nodding as he smiled. However, even if the creature said he had failed, Ell’Hakan felt something far different. He felt himself influencing the creature a lot, the emotions he was reading changing rapidly. This was the thing about eccentric beings… Their emotional landscapes were vast and easily affected. Even if they were aware of his influence, it never really mattered.

“See, why do I get the feeling you don’t actually think that?” Minaga said as he shook his head. “But alright, I’ll play ball. Give it your best shot. Truly take a good look at my wonderful emotional spectrum.”

Ell’Hakan then recalled a moment from his youth. When scanning emotions, he had several ways of doing it. Reading the emotions of individuals was intimate and difficult. At any given time, a person possessed a vast emotional spectrum, with some elements stronger than others, and it was only when certain emotions surpassed a threshold that he had enough to work with and amplify. Due to this, he could only influence a few people at once if he did anything complex.

However, he had learned that he could read more than individuals. Instead, he could focus on all the presences in an area and read the composite of their emotions, understanding the “vibe” of the place. This “vibe” could then be influenced. All the sapient races had some innate desire to follow the flock, so if the majority of people in an area believed one thing, chances were the outliers would just follow them. If not, their own beliefs would, at the very least, be shaken. The common emotion would appear and thus be amplified, effectively making the person fall in line.

Back in his youth, Ell’Hakan had tried to influence a lot of people at once by reading their emotions in a detailed fashion. The sheer overload of information had left him bedridden with a horrible headache for over a week, as it had happened before the system. He had never tried it again. Now, however, with the system, he could influence several people at once in a detailed way…

But…

Reading the emotions of the creature called Minaga was different. Because at that very moment, he felt like the emotional spectrum before him infinitely expanded, the emotions of countless creatures drilling into his mind. Ell’Hakan wanted to scream as he held his head, but he couldn’t even move his hands. He was utterly overloaded as the entire world faded, millions of identical voices echoing at once…

“When you stare into the mind of Minaga… the mind of Minaga stares back at you.”

Then, a moment later, Ell’Hakan found himself standing there like nothing had happened. His head was clear, but his party members stared at him, letting him know that what he had just experienced was real. He knew he had been healed… but…

Clenching his fists, he stared at the creature, not daring to even seek a glimpse of emotions.

“Now, while that was a nice greeting and all, we should really get on with my labyrinth! As I am incredibly creative and awesome, I decided to shake things up, so I came up with a total of five difficulties! Yes, that’s right—five entire difficulties for you to choose from. Isn’t that—”

Ell’Hakan barely listened. He just stared at the monster, shivering as he recalled what he had felt moments prior. One thing was certain… This Minaga was in no way a creature to take lightly. Even more certain was that they could not disrespect him under any circumstances, and moving forward, they had to be incredibly careful with their words lest they offend him.

Chapter 17

The Thirty-Fourth Floor

“Irate this floor nine out of ten when it comes to combat, but a solid negative one out of ten when it comes to creativity,” Jake admonished Minaga while standing atop a tower identical to four other towers in prior rooms. “You just copy-pasted rooms over and over again. Downright shameful.”

“Oh, well, thank you for your expert review of my labyrinth!” With more snark, Minaga added, “Do tell me—for how many years have you been making dungeons, since you are such a master at it?”

“I don’t need to be an expert in feces to know when I see a piece of crap,” Jake said, grinning.

“See, while you think you like constant diversity in encounters, you actually don’t. This was meant to be a gauntlet of rooms where you would take breaks in between, strategize, and get better and better at dealing with the demons as time went on. So they have to be similar for your experiences in all the prior rooms to matter.”

“Didn’t I say I rate it nine out of ten for combat? Combat was good.” Jake smiled as he watched his party members finishing off the last demons in the distance.

The thirty-third floor proved to be far longer than any of the earlier ones. Granted, it was probably meant to take around the same time for the average party, but considering Jake could cheese every single labyrinth they had entered so far, this one became the big time sink.

A total of fifteen rooms had stood in their way, with the first five looking like outside areas, including camps and villages housing prisoners. As Minaga had said, these five rooms had all been pretty much identical, which meant that their strategy, which had worked perfectly the first two times around, could easily be applied three more times.

This naturally resulted in some damn good points through all the achievements they earned.

Current progress: Prisoners freed (100%)

Achievement earned: Free at least half (50%) of the prisoners. 100 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Free at three-quarters (75%) of the prisoners. 200 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Free all (100%) of the prisoners. 400 Nevermore Points earned.

900 Nevermore Points total, if you included the 200 from just completing the objective of saving 25%. This was already a massive windfall, but Jake could see how these achievements—especially the last one—could be difficult. An E-grade could easily die from some random shockwave or explosion during a fight, making 100% completion impossible. It was only because of Dina that they’d managed to do it perfectly, as she’d protected them thoroughly with her vine shells.

After the prisoner rooms, there were no more bonus objectives. Just ten more rooms of pure fighting, which thematically reflected moving deeper and deeper into demon territory. The environment began to change from room to room, with lava pits appearing everywhere and more demonic structures popping up. The last five rooms had all been large military cities with a big tower in the center, which was the one Jake was currently standing on, observing the last demon kills. Could he have helped his party members below with ranged support? Sure, but when he’d done that on the last floor, the Fallen King had complained, so he didn’t. Besides, splitting up like this rewarded more experience. He had helped right after killing the boss, as he could get kills without ruining someone else’s fight, but at this point, it was just cleanup work.

And on the topic of experience… Jake had managed to convince his party to leave the bosses in each room to him. This was not only due to his own vanity, but also because he was truly the best person in their party at killing these bosses. Jake had to admit that when it came to killing foes of equal level, the Fallen King had him beat, and the Sword Saint was a close third after him, but against foes 40 to 50 levels above them?

Jake was by far the strongest. He had so many skills that scaled off level disparity between him and his foe, with Big Game Hunter being the biggest one. This meant that Jake had finally gotten in some good fights, but more importantly… he had gotten levels.

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 212 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 216 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 211 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 213 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Five class levels didn’t seem like a lot, but it had only taken them a week to clear their way to the final room. Jake getting three race levels meant he was the one who had gotten the most over this week, including Sylphie. He knew he had a lot of experience to catch up on and plenty of Records, so he was sure as hell prepared to finally pick up some momentum while he had it. His primary reason for going to Nevermore was to gain levels, after all.

“Well, I guess you did like the fights and even did these rooms the most legitimate way, not abusing your Bloodline or anything like that,” Minaga commented. “However, I feel like giving me nine out of ten feels almost insulting. Eight out of ten, I would get, but nine just feels like you are rubbing it in that I didn’t get top marks, but I was still damn close.”

“I can downgrade it to an eight?”

“I’d rather you tell me what a ten out of ten is.”

“A fight where all five of us have to come together and fight in order to win. Maybe the rematch with the Demon Lord will be a ten out of ten?” Despite his teasing, he genuinely felt he was being nice to give it a nine to begin with. Though perhaps he only felt it had been so fun due to how starved of a good fight he had been. Even if he said the fights had been good, he had yet to truly be pushed to his limits.

“Let’s hope for that, then,” Minaga said just as Jake got a notification.

Achievement earned: Kill every single demon on the thirty-third floor. 150 Nevermore Points earned.

“A bit stingy on the points here?” Jake asked with a raised eyebrow.

“To be fair, killing everything isn’t actually that big of an achievement, considering they don’t really hide or anything. It just rewards you for not rushing to the end after killing the boss without cleaning up. Most people do stay behind to grind levels, and it isn’t like you can ‘fail’ this achievement like the ones related to prisoner survival.”

“Aight, guess I shouldn’t complain too much.” Jake smiled and looked towards the place where the entrance to the next hallway would usually be. Instead, he saw the gateway leading to the in-between room. After a quick mental confirmation from the others, Jake flew down, and they all regrouped in front of the gate before promptly walking through.

“How refreshing,” the Sword Saint instantly commented once they entered the cozy lounge. “The atmosphere was beginning to get to me at times.”

“Yeah... I didn’t like it either,” Dina concurred.

“Could have been more comfortable for sure,” Jake said. The fire-affinity floors had been a bit suffocating due to the high heat and constant smoke in the air, and while it hadn’t really impacted their fighting power, it had still been a bother.

A second or so later, the usual notifications popped up.

Thirty-third floor completed. 330 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-third floor in less than a week (7 days). 200 Nevermore Points earned.

“Fewer points than on any prior floors… though I guess we did do the bonus objective achievements related to the prisoners,” Jake said.

“And you did miss some other stuff, too, like finding out more information about the Demon Lord from the demons there and thus learning a few interesting tidbits of lore,” Minaga came in. “It wouldn’t have given that many points, but I am sure you would have enjoyed the details. Want some insight now? Totally free.”

Jake looked at the others and sensed that they would need some time to fully recover anyway, so he shrugged as he went over to the bar. “Go right ahead.”

“Great! So, the Demon Lord was originally spawned a long time ago in…”

The group split up at that point. The Sword Saint went to the open-air bath to cool off, Dina decided to stay with Jake to have some drinks while taking care of the garden she had hidden in her spatial storage, Sylphie decided to take a nap on the counter, and the Fallen King floated into one of the bedrooms to meditate.

They spent a few hours relaxing as Jake listened to Minaga’s all-out explanation of how the Demon Lord had been summoned through a mad sacrifice by some second-born prince who’d wanted to get power and thus worked with the Demonic Cult, but the Demon Lord couldn’t be controlled and had ended up breaking free and summoning an army of demons to accompany it. These demons had eventually been pushed out of the kingdom and now controlled their own land while waiting for the Demon Lord to return. The area of the labyrinth they were now entering was the demon’s domain.

How exactly all this made sense, considering they were within a labyrinth in a dungeon, Jake wasn’t entirely sure, but Minaga excused it by noting that they only saw set areas of each kingdom and such. Jake guessed it was akin to video games, where one couldn’t exactly explore all the areas of a kingdom, only the set instances.

After their time of relaxation, they moved on to the thirty-fourth floor, not at all sure what to expect. Thematically, they had now entered the inner walls of the Demon Lord’s compound, but Jake assumed they would not meet the boss before the thirty-fifth floor, so he wondered what would be there.

“Say, will this floor also be completely and utterly uncheeseable?” Jake asked.

“I don’t think uncheeseable is even a word.”

Jake grinned. “What a nice attempt to avoid answering my question.”

“Fine, sure, you probably can cheese a bunch of stuff and cheat a lot, but it won’t be as easy as you think it will! This floor is even more special than any prior, and I am not lying when I say I am interested in seeing how you will handle it. So, good luck!”

“Alright, alright, let’s see what you have cooked up this time,” Jake said as their group went through the gateway and entered the thirty-fourth floor. Once more, they were met by a system message with details of the floor.

Welcome to the thirty-fourth floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth (Part 4)

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: Find the three Secret Scrolls (0/3).

Current progress: Secret Scrolls found (0/3), end reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 20,783

As always, Minaga popped in for a nice round of difficulty-choosing. Naturally, they went ahead with the Archmage difficulty, at which point Minaga popped out of existence. Then they walked through the large gate and into the labyrinth proper.

However… Jake instantly noticed something was off when the gate opened. Rather than a long hallway, they faced a brief walk into a room where, surprisingly enough, a demon was waiting. Something he promptly informed his party of, along with what else he saw ahead.

“It looks like we are walking into some kind of small city room right off the bat, not unlike those we just cleared, but rather than an entire city, it is more like a district. Also, we will appear in a house with a demon that I think is friendly, based on how it seems to be waiting, so don’t blow it up before it can talk.”

“Within a city already?” the Sword Saint said. “Perhaps this layer will not be pure combat.”

“Based on what Minaga said, it’s probably not. Also, seeing as we have to find something called Secret Scrolls, their locations are likely hidden, and we need to find them somehow.”

“Rather than theorize needlessly, why not just find out once we enter the room?” the Fallen King said dismissively.

The King had spoken through their telepathic link, and Jake chose to respond in kind. “How come you seem to be in such a shitty mood ever since we entered the labyrinth part of Nevermore?”

“Because we are under the constant gaze of a Unique Lifeform, slaves to its whims and desires,” the Fallen King said, clearly annoyed.

“So, it is down to you, as a Unique Lifeform, just not liking other Unique Lifeforms?” Jake asked. “Man, and I thought you and that Ashen Phantom Devourer having hate-boners for each other was just a unique circumstance, but it is something natural?”

“An apex creature will naturally not desire others daring to approach its station. Unique Lifeforms instinctively compete and are the closest thing to relatives we can have. That we wish to dominate one another and prove our superiority is only to be expected.”

“Not gonna lie—pretty sure Minaga has you thoroughly handled when it comes to being superior,” Jake joked.

“Utter nonsense. This Unique Lifeform is clearly not only a level 275 creature but merely one iteration of something greater, which must mean it is far older than we know. Between us, the only true advantage it has is time. That does not make this Minaga superior to me, only temporarily ahead.”

“You sounded a bit like me there,” Jake joked. It kind of mirrored his emotions toward any god. Sure, they were far stronger than he was right now, but he would reach their level in due time. “Anyway, I got it now. You are being silent because you feel temporarily inferior to Minaga.”

After a bout of silence, the King said, “Let us just finish these ten floors and move on…”

Jake just grinned as they walked out of the fog and into the cellar of a house, where a hooded demon sat waiting for them. It was an older-looking male with aged gray horns and a beard, making Jake more sure than ever that Minaga liked to make every damn character that spoke an old, bearded man.

“You look like you have been expecting us,” Jake said as he looked at the demon.

The demon man nodded to them as he looked up. “Indeed I have. I had heard rumors you would arrive… Finally, we have a chance to fight back. After the return of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas, we demons that hoped for peace with the other enlightened races found ourselves ostracized and even sacrificed, while the worshippers of the Demonic Cult have risen in esteem due to the freeing of the Demon Lord. However, with you here now, not all is lost. There are some problems, though. The castle is sealed off, and in order to enter, we must find out how. No… you must find out how…”

“Where exactly are we?” the Sword Saint asked.

Taking out an orb, the old demon showed them a general layout of the city and even several adjacent rooms with hallways leading to them. As Jake looked at it, the demon spoke again.

“Welcome to the Demon Lord’s harem.”

His what now?

Chapter 18

Demon Lord's Harem

Jake’s first question when he heard about the Demon Lord having a harem related to the logistics. You see, the Demon Lord was quite large, while all the regular demons he saw in his sphere were human-sized, so…

Anyway, not important. What was important was the theme of the thirty-fourth floor, which the friendly demon soon explained.

“The evil Demon Lord Gubrothas had a harem back before he was sealed away, consisting of nine Mistresses and one Prime Consort that he valued above everything else. In the years waiting for his return, the Prime Consort took control and was the most powerful person outside of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas himself. She was the original leader of the Demonic Cult, and after the summoning, she embraced the demonic path and became a half-demon herself. The nine Mistresses and the Prime Consort have been in a power struggle for a long time, and some have even been disillusioned due to the prolonged absence of their lord. However, far more important are the young candidates and common Courtesans hoping to ascend to become Mistresses. Many of them have been here for many years and know secrets that can help us, such as how to open the seal to the castle of the evil Demon Lord Gubrathas, though I suspect that key is held only by the Prime Consort. I also heard that three Secret Scrolls have been given to three of his Mistresses. Locating those will also assist us moving forward.”

In essence, this room, if not entire floor of Nevermore, was pretty much a large red-light district. Jake’s first thought was just quickly finding their targets and going on a slaughter. However…

“Please try to avoid unnecessary death… Many of those who live here are those who never truly joined the army of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas. You must be selective and only kill those who are truly evil while sparing the innocent. We must not raise too much suspicion, either, as I fear the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas may choose to temporarily seal away the castle or perhaps even flee.”

It was a nice request that Jake would certainly have ignored… had it merely been a request.

Floor Penalty activated. Killing any non-designated target on this floor will result in a subtraction of Nevermore Points. This subtraction grows exponentially based on how many “innocents” are killed. Using Identify will inform you as to whether a being is innocent, undetermined, or free to kill.

“Wait, what the hell?” Jake asked after reading it. “Negative points for killing? What kind of dungeon is this?”

“The type that punishes people who go full murderhobo for no reason,” Minaga said.

“First of all, how do you even know the word murderhobo?” Jake asked with a hint of exasperation. “Secondly, how come just killing everything on any prior floor was totally fine?”

“The answer to your first question is that I am smart, and the answer to the second is that I am talented at making diverse encounters,” Minaga said, clearly proud of himself. “Does make life hard for you, huh? Can’t just kill everything and move on? Also, do you like how it contrasts with the prior floor, where it was all about killing?”

“Not a big fan, no,” Jake muttered. “But we could just head straight for the Prime Consort, kill her, and move on, right?”

Minaga didn’t answer. Instead, the Sword Saint shook his head. “That would result in no bonus points being gained, I assume. I am not saying we can’t send one person to quickly finish off the Prime Consort, but that may raise suspicions… I think taking it slow may be for the best.”

“Yeah, I guess,” Jake said. “But how will we even be able to sneak around? I can maybe see the two of us putting on some big robes, but the others…”

Jake looked at the plant lady, the green bird, and the large, floating Unique Lifeform. They didn’t exactly fit into a city of demons. At least there were still cultists walking around, many of them humans, but that would only help Jake and the Sword Saint.

“Ah, do not worry… I have prepared identities for all of you,” the demon in the room said, almost like Jake’s words had triggered a dialogue response. “Here, take these identification badges, and you will be believed to be part of the Demonic Cult.”

“How does that make any sense?” Jake said as the demon took out five badges, each of them flying towards a member of Jake’s party. It didn’t change their appearance or anything. All it did was add a slight change to the feeling of their aura. “And this actually works?”

“The Demonic Cult often has new members joining from the old kingdom, so your appearance should not raise any suspicion, and your identities are perfect as long as you are careful and don’t divulge who you truly are. Now, please, you must locate the three Secret Scrolls and find the key to unlocking the castle so you can finish your quest and slay the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas and restore order. Obtaining the three Secret Scrolls is also imperative, as it will no doubt help you in the final fight against the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas.”

Still incredibly skeptical, Jake pointed to Sylphie and the Fallen King. “You mean to tell me that a Demonic Cult consisting only of humanoids will not at all question the appearance of a green hawk and a Unique Lifeform?”

“The Demonic Cult often has new members joining from the old kingdom, so your appearance should not raise any suspicion, and your identities are perfect as long as you are careful and don’t divulge who—”

“Seriously?” Jake cut him off, hearing the exact same dialogue.

“The Demonic Cult often has new members joining—”

“Thank you for your guidance,” the Sword Saint cut in, bowing. “We will do our utmost.”

“I wish you luck,” the demon said, finally changing what he said. “Please bring the Secret Scrolls back here when you have them all, and I shall decipher them.”

Jake looked at the demon as it seemed to enter a catatonic state, just staring into the wall.

“You mean to tell me that these people are actually sapient creatures, Minaga?” Jake questioned.

“They just have very selective hearing and short-term memory loss. What can I say? Anyway, I will echo his words and wish you luck… I look forward to seeing your performances. Ah, but just one more tip for you. Well, you and the swordsman.”

“What is it?” Jake asked.

“While it is an entirely valid strategy—one I would even recommend for most parties—I will warn you about sleeping with too many of the Courtesans, and I would definitely warn you about trying to get any of them preg—”

“Minaga,” Jake interrupted as he raised a hand, “what the actual fuck?”

“What? Oh, you think I am joking? I had a guy decide to settle down here and abandon his party after falling in love with one of the Courtesans. True, he will be kicked out when the fifty years run out, but the dude was still delusional to the extreme, and last time I checked, he has two kids, and he probably fucked up his own Records pretty badly. Casually sleeping with them is totally fine, though, and a great way to get information.”

“Is this not too disadvantaged towards non-male individuals and monsters attempting the dungeon?” the Sword Saint asked, seemingly unbothered.

“There are plenty of incubi and men around, too, and no one said the Mistresses or even Prime Consort don’t have quite… interesting tastes.”

“Ree?” Sylphie asked, seemingly confused about the entire conversation they were having.

“Don’t worry about it,” Jake reassured her. “Minaga is just talking nonsense.”

“Up to you how you do it, but putting on some charm may prove very beneficial… Anyway, that is the last hint I will give. Have fun!”

With that, Minaga popped out. Well, he’d never been there to begin with, but… yeah. Jake and the others were left to wonder how to proceed on this floor, with Jake being quite unsure for the first time since entering Nevermore. Through his Pulse of Perception, he could locate several interesting places, but if killing was not an option…

“Let us begin by carefully scouting the city and confirming that we can indeed blend into the crowd before we decide to make any more moves,” the Sword Saint said.

“Yeah,” Jake agreed, primarily because he had no other ideas. As a group, they went through a secret exit leading to the cellar and entered the house of the old demon before promptly leaving, emerging on a street of the district designated the “Demon Lord’s harem.”

In all honesty, it was a bit of a silly name, considering there were plenty of people there that had nothing to do with this harem. The name was probably only what it was because the Prime Consort and the Mistresses ruled the area. And, of course, because Minaga had named it.

Once outside, Jake was more than ready to be jumped by some of the many guards walking about. However, to his surprise, the first guard they met outside just walked up to them and nodded as Jake used Identify.

[Celibate Demon Guard – lvl 250 - Innocent]

“Hello, there,” the guard said. “I haven’t seen any of you around before. Are you new members of the Demonic Cult?”

Jake was momentarily not sure what to say as he took another look at their party. There was no fucking way anyone would think they were actually new members. He also confirmed that Identify had designated the guy as innocent, so killing was indeed not an option.

“Yes, we are,” the Sword Saint answered for their group with a smile. “We arrived not too long ago, after hearing about the return of the honored Demon Lord.”

The guard nodded. “Ah, I see. We have had quite a few new visitors recently. Carry on, then, and enjoy your stay! Sadly, the castle is closed off right now, much to the disappointment of the Mistresses and the Prime Consort. It makes me fear that the loneliness and lack of attention from the Demon Lord may leave them vulnerable to being approached by those with untoward intentions. Do inform the guard if you come across any such individuals.”

“Who would dare do such a thing?” the Sword Saint said, looking horrified. “And how would such a thing even happen? I am certain the Mistresses and Prime Consort are all under heavy protection within their residences, and it isn’t as easy as just walking in there to get an audience.”

“Indeed, it isn’t that easy,” the guard said, nodding. “However, these insidious individuals instead approach the young Courtesans belonging to the factions of a specific Mistress to get an audience, and then, through the Mistresses associated with her, they approach the Prime Consort. Recently, there have even been rumors of a lot of these individuals approaching the Courtesans in the inns, but as it isn’t against the rules for the Courtesans to spend time with others before they become official Mistresses, we as guards can’t do anything about it.”

“We will be certain to keep an eye out for such individuals,” the Sword Saint said, nodding with determination.

“It is good to see such upstanding individuals,” the guard said with a smile. “Here, take this signet and show it to a guard if you wish to report someone. It will also ensure other guards don’t suspect you are one of these horrible people who wish to take advantage of the naivety of a young Courtesan or even a Mistress.”

“Thank you for doing such a splendid job to keep them all safe,” the old man said with a deep bow.

The guard nodded before walking away.

Jake just stood there, staring at the Sword Saint and the small signet in his hand, which gave off an interesting aura.

“I must admit, this is a lot easier than I had expected,” the Sword Saint muttered.

Dina nodded. “Yeah.”

Jake didn’t wanna comment on the stupidity he had just observed, though one part of him wished it was that easy to get information out of people in real life.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked.

“As long as you are certain you can stay hidden.” Jake shrugged. “And remember not to kill anyone that Identify marks as Innocent. Actually, probably just avoid killing anyone, period.”

“Ree,” Sylphie agreed as she turned into wind and disappeared.

“Are you certain that sending off the Sylphian will end well?” the Fallen King asked. “She is not the most subtle.”

“That is true,” Jake said, “but she has an overpowered ability to make people like her, so I have a feeling she will be just fine. Whether she will accomplish anything… Now, that is a total toss-up.”

“Sylphie is pretty smart when it matters,” Dina said with a nod, approving of the bird.

“Very well,” the Fallen King said. “I am uncertain what my role will be on this floor, but if it is desired, I can accomplish whatever task is assigned to me.”

“I believe it would be pertinent to first follow the tip given by the guard and investigate the inns to find Courtesans with whom we can form positive relations,” the Sword Saint began, “and through them, meet a Mistress. As long as we can speak to one Mistress, it should allow us far more insight into the actual political landscape of this floor and let us make better decisions from there. I have also checked the fabricated identities we have been given, and nothing links our party together, so splitting up is also a good option. If there are different competing factions—there always are in a harem—then having a person in each camp would be preferable. Internal information is often biased, and we will have to know both sides to make the best decisions.”

Jake slowly nodded, not hearing anything wrong with that. The others also seemed in agreement, probably because none of them knew what to do.

“Would anyone complain if I took Dina with me?” the old man continued. “If we approach the Courtesans as a group of two, it will make them less suspicious we are trying anything. We should attempt to infiltrate and become affiliated with these factions using various means, with perhaps even Sylphie getting lucky. Fallen King, I would advise you to try and approach some guards and join them. Since your status as a Unique Lifeform makes you incapable of reproduction, you will likely be considered a ‘safe’ guard, based on the given description of celibate.”

The Fallen King nodded along as the Sword Saint looked at Jake. “What are your plans?”

“I will try to go for a tavern too, I guess, with my goal being to reach the Prime Consort as soon as possible, by any means necessary. Chances are we will have to kill her one way or another… and as always, I will take on the job of handling the floor boss.”

“We must still bide our time,” the Sword Saint said. “As that old demon warned us, raising a ruckus will result in making our task a lot harder, and it is likely it will make finding these Secret Scrolls impossible.”

“Oh, I won’t go to fight her directly.” Jake smiled. “But that doesn’t mean I can’t handle her through other means.”

“While Minaga did mention it as an option, seducing the Prime Consort may be a bit difficult for you, but I implore you to give it a shot,” the Sword Saint said skeptically yet encouragingly.

Jake stared at him, trying really hard to see if the old man was joking. He wasn’t.

“I am talking about alchemy.”

“Oh,” the Sword Saint muttered. “I guess that works too.”

Chapter 19

Mistresses

It may be difficult to believe, but Jake had barely done any proper dating or even gone to any bars in past years. On second thought, it was probably entirely believable, considering he’d just been coasting through life before the system with little care about anything, just taking it one day at a time.

Even after the system, he hadn’t really done that much with other people that would be considered “normal.” Due to this, Jake felt far from confident as he entered a bar and looked around the place. It was old and medieval-looking, and was filled with people in black hoods, demons, and women and men who wore less than they probably should. Jake Identified a shirtless man currently chatting up a cultist and saw the general level.

[Courtesan – lvl 204 - Innocent]

“Gotta admit, I thought Courtesan was reserved for women,” Jake muttered to himself while still at the door.

“Gender-neutral, actually,” Minaga spoke.

“Really? Huh, I guess you learn something new every day.”

“Not gonna lie… I am actually unsure if it is gender-neutral, but if it isn’t, then why did your translation skill phrase it that way? Definitely couldn’t be my mistake, so let’s just go with it being neutral, alright?”

Jake nodded and smirked, not wanting to get into the most useless argument imaginable.

Nobody in the inn reacted despite the echoing voice of Minaga and Jake standing right there in the doorway. Without engaging in any major actions or dialogue, it was as if he was invisible. When he looked at the person the male Courtesan was talking to, he found a hooded man at a far higher level.

[High-ranking Demonic Cultist – lvl 256 - Undetermined]

It was Jake’s first time running into the Undetermined tag. He was likely supposed to learn information about the person to determine whether or not they were a valid kill target, but he didn’t really need to. Instead, he chose to just go to the bar and order something to drink. Before entering, Jake had taken a break in an alley and dolled himself up a little.

“Dolled up,” here, meant using Shroud of the Primordial to change what he Identified as.

Without any idea if it would work or not, Jake had made himself appear as a level 240 Prodigious Demonic Cultist. He had considered adding another tag, such as one marking him as high-ranking, but had settled on Prodigious instead, as the system already used that word quite a lot for very talented people. If these people—or NPCs—could use Identify, he hoped they would find him worth approaching simply due to his tag, while at the same time not expecting him to actually know stuff since he was a prodigy, not some official. It was a gamble, for sure.

Lo and behold, the moment the bartender turned to him, he called Jake “young master,” and within a minute, three Courtesans had taken the seats around him. Jake channeled his inner arrogant and disinterested young master as the two women and one man spoke to him, responding with one-word answers.

The attention was a tad annoying, but Jake wanted to make himself known to catch a bigger fish. Thus, he sat at the bar for around half an hour while having people buy drinks for him—something he had never tried before. So that was kind of fun, at least. Finally, after this half an hour, a new courtesan came up to him and handed him a small piece of paper while giving a wink.

Jake quickly checked the note and saw it had a name and address on it. The terms name and address, however, were used loosely here.

The Ninth Mistress would like to meet you, Prodigious Demonic Cultist, at her home, Residency Nine.

Yeah… Minaga had truly outdone himself there. Oh, to make it all better, Residency Nine was located just through the Ninth Gate. The Mistresses all had their own separate rooms with hallways leading into them. Jake had telepathically discussed why this might be with the others, and they’d settled on it being a concession to allow some form of combat. As a fog wall still separated all the rooms, information would not instantly spread, and random, wayward attacks would never hit this “main” city in the middle.

Without delaying, Jake left the bar, with no one even making an attempt to try and follow him. In fact, he saw through his sphere that the moment he left the inn, they all just went back to making the same motions as before, with the bartender having cleaned the same unused glass a few thousand times by now.

Finding the gate in question was incredibly easy, as there were street signs everywhere informing him of the way to the different gates. Did it make sense that there would be street signs specifically pointing toward the homes of Mistresses? No, no, it did not.

Reaching the gate, Jake didn’t even have to say or do anything before the guard bowed. “We were informed you would come. Please enter.”

“Thank you.” Jake nodded as the gate opened and let him through, causing him to make a mental note that he then promptly informed his party of. “If someone else enters a gate to another room, you can sneak through with them, and with the mist, you will be hidden. The random residents here do enter the gates at times.”

“Ree,” Sylphie informed him.

“Alright, never mind, then,” Jake said. The hawk had already snuck inside a residence of a Mistress, it seemed, and was currently making friends with the Second Mistress—who had the great name “Two.”

Jake had finally met his match when it came to sucking at naming stuff.

The room he entered after a very short hallway was just one large residence, which consisted of a large main building in the middle and four smaller houses off to the side. One of them was a guardhouse, one had other employees, and the last two looked to be guest houses that had Courtesans living there. From a quick Pulse, it appeared this layout was standard for all these rooms.

Shortly after he had entered the room, the same Courtesan that had handed him the note met him. How she had gotten there so fast, considering Jake had headed straight there and not noticed her on the way, was a mystery. One he didn’t bother to question as she escorted him to the main residency where he would meet the Mistress.

Once inside, he went straight for her chambers while the Courtesan waited outside. Upon reaching the door, it opened by itself, and through it, he could see her obscured form.

[Ninth Mistress – lvl 253]

Jake instantly took notice of the lack of “Undetermined” or “Innocent” after her name, which meant she was a person they were free to kill. Whether killing her would lead to other problems, however… Now, that was a whole other issue.

“My name is Nine—a pleasure to meet you, Prodigy,” the woman said. A large veil hanging from the ceiling hid her form, only allowing Jake to see an outline while still somehow permitting Identify. Of course, with his sphere, he could see her clearly and noted she was a beastkin of some kind. This did surprise Jake a little, as he had expected all of these Mistresses to be demons, given the race of the Demon Lord. Then again, not all of the Courtesans were demons either.

As Jake considered these things, he didn’t even notice that several seconds had passed without him answering. He quickly collected himself and spoke, “I am honored to be invited by the esteemed Ninth Mistress.”

“Please, call me Nine,” she answered, making Jake want to reach through space and punch Minaga.

“As you wish, Nine.” Jake nodded, keeping his cool. “May I know why the Mistress wanted to meet with me?”

Rather than fish for information, he’d let her divulge it of her own volition.

“You are new to this city, correct? From what I was told, you do not belong to any faction yet, and I hoped to recruit you to mine.”

“While I am flattered, I will need to know more about what your faction is. I am currently unaware of the political landscape, as I just arrived in the city today.”

“Very well. I belong to the faction of the Prime Consort. We are competing with the faction formed by One, the First Mistress, who wants to become the Prime Consort. Our faction has three Mistresses within it, while the First Mistress has four others with her, meaning they have two more Mistresses than us, although we, of course, have the Prime Consort. The one remaining Mistress remains neutral, and we hope to turn her to our side in the upcoming power struggle.”

“I see,” Jake said, glad she’d easily offered up so much information. “In that case, I would be honored to join you. However, how would my joining your faction help?”

“It is possible a conflict may happen when we next convene, and we will need as many powerful individuals on our side as possible to intimidate the other side. If you assist us in defending the Prime Consort’s position, I am certain she will even allow you an audience with the Demon Lord himself so you can swear your fealty. Only the Prime Consort can open the Demon Lord’s castle while it is sealed, after all.”

With that one answer, she’d pretty much outlined the way to finish this floor. The goal was to find the exit—something Jake had technically already done, as he’d found it just past a sealed gate marked the “Demon Lord’s Castle”—but they naturally had to open this to gain entrance and finish the floor.

“Are there any ways I can assist you and earn the trust of the Prime Consort?” Jake asked. He saw no reason to beat around the bush, so he just asked directly.

“If you can recruit more Courtesans to our cause, it would be incredibly valuable and strengthen the faction. While the guards currently remain neutral, if you could make them support us, it would also be of massive assistance. Finally, if you can turn any of the Mistresses to our side, it would be most helpful. If not, then see if it is possible to perhaps eliminate some of them, either through killing them or making them lose their positions to Courtesans allied with us.”

Jake nodded at her matter-of-fact answer, deciding to take a chance. “I have also heard rumors of the Mistresses guarding Secret Scrolls, but I did not quite understand what they are.”

“They are called Secret Scrolls for a reason,” the Mistress said dismissively.

Aight, worth a shot.

“I shall not ask more about them, then,” Jake said. “It is just that I heard some unsavory individuals were looking for them, so I wanted to warn you to make sure they are kept safe.”

“Do not worry. They are all safely guarded already.”

Hey, he had to at least check if that one worked, right?

“Once more, I thank you for this audience. Do not hesitate to ask about anything further I can help with, but if not, I will set out.” Jake then bowed.

“Do well, and you will be rewarded,” the Mistress said from behind the veil, clearly happy with Jake and what he had done and said.

Upon walking out of her residency, Jake was given access to two other Mistresses that were also allied with the Prime Consort. From there, Jake headed to one of the many abandoned houses, where he went inside and took a seat leaning against a wall. For some bloody reason, he felt kind of tense after that meeting, despite having felt pretty relaxed while doing it.

After a quick break, Jake shared what he had learned with the others. The Sword Saint confirmed that the Third Mistress had told him the same five minutes earlier. A Mistress who, it turned out, was allied with the First Mistress.

Sylphie had been with the one neutral Mistress, the Second Mistress. From how Sylphie spoke, this Mistress did not like any of the others and, surprisingly enough, seemed outright hostile towards the Demon Lord. The Fallen King had also managed to join the guards and some-fucking-how instantly gotten promoted to a Team Leader with several guards working under him. Through that, he had learned that one of the Secret Scrolls was guarded by the current Guard Captain of this entire city area.

All in all, Jake was the one with the least progress, he felt. Except, his goal had never really been gathering information, but reaching the Prime Consort as fast as possible. Now, however, he felt like there was another way forward.

“Hey, I got an idea,” Jake spoke through their link. “While you all work on finding the Secret Scrolls, maybe I will team up with Sylphie, and we will try to organize a big get-together the Second Mistress hosts, using the excuse that she wants to join a faction. Then, once we have all the Mistresses in one room, I can prepare a little special something through the power of alchemy.”

“I doubt getting them together is that easy,” the Sword Saint answered. “But I do think it would be an idea to work with the Second Mistress. As a sole individual, her position is weaker than everyone else’s, so I could see her ‘winning’ leading to the best rewards. Also, she seems more hostile to the others, so maybe she will have some ideas on how you can apply your power of alchemy.”

“I guess that is an option,” Jake agreed.

“Can I maybe come along too?” Dina asked.

“That would probably be for the best,” the old man said. “Try and find out exactly what her stance is and what she wants to accomplish. Based on the pattern, I would expect her to be the odd one out and actually an enemy of the Demon Lord, and she will offer us an alternative method to conquer this floor outside of partnering with either faction. Perhaps she will even give us access to the option where we simply kill them all.”

“Sounds reasonable,” Jake said. “Dina, let’s meet close to the gate, but not actually group up. I think entering separately is best to avoid suspicion, as people already know you are associated with the Sword Saint.”

“Alright,” Dina said. “I already got an invite from a Courtesan, so I should be able to enter. How about you?”

“I will figure something out.”

“In the meantime, I will further integrate myself with the faction belonging to the First Mistress,” the Sword Saint said. “I am on my way to meet the Fifth Mistress now, and it may take me a few hours.”

“Are you seriously going to… you know?”

“Depending on how it goes, yes, we may enjoy a cup of tea together.”

“Ah, alright… For a second there, I thought you were actually going to—”

“That was innuendo.”

Chapter 20

Second Mistress

Jake watched from afar as Dina effortlessly passed through the Second Gate—again, brilliant name—and entered the residence of the Second Mistress. He purposefully waited a few minutes before he also made his way there.

Now, whether waiting actually helped, Jake didn’t know. The “people” in Minaga’s Labyrinth were not the smartest, but it was possible some of them could display some level of intelligence when it truly mattered. After all, the Demon Lord seemed like it wasn’t a complete moron.

Upon walking up to the gate, its two guards raised their hands to stop him. “Halt,” one said. “May I know why you wish to enter the residence of the Second Mistress?”

“I have something of utmost importance I must discuss with her,” Jake tried, seeing if that would help.

“Without an invitation, I sadly cannot allow you access.” The guard shook his head.

Should have seen that coming, Jake thought. Oh, well. I guess I will have to head to a bar and get lucky, or maybe sneak in when another visitor comes b—

“Excuse me,” the other guard said as he looked at Jake, “do you know a Courtesan by the name of Sylphie?”

Jake’s mouth opened wide for a moment. “Yes?”

“Ah, in that case, you are naturally welcome. We were informed by the Second Mistress that someone matching your description would come by.” The second guard then opened the gate.

“Thanks,” Jake said, still not sure what was going on. Sylphie? A Courtesan? How in the hell did that even…

If something happened to her… we are going full-on murderhobo, Jake told himself, trying to restrain his bloodlust. Luckily, it didn’t look like he had to be worried. The second he went through the gate, a bird flew out of the primary residence in the room and landed on his head to greet him.

“Ree!” she said with excitement.

“Oh, you made a friend?” Jake asked, a bit surprised.

“Ree,” Sylphie explained, making Jake nod.

Inside the largest building in the room, Dina sat opposite another woman, and they looked to be discussing something. Sylphie had told him about how nice the Second Mistress was, but Jake naturally questioned that assessment if he went by the standards of any other natives of the labyrinth. Nevertheless, he knew he would have to go meet her, so he walked towards the house with Sylphie proudly standing on his head.

He was fully prepared for another conversation that consisted of him trying to find the right dialogue lines to get a proper response, which was why he was a bit surprised when he entered the room where Dina and this Second Mistress were talking. She was not behind a veil like the other Mistress, but sitting at a table with Dina. She casually looked his way when he entered.

The Second Mistress smiled. “You must be Jake; Sylphie told me a lot about you.”

“Greetings, Second Mistress,” Jake said, nodding at her. She felt more animated than the other Mistress just from her change in tone as she spoke, and more than that, her level was a lot higher.

[Second Mistress – lvl 268]

As far as Jake could tell, she was also a human, but there was one other big difference. She gave off an actual aura of power—something the other Mistress had not—whereas the Sword Saint had also hinted at the other Mistresses all feeling weak. Not the Second Mistress.

“Please, no need for such formalities,” she said, waving him off. “I heard you were the uncle of Sylphie here? Truly a wonderful niece you have.”

“Ree!” Sylphie protested atop his head.

“Oh, you are not his niece?” she asked, looking a bit confused. “I thought he was your uncle?”

“Ree!”

“So, not your uncle… but he is still Uncle?”

“Ree.” Sylphie nodded, satisfied.

“I… am not entirely sure I get it, but on the other hand, I don’t feel like I should.” The Second Mistress chuckled as she looked at Jake again. “Considering Sylphie’s power, am I right to assume you are strong too? If Dina is anything to go by… things around here may get very interesting.”

Okay… definitely not the usual NPC energy, Jake thought.

“I am not too shabby when it comes to combat, no,” Jake answered. “None of us are.”

The Second Mistress nodded before looking deep in thought. “When the Demon Lord returned, he was injured, which is part of the reason why they chose to seal off the castle. Are you people perhaps the cause of those injuries?”

Now Jake was really sure she was not a regular person of this labyrinth.

“What makes you think that?” Jake asked. “We just arrived here in the city recently, and if we had fought the Demon Lord and were truly antagonistic, would it not have been discovered already?”

The Second Mistress sighed. “I would not expect anyone here to ever notice anything. I am uncertain why it is like this, but the majority of those who live here just go through the motions, seemingly with little thought behind it.”

Jake raised an eyebrow. She seemed aware something was wrong with all the other people, but clearly not that she was within a dungeon. Which made him curious. “Why do you think this is?”

“Who knows. Perhaps it is the influence of the Demonic Cult, perhaps the odd environment, or it could just be they have all given up on life. Ultimately, their catatonic states only help me achieve my goal.”

“And what is your goal?” Jake asked.

The Second Mistress did a double-take with Sylphie, who happily screeched, before saying, “To kill the Demon Lord and put an end to the Demonic Cult once and for all.”

Jake nodded, as that was the expected answer. “And to do that, you became a member of the Demonic Cult yourself to destroy them from within?”

Smiling, the Second Mistress returned his nod. “You know, I am so used to talking with people who never truly question anything… Today has indeed been refreshing. But yes, that is exactly what I did. My initial goal was only to kill the Prime Consort, who was the original summoner of the Demon Lord, but since the demon was freed, he will now have to die, too. Along with all the Mistresses, if possible. In fact, I would love to burn this entire place to the ground, but I guess that would be going overboard.”

“Say, why do you want them dead that badly?” Jake questioned. She had way more emotion than anyone else he had met, besides maybe the Demon Lord and Minaga, and he clearly felt bloodlust bubble up as she spoke.

“I am not a big fan of sharing my personal history… but let’s just say that the Demonic Cult took all I had, and now I have dedicated all I am to taking everything from them in return,” she said with determination.

Jake nodded, having a pretty good understanding of the situation on floor thirty-four by now.

So, to summarize all Jake had learned so far…

Two factions existed in the Demon Lord’s harem. One was ruled by the Prime Consort, who was afraid of being ousted and never really left her residency, while the other was ruled by the First Mistress, the prime candidate to become the new Prime Consort.

Then there was the Second Mistress, who had actually only joined the Demonic Cult to put an end to it because of her tragic backstory. The common determined heroine. Her wish was to kill not only every other Mistress, but also the Prime Consort and Demon Lord. This Second Mistress was definitely the prime candidate for parties like theirs that specialized in combat.

However, these factions and the Second Mistress didn’t really have much power besides what they themselves wielded as individuals. They had some allied demonic cultists, but none were truly powerful. No, the most powerful faction was, by far, the Guards, ruled by a Guard Captain. He was the one who had kept order while the Demon Lord was absent. These guards were, as of that moment, not associated with any faction.

So, two factions, one standalone Mistress, and a group of unaffiliated guards.

“If I may… how exactly did you plan on doing this?” Jake asked the Second Mistress. “Don’t get me wrong—your level is high, and you are stronger than the other Mistresses, based on what I have seen, but are you enough on your own?”

“I am not. While I have confidence against any of the Mistresses, I am uncertain I could defeat the Prime Consort, much less the Guard Captain or the Demon Lord.” She shook her head. “The original plan was to get help from the Light’s Dawn, but the Demonic Cult managed to strike at them before they could properly gather their strength. Only the Knight of Light’s Dawn survived, but I heard he was slain by the Demon Lord recently… Now that you are here, however, I would love to offer an alliance, as I believe our interests align.”

“Hm,” Jake said, nodding as he looked deep in thought. Through the telepathic link, he quickly communicated what he had just talked about with the Second Mistress to hear the group’s opinions.

“I say we go with her, as it allows us to gain the most experience and end this floor sooner rather than later,” the Fallen King commented. “Not fighting the Guard Captain would be a waste…”

The Sword Saint took a bit longer to answer. “Ask her if killing the Mistresses is necessary to her route for completing this floor.”

“How important is it to kill all the other Mistresses?” Jake asked her.

“Hm… not extremely so, but the main problem is that any of them could potentially try to restart the Demonic Cult. As Mistresses, we are all trained in the art of summoning demons, including Demon Lords. If we can ensure they will not do so, they don’t necessarily have to die, as I have no grudges against them as individuals.”

“As long as we can ensure they won’t go on a demon-summoning spree, it should be fine,” Jake informed the Sword Saint.

“In that case, we should ally with her,” the old man said. “But give me time with the other Mistresses before making any big moves. A few days should be enough.”

“What exactly are you up to?” Jake asked, really confused about what he was doing.

“Negotiations, and let us just leave it at that,” the Sword Saint said. “You four should instead try to focus on obtaining the three Secret Scrolls. One of them is held by the Prime Consort, and a second one is held by the Guard Captain, so they should only be slightly tricky to get. As for the final scroll… none of the Mistresses I have spoken to knew anything.”

“Alright,” Jake answered. He kind of wanted to ask what the Sword Saint had been doing before he contacted him… but did he really wanna know? Probably not.

“Do you have any more questions?” the Second Mistress asked.

“Would you happen to know anything about something called Secret Scrolls?” Jake asked.

The Second Mistress seemed momentarily taken aback, then sighed. “I guess it is only expected you know of them. Yes, I know about them, and we will need them if we wish to battle the Demon Lord. There are three, and the problem is that while I know the Guard Captain and Prime Consort each have one, I have no idea about the third.”

“Why would we need it to battle the Demon Lord?” Jake asked. This was the first he had heard of that.

“While I am not certain exactly what these Secret Scrolls say, I do know they are related to the three artifacts of the Demon Lord within his castle. When the Demon Lord was sealed away, he was without three of his most powerful treasures, as these three are so powerful the Demon Lord can only use them under certain circumstances and while within his castle. I suspect these Secret Scrolls hold the method to ensuring the Demon Lord cannot use these treasures… because if not, then I have a difficult time seeing us ever defeating him.” The Second Mistress shook her head.

Her answer made Jake reconsider if they even needed or wanted to gather the Secret Scrolls. Assuming she was telling the truth, would they even want to use these scrolls to weaken the Demon Lord? Probably not… Oh, well. They could gather them either way for the bonus points. Not like they had to use them.

Jake talked a bit more with the Second Mistress and consulted his party before they decided to let the Sword Saint and Fallen King do their thing. Meanwhile, Jake began working on something he had a good feeling would come in handy: a special little poison.

Sure, Jake did have a lot of special poisons, but he wanted to make a variant of his Sleeping Night. Sleeping Night was currently still designed to be injected and not ingested, so he would have to make some minor changes to retain its full potency. Luckily, he had all the ingredients, and the Second Mistress graciously allowed them to stay in a guest house within her labyrinth room, letting Jake work in peace.

This was how the next four days went by. Sylphie and Dina did go out occasionally, but Jake stayed back and worked on his poison while he was sure the others were hard at work. They had update meetings here and there on how things were doing, with the Fallen King having now met and spoken to the Guard Captain quite a few times. Apparently, he was some-fucking-how close to getting promoted to vice-captain.

As Jake was sitting and working on his poison on the fourth day, he was contacted by the Sword Saint, who delivered an update to the group.

“I have made contact with all Mistresses so far besides the Second Mistress, and I believe I should be able to… let’s just say… neutralize them all. The only issue is the Prime Consort. My method of neutralization required me to get rather unfriendly with her, and she is aware of my existence by now. There is no way I will ever be allowed near her chambers.”

“The Guard Captain is also aware of you, and we are to keep an eye on you at all times,” the Fallen King added.

“Right,” the Sword Saint said. “So, this means I cannot approach her directly, which may be a problem, seeing as I have learned that even if the Prime Consort does not have the third Secret Scroll… she knows where it is.”

“We will need to get to the Prime Consort, then,” Jake said.

“Not we, Jake. You will have to get to the Prime Consort. Didn’t you say that was your original plan? To get to her fast?”

“Well, sure, but I am still working on the poison,” Jake answered.

“I am not saying you should kill her. I am saying you should learn the location of the third Secret Scroll from her while potentially obtaining the scroll she has on hand.”

“Alright, alright,” Jake relented, “but how do you see me gaining an audience with her? Based on the Mistress I spoke to, I will have to do some things to assist her first. Can we maybe use one of the Mistresses you talked to and say I have convinced her to join the Prime Consort? Maybe the Second Mistress is up for it…”

“Jake, you are overthinking this,” the old man said in a semi-admonishing tone. “You have something she already wants, don’t you? The Prime Consort cares about power and influence through her faction, and you can offer her something that will give her both.”¨

“And… what is that?” Jake asked, getting a feeling he really wouldn’t like this.

“You know already. Be honest with yourself, Jake. Do you really think she will say no to the chance of passing down such a powerful Bloodline?”

Yep, Jake didn’t like this.

Chapter 21

The Greatest Poison of All: Alcohol

The Sword Saint’s absolutely brilliant plan to make Jake try and seduce the Prime Consort through the power of dangling his Bloodline in front of her had just one minor problem: How was he supposed to prove he had one?

Only people with Bloodlines could tell if others had one, and Jake had not encountered anyone with a Bloodline there in the labyrinth, so he really wondered how in the hell the old man expected him to sell the lie.

This was totally not Jake trying to find a way around the plan by arguing that it was unfeasible to begin with, and that they’d need another way to get to the Prime Consort. Totally not. It was just that the plan was actually really bad and totally impossible to pull off, and—

And…

Why am I here? Jake questioned himself as he leaned against a wall in the small, fogged-up hallway leading to the Prime Consort’s residence. So, yeah, the old asshole had already planned for this. Sure, the Sword Saint couldn’t exactly go around spreading rumors himself, but they had someone in their party whose job was knowing about the people entering the city.

The Fallen King had simply informed the Guard Captain that he had discovered Jake had a Bloodline. When asked by the Guard Captain how he had discovered this, the Fallen King had just said he had a special ability to detect them, which was tied to his existence as a Unique Lifeform. The Guard Captain had the ability to tell truths from lies, so when he’d seen that the Fallen King spoke the truth in both instances, he’d instantly informed the ruler of the city: the Prime Consort.

Technical truths were still truths. The Fallen King had indeed “discovered” Jake had a Bloodline a long time ago, and he also had a special ability tied to him being a Unique Lifeform that helped him do this… That is, his ability to die and become a mask that Jake then Soulbound.

So, yeah, the Fallen King had been Jake’s downfall. He had even spread details about Jake’s Bloodline. The original plan was to merely mention that it amplified his presence and made him immune to other presences… but the Unique Lifeform had also decided to add Jake’s ability to sense other presences far better, thus more easily reading their intent and predicting any and all attacks. It wasn’t even a lie, either, as his ability to better detect presences was just one part of his overall increased ability to sense… well, everything.

This meant Jake was now stuck between a rock and a hard place. For some bloody reason, the Sword Saint seemed convinced Jake wouldn’t need any assistance when it came to the Prime Consort, showing complete and utter confidence in his seduction skills.

Jake had no seduction skills.

He had never even asked someone out. Alas, this was a challenge he had to overcome… His party relied on him to get the job done, and as much as he hated it, Jake was the only one who could do it. Sure, the Fallen King could have gotten an audience, given enough time, but they still hoped to get the floor done within a week, so that wasn’t an option. Sylphie was known to be aligned with the Second Mistress, and Dina was known to be aligned with the Sword Saint, so… yep, that left Jake.

Just bite the bullet, he told himself as he walked through the fog gate and entered the labyrinth room that belonged to the Prime Consort. This room was far larger than any of those prior and had a dozen or so buildings, with the central building being a large, circular structure. Through a pulse, Jake saw that the structure had a vast underground complex in the shape of a pentagram. Definitely a hidden magic circle.

Also, even if the guard faction was not allied with any of the Mistresses or even the Prime Consort, they still protected them, and there were far more guards present here than in any of the other rooms. There were also a lot of high-ranking cultists around, making Jake surer than ever that this room was designed to potentially host a big fight.

Shortly after entering the room, two male Courtesans walked toward him, both at a higher level than the ones on the outside. He also felt several people observing him from the shadows. Demonic cultists, no doubt.

“Welcome to the Prime Residence, my lord,” one of the Courtesans said as he bowed. “Her Excellency is awaiting you inside. I would heavily advise not making her wait more than necessary.”

“Thank you; I shall go immediately,” Jake answered with a bow, the two Courtesans seemingly satisfied with his answer. He then walked up the many steps leading to the house of the Prime Consort. Through his sphere, he already saw her within.

While the other Mistresses were distinctively non-demonic, the Prime Consort clearly had demonic aspects to her appearance, such as small horns on her forehead. From a cursory scan, she looked to be half-succubus, though she lacked some distinctive features, such as the tail. Rather than sitting on a large bed like the Ninth Mistress or casually at a normal table like the Second, the Prime Consort was sitting at a small table close to the ground on some pillows within a large room, likely waiting for his arrival.

Taking a final deep breath to calm himself, Jake entered the building. The moment the door behind him closed, he felt the magical seals set in, and he knew it was only the two of them in the entire structure.

Continuing inside, he finally entered the room where the Prime Consort was waiting. He looked at her as she scanned him up and down. Feeling the use of Identify on him, he responded in kind.

[Prime Consort – lvl 269]

Nothing about her being innocent, Jake noted instantly. He wasn’t there to kill her, but it was still good to know.

“Nine did tell me about you shortly after you met… Described you as giving off a powerful feeling, and as a worthy candidate,” the Prime Consort said as she summoned two wine glasses from her spatial storage as well as a bottle. “Come, join me, and let me learn if she was correct or not.”

Jake nodded, walked over, and took a seat without saying anything as the bottle levitated up and poured them both a glass.

“A man of few words?” she asked with a raised eyebrow.

“I apologize; I meant no offense,” Jake said, trying to be polite. “I am just not usually in a position like this.”

“Oh? A C-grade human feeling uncomfortable around the opposite sex? Now, that is something I have not encountered before… or is it perhaps due to the company?”

“I can’t deny that.” Jake smiled slightly.

“The demonification can be off-putting to som—”

“Not that…” Jake interrupted, scratching the back of his head. “It is just rare for me to spend time with someone like you… like this… In fact, I don’t actually think I ever have before.”

Jake felt slightly cringe saying that, but it wasn’t a lie. In fact, he had never spent any time with a woman “like this.” The Sword Saint had also warned him that the First Mistress had a skill to discern lies from truths, and seeing as the Guard Captain did too, Jake had gone in with the assumption the Prime Consort could as well.

Despite Jake feeling like his words were rather cringeworthy, the Prime Consort seemed quite pleased. “Oh, please. I heard you met with the Second Mistress and even spent some time within her residence. Several days, in fact… Do you mean to tell me you managed to avoid having her dig her fangs into you during all that time?”

As she asked, Jake felt something impact Shroud. A lie-detection skill. He instantly let it through as he shook his head and answered, “The thought never even crossed my mind. I only had one real conversation with her, and I truly have no interest in her. She only allowed me to stay with the hope I would assist her.”

“Did you agree to assist her?” the Prime Consort asked.

“I only agreed to do what I believed would benefit me, and it wouldn’t be wrong to say that I simply took advantage of her offer to further my goals,” Jake answered decisively.

Once more, the Prime Consort seemed satisfied with his answers, her lie-detecting skill having assured the authenticity of both. The last one had been a pre-prepared line, so he damn well hoped it would work.

“Two is an indecisive girl but talented, and I do have high hopes for her. I also know that, unlike some others, she truly does not covet my position as Prime Consort. That it is contestable is a bit silly to begin with. In all honesty, I see no need for this entire setup with Mistresses and me as the Prime Consort anymore… The Demon Lord has no interest in us anyway.” The Prime Consort shook her head. “He never truly did. Our titles are more there to indicate that we belong to him and heighten his status, and that is a position we will uphold as long as he desires.”

“You truly admire the Demon Lord,” Jake said with a smile. While it was certain that the Prime Consort was far more “real” than the common person in Nevermore, she still had an odd proneness to just divulging information.

He wanted to follow this line of dialogue if he could and eventually turn it toward the topic of the Secret Scrolls.

“Naturally. Do you not?” the Prime Consort asked, only a hint of suspicion in her voice. He also felt the lie-detecting skill again.

Jake smiled. “To gain an audience with him would be a dream come true.” Because if I had an audience, I wouldn’t have to be here right now.

“Sadly, that is not feasible right now, but depending on how things go, we might be able to figure something out later,” the Prime Consort said in a suggestive voice as she drank a bit of her wine. Jake did the same to be polite as he prepared himself.

Sense of the Malefic Viper had made him aware of a strong toxin coming from the wine bottle the moment it was summoned. Intended toxins, mind you, as the magical alcohol potency was quite a lot higher than one would usually consume in low-tier C-grade.

Drinking it, Jake actively held back on activating Palate, as him not being at all affected by the alcohol would be damn suspicious. Upon noting that the bottle had seemingly not lost any of its contents despite her pouring them both a glass, Jake got an idea.

If Jake asked about stuff he shouldn’t, it would obviously be suspicious, but if he asked while drunk? Even better if she was also drunk and didn’t hold back many secrets. Of course, Jake never actually planned on getting drunk in the first place, just a little tipsy at most. While the wine was strong, Jake had had stronger before with Villy several times. A lot stronger… which, yes, had probably resulted in alcohol being the type of toxin Jake best resisted.

Alcohol was an interesting kind of toxin that wasn’t really a poison. Not truly. It instead fell into the same camp as some herbs that made you hallucinate or maybe feel more clearheaded. These were not actively harmful and didn’t deal any damage to the person who consumed them, so long as it wasn’t done in massive quantities, but they could still be extremely dangerous due to the type of toxin:

Soul poison.

That’s right—alcohol was by far the most common soul poison in the multiverse. Granted, it wasn’t that deadly, never left permanent damage, and was easily detectable and pretty much impossible to hide. If you wanted to hurt someone, it was shit. However, what it was really good at was hiding other toxins mixed into the drink and bypassing most lower-grade detection skills.

Anyway, all of this is to say that Jake was drinking and getting drunk purely for work, and not a single part of him enjoyed the expensive wine. Definitely not.

As they were drinking, they naturally got talking, and after the fifth glass, Jake began to share some vague things about himself while also trying to learn more about the Prime Consort.

“When did you first discover you had a Bloodline?” she asked after more useless small talk, finally changing the subject to discussing it.

Jake shrugged and answered truthfully, “Back when I was still too young to understand what it was, but only knew I was different from everyone else. Something I guess hasn’t changed much.”

“Did you not have an Elder or other family member teach you?” she asked with a raised eyebrow. “I believe that is customary among Bloodline Clans.”

Jake shook his head and pointed to himself. “Bloodline Patriarch. No one in my family even knew what a Bloodline was. I didn’t even know for quite a while.”

“Truly? A Bloodline Patriarch? Those are… rare.” Her smile widened in tandem with her growing interest. “My first encounter, in fact. That must have been quite an upheaval for your clan or family.”

“Oh, there was an upheaval, alright,” Jake said with a nod, referring to the initiation of the 93rd Universe.

“Being the sole outlier can be… difficult.” The Prime Consort sighed. “Did you know I used to be a royal court mage? Not many do. I studied under many mages, as people kept telling me how talented I was, yet I never felt that talent myself. You see, the old court only cared about the ‘approved’ concepts. Those were the only ones you could study. Me? Sure, I was talented… but only as a warlock.”

“A concept of magic that I assume was off-limits?” Jake questioned as he finished off the wine in front of him.

“Naturally,” she said, waving her hand to fill both glasses again. “Yet even when I was discovered studying this banned school of magic, the royal family did nothing. They just allowed me to continue my research while keeping an eye on me. In their hypocrisy, they never truly cared as long as whatever I did led to making them more powerful. They just wanted to use me.”

“Woe of the strong,” Jake said, sighing as he raised his glass.

The Prime Consort responded in kind, and they both downed their wine.

“Even so… how did things end up as they are now?” Jake asked. He felt his face turn slightly red as he controlled Palate to keep his head clear. The Prime Consort was still nearly unaffected by the alcohol.

“Oh, the Second Prince was especially interested in my magic, and when he lost his bid for the throne, he came to me. He wasn’t happy just getting assigned some faraway land to rule over, as he knew his chances of ever reaching C-grade would disappear if he was. I was his solution. The desperation of a prince with no magical knowledge and access to the royal coffers did wonders for my research.” The Prime Consort grinned. “But enough about old history… How did you end up joining us? From what I see, you are not a warlock or even a true cultist?”

Jake was taken aback by the rather sharp question. His “fake” identity did not really include much of why he was there, so he had to make something up on the spot. Luckily, appearing slightly drunk made it easier to make up a convincing story. Or…

“Why would I not come here?” Jake smiled. “Where else would I find such pleasant company?”

The Prime Consort just smiled and kept their glasses full. Jake gladly cheered again and again, commenting on how good the wine was. The Prime Consort clearly had some powerful resistance to the alcohol, and coupled with her higher level, she should’ve been able to handle far more than Jake. If not for Palate, of course.

Soon enough, two hours had passed with Jake learning more and more history while discussing things he himself had done. A lot of it was just metaphors, and while it wasn’t really intentional, the two of them seemed to have in common the woes of not fitting in. As they talked, Jake increasingly began to feel that the Prime Consort was perhaps not that bad… only for her to add a sentence about how child sacrifices were better in demonic rituals, as their souls were “cleaner” and thus lowered the chances of the ritual being damaged by a curse of resentment. So, yeah, definitely still not a good gal.

By now, Jake looked pretty damn drunk, if he said so himself. He purposefully began to broach more and more “silly” topics, such as asking why the cultists still wore robes when inside, mentioning the overabundance of bars for the number of people who lived there, and even making a dumb joke about one of the guards he had seen.

Throughout these two hours, the Prime Consort had slowly shifted her position from sitting opposite Jake, to sitting beside him, to slightly leaning against him every time she poured wine from the bottomless bottle. He acted like he didn’t notice and just seemed jollier than ever.

Finally, he believed it was time. After taking a large chug of the wine, he made another dumb joke.

“Also, why do you have something called Secret Scrolls? Like, if you call them Secret Scrolls, doesn’t that make people want to know about them just because of the name, making them not really secret? Should call them… eh… Boring Scrolls?”

It took Jake’s full Willpower to not die from cringe saying that.

Chapter 22

Worst Date Ever

“Now, where did you hear of the Secret Scrolls?” the Prime Consort asked with a raised eyebrow. She did not use her lie-detection skill, though.

“Eh… somewhere, I think?” Jake said, a bit slurred. “People are all secretive about them…”

The Prime Consort giggled. “They are called Secret Scrolls.”

“Yeah, but, like… what are they? Who even decided they are secret?”

The Prime Consort seemed to consider that for a moment, enjoying a moment of sobriety as she asked while using her lie-detection skill, “Let’s say the Secret Scrolls were potentially capable of weakening the Demon Lord… Would you use them if given the chance? Or allow others to use them?”

Jake laughed. “Why would I ever want the Demon Lord to be weaker? The stronger he is, the better! Shit, if these super Secret Scrolls could make the Demon Lord stronger, it would be awesome!”

And those were his genuine thoughts—something the Prime Consort clearly noticed, as she snuggled up to him and whispered in his ear, “Wanna see one?”

Jake raised an eyebrow. “Really? You know where they are?”

She smiled. “Oh, course I do, silly… I helped make them.”

“How can I possibly not look forward to seeing something like that?” Jake said with his own smile.

“If I show you, perhaps you can show me something of yours after?” she said, looking down.

“That could certainly be arranged.”

“In that case, you just wait right here,” the Prime Consort said as she stood up.

Jake smiled after her as she left the room. The second she closed the door, Jake’s smile disappeared, and he looked at the wine glass she had left on the table. After not even a moment of hesitation, he activated his stealth skill and the enchantment on his cloak, then touched the wine glass as his hand began glowing dark green. Touch of the Malefic Viper was at full power as he amplified the level of toxicity—alcohol potency—within the wine. After only a brief second, Jake also did the same to his own glass, ensuring they at least had the same level of energy within them.

While doing this, he kept track of the Prime Consort using his Sphere of Perception and even sent out a few pulses. The alcohol level within the two glasses quickly increased as he amplified it using Touch. While he had confidence in resisting any effects, he doubted the Prime Consort could, as she was already getting tipsy.

Also… yes, the messed-up implications of what he was doing weren’t lost on him, but to be fair, she was the one who’d wanted to get him drunk first. She returned a few minutes later, having gone to the underground pentagram cellar to fetch the Secret Scroll. When he saw her returning, Jake quickly stopped using his stealth skill and deactivated the cloak. Then he leaned back and just lay on the floor with a pillow under his head and eyes closed. He had to sell being plenty drunk, after all.

The Prime Consort entered the room soon after and saw him relaxing. She flashed a slightly sinister smile for a second before quickly returning to her usual demeanor. Seeing that brief smile across her face instantly made Jake aware he wasn’t the one with ulterior motives. And no, he was not just talking about trying to get the other person blackout drunk and into bed. He had a feeling she wanted something else.

“Already asleep?” she asked, walking toward him.

Jake quickly sat back up and momentarily feigned disorientation. “Oh, no, I was just resting my eyes.”

“Sure.” She smiled as she showed off the scroll in her hands. Or, well, the metal tube with a scroll sealed within.

Looking at it, Jake could instantly tell opening the tube wouldn’t be easy. It looked to have some kind of locking mechanism. “Is that the Boring Scroll?” Then he grinned, trying to act the fool.

“It is indeed,” she answered as she infused some energy into the metal tube, causing seven magical circles to appear across it. The Prime Consort channeled energy into each of them in a set pattern, and as they all changed, the end of the tube opened up.

Seems easy enough, Jake thought. Perception came in clutch once more, allowing him to see everything going on with just one glance.

The Prime Consort then pulled out a scroll that looked to be made from old, golden parchment. Jake stared at it for a bit. “Looks boring, too…”

“Oh, but it is just the opposite,” the Prime Consort said as she sat down beside him. “Do you know what these Secret Scrolls really are?”

The lie-detection skill was activated once more.

“Not really,” Jake said, shrugging.

Once again sensing that he was truthful, she gladly explained, “The Demon Lord was already powerful the moment he was summoned, but he was far from invincible, as he still had to grow. We constructed what is now the Demon Lord’s castle to nurture him, then created artifacts to make him powerful enough to battle the entire kingdom… and it worked.”

She held up the scroll with clear pride. “And this… This is one of the control scrolls for the artifacts. This one controls the Heart of the Demon Lord, an incredibly powerful fire-affinity natural treasure that bathes his throne room in flames and allows him to grow far more powerful in a short span of time. Having returned, he is once more bathing in the accumulated energy that has gathered during his sealing.”

“Wow,” Jake said, amazed. It sounded like that artifact would add a domain of sorts that helped the Demon Lord. “What about the four other artifacts?”

“Four?” she giggled. “There are only two more… Well, three if we count the Sword of the Demon Lord, but that never had a Secret Scroll. No, the two others are the Armor of the Demon Lord and, finally, the Crown of the Demon Lord. Two artifacts that have also only grown more powerful in his absence.”

“Those all sound amazing,” Jake said, keeping up the act. “The Demon Lord must be so much more powerful now…”

“Yes… indeed,” the Prime Consort said with a slight change in expression. “Now… I believe you had something you promised to show me, too?”

She leaned on him and pushed him onto the floor. He momentarily panicked, but then he saw she had done it to obscure his view of the two wine glasses. With a hand behind her back, she summoned a small pill from her spatial storage and put it into Jake’s wine glass using telekinesis. Sense of the Malefic Viper went kind of wild feeling that pill… making him aware it was quite the potent poison. A neurotoxin, as far as he could tell.

“Oh, goodness, I almost lost myself there.” She smiled flirtatiously as she looked down at Jake.

Jake smiled in return as she backed off, sitting up again with her. “I wasn’t complaining.”

“We have all day and night.” She winked at him as she picked up his wine glass and handed it to him, its pill having entirely dissolved. Picking up her own glass, she looked him in the eyes.

Jake smiled goofily and lifted his glass. “Cheers!”

She followed suit, and they both downed the wine glasses. Jake saw her wince slightly as she drank it, but she didn’t spit it out or anything.

Jake also didn’t show anything despite feeling a powerful toxin begin spreading through his system. It had merged with the alcohol, and it was quite a high-level toxin. It was clearly made to be hidden, and if someone already had a lot of alcohol in their system, it would bind to that, effectively making it undetectable and more potent than usual. Sadly for her, Jake did not contain a lot of alcohol, and even if he had…

Well, it had just entered the body of the Chosen of the Malefic Viper. He quickly analyzed it and had it under control within seconds, but he didn’t dispel it; he just controlled the majority of it, allowing some to spread through his system.

Once he felt it spread further, he purposefully slouched even more and muttered, “Man, that one hit hard… My arms and legs are tingling.”

He’d been fed what was effectively a paralysis poison—one that would work fast and take away all voluntary movement without shutting down his mind and usual bodily functions.

The Prime Consort smiled. “There is one thing I didn’t quite share before… While these artifacts have strengthened, this empowerment is not active. You see, in the absence of the Demon Lord, a lot of things changed. While we do need a protector… the Demon Lord can no longer be controlled like before. He was sealed, yes, and while it made him weaker, it also gave him time to develop… let’s just call it independence.”

“Wha are yo…” Jake said, his mouth hanging a bit as he allowed the paralysis poison to partly affect him.

“That means he is not quite as… required as before. No, we need a new Demon Lord. A better one.” The Prime Consort smiled deeply as she stood up, a bit unsteady on her feet. “You see, my specialty was never just summoning rituals. It was demonification rituals. But to do that, I need a good base. Rejoice, for I shall give you the chance to be reborn more powerful than ever. Do not worry; I shall allow you to retain as much of what makes you you as I possibly can. We wouldn’t want to risk the improved you not having that Bloodline, now, would we?”

“I...” he tried as the poison spread more in his system.

“Shush, do not overexert yourself. This is a good thing.” She sat down beside him and laid a hand on his chest. “You shall become the new Demon Lord… the new master of this entire domain. Of course, we will need to get rid of the old Demon Lord for that, but as I said, I made these Secret Scrolls. While the artifacts can indeed help empower the Demon Lord, they can also do just the opposite. The Secret Scrolls do not only contain the method to empower, but also a way to weaken, if not outright kill him.”

Jake just lay on the floor, unmoving, acting utterly paralyzed. He glared up at her with angry eyes, only making her smile more as she leaned in and kissed his forehead.

“Do not be angry. Once you are reborn, we will have plenty of time together, just you and I.”

He didn’t stop glaring at her.

The Prime Consort kept smiling before getting off him. After that brief movement, she held her head before shaking it. “That wine was a bit stronger than I thought it would be…”

She tried to stand up once more but briefly lost her footing, then managed to stabilize herself. Having turned her back, Jake now had the opportunity. His hand began to glow dark green as he amplified the alcohol within her body even more than before, as it now counted as “his” poison.

The Prime Consort kept trying to walk but soon wobbled and nearly fell. “Goodness…” she said before giggling.

Trying to stand up, she fell on the floor again. She tried two more times before giving up. Instead, she did a silly roll as she went back to Jake and leaned on him. “Heh… I guess we got time… All day… night… and…”

Jake was almost expecting a notification from killing her via alcohol poisoning, but she had only passed out. Exhaling in relief, Jake stood up and stretched, then contacted the group using his Golden Mark, not bothering to act paralyzed anymore.

“So… I have one Secret Scroll from the Prime Consort, but I did not get any information out of her regarding the location of the lost one… though I did learn something interesting,” Jake shared before delivering all the information the Prime Consort had given about the artifacts.

“A way to make the final encounter either easier or harder unlocked from gathering the Secret Scrolls? That does seem to track with prior floors.” The Sword Saint was even polite enough not to ask for any details about how Jake had gotten this information.

“What are the chances you can make the Prime Consort tell you about the location of the final Secret Scroll?” the Fallen King asked. “Or did you manage to turn her into an enemy?”

Looking at her snuggling up to him on the floor, Jake wasn’t quite sure how to answer that. In the end, he just had to share the situation he found himself in. “Well…”

After he was done explaining, he expected the Sword Saint or the King to make fun of him, but it ended up being Dina, who spoke first.

“That makes no sense… A Demon Lord cannot be born from a single sacrifice, much less retain the Bloodline or any part of the personality of the sacrificed person,” Dina said, poking holes in the entire narrative. “At most, she should be able to do a demonification ritual that will turn you part-demon, but even that would require your enthusiastic consent…”

Now, Jake could choose to make fun of Minaga for not knowing how stuff worked, but he imagined there was a better chance the Prime Consort was simply wrong or had purposefully lied to him. However, with that being the case, what would have happened if Jake had indeed been paralyzed? He asked their resident expert.

“Well…” Dina muttered. “You would just die, probably. No, definitely.”

“So, either she is a misinformed idiot who doesn’t know how the ritual actually works, or she is maliciously intending to kill me through a demonic ritual?” Jake summarized. “Well, this is officially the worst date I have ever been on.”

“You got the Secret Scroll from her, and you also learned to unlock the containers they were in,” the Fallen King said. “That is an acceptable level of success for a date. The scroll possessed by the Guard Captain is also in a similar container, so just give me the go-ahead when it is time to retrieve it. However, we still have to find the final scroll.”

Jake looked at the scroll in the room and picked it up along with the container. He then lifted it up to his nose and took a whiff as he analyzed it. Feeling the energy from the container, he detected a very distinct signature. Activating his tracking, he felt for a similar signature in the Prime Consort’s residence but felt nothing.

“Do we have any idea at all where it might be?” Jake asked. “If I am inside the same room as the container, I am fairly confident I can find it.”

“None of the Mistresses I spoke with have it, so I would guess it is within the main room,” the Sword Saint said.

“Alright,” Jake said. “Say, any idea what I should do with the Prime Consort?”

“Bring her to the residence of the Second Mistress,” the Sword Saint answered. “We are here, and she wants revenge, correct? At the very least, we can allow her to have the kill, which I believe could give us an achievement.”

“Good thinking,” Jake said. Now he just had to figure out how to smuggle her out of the room and back to the Second Mistress. Ultimately, he took off his cloak, put the half-demon lady into it, and swung it over his back in the most cliché kidnapping imaginable.

He thought it would be hard to sneak out, but once more, it came in handy that they had integrated themselves with all of the factions on the floor. The Fallen King diverted nearly all the patrolling guards to another area, and the Sword Saint convinced two Mistresses to go and “visit” the Prime Consort, allowing Jake to quite easily get out and back to the residence of the Second Mistress.

The guards at her residence were in full NPC mode, not even questioning Jake before they let him in.

Right inside, Jake saw that all the guards had been dismissed. His entire party, save for the Fallen King, stood just inside, along with seven women—all of the Mistresses except the two who’d gone to the Prime Consort. Upon entering, all eyes landed on him.

“Did he truly?”

“How…”

“Truly a master,” the Second Mistress said as all the other Mistresses admired Jake’s accomplishment.

He dumped the unconscious Prime Consort on the ground. He had made sure the level of alcohol in her body had stayed as stable as it could by using Touch on his way there.

Jake nodded and wanted to question why all the Mistresses had gathered, but before that, he had just one tiny question as he looked at the Second Mistress. “Say, how come you have a Secret Scroll hidden in a secret cabinet within your house?”

Chapter 23

Guard Captain Down

Needless to say, Jake’s question made the entire situation quite tense as he looked at the Second Mistress. She was taken aback and stared at Jake for several seconds, clearly having not expected him to find out.

The moment he had entered the residence of the Second Mistress, he had felt the familiar mana signature of the container with the Secret Scroll inside. Considering the Fallen King had made it clear the Guard Captain still had one, it wasn’t hard to figure out this was the “missing” scroll.

It took her a moment, but the Second Mistress collected herself and sighed. “Why hide it? Why would I not? Would you have helped bring the Prime Consort to me and assisted in slaying the Demon Lord if I didn’t have anything to offer?”

“Probably.” Jake shrugged.

She seemed taken aback by his answer. “Why?”

“Why not?” Jake asked. Doing that was bound to earn a better achievement, so helping her out only made sense in his head. Of course, she didn’t know about achievements, so maybe it made sense in her mind to keep it a secret for now.

“Why would the Prime Consort give it to you?” the Sword Saint asked. “From my understanding, you were not allies.”

“We are most certainly not. No, she gave it to me because I am not allied with the First Mistress. Or, well, I wasn’t allied with her. The Prime Consort said that she hoped it would foster trust… In reality, I believe she knew I had a distaste for the Demon Lord, and she knew I would never offer anyone a scroll that would empower him.”

“I see.” The old man nodded, looking to be deep in thought.

The Second Mistress clenched her fists and looked at the Prime Consort. “If you let me kill her… you can have the scroll, and I will even show you how to unlock the containers for when you get the last one from the Guard Captain.”

“Now, wait a second, here,” Jake said, wanting to understand what was going on with all the Mistresses. He looked at all of them for a second, then asked, “Nobody gonna protest someone wanting to kill the Prime Consort?”

“Why would we?” a woman said, smiling. Jake Identified her and saw it was the First Mistress.

[First Mistress – lvl 264]

“She used to be your leader?” Jake questioned.

“That lunatic has needed to go for a long time,” the First Mistress said with disdain, the other Mistresses all nodding. “Also, if it helps hubby, why would we not want that?”

Jake didn’t need to question who “hubby” was as he threw the Sword Saint a glance.

The old man looked at the Prime Consort while questioning the Second Mistress. “Will killing her like this be wise? Are you certain we do not need her for the Secret Scrolls in any way, or to see if she knows any other big secrets, such as what the Secret Scrolls are used for? Jake told us that she said they were created to weaken the Demon Lord in case the Prime Consort lost control of him, just like you told us before.”

Jake was about to protest—she had also said they could be used to empower him—but he quickly realized what the Sword Saint was doing. He wanted to see if she knew and, if she did know, would share the full truth with them.

“That is one of their uses, yes,” the Second Mistress said. “The other is to empower the Demon Lord’s artifacts. I don’t know why they hold both functions, but the weakening aspect was added later.”

“I see,” the Sword Saint said, nodding.

Alright, so she does tell some truths, Jake quickly noted.

Suddenly, the Prime Consort groaned. Jake quickly knelt down and used Touch to give her another rush of alcohol, buying them some time.

“So?” the Second Mistress said. “Only the Prime Consort, myself, and the Guard Captain know how to open the containers with the Secret Scrolls, and as I said, I will teach you how if you give her to me.”

“Well, you three and me.” Jake shrugged, getting looks. “What? She taught me. Not voluntarily, but she opened it right in front of me.”

“Just because you saw her open it once doesn’t mean you can replicate the process,” the Second Mistress protested.

“Pretty sure I can,” Jake said with a high level of confidence.

“So, what are the thoughts of everyone on this?” the Sword Saint asked through their link. “I believe handing the Prime Consort to the Second Mistress will be fine. We don’t need the Prime Consort, and having found the final scroll, we don’t really need to stay here much longer. Fallen King, I would say it’s about time you got everything handled on your end and brought back the scroll from the Guard Captain.”

“Sure he will be enough on his own?” Jake asked. The Guard Captain was supposed to be pretty strong, and finding somewhere to kill him…

“Do you question my abilities?” the Fallen King said, offended. “I am ready at any point. Besides getting rid of the Guard Captain, we only have one more loose end… Who was the demon we met when we first entered this floor? The one who knew about the Secret Scrolls and offered to translate them?”

“I… had completely forgotten about that guy,” Jake admitted. The old demon’s full-on NPC energy had made him utterly forgettable, but on second thought, he’d been set up to matter on this floor…

“That is a good question,” the Sword Saint said. “I did ask the Mistresses, and no one knew about him.”

“The Second Mistress didn’t either… and I think she was telling the truth then,” Dina chimed in.

“Ree,” Sylphie added. The wind didn’t know either.

“Alright, then we can go check out that old house while the King handles his business with the Guard Captain,” Jake said. “Are we all happy moving on quickly and just getting this place done with?”

Affirmatives all around.

“Great. Let’s go, then.”

“Very well,” the Sword Saint said to the Second Mistress. “We agree. Bring us the Secret Scroll.”

She hesitated only for a moment before nodding and going inside her house. Dina had walked over to Jake during this and asked to see Secret Scroll he had gotten from the Prime Consort.

The druid read it and nodded. “Yeah, this is pretty simple. We wouldn’t need a translator for this.”

Which, again, just made it weird that the demon had offered to translate.

Soon after, the Second Mistress brought them their Secret Scroll. Jake was allowed a shot at opening it, but was warned that the scroll inside would be destroyed if he failed three times.

He only needed one attempt.

With two scrolls in the bag, they just needed the Fallen King to get the last one, and then it was time to finally face the Demon Lord. In the meantime, they allowed the Second Mistress to drag the still-unconscious Prime Consort away, accompanied by quite a few of the other Mistresses. Probably because the Sword Saint followed.

Jake decided to check up on this old demon who’d originally wanted the Secret Scrolls just to wrap up all loose ends. On his way there, he got a notification.

Achievement earned: Allow the Second Mistress to get her revenge on the Prime Consort, fully earning her support. 300 Nevermore Points earned.

Jake didn’t really feel anything about that. She had tried to do some fucked-up ritual on him, and she had only gotten her just desserts. Now all they needed was for the Fallen King to finish enjoying his time with the Guard Captain.

“You are certain that the reports came from here, Vice-Captain?” the large demon in full plate armor asked.

“The reports were quite clear,” the Fallen King insisted. “The rebels have all met here and prepared to launch an attack on the Third Mistress when she returns. This is a prime opportunity to strike at them while they least expect it.”

Floating forward, the Fallen King identified the man he was following.

[Guard Captain – lvl 265]

“Good thinking; keep up the good work,” the Guard Captain said as they entered the gate leading into the Third Residence. Walking through the fog, the gate closed behind them once they properly entered the room.

“They are well hidden,” the Guard Captain said with suspicion. “And where are all the usual guards and Courtesans?”

The Fallen King did not answer. Instead, his claw began glowing golden as he lunged forward. The Guard Captain was taken by surprise, failing to respond before his back was ripped up and he was launched across the empty room, smashing into a wall.

An explosion erupted soon after as the demon tore himself free from the wall.

“How dare you,” he yelled from across the room, his voice infused with Willpower. “To betray the great Demon Lord…”

The Fallen King saw no more need for words. Instead, he condensed a wave of force and sent it toward the Guard Captain, who responded by taking out a shield and blocking the blow… yet still being blasted back.

One challenge the Fallen King had when fighting with a party was his control. He had never needed to care much about collateral damage, but when fighting with others, things were not as simple. A large-scale blast would hit indiscriminately, so he had to communicate and try to limit the scope of his blows. Having spent so many years not caring, it took time to adapt… and he certainly didn’t complain when he got a chance to go all-out.

Golden lines appeared all across his body as he activated his boosting skill. When power erupted from his body, the Guard Captain seemed taken back.

“You—”

The King took advantage of the demon’s surprise by sending a blast of force into his shield, sending him back into the wall for a third time. Grasping, he pulled on the wall itself as it began to collapse down on him. Still, the armored Guard Captain managed to quickly get free.

Only to be hit once more by a telekinetic blast.

These rooms were the perfect size for the Fallen King. Not too large or too small, meaning he could keep his opponent constantly within his effective range while still not allowing the melee-specialized Guard Captain to get close.

“For your betrayal…” the demon yelled as he landed, “I sentence you to death.”

Then his body bulked up, signaling he’d decided to go all-out. He teleported across the entire room, appearing nearly right in front of the Fallen King with his sword already mid-swing.

It hit nothing.

He had been just a single meter short, and he looked confused as a golden claw hit him in the face, sending blood spraying.

“I expected more damage,” the Fallen King said, assessing that the Guard Captain had barely been damaged despite the direct hit. His body was tough. Tougher than the Demon Lord that they had fought in the hallway. Luckily, his soul was… pathetic. So easily confused and muddled with.

The control he’d learned from the Nevermore party affected more than his own magic. It also influenced how much others relied on it. He’d never needed to care much about being overly accurate, and most of the melee attacks he used had at least an optional long-range aspect. Warriors like the Guard Captain needed to be far more accurate with everything they did.

A single meter seemed like a lot, but when they all moved fast enough to cross hundreds of meters in the blink of an eye, it suddenly became a distance that could make a significant difference. Distorting the reality others perceived through soul magic was difficult, but the Fallen King could slightly nudge it with these low-Perception creatures. To make a single meter look like two was difficult, especially if he didn’t want the other person to instantly notice. But to make a kilometer look like nine hundred and ninety-nine meters? That was doable.

The Guard Captain was the test subject, and the King was pleased as he continued his assault. Golden claws, constructs, and blasts sent him repeatedly flying like a ragdoll, never quite managing to land a hit. His durability was high, but his attacks were limited, and what hits he did manage to land were expected blows the King’s barrier blocked perfectly.

Ultimately, it was a slaughter. The mighty Guard Captain, an individual many hailed as the most powerful fighter on the floor, was killed without many chances to fight back in a long and drawn-out beatdown.

Nearly half an hour later, the Fallen King found himself standing within a large ruin. All the houses were utterly destroyed, and the walls were filled with holes. On the ground before him was the Guard Captain, his armor distorted and broken, his body in even greater ruin.

“The Demon Lord… will avenge me,” he muttered.

“Let us hope he will try,” the Fallen King said before a golden blast removed the demon’s head.

With his death, the Fallen King got a seal to unlock the Guard Captain’s Vault. Making his way back to the main office of the guards, the King greeted them as usual. Then he went straight for the Guard Captain’s office and opened the vault, which only had the scroll container in it.

“I am done with my part—making my way to you now,” the Fallen King sent to the rest of the party. While the Guard Captain had been a good test dummy, the King was far from satisfied. Nevermore had been too easy so far, and he hoped the Demon Lord could finally offer a proper challenge.

The old demon was gone when Jake got to the residence they had first entered on this floor. In his stead was a letter informing Jake that he had found a secret entrance into the Demon Lord’s castle and would be waiting just inside. In other words, he was a reused character that they would meet again on the next floor.

As for what his deal was… well, Jake would guess he was there for one of two reasons. One was to have a person that could help them if they got “stuck” with anything, such as opening the scroll containers or just reading the scrolls, but the other purpose was quite a bit more interesting:

He’d been sent there by the Demon Lord to get the scrolls to help empower the artifacts.

That kind of made sense to Jake. If the Demon Lord knew the Prime Consort was not really loyal, Jake could see him sending someone, and it also explained how the old demon had suddenly found a “secret entrance.” Because that was complete bullshit.

After having confirmed the demon was gone, Jake made his way back to the residence of the Second Mistress and regrouped with everyone. Shortly after, the Fallen King also returned with the final Secret Scroll in hand. Well, it was still in its container, but Jake got that opened in a jiffy. Once he took out the final scroll, they all got a notification.

Bonus Objective Completed: All Secret Scrolls found. 250 Nevermore Points earned.

“Not exactly a lot of points for all three scrolls,” Jake commented. “Especially considering all the trouble we went through to get them.”

“It is as expected,” the Sword Saint said. “Their true value lies on the next floor, not this one.”

“True.” Jake nodded. “But still… a lot of trouble.”

On a side note, none of the Mistresses seemed to even notice what they were talking about. It was as if the mention of “points” and “floors” didn’t exist. It appeared that no matter how human they seemed, they still fell before the mighty NPC concept.

“With all the scrolls gathered… it is time to take down the Demon Lord,” the Second Mistress said. All nine Mistresses were now gathered, and they all seemed in agreement as they stood around the Sword Saint. “Please allow us to assist you in this final—”

“No,” Jake said, shutting her down right away. “The Demon Lord is ours and ours alone.”

“Please,” she pleaded. “Even with the artifacts sabotaged, it will not be an easy fight. Gubrothas will have grown stronger since you last fought him. You may not win a second time.”

Jake shook his head. “Still no.”

“Are you certain?” the First Mistress asked. Not Jake, mind you, but the Sword Saint. “While I do have confidence you will win, I do not wish to see you hurt.”

“There are some things a man must do, and this is one of them,” the Sword Saint said as he smiled at her. “Do not worry about me.”

Her face turned red as she nodded. “I shall believe in you, then.”

“We all will,” the Third Mistress said with a radiant smile as all the Mistresses joined in on encouraging him.

Jake refrained from commenting on how “things a man must do” didn’t make sense with Sylphie and Dina on the team, mainly because he didn’t want to waste any time getting to what mattered.

“Give me the seal to unlock the Demon Lord’s castle,” Jake told the Second Mistress.

She seemed reluctant but still nodded. “I will entrust it all to you, then. Should you fail… we are all doomed.”

The Second Mistress handed Jake the seal the Prime Consort had been carrying, which allowed them to open the next door. The second Jake had it in hand, he spoke to the group.

“Now, let’s get the hell out of here.”

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched as she flew over and landed on Jake’s shoulder. She waved goodbye to all the Mistresses with her wing as Jake began heading out.

The Sword Saint said goodbye to all his Mistresses and departed, with Dina and the Fallen King quietly following.

Jake couldn’t lie… He was glad the floor was over, and his relief when they made it to the giant red gate leading to the Demon Lord’s castle was palpable. They were finally done and could move on to something far more fun…

Fighting a (hopefully) proper boss.

Chapter 24

It's Demon Lord Time

Jake and company finally stepped out of the thirty-fourth floor after what to him felt like weeks. In reality, it had not even been a week, but the entire ordeal had been quite mentally taxing.

Once more, they found themselves in the in-between room designed by Minaga, and Jake was more than happy with taking a breather and spending at least a few hours fully recovering. He wasn’t the only one, either.

The Fallen King was also tired after killing the Guard Captain. At least, Jake thought that was the reason.

“How could I not be tired after acting like I am beneath a lesser creature for so long?” the King said with disgust. “For a rightful King to act subservient to a mere Guard Captain… You cannot even begin to imagine the sacrifices I made.”

“Oh, woe is you,” Jake grumbled. “I had to try and seduce some half-demon lady who wanted to sacrifice me in a demonic ritual.”

“You complain as if humans do not tend to enjoy such things. The swordsman does not seem bothered despite doing far more than you.”

“Don’t bring him into this.” Jake shook his head as he stared at the Sword Saint. “That old geezer is just… Let’s change the damn topic already.”

“I do agree with that assessment,” the old man said, smiling. “We all did our jobs, and we managed to complete the floor in a satisfactory fashion, if I may say so myself.”

“Yeah…” Dina nodded. “Sylphie and I were the only ones who didn’t really contribute much…”

“Ree!” Sylphie complained.

“I see… You also made sacrifices,” Jake said in a serious nod as he scratched her feathers.

Sylphie had perhaps sacrificed the most out of them all… She had allowed the Second Mistress to pat her head. Once. In a ruse to get close to the woman.

It had worked… but at what cost?

As they were feeling sorry for themselves, they got the system messages from having completed the floor.

Thirty-fourth floor completed. 340 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-fourth floor without any guards, Courtesans, or other innocent patrons finding out anything is amiss. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-fourth floor while not killing a single Mistress. 200 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-fourth floor while turning all Mistresses into allies. 400 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete the thirty-fourth floor in less than a week (7 days). 350 Nevermore Points earned.

“That is a lot of achievements,” Jake said. “Coupled with the one we got on the floor and the one for completing the bonus objective, this may be the best one yet, points-wise.”

“Yet it is not something I would wish to experience once more,” the Fallen King said.

“Oh, yeah, fuck that,” Jake wholeheartedly agreed. Dina and Sylphie also didn’t seem like fans. Only the Sword Saint silently muttered how it wasn’t that bad.

As they stood there, someone they had not heard from for a while also made his reappearance.

“You know how you sometimes have a concept you thought could be fun, and then decide to expand on it and build something, only to end up with an experience you aren’t quite sure about and ultimately kind of regret having made, but you have spent so much time on it that the sunk-cost fallacy sets in hard, and you decide to just say ‘fuck it’ and use it anyway?” Minaga said. “Yeah, that’s the thirty-fourth floor for me. Granted, it isn’t downright horrible, but I think I tried a bit too many things… ninety-five percent of which you missed.”

“Welcome back,” Jake said with a smile. “Amazed you managed to shut up for nearly that entire dungeon floor.”

“I apologize. I was too busy trying not to die from embarrassment watching you.”

“Ouch… but fair.” Jake shrugged. “Anyway, since we are taking a break here… what did we miss?”

“I am not staying to listen to this,” the Fallen King said dismissively as he floated out of the lounge and entered one of the bedrooms to meditate.

“What a downer… but super glad you asked!” Minaga said. “You see, I wanted to make a floor where the socialites had a real shot, and I also decided to make it more fun by adding another concept… Plot twists. Like… a lot of plot twists. You see, the Mistresses, Prime Consort, Guard Captain, and pretty much every other major character have different paths to be taken down, and they will even change based on what happens. The Second Mistress could have had several personalities, as an example, based on what you did. Had you managed to find out her real identity—spoiler: She was a princess of the kingdom destroyed by the Demon Lord—she would’ve offered a lot more dialogue. She would’ve even opened up a method to make all the Mistresses and the Demonic Cult faithful to the kingdom once more, shunning the Demon Lord. This one would have given a lot of Nevermore Points, and I only feel comfortable sharing it because it would have required you to work with the friendlies on prior floors.”

“Say, how many methods would there be to turn the Demon Lord into an ally?” Jake asked.

“None set by me.”

“Really?” Jake questioned, finding it hard to believe.

“See, people sometimes think they would like a story going in a certain direction that actually sucks. The Demon Lord is set up as a boss, not as a potential ally, and there has been way too much build-up for it all to just result in a small conversation and an amicable solution. That would suck for sure.”

“How are you sure it would suck?”

“Because I say it would, duh,” Minaga said unapologetically. “I am the expert here, after all.”

“Fair, fair.” Jake grinned. “I assume you are not going to answer any questions related to the thirty-fifth floor?”

“Nope, that is for you to experience. No spoilers from me! Outside of the spoilers I do decide to give, of course.”

“How shameless,” Jake said, chuckling.

“Alright, alright, one freebie. If you plan on doing what I think you plan on doing… I would open the lockbox that the thirty-fourth floor rewarded,” Minaga said in a hinting voice.

“Oh, yeah, that is a thing,” Jake said, suddenly remembering it. Even Sylphie seemed to have forgotten, proving they were all a little off their game after that damn harem floor.

Sylphie did her job by flying over and poking the lockbox on the elevated platform with her talon. It instantly opened, and out floated five stone coins. Stone coins with the face of Minaga printed on both sides—a goofy smile on one, and a fake horrified look on the other. Jake stared at them and used Identify.

[Minaga’s Best Nevermore Escape Talisman (Unique)] – This is quite literally the best escape talisman Nevermore offers, and I am only giving it out because the people who earned it are pretty darn good at what they do. Just break it, and poof, you go right back to the last rest floor you visited. I know you might be questioning if it is really that simple. Is there really no point penalty? And you go to the rest floor and not city floor? Or any other punishment? Well, question no more, for it is indeed that awesome! Oh, but don’t bring it out of Nevermore, or I’ll take it back. Also, the talisman is single-use, which in retrospect should be pretty obvious, considering you need to break the talisman to use it.

Staring at the “description,” Jake failed to hold himself back. “Is this seriously an item?”

“Oh, do you have any issues understanding what it does?” Minaga questioned, sounding annoyingly genuine.

“No, I am questioning why the hell the description sounds like you are describing the item to me in your usual tone. It doesn’t read like an item description.”

“Because I made it, including the description? If you understand what it does, why are you complaining?”

“I wouldn’t say I am complaining… just questioning…” Jake said somewhat defensively.

“Well, let me help you by not hurting your dear sensibilities.”

One of the talismans flashed out of existence, only to be replaced by one that was the same size but had nothing printed on it besides a basic-looking magical circle. Jake used Identify again.

[Incredibly Boring Nevermore Escape Talisman (Unique)] – An Escape Talisman. Crush = teleport to the latest rest floor. Can’t be brought out of Nevermore. One use.

Requirement: Jake Thayne

“Is that better?” Minaga said with snark. “Or do you want me to simplify it even more? I am sure I could find a fluff word to remove somewhere.”

Jake looked at the talisman and sighed. “I liked the original version more.”

With another flash, the original talisman reappeared. “See, you never know you’ll miss something before it is taken away.”

“Truly wise words,” Jake said as he went over and took one of the talismans. All the others followed suit, with the last one left floating there for the Fallen King. He could pick it up when he returned from resting.

Whether they would actually need these talismans, Jake didn’t know, but he did know that he wanted the “original” version. Because if they didn’t need them, they could at least sell or trade them, while the “special” talisman was effectively Soulbound to Jake. It couldn’t even serve as a nice collectible, as it couldn’t be brought out.

“I guess you can all imagine why you get these talismans… Let’s just say the Demon Lord can be quite a boss if you want him to be! So, if you are at risk of dying, just crush the talismans, and you will be brought back to this room right here instantly. A real lifesaver. Ah, but do note you will not be able to reenter the thirty-fifth floor before your party is done in there. If you do so, and if they pass the floor, the gate here will be replaced with one leading to the city layer after the thirty-fifth.”

Jake listened to Minaga and considered that for a moment. Did he even want this talisman? If he had it, wouldn’t the upcoming fight be less exciting? He would know, in the back of his mind, that he had an escape at any moment. Maybe he should just—

“Don’t even think about it,” a voice suddenly said in his head.

Jake turned and saw the Sword Saint looking at him with a judging look.

“Think about what?” Jake responded telepathically. The conversation was not through the Golden Mark, but directly between the two of them.

“Handing off that escape talisman to someone else. I know you are thinking about it. You may not want it because you believe it will cheapen the fight, but discard such selfish thoughts.”

Nonchalant, Jake replied, “Selfish? Sure, it is selfish, but we are all the owners of our own lives. Besides, I don’t plan on dying.”

“Nobody expects to die until the moment they do,” the Sword Saint said sternly. “Have you considered the consequences of your demise? How it will affect Sylphie? Not to mention whatever effects it may have on the Fallen King and his existence, or the fate of Earth. I cannot tell you how to live your life, but I can tell you that as long as we are in the same party, you will keep that talisman.”

“Or what?” Jake said defensively.

“Or we will have to part ways and find separate parties. Whether you choose to use the talisman or not is up to you, but you are to, at the very least, keep it.”

“What a weird hill to die on. Me keeping it, but not necessarily using it.” Jake scoffed internally.

“You may not agree or understand why, but just humor me in this and keep it.”

Jake gave up. “Fine…” While the Sword Saint was willing to die on that hill, Jake saw no reason to. In reality, he wasn’t that upset with keeping the token; he just never liked being told what to do. This token was also a lot different from something like Villy offering to resurrect him if he died or some automatically activating talisman that would save his life.

This one was optional. Jake had to use it himself. An option, if you will. Granted, it wasn’t that different from normal, as he always had the possibility of attempting to escape using his impressive speed, One Step, and his Wings of the Malefic Viper—a skill with an option that was pretty much all about escaping a tricky situation.

“Think about how you would feel if Sylphie didn’t have the talisman and you saw her in mortal danger. It would plant an unnecessary seed of worry.” The Sword Saint clearly just wanted the last word.

Jake just threw him a glance, not bothering to keep the discussion going more than necessary. “So, Minaga… got some more interesting scenarios we missed on that last floor?” he finally asked aloud.

“What a silly question. Of course I do! So, wanna hear about how the First Mistress actually has a crush on the Second Mistress, or maybe about how the Guard Captain can be manipulated into pursuing the Prime Consort romantically? That would have created some real hijinks. Wait! How can I forget about how…”

Jake just leaned back and relaxed while enjoying the local non-alcoholic drinks—he’d had enough alcohol for now—and waiting for everyone to feel ready to move on. Hearing Minaga talk was oddly relaxing, and Jake had a good time just sitting there at the bar.

In the end, they spent around ten hours on this in-between floor. While the majority was spent relaxing, they also took the time to gather towards the end for something they had rarely needed on any of the prior floors: strategizing.

If Minaga was to be believed, then the Demon Lord would be far more difficult than any prior opponent they had faced in the dungeon. Especially considering their plan of purposefully powering him up with all three Secret Scrolls.

On that note… the Secret Scrolls were gone the moment they entered the in-between floor, but Minaga assured them that the items would reappear with them upon entering the thirty-fifth floor.

Either way, their plan was clear. If Jake was correct, and the old demon was, in fact, working for the Demon Lord, then handing off the Secret Scrolls to him would perhaps be an option. Assuming it would work, they still had the actual battle and their plans for that to discuss.

After they finished all their strategizing, they made sure everyone had everything they needed, and Jake even went as far as to craft a new batch of health potions for the group to ensure they had the best he could make.

Gathered in front of the gateway, with Sylphie on his shoulder and the party around him, Jake nodded. “Let’s go.”

“Good luck with the Demon Lord! I hope you all have a great time, and if you don’t, then you can only blame yourselves for not knowing what’s fun and what’s not. Oh, yeah, and don’t die!” Minaga’s encouraging parting words reached them moments before they entered the thirty-fifth floor.

It was Demon Lord time.

Chapter 25

Evil Demon Lord Gubrothas

Asudden burst of heat hit Jake as he stepped out of the gateway and appeared on the thirty-fifth floor. One thing was already different about this floor compared to any prior: There was no difficulty selection with Minaga. Instead, they just appeared within the Demon Lord’s castle.

Before anything else, Jake released a Pulse of Perception to get a lay of the land. What he saw was probably the smallest floor they had encountered so far.

The floor was just one unrealistically giant castle. It consisted of three different sections of note: the massive central throne room, a large, circular hallway surrounding it, and three towers that each had hallways extending from the large, circular hallway. Jake also spotted a certain someone hidden in a room pretty much right next to where they appeared.

As Jake was still looking through the mental map from his pulse, they got the usual welcome message for the floor.

Welcome to the thirty-fifth floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth (Demon Lord’s Castle)

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: Slay the three Tower Demons (0/3)

Current progress: Tower Demons (0/3), end reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 23,123

Minaga had even bothered to name this floor instead of calling it part five. Using his mental map, it was easy to spot all three Tower Demons, as each was within its respective tower. Moreover, each Tower Demon seemed to be guarding something, and Jake couldn’t help but make the connection between the three Secret Scrolls and the three towers.

Speaking of the secret scrolls…

A small pedestal was right in front of them where they appeared. All three Secret Scrolls were stacked on top of each other, with a letter placed atop them all.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked as she shuffled on his shoulder, uncomfortable with the heavy fire affinity in the air.

“Yeah, sure,” Jake agreed. Sylphie released a small gust of wind that made the letter fly over to him, and they all looked at Jake as he cleared his voice and read it aloud.

“Dear heroes,

I hope you all have arrived at the Demon Lord’s castle safely, and I hope this letter reaches you in time. Throughout the years of plotting to take down the Demon Lord, I managed to obtain the schematics of the Demon Lord’s castle and memorize them, and I wish to share my findings with you. For now, avoid the central throne room and, instead, head to the three outer towers. You must defeat the three Tower Demons atop each tower and gain access to each Sealstone up there. These Sealstones are attuned to the artifacts, and you need to read out the incantation written on each corresponding Secret Scroll. Remember to read the correct phrase to sabotage the artifacts of the Demon Lord. If you read the other one, you may accidentally empower the Demon Lord, making beating Gubrothas nearly impossible.

May you succeed in your quest for righteousness.

- Second Mistress.”

Jake finished reading it, and just as he did, they heard shuffling footsteps and the sound of something impacting the tiled floors. Out of a small, hidden room walked the old demon, now with a cane in hand.

He shuffled in their direction, smiling and calling, “Heroes! I could not help but hear you read the letter from the Second Mistress, and I came out as soon as I could. I am glad to see you arrived at the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas’ castle in one piece. You even managed to obtain all three Secret Scrolls! Truly impressive.”

Things were as expected, and Jake smiled at the old demon. “I found your message at your old residence. Say, how did you manage to find a secret entrance to the castle? Could you not have told us about it?”

“I wanted to, but there was limited time to make use of the opening, and the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas found the flaw in the defenses right after I managed to sneak inside. Also, it may have interfered with your quest to obtain the Secret Scrolls. In the end, we all made it here safely and are united in our goal of ending the menace that is the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas, so there truly is no need to discuss this. Instead, we should focus on the task at hand.”

“I think Jake is right… This demon is clearly not actually here to help us,” Dina said through the Golden Mark.

If even the sheltered Dina noticed how off the demon was, it was pretty damn obvious. However…

“Indeed, we should,” Jake said. “You heard the letter from the Second Mistress. What say you? How do you think we should approach this?”

“Sabotaging the artifacts of the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas is naturally imperative to ensuring his defeat.” Appearing to think deeply, the old demon added, “Of course, if you are truly confident in your victory, then you can simply choose to face the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas without weakening him first. However, not using the scrolls would be incredibly risky…”

“We want to do what will give us the highest chance of bringing the evil Demon Lord to justice,” Jake said, trying to sound as heroic as he could.

“In that case, may I be allowed to offer my assistance as best I can?” the old demon asked.

Here we go, Jake thought. “Of course, but in what way?”

The demon looked at them all suspiciously for no damn reason as he spoke, “Could you lend me the Secret Scrolls? I want to ensure their authenticity.”

“Oh, no problem,” Jake readily agreed, only to hesitate and turn to the party. “No complaints, right?”

“He has only helped us so far,” the Sword Saint said with a smile. “No need to be suspicious.”

“My apologies; you can never be too safe,” Jake said, bowing slightly to the old demon and handing him the scrolls.

“No need to worry,” the demon said, his eyes full of greed and showing acting talent on par with the average child actor as he received the scrolls and smiled creepily. “Now, I just need to do a quick ritual to confirm they are real, if that is alright with you all? I may need your slight assistance.”

“Sure, sure.” Jake nodded as he watched the old demon draw a damn pentagram, nearly identical to the one the Demon Lord had made when he teleported away during their first encounter. His insight into magic circles also instantly let him know it was a teleportation circle of some kind, and Dina also looked to have a hard time holding herself back from commenting on the obvious nature of the demon’s actions.

Nevertheless, both Dina and Jake poured in a bit of mana, as the old demon was not strong enough to do the ritual himself. Then, suddenly, to the surprise of absolutely everyone, the secret scrolls were all teleported away, and the old demon began laughing maniacally.

“You fools! You fell for my deceit, and I have now managed to get the Secret Scrolls into the hands of the three Tower Demons! They shall now read the incantations to empower the artifacts, and unless you manage to kill them all and reclaim the Secret Scrolls to then read the other incantation and sabotage the artifacts of the Demon Lord, you are all doomed! Muahahahaha!”

Jake barely held himself back from facepalming as he tried to act shocked. He didn’t succeed. “Oh, nooo… what will we do now?”

“You can do nothing but defeat the Tower Demons and reverse the process! Just because you can recover the scrolls and read the incantation to sabotage the artifacts and reverse any empowering doesn’t mean you will be able to accomplish it! Of course, you can also face the Demon Lord in his strongest state possible in an impossible battle that you would only ever be able to overcome if you were true talents sitting at the peak of the multiverse! And it isn’t like you have any methods to escape the castle and return to where you came and then reenter to go for the Tower Demons the second time around, should you choose to face the Demon Lord at full power!”

“We were truly bamboozled,” Jake kept muttering.

“Of course you were! The designs of the glorious Demon Lord are beyond your comprehension! Now that I have accomplished my goal, the Demon Lord will take over the entire multiverse, and unless you manage to somehow kill the Demon Lord in his empowered state or go and slay the three Tower Demons to recover the Secret Scro—”

“May I kill him already?” the Fallen King practically begged.

“Sure.”

“Go ahead.”

“Please do.”

“Ree.”

In the next instant, a blast of force blew off the head of the old demon, whose corpse then fell over backwards. At barely C-grade, he’d been so weak it wasn’t even worth mentioning. They stared at the corpse for a while before Jake sighed and said, “So…”

“We proceed as planned,” the Fallen King said. “Let us face this Demon Lord with all of his power and ignore these Tower Demons. Perhaps we can hunt them down for the bonus objective after slaying the Demon Lord for a higher overall reward.”

Jake shrugged. “Eh, I don’t think that will be necessary. Video game logic dictates they will join the Demon Lord fight anyway, so we should get the bonus objective done no matter what.”

“What do you mean?” the Sword Saint questioned.

Jake chuckled. “Come on. Three mini-bosses, each guarding a method to empower the final boss? What do you think will happen when you ignore them and allow them to fully empower the boss? Of course they will join in on the fight in a second phase of sorts.”

“Hm, do you believe it wise to make assumptions based on Earth’s video game industry?” the old man asked.

“One hundred percent,” Jake said, fully serious.

“Very well,” the Sword Saint said with a nod.

“Alright, final planning time. The general layout of the room is…”

Jake proceeded to explain what he had seen and what they could expect. They already had assumptions, but based on the size of the Demon Lord’s arena, they would adapt. Luckily for them, the throne room was utterly massive. It was a giant hall more than ten kilometers across, with four pillars around a hundred meters in diameter surrounding a large throne in the middle. Right above the throne, suspended by meter-thick chains extending from the four pillars, hung a red crystal pulsing with energy. It was shaped like a heart—the anatomic kind—and Jake had a good feeling that it was one of the artifacts mentioned: the Demon Lord’s Heart.

On the throne beneath it, naturally, sat the Demon Lord.

After their strategizing, the group got ready. Standing in front of the large gate, Dina summoned her staff and spoke an incantation, and they were all surrounded by a green aura. Sylphie also followed suit, and a green gust of wind blew through them, making Jake feel slightly lighter once Sylphie told them the wind was now on their side.

“Let’s go.” Jake smiled as he raised his foot and kicked the giant gate leading into the throne room. It slammed open to reveal the Demon Lord in the distance sitting on his throne in boredom, resting his head on his knuckles.

“At last, you arrive,” the Demon Lord spoke, not bothering to get up.

The arm they had severed was fully regrown, and the Demon Lord was clearly in peak condition. Rather than only wearing a loincloth, he now had a full set of black plate armor covering his entire body, with pulsing, lava-like lines running through it. The only exposed red skin was on his hands and head, as, rather than a helm, he wore a crown that looked to be made of black metallic thorns.

“For too long, I was sealed. Trapped with only my own thoughts within a space of nothingness. It put many things into perspective, and I realized that I had been too lenient on those beneath me. Why had they never come to free me? Why had the pathetic woman who dared call herself my Prime Consort merely sat back and waited? Well, I guess I cannot complain too much. She did manage to breathe new life into some old keepsakes,” the Demon Lord said. As he spoke, the heart-shaped crystal, sword leaning against the throne, armor, and crown momentarily flashed with energy, indicating their empowered state.

The Fallen King had already begun floating to the right while Jake moved to the left. The Sword Saint walked forward with Dina behind him, and Sylphie prepared to take to the air.

“It took you fools to free me…” The Demon Lord sighed as he stood up from his throne. “I guess I should thank you. So let me give due compensation. Not just for freeing me, but to pay you five back for our last encounter.” He reached out and grasped his sword, not even looking at what Jake and the others were doing as he recited his monologue. “Rejoice. My gift to you all is that you will be remembered. Remembered as the heroes who valiantly dared to meet me in combat. Now, let it be known!”

The entire throne room seemed to shake as the Demon Lord’s Heart—the giant crystal—began to glow intensely and release a red sheen that nearly set the air ablaze.

“You face Demon Lord Gubrothas. Prove your worth.”

He had barely managed to say this when two explosions sounded out. From one direction, a blast of pink-purple energy soared through the air, surrounding a fully charged Arcane Powershot with an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. From the other came a golden beam released by the Fallen King, tearing up the ground as it passed.

The Demon Lord seemed surprised but still reacted far faster than in their last fight. He chose to block the golden beam with his sword, and against the Powershot, he raised a hand and summoned a flaming sigil. Neither attempt succeeded.

Two large explosions erupted as the attacks arrived at the same time, bathing the Demon Lord in the destructive energies of Jake’s arcane affinity and the powerful force magic of the Fallen King. With a roar, the Demon Lord released a massive shockwave of fire from his body, revealing a body now filled with marks and burns. The hand he’d used to block Jake’s blow had been thoroughly torn up, revealing bone. Just as he looked ready to speak again, the real attack arrived.

There was no sound as a green line cut through the throne room. The Demon Lord stood with both hands out to his side, prepared to respond, when a green wing cut halfway through his neck, leaving the head still affixed only because he managed to lean slightly as it arrived…

Only for an old man to teleport right up to him and swing his blade at the uncut side of the Demon Lord’s neck. The demon’s eyes opened wide as the Rainblade prepared to decapitate him, his own attempt to dodge Sylphie making him lean into the Sword Saint’s strike. At the very last moment, he roared and loosed another blast of flame, but a dense green barrier covered the Sword Saint’s body as Dina stood with her staff raised right behind him.

The demon’s attempt had failed. The attack landed, and the large head of the Demon Lord was sent flying in a spray of rain and blood.

As it flew a few meters into the air, the Sword Saint was forced to block against the Demon Lord’s headless body swinging its weapon. The blast of fire hit the old man, but Dina’s barrier still managed to block it, only forcing him to retreat ten meters.

A tentacle of pure red energy shot up from the severed neck of the Demon Lord and dragged the head back in place, the Demon Lord’s Heart thrumming with energy above and dimming slightly.

The Demon Lord’s unfocused eyes refocused as his head reattached, and the rest of his body also rapidly healed.

“Crystal above is feeding him energy,” Jake told the others via the mark.

“You…” the Demon Lord said in an angry tone.

Jake, readying another arrow, smiled. On the one hand, it would have been funny to instantly kill the big boss with their opening strike, but on the other…

He did want to see what the big evil Demon Lord Gubrothas could do.

At the very least, they had taught the fucker to stop monologuing like an idiot and pay attention to his opponents charging up attacks.

Chapter 26

A Broken-Hearted Demon Lord

It was a good attempt, but ultimately they failed to finish the fight immediately. They had hoped to at least leave a debilitating injury even if they failed the kill, but even that had failed. Not that they had completely wasted their time.

Even if the Demon Lord was still standing, reattaching a head and healing his body was not energetically cheap. The crystal above had lost noteworthy power from their opening attack, and that was honestly good enough, as it had given them some good info.

From their brief exchange, it was also clear the Demon Lord was stronger and faster than during their last encounter. He was now fully recovered—not to mention his new armor, which their opening attack had not managed to damage in any meaningful way. They had gone for the neck with the expectation that the armor would not be easily overcome.

However, even if the boss had grown… Jake was fully confident they could handle anything he could throw at them.

One had to remember that they had also grown a few levels since the last fight, primarily due to the thirty-third floor and the gauntlet of demons.

Anyway. If the first strike fails, try and try again.

Golden shockwaves rumbled from one side of the large throne room as the Fallen King let loose, releasing a barrage of interlaced blows. The Demon Lord scoffed and took a wide swing using both hands, releasing a crescent inferno to burn away the Unique Lifeform’s attack… but also leaving him open from behind. An arrow struck the demon right in his midsection, exploding upon the armor and slightly throwing off his balance.

Sylphie descended from above in a whirlwind, cutting away at him like a meat grinder. Annoyed, the Demon Lord stomped to make fire erupt from the ground all around him, but the wind refused to let up.

Right as the flames from the stomp subsided, an old man dove through the hurricane, the wind passing harmlessly over his body. He aimed for the leg of the boss, who tried to kick him in response, but the foot was thoroughly stuck as a semi-burnt vine slithered up from the broken floor and held him down.

The sword struck true, cutting across the armor and leaving a thin slit yet failing to fully penetrate.

“Armor slightly above the predicted level of durability,” the Sword Saint communicated through the Golden Mark.

Retreating, the old man got out of range from the follow-up strike from the demon, and they both left the green whirlwind’s radius. Sylphie materialized with the boss out of her attack, not wanting to waste more energy than necessary to keep herself safe.

As the Sword Saint prepared to attack again, the Fallen King flew closer to join him. Sylphie also prepared to dive down from above as Jake aimed elsewhere. Rather than target the Demon Lord, he went for the giant floating crystal above the boss’s head, wings springing from his back as he approached it.

While the four others kept the Demon Lord busy, Jake would address the giant artifact. This was one of the strategies they had discussed already, and Jake quickly closed in on the Demon Lord’s Heart. The heat it gave off was intense, but Jake coated himself in scales and managed to get right up to it. As expected, a barrier sprang up the moment he did, but Jake had come prepared.

Summoning his Blackpoint Blade, he stabbed forward. The special void-attuned blade impacted the barrier and, with a solid push, pierced through, allowing Jake to embed his arm. As it entered the barrier, he had to grit his teeth from the sheer heat sealed within. The scales began to slowly turn red, and his flesh burned, but he managed to dismiss his katar and, with his arm pushed in all the way to his shoulder, lay his hands on the actual Heart.

His hand began turning red, but luckily his legendary gloves empowered with Scales allowed him to hold on as he activated Touch of the Malefic Viper. He deployed the tried and tested strategy of just corrupting the living hell out of any energy source a boss used. It had worked against the Great White Stag, and he believed it would work here.

Below, the Demon Lord was pressed by the four people attacking, but he instantly noticed when Jake used Touch, confirming that corrupting the Heart was a good idea. The demon’s head whipped up, allowing the Sword Saint to hit him, but he only roared as he jumped.

Or at least, he tried to.

He had barely left the ground when a blast of force sent him flying off-course, missing Jake. Mid-air, the demon still released a wave of flames towards Jake, but a wall of roots speared up from the ground, blocking the fire completely.

Before the boss could even land, a green gust swept him up and sent him flying down toward the far end of the room. The King followed up, with the Sword Saint also joining in. Crescent water blades, green wind blasts, and waves of force kept the demon at bay as Dina assured nothing the Demon Lord tried would reach Jake.

A heavy thumping noise came from the Demon Lord’s Heart as it resisted Jake’s infusion of energy, and then he felt himself connect to it and the vast amounts of fire-affinity energy sealed within. As the Prime Consort had said, the energy had accumulated for a long time. Even if the Demon Lord had absorbed some of it to heal himself—both to recover after being sealed and to deal with the wounds their party had just given him—there was still so much left.

The heat intensified as the Heart tried to fight him off, but it was a losing battle. Touch of the Malefic Viper slowly took hold. Wisps of dark green energy slithered into the artifact, and small veins of the same color began pulsing around Jake’s hand, marring the Heart’s surface.

In the distance, the Demon Lord tried what it could, but the Fallen King, Sylphie, and Sword Saint were going all-out, having even partially activated their boosting skills to ensure the Demon Lord couldn't do anything. They had not fully activated their boosting skills yet, but they were running. Due to the Demon Lord focusing more on trying to get to Jake, they managed to land several worthwhile blows, but the Heart was still able to deliver energy despite Jake corrupting it.

Jake also knew he couldn’t stop, or the corruption would be burned away, purified by the flames. The energy the Demon Lord received was already purified, as only parts of the Heart had been corrupted so far. Given enough time, the corruption would reach a threshold where it could spread on its own, and when that happened, nothing the Demon Lord could do would be able to reverse the process. Even now, Jake could feel the connection between the Demon Lord and Heart waver. Yeah, Jake would only need a good minute mo—

“You wish to destroy the Heart!?” the Demon Lord roared as he released a large blast of fire, making everyone retreat for a moment. “Then I shall grant you your wish. I no longer need it.”

The demon raised its hand in the direction of the Heart and grasped. Jake’s danger sense went into overdrive, so he tore his arm away from the Demon Lord’s Heart and pushed off the barrier to launch himself backward right as it shattered.

For a moment, the entire world turned red. Jake was the first to get hit by the inferno as he crossed his arms in front of him and conjured a stable arcane barrier. It melted nearly instantly, and Jake was prepared to take the hit, only to suddenly feel as if a light breeze had hit him from behind. A green glow surrounded him, followed by an odd orange sigil flashing from his body. As it did, he instantly felt the effects of the fire lessen significantly.

“Used Greater Firebane Talisman,” Dina spoke through the link. Yep, Jake had definitely forgotten they even had that reward from the thirty-first floor, but an hour of increased fire resistance was more than welcome.

Jake refocused and adjusted to the changed color palette of the throne room now that everything was burning. Dina stood, giving off an intense aura as she held the flames at bay around Jake, the Sword Saint, and herself, while Sylphie and the Fallen King attacked the Demon Lord again, seemingly not caring much about the fire—the Fallen King, due to his barrier, and Sylphie due to her now active overpowered defensive skill: Green Shield. He was pretty sure that wasn’t the actual name, but that was what she called it.

“One artifact down,” Jake sent encouragingly through the mark.

“The Demon Lord powered up after its destruction,” the Fallen King responded. “Likely due to the more favorable environment.”

This was all in line with the expectations given by the “people” they had met on the prior floors. And while they did not have a direct counter to the overwhelming fire-affinity domain, they did have one way to alleviate it.

The Sword Saint raised his sword towards the sky. What looked like clouds began to condense, unbothered by the flames. Raindrops fell and evaporated long before they reached the ground, but rather than making the entire throne room into one big steam chamber, it was all absorbed back into the cloud, and a new cycle began.

Jake took out his bow and winced as he held it. His right hand and entire arm were burnt to a crisp, flesh and bone showing in places, making it painful and difficult to hold the bow properly. Still, he soldiered through the pain and nocked an arrow to help Sylphie and the Fallen King.

Unblemished Arrows also worked wonders, allowing his arrow to resist being destroyed by the environment, and the pain in his arm proved short-lived. Dina pointed her staff at Jake and fired a green bolt of lightning, and new flesh instantly began growing from the impact site, his arm regenerating in real-time from the infusion of life energy.

His stable arrows landed on target when the Demon Lord failed to dodge, too preoccupied with the Fallen King, and pierced the demon’s cheek. He winced and unleashed his anger on the Fallen King, swinging faster than before and launching the Unique Lifeform backwards.

Now only Sylphie was in melee with the Demon Lord. The Sword Saint had to focus on keeping the cycle of rainfall going, and if Dina stopped protecting them from the exploded Heart, they would all be in trouble. While the rain didn’t look to do much at first glance, Jake felt the environmental fire mana rapidly weakening in intensity, the temperature dropping. The Heart had finite energy, and even if the Demon Lord had unleashed it all at once, it would still run out of power if they kept this up.

The Demon Lord knew this and switched his target to the Sword Saint. With the Fallen King out of the way, Sylphie didn’t stand a chance at stopping the large boss. With a wide swing, a massive wave of fire rushed toward the Sword Saint. Dina conjured a green barrier, but it failed to block, and in the end, the Sword Saint had to jump back while releasing his own Rainblade slash into the flames to avoid getting injured.

The raincloud instantly began to shrink, forcing the Sword Saint to raise his katana again to try and keep it going. Jake triggered One Step to cross the hall quickly, but the range was severely limited due to the fire domain, so he wasn’t able to assist as the Demon Lord closed in on the old man.

In the end, the Sword Saint had to abandon what he was doing when the Demon Lord jumped and smashed his sword down toward the old man. Shifting his stance, the Sword Saint met the edge of the massive, burning sword with his own and somehow managed to slightly divert its path, causing it to slam down beside him instead of right on top of him.

The blast from the impact still sent the old man reeling back, his robe burning and raincloud soon dispersing. Then the Demon Lord gave chase. The Sword Saint managed to dodge and parry a few blows by diverting their paths, but the difference in sheer power was too great.

The Sword Saint was sent airborne by an upwards slash, and a follow-up slash sent him tumbling, flying through the air with the upper portion of his robe burned off, seared flesh showing beneath. Luckily, Jake managed to get close before the Demon Lord could launch further attacks.

Jake released a Descending Dark Arcane Fang as he stabbed, but the demon shifted his stance and caused the katar to strike armor, which it just skirted across to leave a shallow cut. With a grin, the boss attempted to grab Jake, but he vaulted over the hand and stabbed it with his other weapon.

Annoyed, the Demon Lord focused on Jake, buying time for Dina to assist the Sword Saint, and for Sylphie and the Fallen King to stabilize. Sylphie had flown far up in the air and begun the backup plan they’d formulated to employ in case the Sword Saint couldn’t resist the heat.

A large whirlwind appeared towards the ceiling as a hurricane was born. The heat was rapidly dragged in, lessening the pressure on everyone and ever so slightly weakening the Demon Lord himself. Jake stayed close to the boss as the Fallen King summoned two golden hammers, which he promptly slammed into the side of the Demon Lord.

Cutting attacks seemed to have little effect due to the armor… but blunt force still did a good job. The boss slid across the floor from the impact, tearing up half-melted stone tiles in his path as a slight trickle of blood ran down his lip.

Up above, Sylphie had created a potent whirlwind that sucked in the flames throughout the room, and as the Demon Lord stood up, he stared at the hawk.

“So be it… Have it your way,” the Demon Lord said, standing tall as his aura subtly changed. The crown of metallic thorns—another of the artifacts—began to light up. “You fight valiantly… but you seem to have forgotten… I am a Demon Lord, not a mere brute.” As he spoke, he spread his arms to the sides, and three large pentagrams appeared in the throne room, spreading out toward the edges.

In the center of each circle, a demon more than four meters tall appeared. All three had slender bodies and were armored from top to bottom, not showing a single inch of flesh anywhere. Each also wielded a shield and a staff with a burning brazier at its end. The three of them did not have any legs, simply floating just off the ground.

Jake threw one of the three a glance, already knowing what he was looking at.

[Tower Demon – lvl 260]

Each summoning circle flashed again as the Tower Demons raised their staves, and four more demons appeared around them.

[Tower Guardian – lvl 250]

Each of these also gave off potent auras. They wore various pieces of equipment, making it clear that these three Tower Demons had essentially appeared with full parties.

Suddenly, the fight had turned from Jake and company winning by teaming up to being thoroughly outnumbered. Moreover… the Demon Lord had broken one of the usual video game rules:

He didn’t enter a passive state while the party was dealing with the adds.

Fortunately, they had somewhat planned for this.

“Now, the time of your doom approaches,” the Demon Lord said as he lifted his sword toward the sky. He prepared to swing down and release a blast toward the Sword Saint and Dina, but Jake appeared before him once more.

“Oh, no, you don’t.” Jake grinned and kicked the arm of the demon, throwing off his aim.

His party spread out, with Dina and the Sword Saint heading for one Tower Demon, the King another, and a green whirlwind the third.

That left Jake standing alone before the Demon Lord, who looked at him and scoffed. “You mean to face me alone, pathetic human?”

Jake grinned as he took a stance and infused his voice with Willpower, activating Pride of the Malefic Viper to mentally attack the boss. “I should ask you the same… You mean to face me alone, pathetic demon?”

For a moment, the Demon Lord just stared, making Jake wonder if his taunt had failed. Then, it was as if the large demon’s eyes were set ablaze as he roared and attacked, his entire body erupting in flames of anger.

Never mind… Taunt successful.

Chapter 27

Big Wind Meet Go Big Bang

In any encounter, dealing with adds—short for additionals, or enemies that one had to fight alongside the boss—was a bit annoying. In most cases, the boss would enter some charge-up phase during the fight with the adds, and Jake had kind of expected this to be the case during their planning. This turned out not to be the case, and Jake had the sneaking suspicion it was due to them allowing the artifacts to be empowered.

Yeah, that seemed like something Minaga would do. If they were sabotaged, the Demon Lord would be unable to summon anything. If they did nothing, the boss would channel the spell or something to summon the Tower Demons, immobilizing himself for a while… And if they empowered him, they would have to face the boss and all his minions at the same time.

Alas, it was not entirely unexpected, so they had planned on taking advantage of one of their party’s unique traits: individual excellence. Each of them could fight exceptionally well on their own, which was why they spread out and each tackled a different Tower Demon. Dina would rotate and assist all three of them, but seeing as the Sword Saint was the most injured, she started out by helping him. If any person managed to kill their Tower Demon, they would then help the others.

It was a good plan, with just one problem: the Demon Lord himself.

If he was also in full fighting condition, it would be a nightmare battling him alongside a Tower Demon, much less a Tower Demon with its four Guardians.

That was where Jake came in.

As shown with the Sword Saint earlier, no one could fight the Demon Lord alone and keep him preoccupied. No one but Jake. If there was one thing he excelled at beyond anyone else there, it was dealing with a foe far more powerful than himself. He didn’t need to win, just buy time, keeping the Demon Lord focused on him while the four others killed the Tower Demons.

That was why he went straight to taunting. While repeatedly proving himself a threat and dealing damage was one way to keep the Demon Lord on his ass, constant insults and attempted “attacks” using Pride also did wonders. In fact, maybe it worked a bit too well.

“HOW DARE YOU!?” the Demon Lord roared as he slammed his sword into the ground, exploding the area around him.

Jake had already stepped down and teleported out of range, but the demon was relentless. “How dare you ask if I dare!?” he yelled in response.

Several swift swings aimed to decapitate Jake, yet he dodged in between them, never allowing himself to be caught in any combo. His boosting skill was already active at the offensive 50%, as that also increased Agility, the most important stat at present.

“You!” The boss groaned as several magic circles appeared around him, the crown glowing and manifesting its magic. The casting had only taken a brief moment, and several flamethrowers fired in Jake’s direction in concert with the demon’s charge. “Yes, you!”

Jake met the boss in his charge. A quick barrier of stable arcane mana was enough to slightly divert some flames, opening a path for Jake to dodge. As he slid under the legs of his opponent, he managed to wrap them in a string of arcane mana that he swiftly pulled on.

The demon was only slightly yanked before cutting the mana rope, but the action alone clearly annoyed him. Seemingly keeping his cool—as much as a Demon Lord on fire could, anyway—he shifted his stance slightly.

“For your insolence… death.”

Jake’s danger sense reacted, and he barely managed to avoid the stab heading straight for him. Still mid-dodge, the angle of the blade shifted, the direction changing in an attempt to bisect him. Using his katars, he managed to block and redirect the momentum to launch himself back. Yet just when he thought he was safe, the boss pointed a finger in his direction.

Crossing his katars in front of his chest, Jake blocked the demon’s incoming strike: a small red beam. It had no physical impact as it hit his katars, but Jake instantly felt both weapons heat up to a ridiculous degree, burning his palms even through the gloves.

Focusing, he allowed Eternal Hunger to react. It was momentarily bathed in a shadowy aura, instantly consuming the heat—and just in time, too, as he dodged another beam, followed by a wide swing from the Demon Lord.

Not as easy as I thought, but…

“I am still waiting over here,” Jake said as he bent his back to dodge, looking like he was going for the world record in limbo. “When is that death coming?”

He didn’t get a response, but the boss kept up his rapid attacks. They were a lot faster than before, no longer going for massive damage but simply catching Jake. The demon was waiting for him to make a mistake, hoping to take him by surprise with an otherwise unseen move.

Sadly for the dear demon, it had chosen the worst opponent imaginable. Granted, the Demon Lord was a lot more powerful than Jake, and in a one-versus-one, he would’ve had to fight far differently and take significant risks, but if all he had to do was buy time, this was easy enough. If things did get a bit too hairy, he still had Eternal Shadow, too.

No, for now, he was just happy with building up Hunting Momentum. His one annoyance was that none of the poison he had infused into the Demon Lord had managed to stick. The internal fire energy had simply burned it away too quickly.

As the fight went on, Jake even began to land a few minor counterattacks. Not with the intent to do damage, of course, but to keep the Demon Lord mad at him. The taunts also did wonders.

“I think my death is late? Still can’t find it. I guess the deliverer is just incompetent…”

The angry demon roared in response, and Jake just grinned. He didn’t have time to look at what was happening elsewhere in the throne room, but he believed that his party members were doing their jobs just fine.

Sylphie didn’t like Horny Red Guy, and she definitely didn’t like Horny Red Guy’s house. Sylphie was smart, so she, of course, knew that no one needed their house to be that hot. She also knew how rude it was to make it super hot when inviting friends. Even if Sylphie & Friends were not really guests, she still thought it was super rude to anyone who just came to visit.

At least she had managed to help make the house less hot, even if it had made Horny Red Guy super mad. But that was okay, because Horny Red Guy was one of the baddies, and making baddies mad was good.

She’d been a tad worried about Uncle when he wanted to touch the big red glowy thing, especially when it began burning him, but she had to follow the plan. Sylphie was the best at following plans, after all. Plans were good; Slashy Saint had said that many times. Slashy Saint was also pretty smart—not as smart as Sylphie, but probably a little smarter than Uncle. Uncle wasn’t very smart, after all.

He hadn’t even used his Smelly Pot to defeat the baddies yet.

Then again, saving your secret weapon was kind of smart. Sylphie saved her own, but that was mainly because using her secret move made her very tired, and she didn’t want to nap right now. Not before she was done following the brilliant plan made up by Sylphie & Friends to kill the Tower Guy. Tower Guy wasn’t actually a tower, but Flower Lady also didn’t look like a tree despite smelling of one, so Sylphie knew things weren’t always as they appeared.

Tower Guy was still super tower-like, though, as he didn’t care much about Sylphie’s wind. Sylphie also had to fight the Tower Guy with four other baddies, so she knew she had to be careful. She tried it her way, ensuring the baddies couldn’t go anywhere to help the Horny Red Guy who was fighting Uncle. It also helped make her invisible when the big tornado was there, so it was definitely smart to use.

The Tower Guy was not nice. He used his fire stick to shoot stuff at Sylphie, and all of the other baddies also tried to stop her from flying around. They were not super fast like her, but they were slowly ruining her wind, which was rude. In fact, Sylphie had deduced that all these red guys were rude.

Sylphie tried a bunch of stuff, but the Tower Guy was too tower-like and made all of Sylphie’s attacks not as good as Sylphie would have liked. The other baddies also worked together, and one of them even healed the damage from her attacks, which was even more rude than ruining her wind. She thought really hard, and instead of using her super-secret skill, she decided to keep using one she didn’t like that much because it was super-duper hard to use. But at least the Tower Guy stood still, so maybe it would work. That was one of the good things about towers.

Flying even faster than before, Sylphie began to make herself windier. At the same time, she also summoned another wind that was even more windy than her usual winds. She wanted these winds to be as windy as they possibly could. It got so windy that the baddies decided to try and stop Sylphie, not knowing that was dumb. They were definitely not as smart as Uncle or the other members of Sylphie & Friends, as they all knew that when Sylphie made herself into a super wind while making another super wind, they had to go away.

The wind got faster and faster, tiring Sylphie out a bit, but she had to do it for her kinda-super skill to work. Then the wind—not her own super winds, the big wind that was everywhere—told her that her two winds were windy enough. That was good; that meant Sylphie could do the Big Bang.

Sylphie focused super hard as she flew away from the baddies while also pushing away the other super wind. Then she made herself and the super wind turn around. Sylphie didn’t like the skill because it was so hard to use, but Big Wind Meet Go Big Bang was good. The real name was super boring, though.

[Sylphian Storm Convergence (Legendary)]

The Sword Saint struggled a bit with the pain as he stayed on the defensive, Dina healing him up all the while. It was difficult to accept, but he was the least durable member of their party, and the matchup of fire affinity and his own water was a double-edged sword. While his rain-based attacks were incredibly effective, he was also very susceptible to fire-based attacks, which was how he got into the predicament requiring lots of healing. The Demon Lord was simply too powerful for him to face alone due to the large sweeping attacks and their area of effect.

Fighting the Tower Demon and the four demons alongside it was a reprieve, especially considering Dina’s help. Once he was healed and began to feel better, Miyamoto went on the offensive, whittling down the fire healer in the group of summoned demons. Dina assisted him by restricting two Guardians, allowing him to land several blows before he had to disengage due to the Tower Demon. The demon in question was capable of summoning fire beasts of some sort and releasing constant barrages of fireballs using its brazier staff.

Nevertheless, after he pushed his boosting skill a touch further, they firmly had the upper hand. As the sole group of two, they were meant to quickly finish the Tower Demon, then go and assist the others. Miyamoto was especially worried about Jake, who had to face the Demon Lord on his lonesome.

Using Rainblade on full power, he severed the arm of a demon that turned and pointed his sword at the healer. Droplets appeared in a line as he used his Erosion Stab. Time slightly warped during his lunge, and even through a barrier, he pierced the head of the demon. Before any of the other demons could assist, he pivoted and beheaded the first of the demons. He was about to be struck from behind when vines shot up and pushed away two demons while simultaneously blocking a blast of fire from the Tower Demon.

Just as he prepared to move in and strike another demon, a powerful gust of wind swept through the entire throne room, buffeted and warped by the large pillars.

Miyamoto couldn’t help but throw what was happening a glance. Despite the pillars, he had a clear line of sight. What he saw looked like two giant, swirling waves flying around the demons, the circling winds looking like they were trapped within a larger tornado. One of them gave off the aura of Sylphie herself, and the other was controlled by her, flying opposite—almost mirrored—to her own movements.

Then she changed direction. The entire tornado expanded as these two waves went in opposing directions. Sylphie promptly turned in the air and flew back toward the demons trapped in the middle of it all. The other massive, wave-like gust of wind once more mirrored her movements.

Like two oceans meeting, the winds clashed. For a moment, it felt as if all of the air in the entire chamber had been sucked out, and even the brazier of the Tower Demon before the Sword Saint was momentarily extinguished.

Then, just as the air had all gathered, it exploded outwards in a flash of green lightning that forced all of them to put up defenses. At least, the Sword Saint momentarily thought he had to… until he remembered her words. The lightning actively avoided any of Sylphie’s party members, as they, according to her, were “wind friends,” so her wind wouldn’t hurt them. That apparently also extended to this green lightning.

Sylphie’s attack had given them all momentary pause, and the Sword Saint threw one more glance to see the aftermath. What he saw was a giant crack along the entire back wall, floor, and even ceiling right where the two massive waves of wind had clashed… Two demons, now cut into four pieces, lay alongside the fissure, both sliced from head to groin due to standing right where the clash had taken place.

Even the Tower Demon had lost an arm from failing to move away in time. Miyamoto had barely taken in the sight when the green wind descended on the Tower Demon once more. Despite having just landed a massive blow, she instantly resumed her attack.

Shaking his head, the Sword Saint flashed a smirk.

A bit embarrassing to see myself outdone by such a young one… and I even have help, he thought to himself. Taking a deep breath, he shifted his stance slightly as his boosting skill fully activated. Rain descended from above, defying the fiery environment.

The demon screamed as the Fallen King crushed it against the wall while tearing the legs off another with a Golden Claw. Finally, he had broken the formation of the annoying demons, but before he could finish off his target, the Tower Demon lunged forward, swinging its staff.

Contrary to the others, this Tower Demon happily engaged in melee. Not that the Fallen King found this unfortunate, as he gladly proved his defenses were superior by summoning a golden, rectangular barrier. Then he pushed on it, the golden energy still connected to him.

Annoyingly, it allowed the demon to get some distance, even without its legs. Spreading his aura, the Fallen King faintly put pressure on them all while directly attacking their souls. He felt their relative fragility and gladly took advantage.

Turning his attention back to the demon embedded in the wall, the King showed no mercy. He fired a charged beam towards his stuck opponent, blasting a hole in the wall and blowing the demon’s entire torso to smithereens. Just as he prepared to attack again, the wind swept past.

The Fallen King felt the Sylphian’s power as it proved its dominance over the demons. An acceptable display of power by the party member he had been the most skeptical about, but her rapid growth and power had won him over. Though perhaps it was to be expected. She was a creation of the little hunter, after all. Considering the power of the Cosmic Worm and the True Royal…

How could his firstborn possibly be weak?

Chapter 28

Third Phase

For the most part, Jake ignored all the happenings around him, though the flashing golden lights, giant raincloud, and what sounded like a category-five tornado were somewhat distracting. The Demon Lord also clearly noticed his summoned help was being pressured, yet each time he prepared to go and help a Tower Demon, Jake pulled the big guy’s attention back to him.

“You dare try and run away!?” Jake yelled as the Demon Lord took a single step in the direction of the Sword Saint.

Enraged, the boss attacked, but he still seemed a tad distracted by all the other fights. Jake easily dodged the blow, but the boss only gave a lazy follow-up. He was losing his opponent’s attention.

Perhaps I was a bit too relaxed offensively, Jake surmised.

If that was the case…

Charging forward, Jake took advantage of the Demon Lord’s partial distraction. With full power, he thrust both katars into the chest of the Demon Lord, sending him skirting back from the impact. Although his blow did little, he charged in again as the annoyed boss tried to swipe him away. When the hand approached, Jake grinned and made his move.

He jumped straight up with Eternal Hunger aimed at the Demon Lord’s one eye. At the same time, another version of himself simply took a step forward and placed a hand glowing dark green on the armored chest of the demon. As expected, his opponent went for the version of Jake aiming for its head, the Jake below obscured from vision by his jumping clone.

At the very last moment, the jumping version stabbed toward the hand trying to grab him, and the Demon Lord happily took that trade. Two katars penetrating flesh in exchange for grabbing the annoying human that had pestered and insulted him? Why would he not go for that?

“I got yo—”

The moment the boss closed his hand, Jake turned into black mist. Confused, the Demon Lord tried to figure out what was going on. Only then did he seem to notice the other Jake standing with a hand on his armor.

For a moment, the Demon Lord just stared at Jake, who looked back up at him with a grin.

“Blind as a bat,” Jake said, not even bothering to infuse his voice with Willpower. He didn’t need Pride to make this taunt work.

The demon’s expression warped as he roared, yet Jake jumped back, landed, and teleported even further away. Right as he landed, the Demon Lord charged, swinging his blade widely and forcing Jake to once more go fully on the defensive.

“Actually, that was rude—bats aren’t even blind,” Jake muttered as he dodged a large swing, closing in and briefly touching the same spot as before to activate Touch again.

In an attempt to crush him, the Demon Lord summoned a giant seal of fire above himself and brought it all down, exploding an area nearly fifty meters in diameter. Jake had already teleported away, and the moment the flames subsided, he stepped down once more, teleported into melee, dodged under a punch, and gave the boss yet another poke with Touch.

“Yeah, you are worse than a bat,” Jake continued as he dodged attack after attack. “Wait, do you even know what bats are? Probably not. You don’t strike me as the clever sort.”

“Silence, pathetic vermin!” the Demon Lord roared as he quite literally breathed fire.

“Wow, yeah, that is nearly correct; some do classify bats as vermin. Some also call them flying rats. Or mice. Not sure. Either way, good job. I am proud of you!”

“I said silence!” the boss yelled, slamming his sword into the floor to send tiles and fire flying everywhere.

Jake had already jumped and protected himself with an arcane barrier as he prepared himself for the next blow. Grinning, he said, “Silence? Nah, I don’t think so. Unless you want to start by listening to me first?”

The Demon Lord stabbed toward Jake, but he once more used Eternal Shadow to split himself. His two versions dodged to either side of the wide blade. The demon looked momentarily confused at seeing him split in two and failed to respond when Jake landed his next blow. This one was purely mental in nature.

“Could you…” the real Jake said as he kicked the Demon Lord in the face for no real damage.

“… be nice…” his Eternal Shadow followed up as he kicked the other chin.

Angry, the boss went for the real Jake, yet as he tried to grab him, Jake used the Demon Lord’s own chin as a stepping stone to activate One Step.

“… and stop…” Jake said just as he teleported away.

The Eternal Shadow didn’t have time to finish before the Demon Lord summoned a magic circle and blasted the clone away, leaving only the real Jake. Rather than attack again, Jake just stood there and stared at the Demon Lord, as the boss seemed to be waiting for something. After nearly two full seconds, the boss groaned.

“What did you dare attempt to ask me?”

“Oh, not telling you now that you’ve so rudely interrupted,” Jake said, acting extremely offended. “Calling yourself a Demon Lord and having the manners of a common… Wait, what is the name of a really low-tier demon vermin? Actually, never mind. Let’s just use that.”

“Use what?”

Jake smiled. “Your new name. Rather than calling you Demon Lord… I shall henceforth refer to you as Demon Vermin.”

The Demon Lord—or Demon Vermin—flinched, but the taunting now seemed less effective, as he didn’t attack in a rage anymore. Jake also understood why. On the other side of the room, the final Tower Guardian was about to be torn apart, the Sword Saint and Dina proving themselves the slowest at killing their assigned enemies. With Sylphie and the Fallen King joining, the cleanup would be swift, and the boss knew it.

He knew he would soon face their full party again.

They seemed to have entered a lull, so Jake took the chance to properly catch his breath and allow what minor burns he had suffered to fully heal. He was lucky that his Hunting Momentum gave him some leeway to take minor damage, because completely avoiding everything had been impossible.

The entire party approached from behind Jake. They looked a tad worse for wear but were otherwise still fine. He did see they had all used their boosting skills to some extent, which put them on a timer.

“Everyone is good?” Jake asked through the Golden Mark.

“Acceptable, but mana has been dropping fast,” the King answered.

“Better than ten minutes ago,” the Sword Saint said, now at least healed.

“Fine,” Dina said.

“Ree,” Sylphie explained, making Jake aware that she was also low on resources but otherwise fine.

“The three towers have fallen… My castle is in shambles,” the Demon Lord said, having once more entered his scripted boss-dialogue portion of the encounter. As he turned his gaze towards the party, Jake knew they were about to enter the third phase of this boss fight. “You have ruined everything. As such… I shall ruin you in return.”

“Go!” Jake said, his danger sense warning him. He pulled out his bow, and the four others all attacked instantly. The Demon Lord’s armor began shining and expanding, covering his entire body as he raised his sword high.

“Behold…”

The sword shone bright red, seeming to resonate with the entire hall. The four massive pillars around the throne room then suddenly began to shake as spiderweb cracks appeared all over them, each pulsing with energy.

“Ruination.”

Four pillars exploded, each releasing an inferno upon their destruction. The ceiling began crumbling, and it didn’t take a genius to figure out what was about to happen.

“The fucker is bringing down the entire castle,” Jake cursed.

“No,” Dina said with a resolute voice. “We will end it here.”

Jake felt her determination and grinned. “Then let’s fucking go. No holding back.”

Nobody knew what the next phase of this fight was supposed to be, and they didn’t see any need to. With all of their boosting skills activated at full power, Jake gladly pushed his Arcane Awakening to the maximum 60%. They all powered up significantly, but one more than the others.

Dina’s body erupted with power as her aura rapidly spiked. Bobo, her living armor, grew to cover even more parts of her body and changed shape to resemble a dress filled with glowing green runic script. The small outgrowths on her head rapidly grew into large, wooden antlers. Her vine hair grew in length as more and more flowers bloomed upon it. She even grew a few centimeters as she transformed.

Finally, she lifted her staff and slammed it into the ground. “Nature, heed my call.”

A green fissure spread from the impact, and the entire floor erupted. Thousands of vines speared up from nothingness. The collapsing pillars were suddenly reinforced by an invading network of vines, stitching together the collapsing stone. These vines were teeming with pure life, capable of fighting off the heat.

As fast as the collapse of the castle had begun, Dina had stopped it dead in its tracks. The Demon Lord stared with confusion at the transformed Dina as she pointed her staff at him, his eyes barely visible through the helmet that now covered his head.

A massive trunk erupted from the ground and smashed into the demon, sending him flying. He smashed into the wall at the far end of the hall, and before he had time to extricate himself, the wall behind him exploded with hundreds of thick, emergent vines that wrapped themselves around him and aimed to crush his body.

Fortunately—in Jake’s eyes, at least—the Demon Lord would not fall that easily. An orange glow came from within the mass of vines as a large cut carved out a path. Out of this path walked the Demon Lord, fully covered in his black armor and holding his massive sword. The crown had seemingly merged with the armor, and Jake sensed that the boss was stronger than ever.

Moreover, the fire-affinity mana in the air had rapidly decreased. But it was not gone. Instead, the Demon Lord had absorbed it through his body and into his sword. It appeared that despite collapsing the castle, the boss had still powered up fully.

However, even if he had gotten stronger, their group had also used their own boosting skills. Jake observed the boss’s armor closely as he approached. His suspicions confirmed, he smiled and relayed his plan.

They were on board.

No more holding back now.

“Your pathetic attempt to—”

He didn’t manage to get further before a giant, golden hammer descended from above, smashing him into the ground and forcing him down on his knee. A tornado descended from above right after, increasing the pressure further while Jake released a Powershot aimed straight for the chest of the Demon Lord. The arrow exploded on impact, leaving a mark slightly bigger than usual. That was the last piece of confirmation Jake needed.

The Sword Saint then stormed forward and delivered a dozen of minor slashes all across the armor, leaving small nicks here and there. Overall, their attack had done little damage. The Demon Lord smashed his fist into the ground, momentarily summoning a giant formation all around him as the crown shone bright red.

A fiery explosion erupted, but the combination of a green wind and pure nature-affinity mana heavily weakened the blow, allowing the Fallen King and Sword Saint to attack rather than retreat. Jake coated several arrows with his blood, trying to use a specific type of poison he didn’t have a good version of, and let loose arrow after arrow, aiming at the same spot on the Demon Lord’s armor every time.

Noting that his first attack had failed primarily due to Dina, the boss quickly directed his anger toward her. She seemed ready for his charge, as did the King, which was why they were taken by surprise when the Demon Lord didn’t go after her physically. Instead, he pointed his sword her way and launched it, aiming to pierce her chest.

Dina hastily erected a barrier of roots, and Bobo reacted by forming a shield of green, life-filled wood. The sword pierced both barriers before exploding, sending a burning Dina flying through the air. For a moment, Jake was worried, but the fire was soon extinguished in a green flash, and then Dina’s slightly burned form emerged.

The demon’s thrown sword didn’t remain idle after it exploded. Rather than return, it seemed to take on a life of its own, flying straight toward Jake under the boss’s command. Without his sword, the Demon Lord had lost his most potent offensive measure, but that didn’t mean he wasn’t dangerous. With both fists raised, he began punching, showing the skill of a talented pugilist as he pressured both the Sword Saint and Fallen King.

He also began to use even more fire magic, even if it was clear this was not his forte. Jake kept going with his ranged attacks, yet the Demon Lord ignored him for the most part, as none of his arrows managed to do any worthwhile damage. At least, not in the eyes of the boss.

The improved full-body armor truly made the Demon Lord into a living fortress, limiting the damage of their attacks. The only good thing was that blunt damage still proved effective, making the Fallen King their primary damage dealer as he pummeled the demon over and over again with giant golden hammers. The Sword Saint went for precise cuts around the joints of the armor, but even that proved nearly impossible. Slashing damage simply wasn’t cutting it.

Even the Fallen King had issues getting through, and Jake had to try and get potshots off in between dodging the flying, flaming sword that had an annoying tendency to explode whenever it got close to him. Luckily, Dina rejoined and began to assist Jake and the others, though it proved difficult for her to handle the sword. That was where Sylphie came in. She had difficulty doing much to the Demon Lord, but the flying sword? That, she could handle. She began to throw it around the room with massive gusts of wind, pretty much nullifying it. Even when the Demon Lord wanted to recall it, Sylphie kept it away, primarily by hiding it behind the large pillars.

Even so, as the battle dragged on, their party didn’t do a significant amount of noticeable damage to the Demon Lord. In fact, he seemed to be slowly gaining the upper hand. Their resources were dwindling faster than his health pool, their boosting skills couldn’t be sustained forever, and the Sword Saint even had to drink a health potion after a hit from the boss fucked up his arm.

Not that it was a problem… because they had a strategy. Minutes passed as a status quo was established; the group primarily defended Jake, who just kept shooting his seemingly useless arrows. Sylphie and Dina focused solely on making sure no one was injured further, with Dina nullifying the demon’s magic and Sylphie handling the flying sword.

This dragged on a while longer, but soon enough, Jake got a gut feeling, and his skill also confirmed it. It’s enough now.

It was time to finish this.

Without hesitation, he spoke through the Golden Mark.

“Now.”

Chapter 29

Evil Demon Sword Gubrothas

Instantly, the entire party shifted movements. The Sword Saint retreated back as Sylphie summoned a tornado that completely sealed the movements of the sword. At the same time, roots appeared from below and slithered up the legs of the boss while the Fallen King threw out two chains, catching both his arms. In an instant, the Demon Lord’s movement was completely restricted. They all knew he could break out within a second… but they wouldn’t give him a second.

Jake dismissed his bow and used One Step to appear right in front of the boss, both katars already out. Eternal Hunger stabbed the otherwise impenetrable armor, but the expected did not happen. He felt the surprise of the Demon Lord as the katar managed to penetrate the armor by several centimeters. It was only now that the boss noticed what Jake had been doing. The spot he had used Touch of the Malefic Viper on during their one-versus-one had turned an even darker shade than anywhere else, and his repeated poisoned arrow had only made it worse. Jake had used a type of poison he hadn’t really ever used before:

Corrosive poison.

Ever so slowly, Jake had made that spot of the armor brittle and weak. Weak enough for his weapons to penetrate. For a brief moment, Jake made eye contact with the Demon Lord and flashed a smile, then punched with the other hand wielding the Blackpoint Blade, pouring in all of his Hunting Momentum. The katar shot forward with his full power and shattered a huge section of armor, the blade penetrating all the way to the handle.

Not done yet.

The enchantment of the Blackpoint Blade activated to cause an explosion within the armor, sending blood and metal flying. Jake had just opened a bucket-sized hole in the Demon Lord’s chest and sent cracks running all across the armor. What’s more… Jake was just the armor-breaker.

Pulling his katar out of the demon’s body, Jake ducked just as the old man materialized right behind him with a hand on the handle of his sword, ready to draw. His entire aura changed and exerted pressure upon the half-ruined throne room, its strength so profound it even gave Jake pause and reminded him of the duel they’d had way back in the Treasure Hunt.

And like back then, the old man also began to change. His features softened, his hair grew, and his muscles toned up as his entire body was revitalized. In an instant, the Sword Saint had gone from an old man to someone in his prime, and in that same instant, he drew his blade.

“Glimpse of Spring: Stormcut.”

Jake felt the flash pass over him, and the world itself seemed to freeze for a moment. There was no big explosion, but simply a slash that left wayward raindrops in its wake. The second the swing was over, the Sword Saint rapidly aged, returning to normal.

In the distance, a loud crack sounded. Two of the massive pillars in front of them began to fall apart once more, having been severed by a cut that left only a fine line. Just as Jake heard the crack, he was hit by a shower of blood from the Demon Lord.

Then he watched the top part of the torso slowly slide to one side. With his armor broken and his movements hampered, the Demon Lord had been utterly incapable of defending himself, resulting in him being bisected right above his stomach. Although the armor covering the demon’s arms carried a deep cut, the Transcendent skill had failed to fully slice through, truly showing how utterly ridiculous the armor was.

However, even if the fight seemed over, Jake did not let his guard down. None of them did. Because they still hadn’t gotten any notification.

The shining red flames in the Demon Lord’s eyes had been extinguished, but Jake still felt power radiating from his body.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched using the Golden Mark, and Jake’s eyes opened wide. Luckily for them, they had all spent enough time with her to know what her warning meant. In concert, they retreated from the” corpse” of the Demon Lord.

From afar, the sword of the Demon Lord pierced one of the pillars and shot straight toward him. It slammed down onto the corpse, releasing a massive explosion. Fire bathed the entire room as Dina put up a defensive barrier, with Jake staring through the flames to see what was happening.

He watched the sword stab straight into the armor, which it then melted and absorbed. The metal crown also began to shine brightly as it floated up and merged with the handle. Within less than a second, the armor had been reduced to nothing. The only thing left was the Demon Lord’s body, which swiftly turned to an odd red energy that was promptly dragged into the handle, where a red gem appeared, looking eerily like an eye. Coupled with the already-absorbed energy from the broken Heart of the Demon Lord, every single artifact had now combined.

Moreover, the merged sword now gave off the aura of the Demon Lord. However, it was far weaker, and Jake instantly knew what was about to happen as arcane mana began to gather in his hands.

“I lost… but I shall return… reborn stronger than ever!” the Demon Lord’s voice echoed from the sword as a magic circle appeared around it.

“Not gonna happen,” Jake yelled, his voice infused with the Willpower and Pride of the Malefic Viper as he unleashed the arcane mana to disrupt the teleportation.

He was not the only one, either.

A green wind also swept through the circle from Sylphie, a crescent wave of water was sent out by the Sword Saint, and an odd golden beam was released by the Fallen King, the latter aimed at the sword itself. Dina had been the one who was most prepared; she pointed her staff, and a large, green magical circle seemed to superimpose itself upon the Demon Lord’s.

“NO!” the boss screamed as the teleportation circle was utterly broken. The sword was also slightly destabilized, but it seemed that even if teleportation was not an option, the Demon Lord refused to surrender. Shooting upwards, the sword tried to escape, only for Dina’s control over the castle’s structural integrity to come into play.

While the sword was likely capable of piercing the ceiling given enough time, it couldn’t just strike through. Dina made it even harder by sending forth an army of vines that worked to snatch the merged artifact, and Sylphie easily caught up with her high speed.

With her there, the wind became the enemy of the Demon Lord. A summoned tornado dragged the blade downwards, and when the Fallen King also joined, he summoned more large chains of golden force. As the sword struggled, the Fallen King restricted it with chains using one hand and created a barrier all around it with the other. The Demon Lord within the sword seemed to realize escape was not possible right away, but they all knew the demon was looking for a chance to escape, likely even gathering energy within the blade for an attempt.

Floating down to the ground within the restrained sword, the Demon Lord spoke, “You may be able to keep me trapped for now… but so what? I will return once more. With my soul sealed within the sword, the moment my body has regenerated through my innate power as a Demon Lord, your lives shall be mine, and the final resistance to my rule slaughtered. And there is nothing you can do.”

“Are you so sure about that?” Jake asked while walking forward with Eternal Hunger in his hand.

As he walked, he began to slowly change the shape of the weapon. Altering a mythical weapon mid-combat wasn’t practical due to how long it took and the requisite stabilization period, but with the sealed Demon Lord, that wasn't an issue. He allowed it to turn all smudgy, looking almost like a black ferrofluid that stuck to his arm.

“I do not fear your pathetic threats… Release me, and I shall swear that our next encounter will truly be our last,” the Demon Lord semi-threatened, semi-promised.

“No… No, I don’t think we will.” Jake smiled as he looked at the Fallen King. The Unique Lifeform nodded with recognition.

While the Demon Lord transforming into a sword had not been part of the plan, they had discussed what to do and expect when the Demon Lord “died.” They knew some energy would remain, and they had even anticipated that the demon would try and resurrect again in some way by safekeeping parts of its soul.

Too bad for the Demon Lord, however, because it faced two monsters, one of whom wielded a weapon capable of absorbing all kinds of energies. Eternal Hunger would consume any energy it could, its curse unable to ever be truly sated. Considering it also consumed the souls of those it killed, it was the perfect weapon to truly vanquish a Demon Lord.

When a Demon Lord died, its Truesoul would disperse, leaving behind energy and a shattered soul embedded within that energy. Based on what Dina had said, the unique Demon Lord energy was something no one truly knew how to control or manipulate. All they knew was that given enough time, a new Demon Lord would spawn somewhere in the relative vicinity of where one had died. Sometimes it was as far away as the other side of a planet, and other times it would be right where the original had died. With this knowledge, it was only natural that Demon Lords such as the boss had found some ways to influence their resurrection, and the Demon Lord entering the sword right before he truly died was clearly one such method.

Jake theorized Gubrothas would flee somewhere else before using some special, unique method to reforge his body—a good plan that had only failed to take into account that the party he faced had a Unique Lifeform specialized in soul magic, and a mythical weapon that loved eating souls and energy.

The Fallen King laid his claw on the blade on the sword, and Dina assisted by keeping it sealed in his stead. Golden light erupted as a shockwave of soul magic went through the sword, and the voice of the Demon Lord echoed, “You… You dare try to extinguish my soul!? You will fail, and as your power wanes, I shall escape.”

He was probably right on that one. The Demon Lord was quite hard to fully get rid of. Breaking the sword wasn’t an option, either, as with the demon inside, it was still a bound weapon and a powerful artifact, making Jake’s Alchemical Flame useless since it only worked on passive objects. The Fallen King would lose the battle of attrition, as the Demon Lord could consume energy to fight off the Unique Lifeform that would soon need to stop due to overusing his boosting skill.

That was where Jake came in. Kneeling down, Jake placed his hand on the gem of the sword. Eternal Hunger slowly took shape, almost using the Demon Lord’s sword as a mold. Dark energy began to emanate from the mythical weapon as the metal formed a hand and grasped the Demon Lord gem.

Jake took a deep breath and closed his eyes. This was not something he had tried before… but he knew he could do it. He did not even hear when the Demon Lord taunted him, as he truly connected himself to Eternal Hunger. Resonated with it.

In his mind’s eye, the curse manifested. At first, it was an undefined mass of pure curse energy, but it soon gathered and took shape as his Eternal Shadow manifested. In the real world, his body momentarily gave off curse energy as his figure was superimposed against the Eternal Shadow.

“Go,” he spoke to himself. His other self. The Eternal Shadow shifted slightly before turning into black energy that drilled into the blade through Eternal Hunger.

“I told you tha… WHAT IS—”

In an instant, the entire sword turned black and began to emanate dark smoke as the red light in the gem faded. Cracks formed all over the merged artifact, and all Jake heard was the echoing screams of the Demon Lord within his mind as the sword shattered, broken pieces of metal devoid of energy falling to the ground.

Kill message: *You have slain [Demon Lord – lvl 270] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’ DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 217 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’ DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 218 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’ DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 214 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

With a slight nudge, Eternal Hunger began reverting into a katar as Jake stood up. Everyone looked at him, with the Fallen King especially giving off an incredulous vibe.

“You did not need my assistance,” the Unique Lifeform spoke.

“Thought I would.” Jake smirked, looking at the mythical weapon slowly warping and reforming in his hand.

“That weapon of yours is a disaster waiting to happen,” the Fallen King said. “I felt the pure gluttony emanating from it. An unstoppable desire that can never be satisfied.”

“It’s a Sin weapon, isn’t it?” Dina asked, getting a nod from Jake. “My grandfather spoke of them. They are rare and powerful, but often avoided due to their tendency to negatively influence the wielder. But… I have never heard of one taking on a human shape like that. They also tend to be uncontrollable, so how did you manage to direct it into the Demon Lord’s sword, much less have it take that shape?”

Jake didn’t feel like sharing his entire story about sim-Jake—his other self, who had become one with the weapon—so he just smiled. “Its instinct is to hunt, and I offered a feast.”

Dina frowned. “That does not explain the shape…”

“Let’s just say we have a close connection.”

“It was also too efficient… almost like it had a mind of its own. No, not quite a mind… but close?”

“Let’s leave it at that,” the Sword Saint said as he smiled. He looked at the broken pieces of metal on the ground and patted Jake on the shoulder. “Good job.”

Jake smiled back. “You too.”

He had to admit, things had gone far more smoothly than he could have ever predicted. The original plan had been for the Fallen King and Dina to gather all the energy of the Demon Lord right after he died before it had time to spread. The King would’ve shattered the Demon Lord’s soul, with Jake potentially helping with Gaze. Using Eternal Hunger, Jake would’ve then slowly absorbed all the energy, along with the soul fragments.

What had instead happened was Jake connecting Eternal Hunger to the sword the Demon Lord had sealed himself within. He had pushed in the curse energy through the mythical weapon, which had manifested as his Eternal Shadow. The Eternal Shadow had then effectively entered the “space” the Demon Lord occupied within the sword, slain him, and devoured every single speck of energy in the merged artifact.

All within a second.

Jake knew what set his Sin curse apart from any others. Usually, a Sin curse was just a singular desire. All Eternal Hunger had been about was eating. But Jake’s curse had warped. Sim-Jake had introduced another element: instinct.

Proper instinct. Jake’s own instinct. It was merged with him, after all. This meant that contrary to what the textbooks said about Sin curses, Jake’s version would follow his own will.

In some ways, sealing himself within an item had been the worst thing the Demon Lord could’ve done against Eternal Hunger. It had allowed the curse to face him directly—a curse holding energy far above what a C-grade could possibly face.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked, having flown down and landed on top of Jake’s head.

Jake smiled. “Yeah, I think that is a good idea.”

Looking at the party, they all looked worse for wear. Jake also knew that the instant they released all their boosting skills, they would be tired as fuck. Also, they had something important to do… Celebrate.

And Jake knew just the place once he released a Pulse of Perception and saw that a formerly hidden gateway had been revealed.

“Drinks are on me when we get to the lounge,” he said with another smile.

“I thought they were provided freely?” the Sword Saint asked, looking genuinely confused.

Jake grinned. “Exactly.”

Soon after, they all made their way to the gateway that led to the in-between room. It was time to see their rewards for this floor and relax before heading on to Minaga’s city floor.

Chapter 30

A Healthy Team Dynamic

The thirty-fifth floor had been the first to truly push their party. It had also been the most fun, in Jake’s opinion.

After they all entered the in-between room, the boosting skills were deactivated one by one, and Jake tossed himself into one of the lounge chairs. The others also sat down, with the King even stopping his usual levitation to sit on a large chair. They would all need a good while to fully recover, and they had already agreed to stay in the room until they were all back in peak condition. Even if the next floor was a city floor, this place was just safer.

Jake closed his eyes and relaxed a bit as he waited for the system message to appear. It didn’t take that long before he saw the notifications, but when he saw them, he couldn’t help but frown.

Only two?

How was that possible? Jake instantly checked them and saw that the first one was the expected, basic one.

Thirty-fifth floor completed. 350 Nevermore Points earned.

Some-fucking-how, they had only managed to get a single achievement, and he felt kind of pissed before he even read it.

Achievement earned: Kill the fully empowered Demon Lord Gubrothas along with all three Tower Demons within five hours without any party members dying. 5000 Nevermore Points earned.

Okay, Jake was totally fine with just getting one achievement after reading the one they had gotten. It seemed like the system—or Minaga, or whatever managed these achievements—had just decided to throw them all together into one massive achievement.

5000 Nevermore Points was more than they had earned on any prior floor by a significant margin, and that one achievement had netted their overall points an increase of twenty percent.

“A good windfall,” the Sword Saint said with a smile, having also read the achievement.

“Satisfactory, indeed,” the Fallen King agreed.

“Ree!” Sylphie also screeched gladly. Being the smart bird she was, she knew big numbers were good.

“I wonder how this will affect later floors?” Dina questioned out loud. “Clearly, the Demon Lord was set up to appear on one of the later five floors for one final fight.”

“Good question,” Jake said. “Man, if only there was someone who really loved telling us about the great story he has been spinning up. Someone who has been surprisingly silent for a while now, not offering a single comment during the entire boss fight.”

“Hey, I just didn’t wanna distract you from the big fight with the Demon Lord,” Minaga said as he reappeared. Well, he did not really reappear. Jake knew he had been watching all along as he usually did. “Imagine if a comment of mine made you lose your focus, and it ended in your death? That would be silly, wouldn’t it? Can you imagine the number of complaints I would get if that actually happened? Definitely not worth the hassle.”

“Why do I get the feeling that has happened before?” Jake mused with a smirk.

“No comment. Anyway, thoughts on the big boss fight?”

“Pretty good,” Jake admitted. The Demon Lord had been strong and not as “gimmicky” as Jake had feared. “You needed to be good in many different areas to win, but I have a really hard time seeing barely any parties beating it. The Tower Demons being summoned with full parties is pretty brutal, especially if you have a more classic setup. I guess the healer and tank can handle the boss, but the three damage dealers having to handle a Tower Demon each is a tall order. Not to mention the final phase where the Demon Lord felt nearly invincible with his armor on full power. I can see him outlasting many groups simply due to how damn durable he was. Especially if they don’t have any good methods to address the Demon Lord’s Heart.”

“The end part, too,” Dina chimed in. “Without knowledge of rituals or soul magic, killing the Demon Lord and not allowing him to escape seems impossible. Maybe you could seal him due to his weakened state, but…”

“It wasn’t meant to be easy or even beatable by any parties that could consider themselves in any way average,” Minaga explained. “That is also why you got the escape talismans as rewards for floor thirty-four. You only get those if you unlock the possibility to face the Demon Lord with empowered artifacts, so you get the chance to reset and try again without empowering the artifacts. Something a lot of parties have done, mind you. Overestimating your own abilities is quite a normal thing for young C-grade geniuses, and I do recognize that the difficulty spike was quite severe. Not to mention the difficulty of fully killing the Demon Lord after he merges with the sword. The most common method is a big formation that drains the energy of the artifact over time, but that isn’t very effective or fast. My sample size is also pretty pathetic… but hey, I would say you guys—courtesy of an overpowered mythical weapon—probably set the kill-time record from sword stage to death.”

“So, to summarize, we are just damn awesome?” Jake grinned.

“Duh. Not to toot your horns, but you are a top-of-the-line party. If you were not, there is no way you would have beaten this.”

Jake just smiled as he leaned back a bit further and relaxed.

“How about the impact on later floors?” the Sword Saint asked as he took a seat at the bar and grabbed a bottle. “It sounds like killing the Demon Lord outright is not entirely beyond expectations.”

“If you hadn’t killed the Demon Lord here, who is to say what it would mean for the later floors? What I can say is that it is a requirement to earn the most rewarding achievement available within my labyrinth later on. It will be the most rewarding by quite a margin, too. Let’s just say that the five thousand from the Demon Lord is far from the highest a single achievement can give.”

Jake smiled. “Man, and here I had hoped that it would at least throw you off your game a little.”

“Because you kill a boss that is designed to be killable? No, what throws me off my game is people using Bloodlines or Transcendence skills to screw up everything and ruin all my hard work. Not that I dislike these two by default. The swordsman’s use of his Transcendence skill in the boss fight is how I expect them to be used. What you do is just willfully ruining my labyrinths.” Minaga was clearly still salty about Jake ruining the exploration on prior floors. Yet Jake also felt something else…

He grinned again. “So, you are telling me that the labyrinth will make a return on floor thirty-six, ripe for my exploitation?”

“I did not tell you that, no. And if that is the case, you will find out yourself when you arrive. Even if it is a labyrinth again—which I am totally not saying it will be—that doesn’t mean it is as easily exploited as the ones before.”

“You have said that several times before, and yet we always end up with you complaining about how I broke something of yours again,” Jake shot back.

“Time will tell.”

“Indeed, it will.” Jake nodded with a smile.

“Now… want some nice lore bits as you relax? Facing the Demon Lord didn’t just have to be done by your party, you know… Had you done things differently, you could have brought many helpful allies along…”

“In a bit,” Jake said as he looked at the pedestal with loot.

“Oh, fair, get the rewards first. But… lore time afterward?”

“Sure.” Jake shrugged.

“Great. Enjoy your loot; it should be useful.”

Jake sure hoped it would be. Rather than just have Sylphie fly over and unlock the boxes, they all went together. There was not just one box this time around, but three. Two of them were small, one large. The large one was even bigger than a mini-fridge, and Jake kind of wanted to open it first, but with permission from the others, he started with one of the smaller boxes.

He opened it and instantly felt the odd energy spread throughout the room. They all recognized it as being reminiscent of the Demon Lord’s signature. Which made sense, considering the item that floated up. It was a small, fist-sized version of the large artifact Jake had corrupted, though Jake wasn’t sure it was the same kind of item after using Identify.

[Crystalized Demon Lord Heart (Legendary)] – The crystallized heart of a Demon Lord. The immense energy contained within the crystal can be absorbed by any demon, allowing them insight into the heritage of Demon Lords. Grants demonic powers to any item it is fused with. Can be used in a limited number of alchemical products of a demonic nature.

“No fire affinity mentioned?” Jake questioned. He didn’t feel the slightest tinge of fire energy either.

“Not all Demon Lords have the fire affinity, though it is the most common,” Dina explained. “And to find a Crystalized Heart… I heard that some talented ritualists can transform a Demon Lord into one. They are incredibly valuable artifacts to all demons and warlocks.”

“Let us give it to the Hunter; I am sure we will then see him birth some primeval Demon Lord within a few centuries,” the Fallen King said. Jake was about to protest when the Sword Saint looked at Dina.

“Can Demon Lords be female?”

“Yeah,” Dina said, nodding.

“Then I guess that is a possibility.”

“Ree?”

“No!” Jake protested as he looked at the green bird. “You are not getting a new little sister, I am not taking that damn heart, and I am definitely not going to make some Demon Lord.”

The Sword Saint smiled teasingly at him. “Then who else wants it?”

Nobody said anything. The Fallen King was disinterested, Sylphie said it looked gross, it did not fit Dina’s Path, and the Sword Saint had nothing to use it for. In the end, Jake ended up grumbling as he tentatively took the damn thing.

“If all else fails, you can give it to your succubus mistress; I am sure she will appreciate it,” the Sword Saint tried to comfort him.

“I don’t have any mistresses…” Jake muttered.

“Sure, you don’t.” The old man smiled and chuckled.

“Let’s just open another damn box,” Jake grumbled as he went straight for the larger of the two remaining lockboxes. It was quickly opened, and out came a metal box without a lid. This time, Jake did feel the expected wave of fire-affinity energy. Looking at what was inside, he found a dozen black metal ingots.

[Obsidian Hellfire Ingot (Legendary)] – An Obsidian Hellfire Ingot. This metal is incredibly hot to the touch and has supreme mana conductivity towards any fire-affinity mana. Its innate properties also grant this metal high natural resilience to all types of attacks. Limited alchemical uses.

Jake would classify this as another dud. None of them were blacksmiths, and Jake couldn’t really come up with anything to use these ingots for. Not that it was a bad reward… This was the kind of metal the armor of the Demon Lord had been made with. Potentially the sword, too.

“Anyone want this?” he asked.

There was silence all around for a moment before Dina shyly spoke up. “I… I can maybe use them?”

“Oh?” Jake said, surprised.

“I… have a plant that can maybe absorb them, but not sure,” she said, clearly uncomfortable asking for it. Probably because this was one of the first actually valuable items they had found.

“Take it, then.” Jake shrugged, already knowing the three others didn’t care.

“Alright,” Dina relented, storing away all the ingots.

Jake did know that their way of distributing loot was different from the norm. Dina knew it too, as she had apparently been taught how loot distribution usually worked before going to Nevermore, and was thus surprised that Jake and the others broke those conventions.

It was considered pretty standard that crafting materials would be sold if no one needed them badly, or if the materials were so rare they were impossible to get your hands on under normal circumstances. Any profit would then be split. Even if someone got the materials, it was usually expected they would compensate the others, either by paying a fair market price or giving up something else. Their laissez-faire approach to loot distribution, where they just gave it out semi-randomly if someone wanted it regardless of “fairness,” had thus come as a surprise to Dina.

They did still follow some norms, such as giving loot to the people who truly needed it, as that would help everyone clear more floors. Case in point? The reward from the final lockbox.

[Supreme Firebane Ring (Legendary)] – A ring crafted for an incredibly talented knight that was slain by the Demon Lord before he was able to reach his prime. Passively grants the user resistance to all fire-based attacks. This effect can be further amplified by infusing mana into the ring, extending it to affect all their energy. Enchantments: +600 Toughness, +600 Vitality, +500 Willpower. Supreme Firebane.

Requirements: Lvl 230+ in any humanoid race.

A certain old man in their party could surely use this item—something Jake and everyone else knew as he grinned.

“Hey, old man, you should just take this.” Teasingly, Jake added, “You kind of lost your cool during the fight with the Demon Lord, so hopefully, this can help you chill if we meet more fire-affinity opponents.”

“Indeed… much of your offensive prowess seemed to evaporate before the flames of the Demon Lord,” the Fallen King chimed in. Jake felt oddly proud of the Unique Lifeform for his joke.

“In the heat, you just couldn’t cut it,” Jake piled on. “I hoped you would have rained on the Demon Lord’s parade a bit more.”

Dina looked confused for a second before smiling. “Ah! I understand now!” she said before thinking deeply for a moment. Looking full of inspiration, she grinned at the Sword Saint. “They are giving you heat for your performance.”

“Good one, but I think we should lay off flaming him for now.” Jake grinned, damn proud of his party. Only Sylphie didn’t join in, but she had a good reason not to. She was busy trying to open a bottle with some kind of juice at the bar counter, sad there was no snack for her among the lockboxes.

“I do not even fully understand the last one… but I guess I do feel the burn,” the Sword Saint chuckled, taking it in stride. They didn’t even need to argue as he picked up the ring. Sadly, he couldn’t use it yet due to the high level requirement, but he would reach level 230 soon enough.

“What a healthy team dynamic,” Minaga said. “Now that you are all done bullying the old swordsman like you bullied that poor Demon Lord with your constant insults, wanna hear some lore about why the Demon Lord got so offended by these insults?”

“I didn’t bully him; I just deployed a tactic taught to me by a master to keep the attention of the boss on me by speaking constantly.” Jake smiled. “I call it the Minaga Stratagem.”

“That is just hurtful… Anyway, to the lore. Remember that Old Royal Mage? Yeah, he could have helped you during this encounter if you had…”

Jake relaxed as he listened to the Unique Lifeform happily explain a bunch of scenarios, some of them so silly Jake doubted whether they were real—such as one where a party member became the Prime Consort to creep in and land a sneak attack. Knowing Minaga, however, it was probably real.

The others also just recovered in the lounge. Even the Fallen King chose not to leave for one of the rooms, tolerating Minaga. The Sword Saint was busy infusing energy into the self-repair enchantment of his robe that had been burnt, and Dina once more tended to her hidden garden.

Time slowly passed as they awaited their return to prime condition. Soon, it was time to explore the city floor, though they didn’t really plan on doing that much there. They did have some things to check, such as how many solo dungeons there now were, and of course, there was one thing they wanted to know more than anything…

Had they finally claimed that top spot on the Leaderboards?

Chapter 31

Minaga's City Floor

Jake and company had visited many city floors before and knew what to expect. Except, this was not a normal city floor. This one had been made by Minaga, and the Unique Lifeform had already warned them this place would be special. A special floor made by a special guy.

Upon their immediate arrival, Jake did not see what was so different. At first glance, it looked just like a usual city. As long as you ignored the fact that Jake spotted at least a dozen statues of Minaga just from where they’d entered, and that the general architecture reminded him of that mage area he had visited to buy his current bracers.

As usual, the system messages also appeared, inviting them to the floor.

You have arrived on Minaga’s City Floor of Nevermore.

All violence outside of the arenas is strictly prohibited on all city floors, including this unique City Floor. Challenge Dungeon(s) can be found in the central square. If Nevermore is left and reentered, you will automatically be taken to the latest city floor unlocked.

Nothing really seemed off… until he saw the next part.

Due to the nature of Minaga’s City Floor, you cannot proceed to floor thirty-six immediately. In order to proceed, you must pay the toll at the city gates. Minaga’s City Floor uses the currency known as Minaga Coins. Minaga Coins can be earned by selling items through brokers in the many stores spread throughout the city. Normal Credits can be used to pay for other goods through the stores or between non-residents of the floor. Minaga Coins cannot be traded between dungeoneers. All party members must pay their own toll.

The toll to enter the next floor is calculated using the level at which you first entered this floor.

“Hm, this is quite the curveball,” the Sword Saint muttered as he read the description.

“Yeah…” Dina nodded.

“This is definitely something,” Jake said, “but what exactly is the point of this? It wants us to sell items to some stores? And we can only buy stuff using Credits… Is this some kind of money sink created to battle Credit inflation by forcing us to spend money on getting a currency that is useless to us outside of paying some toll?”

“I find the lack of ability to trade these coins a severe oversight,” the Fallen King complained. “What exactly is one meant to sell? I can see the Hunter selling his potions, and perhaps the dryad selling her herbs and such, but why would the Sylphian or I have any goods these brokers are willing to buy?”

Jake was about to propose that someone could maybe just leave Nevermore and bring a bunch of valuable stuff to sell… but then he saw the next message.

Main objective: Pay the toll to move on to the thirty-sixth floor.

Bonus objectives: Do not leave Nevermore before paying the toll.

Current progress: Pay the Toll. Do not leave Nevermore.

Note: This floor has no hidden objectives, achievements, or events.

Current Nevermore Points: 28,473

According to the bonus objective, they were not allowed to leave this place, so even if one wanted to get help from outside, it wouldn’t work. Jake thought for a second before sighing and shaking his head. “Worse comes to worst, I am sure we can scrounge stuff together. I quite frankly have a shitload of valuable stuff hidden away from the ceremony.”

“Hm, I guess that is an option,” the Sword Saint said, nodding.

“Won’t work,” a voice spoke from ahead of them as a figure teleported in from outside of Jake’s Sphere of Perception.

Instantly, Jake was put on guard by the aura of the figure. He used Identify, going for a full scan.

[Human – lvl 349 – Minor Blessing of Alcradia]

He was at the peak of C-grade… nearly B-grade. Jake knew, without a shadow of a doubt, that if it came down to a fight, he would not stand a chance. Luckily, a fight was not even on the table. They were on a city floor, and the guy showed no hostility.

“What do you mean it won’t work?” Jake asked. “And who are you? Sorry, but I do find it a bit suspicious when a random person just teleports right in front of me after listening in on my conversations.”

“Apologies,” the man said as he bowed. “I am but a mere worker from a subsidiary of the Golden Road Emporium, and I serve the merchant god Alcradia. As for why it won’t work… anything that the brokers here buy must be from Nevermore.”

“Huh.” Jake nodded. “And why did you feel the need to teleport over to volunteer this information?”

“My job here is to keep track of individuals of note entering the floor, and I teleported over because I was informed of a change on the central Leaderboards. Seeing as your party had just appeared, I put two and two together.” The man bowed again. “Congratulations on taking the point lead.”

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched.

“I agree with her,” Jake said. “Spoilers aren’t nice. We wanted to go and see that ourselves.”

“I apolo—”

“Rather than apologies, divulge the real reason you are here.” Jake shook his head. “Actually, let me guess. Seeing as everything you can trade for Minaga Coins has to be from Nevermore, you are here to buy some valuable items we have that can be exchanged.”

The merchant smiled. “I will not deny that. The Demon Lord on the highest difficulty offers quite the rewards if a party such as yours beats it.”

“Not interested, but thanks for the info.” Jake shrugged as he motioned for them to keep moving.

“Wait—are you sure you don’t want a guide?” the peak C-grade asked, still acting nice. “There are still some things to learn. If any of you are crafters, you can—”

“I assume everything made on this floor counts as ‘from Nevermore,’ even if the creation uses materials from the outside,” Jake interrupted. “Still not interested, and worse comes to worst, we can just ask Minaga.”

The merchant flashed a small smile as he shook his head. “While that may have been true on prior floors, here, that is not possible. The dungeon master does not appear here or speak, as it is a city floor. He does not have a copy here dedicated to your party, after all. Only in extremely rare cases has he made his appearance.”

“This guy gets it; I am not some guy at your beck and call, appearing whenever you want me to,” Minaga agreed wholeheartedly as he stood with his arms crossed beside the merchant.

“I never expect you to,” Jake said.

The merchant had frozen in place when the blue dungeon master appeared. He slowly turned his head as if to confirm the Unique Lifeform was truly there before he rapidly bowed. “This one greets the—”

“Bye.” Minaga waved his hand, and the guy was teleported away.

“He was just about to reveal your godly title,” Jake said, pointing at where the guy had disappeared.

“Nah, I don’t think he was.”

“He totally was.”

“I don’t see why you would think that.”

“Your attempt at gaslighting will not work,” Jake argued.

“I would never and have never gaslighted anyone, and I find the accusation highly inflammatory,” Minaga said with a sad expression before his mood took a one-eighty. He grinned as he turned to the Sword Saint. “Ah, sorry about the fire-related expression. You have already gotten roasted enough for one day.”

The Sword Saint just raised an eyebrow before sighing.

“Fine—I have been successfully fooled,” Jake relented. “Now, could you tell me why you decided to make this floor the way you did… and got any tips?”

“Alright, alright. You see, I don’t like when people just fly through every single floor—you know, like you do—and that includes the city floors. I wanted this one to at least take some time and give people a good reason to spend longer here than on other city floors. So I introduced the Minaga Coin and the toll, but the coins can also be used for other things. Though, I am not going to lie… none of these things matter to your party. I would advise you five to just quickly gather the toll and get out of here.” Minaga sighed. “I can’t believe I am actually advising you not to engage with my creation…”

“Oh, the horror.” Jake smirked. “How would we go about collecting coins, and was my assessment about crafting goods correct?”

“Yep, spot-on.” Minaga nodded. “Lots of merchants around here who want to buy and sell, too, using normal Credits. Ah, but one warning: Even if I tell you to rush through, you will probably still spend a bit of time here to get enough to pay the toll. While you do have some stuff to sell from prior floors, none of it gives a lot outside of those ingots from the Demon Lord.”

“Huh,” Jake said before thinking. “If crafted stuff can be traded for coins, can’t we just spend a shitload of Credits, buy a lot of crafted stuff from others, and sell that for coins to move on instantly? You know, steamroll the place with wealth?”

“I may or may not have put a cap on how many coins you can earn monthly from non-self-obtained items...” Minaga said with a cheeky smile.

“So…” Jake said, sighing. He had a feeling there really was no easy way around it.

“Yep, you gotta do stuff yourself to get coins! Get that cauldron out and get cooking!” Minaga laughed.

“How about us?” the Fallen King asked, referring to himself and Sylphie. “How are we supposed to earn any coins? We are monsters, not crafters.”

“You can do jobs that are non-combat to earn tokens you can exchange for coins,” Minaga said. “You can also fight in the arena once a day—something I feel you both would enjoy. The arena is time-limited and will repeatedly send new things out to kill to rack up more points for a better token that you can then exchange for coins. No experience points, though. This is a city floor, after all.”

“You are awfully forthcoming with information,” Jake said. Usually, Minaga liked to be all secretive, but here, he just shared stuff willy-nilly.

“Because the impact of what I tell you is negligible. No matter how fast or slow you pass this floor, you get no points for doing it. Only the bonus objective gives any bonus points.” Minaga shrugged. “Me helping you while giving some basic advice will have a minimal effect. Plus, I teleported away the guy who would have said something similar, so in some ways, you can argue I am just setting things right.”

“Wait… this entire floor gives no points?” Jake questioned.

“No, of course not,” Minaga said, waving him off. “It is a city floor.”

“Then… you are legitimately just doing this to waste everyone’s time…” Jake sighed.

“I told you—it is for a better overall experience and to allow you all to socialize a bit.” Minaga grinned. “Now, from your point of view, it may seem like a waste of time, which I can totally respect and promptly not care about as I force you to play my game.”

Jake sighed again. The worst part was that he couldn’t even form any ideas to help him cheese this floor. Minaga seemed to have thought of most routes with the limit on things you could sell that you hadn’t made or obtained yourself.

Minaga smiled. “Anyway, nice to chat with you all. I’m gonna head off and do dungeon master stuff.”

“Not even gonna let your title slip before you leave?” Jake teased.

“Alright, alright… as a final treat.” Minaga sighed. “While I am mainly known by you C-grades for creating floors in Nevermore, I go by another name in the wider universe. One echoed throughout existence, as even the most powerful of gods shudder at the mention of my name.”

He’s gonna make another damn joke, Jake had already concluded.

“In the wider world, I am not simply called Minaga… but the Magnificent Minaga!”

“That was bad, and you should feel bad,” Jake said with a deadpan expression, the rest of his party slowly nodding.

“Killjoy,” the Unique Lifeform said, acting offended for a moment before he flashed a slightly more serious smile. “But I didn’t totally lie. They do shudder at the mention of my name.”

With those words, Minaga teleported away, leaving the party there to take in his words. He probably thought he was dramatic, but Jake just chuckled. “For some reason, gods shuddering when having to potentially deal with Minaga doesn’t surprise me in the slightest.”

“Rude,” a voice echoed in their heads, completely ruining any dramatics he may have had going on.

Jake smiled as he turned to the party. “Let’s go check the Leaderboard and stuff anyway?”

“We should,” the Sword Saint agreed. “Trusting the words of a stranger seems unwise.”

With no one protesting, they went to check out the large Leaderboards in the middle of the city. As they walked, Jake did take notice of one thing different about this floor… Outside of the city floor between floors five and six, this was the most populated one. The average levels of those here were quite high, too, with many above level 300.

These were essentially the “boosters” of people from the new universe. They carried them through floor after floor to help them level up, but also for these high-level individuals to explore the later floors on their own. Having a five-man party was optimal, but with a good level advantage, four-man parties also did just fine. “True” parties like Jake’s were still incredibly rare, based on all Jake had seen.

Reaching the Leaderboards, their group did confirm that the peak C-grade had been telling the truth. They did indeed hold the Point Record.

Average Nevermore Points (Floors 1-35): 7582

Current Nevermore Points Record (Floors 1-35): 28,473

“Sitting at the peak right now does not mean we can relax or slow down,” the Fallen King said. “Only that we have to further strengthen our lead and ensure our victory.”

“Naturally,” the Sword Saint said, nodding.

“We’re just getting started,” Jake agreed with a smile.

After they’d confirmed how great their party was, they went to check out the gate to know how high of a toll they had to pay. There was only one gate leading to the next floor, and in front of it was a toll booth and a barrier. Jake went over and placed his hand on the booth, and a system notification popped up.

You must pay 214,000 Minaga Coins (current Minaga Coins: 0) to proceed to the next floor.

Without any reference points for the difficulty or rate of gaining Minaga Coins, Jake didn’t know how hard it would be. After the others in his party also checked, they concluded the cost was equivalent to your race level times a thousand. That meant Sylphie had to pay the highest toll, which, for some reason, made her happy.

“I guess there’s nothing to do but just get to it and figure out the best way for us all to earn our own toll amount.” Jake shrugged as the group briefly telepathically discussed what to do. They decided to find a home base first—there were plenty of hotels around—and then make a good plan. Even if the city floor was meant to be a relaxing place, they had no intentions of taking any breaks.

While it was good to be at the top, that didn’t mean they could in any way be satisfied. They had made it there before many of the other top parties and had a lot of competition on their heels. Maybe they would even meet some of those competitors on this floor if it turned out to take a while to earn those coins.

Jake had a strong gut feeling it would… especially after he asked a random guy close to the toll booth…

“How long it usually takes? No idea about the average, but I think the current record is about fourteen months? Or was it fifteen?”

Yeah, they were definitely gonna run into other parties… which did make Jake wonder, how were all his friends doing? Both those in and outside of Nevermore.

Chapter 32

The Runemaiden

The level 255 Demon Warden—one of the bosses on the thirty-third floor of Minaga’s Labyrinth on Archmage difficulty—dodged the blast of pure kinetic energy and quickly got his footing as the woman followed up, diving in close.

Several deadly strikes flew out as she relentlessly attacked. The Demon Warden summoned barriers to retaliate, manifesting a spear of crystal he thrust down toward his opponent. Rather than dodge, the woman followed through with her attack, punching the demon in the chest right as she herself was speared in her shoulder.

At least, that was what the Demon Warden had expected to happen.

The crystalline weapon shattered upon impacting the woman, tearing up her leather armor but failing to penetrate her skin, leaving only slight marks. In return, he was punched square in the chest, launching him backward.

With confusion, he attacked again, yet his crystalline magic failed to truly damage his opponent every time, and his attacks as a pugilist failed even more disastrously. It was as if her body was made of metal, resistant to all his physical attacks. The Demon Warden thus switched up his strategy and began to use fire magic.

However, even that proved ineffective. The second the magic hit her, runes lit up on her body, weakening the flames. Growing more and more desperate, the Demon Warden kept trying different things. He knew his comrades were struggling elsewhere in the prison camp, but no matter what he did, nothing worked.

The only good thing for the Demon Warden was the low offensive prowess of the woman, but that didn’t help when he himself failed to do any meaningful damage. In the end, the battle turned into a long slugfest. One the Demon Warden would never win. Soon, four individuals appeared nearby, simply watching the fight.

Ultimately, the Demon Warden fell after what felt like the ten-thousandth hit, his entire body broken from the repeated pummeling and his health points utterly depleted.

“Well fought, Carmen,” the young druid said as he flew over. He was a weird one, because even if he tried to talk like an old man at times, he only looked to be in his twenties.

“Finally learned to use my damn name, huh?” she asked, scoffing. “Also, no… that wasn’t well-fought, but a drawn-out pummeling. Fighting without using big finishers seriously sucks.”

“I truly meant no offense with my comment or by failing to use your name as you have asked of me,” the druid said apologetically. “Customs were simply too ingrained in my being, Runemai—I mean, Carmen.”

“She was taking the piss—at least with the name part… Carmen does suck at actually killing anything,” a large, bare-chested man said as he walked over, his chest not actually visible due to how much blood had drenched him. This was Carmen’s favorite guy in the party. He was a berserker that used two massive swords. A pure brawler. He also wasn’t as uptight as many of the others, and was the leader of their party. Warlord Davion.

Carmen scoffed again. “Well, fuck you too.”

Davion just laughed as he took a seat and looked at the pummeled Demon Warden, then back at Carmen. “That mini-boss couldn’t manage to overcome your defenses either?”

“No,” Carmen said, shaking her head.

“Well, fuck me, indeed. Damn Runemaidens… Then again, I guess you are a special case.”

The last two members of the party were a shaman and a seer, serving as the casters of their group. It had to be mentioned that even if druids were usually casters, their druid sure as hell wasn’t. While he liked to act all refined, his primary mode of combat was turning into a large, scaled tiger with wings that could breathe lightning. So at least he could fight properly.

Overall, she didn’t have that many complaints about her party, and they were generally pretty okay people. Though, had you asked her just a few months before entering Nevermore, she would have said there was no fucking way she would enter with Valhal.

Carmen had been less than satisfied with the faction for a long time. The political bullshit pissed her off to no end, and she had even been told not to associate with pretty much anyone on Earth outside of those who belonged to Valhal. She had not attended the meetings Jake had held with all the other factions, nor had she been able to go to that big ceremony of his. Honestly, she hated belonging to the faction she had chosen. It wasn’t like she could just leave, either. Not without fucking herself over majorly, as the Path she walked required her to remain.

In the end, Carmen had reached a breaking point. The status quo had to change, or she would go crazy, and she only saw two choices: abandon Valhal and her entire Path, or make Valhal tell her what the fuck was going on. With this in mind, she had reached out to Gudrun and laid out her thoughts. After some deliberation, Carmen had been offered a deal.

If she wanted to “be in the know,” she had to prove herself worthy.

From the very beginning, since she’d signed up with Valhal, she had been walking the Path of a Runemaiden. Runemaidens were quite peculiar, their names considered both a title and a Path.

Only in C-grade could one become a true Runemaiden, but even those who walked the Path of one were called a Runemaiden in lower grades out of respect. To walk the Path of a Runemaiden was to willingly risk your life to survive the Runemaiden Ascension Ritual, the process through which the Runemaidens were created. A ritual that would either give birth to a True Runemaiden… or death. Well, and a lot of Bone Metal.

Bone Metal was a special material that wasn’t even metal, which made the name pretty damn dumb, in Carmen’s mind. It was only really used by Valhal, as they were the only ones who knew the method for crafting it. As the name indicated, the “metal” was created from bones. The usual way this special quasi-metal was made was through the bodies of the fallen—a final way of honoring them by turning their very bones into weapons, so they could continue to battle even in the afterlife. These weapons tended to be of high quality, with the dead person’s strength determining the final product.

However… this led to a question. What if the process of creating Bone Metal was applied to someone who still lived? There would be one of two results. Either the person would die, their flesh would melt away, and only the metalized bones would remain… or the bones would successfully be turned into Bone Metal, and the entire body would be reforged. Their skin would become as hard as armor, their muscles and flesh making the body more closely match that of a defense-focused beast than a humanoid.

All it would cost was any and all ability to ever do magic—something Carmen was fine, with because fuck magic.

Carmen had strengthened her body throughout the grades to prepare for this ritual, including the process she’d gone through to strengthen her fists. She had even focused primarily on Toughness and Vitality, especially towards the end of D-grade. It had made her slightly weaker in combat, but it was all to build a foundation. Her D-grade evolution had been the final primer.

In reality, Carmen did not have a high risk of dying if she wanted to become a true Runemaiden. If she was satisfied with just barely becoming one, that is, for not all Runemaidens were born equally.

The materials required to birth a true Runemaiden were numerous and rare, and Valhal remained secretive about what they were, but the most vital ingredient was well known in the multiverse:

Blood.

Blood of a greater being.

The deal Carmen had struck was to successfully become a Runemaiden of one of the gods of Valhal by using their blood in the ritual. Gudrun had advised her about which god they could use… but Carmen already knew who she would pick. Usually, one would avoid the blood of gods during the Ascension Ritual due to the overwhelming Records of the god, but it did happen semi-frequently. Which begged the question… which god’s blood should she ask for?

Well, the answer was pretty obvious.

Carmen knew the kind of people that surrounded her. The old swordsman was an utter monster and a Transcendent. Jake was the Chosen of the Malefic Viper and had a Bloodline. She had even felt Sylphie, the cute bird she had met during the Treasure Hunt, surpass her while they hung out together after splitting from Jake as she grew into her own. If she wanted to have even the slightest chance of keeping up with all of these supreme geniuses, she had to take a risk. Carmen didn’t think she was a supreme genius like the rest… but she was too stubborn to not at least try to keep up.

Hence, she had chosen Valdemar’s blood for the ritual.

Something that was instantly deemed forbidden. The risk of the Runemaiden Ritual was directly proportional to how powerful the blood of the greater being was. That meant getting blood from Valdemar would carry a risk higher than anyone else… so high that the success rate was too low for Valhal to use his blood anymore. It simply wasn’t worth the risk. The last forty thousand rituals using his blood had failed, and that was when they had stopped.

Carmen didn’t care; she’d insisted on using his blood anyway. Ultimately, Gudrun had surrendered to Carmen’s stubbornness and agreed on one condition… Carmen had to make Valdemar himself approve of her and donate his blood.

When Carmen had reached level 199, she had thus been teleported from Earth and left the 93rd Universe, heading straight to the headquarters of Valhal itself. She had appeared in the Grand Hall of Valhal. Stood before the gods of Valhal… and found them less intimidating than she probably should have.

This had amused one of them more than anything… because while she didn’t find most of the gods intimidating, the feeling was vastly different when she met her blood donor in the flesh. This was not an instance of her being teleported by the system or talking to a projection. He was truly there, and for the first time, Carmen felt like she stood before the definition of overwhelming power.

Carmen had only been able to grin, which had also made Valdemar smile. Her knees had buckled, her entire body covered in sweat, but she had managed to stand before him—something he clearly liked.

Their eyes met once before he grinned and spoke, “You’re willing to use my blood and risk everything to gain a small advantage over those just using the blood of another warrior?”

A stupid question, in Carmen’s opinion. “I’m not a bloody coward.”

“You’re reckless in your pursuit to get stronger,” Valdemar said with a smile.

“Weren’t you?” Carmen shot back before even thinking.

Silence took over the room. Nobody said anything—not even Gudrun. Several seconds passed as the strongest human in the multiverse stared down at her. Then Valdemar broke into a belly laugh.

“Lass has the guts; let her do as she wants,” Valdemar said in a cheerful tone as he looked at her. “But you have to take an oath before I allow it.”

Carmen knew there was always more to this kind of thing, and upon fighting through the pressure of the man’s stare, she spoke, “What oath?”

Valdemar smiled even more than before. “That we’ll share a mug of mead after the ritual. So either succeed or die a liar.”

It took her a moment to understand what he meant. She couldn’t help but chuckle. “Better have some good fucking mead ready.”

“Brewed it myself, so it bloody better be,” Valdemar said, laughing in response.

From there, Carmen began her preparations for the ritual. First, she had to “cleanse” her body, which required her to spend over a week in large, medicinal baths while performing certain training motions in between.

After the cleaning, she had to strengthen her body as much as she could. This was not done by increasing her stats or even her innate resistance, but by learning how to better use her innate energy and move it in certain patterns to help her properly understand her own body. This ended up not taking that long—less than three days—as Carmen was already bloody good at it. Once that was done, it was time for the real thing.

The ritual itself was… less than pleasant. A large magical circle was created, and Carmen spent more than fifty hours getting the many runes tattooed all over her body. The process was painful, but it was nothing compared to what happened next.

This was a ritual that changed not only her body, but also her soul. Her entire Soulshape would be reforged, her entire being reborn… and she had to do it all herself. This was not a simple process of holding on and just gritting your teeth through the pain. You had to keep your soul from disintegrating as it was repeatedly shattered, all the while controlling the energy invading your body. Carmen did not think herself some genius of energy control… but she did know her own body. Moreover, she was stubborn. She also had to admit that she once more owed Jake… because one of the primary reasons this ritual was so difficult was having to endure the pressure of the greater being’s Records throughout—something Jake had primed Carmen for.

Carmen knew that when she entered the ritual circle, no one present expected her to step out of it alive… besides maybe Valdemar. They tried to hide their scornful faces, their comments of how Carmen was delusional and overestimating herself, and how she was just courting death due to her own stupidity. Carmen was honestly thankful for these people, as they had made her even more resolved to succeed, just to tell them to go fuck themselves once she was done.

Needless to say, Carmen succeeded even if the ritual itself was an absolute fucking nightmare. She felt like her body was ripped apart over and over again, and she experienced pain worse than she could even imagine. There was a constant feeling of not truly knowing who you were, and everything was compounded by the Records of Valdemar seeking to overcome her own and turn her into a statue. A damn good statue, for sure, but Carmen had no intentions of embracing that fate.

The final part of the ritual was the evolution itself. Rather than the usual evolution window, Carmen was asked at the very end of the ritual if she wished to evolve her race and class—both at the same time due to the peculiar nature of the ritual. She had naturally agreed.

After eleven days of suffering through that absolutely hellish ritual, the first Runemaiden of Valdemar in over half an era—and the only one currently living—was born. Not because the other one had died of age, but because one was no longer called a Runemaiden after ascending to godhood.

And Carmen had no intentions of breaking that streak of one.

Carmen smiled a bit to herself as she remembered the first sight that had met her after the ritual. She remembered opening her eyes and seeing a glass full of mead right in front of her. Valdemar stood off to the side, staring down at her. She especially smiled, remembering her first words to him.

“Why are you creeping on a naked girl?”

And his response…

“You’re a girl no longer, Runemaiden,” he’d said, laughing as he turned away. “But, yeah, you should probably put something on…”

After that, Carmen had gotten drunk on the best damn alcohol she had ever had in her life. The mead had not only been damn tasty, but also helped her body somehow properly adapt to its changes. In the end, she had walked away with both a good taste in her mouth and a Divine Blessing from Valdemar… which was a bit silly, as Carmen felt like she was repeatedly changing titles these days. Although she had a good feeling she would keep this one for a while… it could still change again, based on Valdemar’s parting words.

“Keep that obsession of yours, lass. Who knows? I may call on you when I need a new Chosen, if you are interested, but you aren’t quite ready yet. Prove my blood wasn’t wasted on you, aight?”

Still smiling, Carmen stopped reminiscing about the past and returned to the present, standing there on the thirty-third floor of Nevermore. She felt good knowing she was not there just because of pity or because Valhal wanted to keep her happy due to Jake; she now also knew that things were indeed complicated with all of that Yip of Yore shit.

No, she was there because she was one of the strongest C-grades of her generation, and she would gladly punch anyone who told her otherwise in the face.

Chapter 33

Light, Death, Void

“Tyranny has run rampant for too long,” Jacob said, his voice echoing throughout the large room, the many cultists and demons wary but listening. “For how long will you live in fear? For how long will you live under a system of oppression, where you are treated like nothing but objects by a creature that cares not for any of you? Are you willing to face us, risking your lives for someone who hides away within his castle, unwilling to help you? Will you die for someone that would not even shed a drop of blood for you?

“I am not asking any of you to lay down your lives for me… All I ask of you is to not take up arms. Allow our passage, and help us only with your prayers and well wishes. We have come to carry out justice, and you are not yet guilty of anything but being oppressed. Stand behind us, and I swear that the Demon Lord will face righteous judgment and an end to his tyrannical reign.”

Jacob stood atop a floating, golden platform summoned by the light mage in his party. Bertrand stood beside him, ready to react should anyone make a move. To his other side, the Knight of Light’s Dawn stood with a smile on his face, as did the Old Royal Mage. In fact, they had an entire group from the ambiguous “kingdom” these semi-sapient creatures called their homeland.

“He speaks the truth,” one of the people with them said—a woman wearing a cultist robe, formerly known as the Prime Summoner. “I, too, was fooled, and now I can only try to pay recompense for once more releasing the evil Demon Lord Gubrothas. These heroes have given me a chance to, and I implore you all to join hands with us to create a better future.”

Jacob amplified her words using his own skills as he saw doubt marring the faces of all those below. A few Mistresses had even appeared, though the Prime Consort was yet to be seen. Not that he was worried… He could feel from the crowd the situation was under control. If not, they still had the option to fight—a scenario in which they would always win.

Minaga’s Labyrinth, as this part of Nevermore was called, had truly been a mixed experience for Jacob. On the one hand, it had allowed him to make use of his skills as an Augur to negotiate and create allies, but on the other, it had completely screwed over his abilities as an Augur when it came to navigating the labyrinth itself.

On all of the prior floors, Jacob had easily divined the best way to proceed. This had allowed them to fly through the floors at a record pace, and their party had racked up more points than expected, even setting a new point Record as they passed the city floor between twenty and twenty-one.

Once they had arrived in the labyrinth, finished being briefed, and picked the Archmage difficulty, he’d begun his divination once more. Minaga had looked at Jacob funny during the entire briefing, and Jacob did feel like something was slightly wrong as he divined which way they should go. He had still chosen to believe it… A big mistake, in retrospect.

Rather than lead him to the rooms with keys, all his divination had done was lead them straight into traps over and over again until, finally, they’d reached a dead end that featured a giant mural of Minaga laughing. The Unique Lifeform had naturally added an audio track to the mural himself.

From there, High Justiciar Elevian—the co-leader of their party alongside Jacob—had decided that perhaps they should shelve the divination for now. This had proved effective, as they’d stopped relying on purely magical means and shifted to some far more manual ones. Scouts had been sent out, light magic had been shot in different directions to measure distances, and when they’d found their first group of natives from the labyrinth, they’d made use of them. They’d been pretty easy to convince, and Jacob had quickly realized they were almost pre-programmed to want to assist him, making his job far easier than he would have expected.

It was certainly easier than what he had been doing before entering Nevermore.

Jacob had never truly left Earth before the invasion of Ell’Hakan, apart from being teleported away for events or short training stints. However, as he left this time, he’d been tasked with a simple job… Go out into the multiverse and see it for yourself. The A-grade Grand Master had been assigned as his protector during this time, but Jacob was still allowed to go where he wished… so he’d followed his Path as an Augur and sought out those he could help.

He'd visited planets untouched by any factions. Places where D-grades were viewed as demi-gods that could dominate entire kingdoms. Worlds so bereft of Records that a C-grade ever appearing was impossible unless a miracle occurred, such as a random Bloodline being born or the rise of an individual with talent allowing the person to elevate themselves above their fates.

There were worlds where the humanoid races were barely surviving as beasts dominated. Worlds where war raged, with incompetent leaders willing to kill anyone with talent out of fear that they would be surpassed.

Jacob had many doubts about the Holy Church, and a brief stint of exploration wouldn’t change that. However… he had long suspected it, but now he knew for sure that the multiverse was far from a kind place to the weak. The lost would falter in the dark endlessly if they did not have any guidance such as the Records of greater factions lifting them up.

A high tide raises all ships, and the Holy Church was the greatest tide of them all. Yet Jacob was determined not to allow himself to be swept up in it. He would be a lighthouse on solid ground, guiding the ships that would find themselves lost. And, at least for now, he would guide them towards the Church.

Because even if the Holy Church was not the best… for the weak, was there truly a better choice?

“I swear on the Blightfather, my skill said it was this way!” Maltrax, the beastkin undead, said as she manipulated some odd ash before sniffing it. “It is as if it isn’t working as intended, but… no, I can do this!”

“Told ya we were walking in circles.” Casper shrugged, unbothered.

“I… It may be that way? Yeah, it definitely is that way!” Maltrax insisted.

Casper sighed. “If by ‘it,’ you mean more traps, then yes, it is that way.”

They had been on the thirty-first floor of Nevermore for nearly twelve hours already, and had spent all that time getting fucking nowhere. At first, they had used the ghost summoned by the banshee in their party, but that had quickly proved ineffective when they got disoriented and lost their way within the fog. Some of them had even ended up fading, having failed to find their way back to the banshee.

After that, Maltrax the beastkin had taken charge and used her tracking. She’d initially been filled with confidence, but after leading them through over a hundred traps—Casper had forewarned them about each one—she seemed to be at her breaking point. Casper did offer input here and there, but she was too stubborn, so he didn’t bother arguing.

Azal finally glanced at Casper and also sighed. “You’re certain you can actually find the way?”

“Pretty certain, yep,” Casper said, nodding. He placed a hand on the wall and briefly closed his eyes. “Gotta head back to where we came from; we have been walking in the exact opposite direction of any keys for the last two hours.”

“I… He is lying!” Maltrax said, frustrated.

Casper didn’t even bother arguing, yet Azal nodded and motioned for them to follow him. Three hours and a lot of complaining from Maltrax later, they stood in front of the second room they had encountered on this floor. The first one did not have a key.

“He… He just got lucky… There probably isn’t even a key here…”

There was a key there.

Finally, Maltrax had to surrender and agree the dungeon engineer was indeed correct. Casper had to admit that things were far easier than he had expected. In fact, he would say his knowledge of dungeons was more valuable on this floor than the thirtieth, which made him wonder…

“Hey, Minaga?”

He got a few glances from his party members. They had discussed and agreed on engaging with the dungeon master as little as possible, but Casper felt like it was worth asking.

“What’s up? Or down. I guess it depends on your perspective.”

“I don’t mean to accuse you of anything… but did you make your labyrinth incredibly favorable for people with dungeon-related skills?”

More glances at him, one of them quite stern, very clearly telling him not to piss off the Unique Lifeform. Casper still felt like it was fine, though.

“Are you saying that I am purposefully making the dungeon easier for other aspiring dungeon masters?” Minaga said in an angry voice. “Are you insinuating that I would be so biased just because we both make dungeons!?”

“Yes?” Casper answered with a deadpan face.

“Good, because you would be absolutely correct!” Minaga said in a gleeful voice. “Man, you know how rare proper dungeon masters are these days? They all tend to suck or only pick up dungeon engineering in the later grades. True, it is difficult to do much while still weak... but that only makes those who succeed young more admirable! It is only natural that as a Progenitor Dungeon Master, I think you are a pretty swell guy.”

“Dungeon engineers are actually that rare?” Casper asked with some genuine confusion. “Why? It’s awesome.”

“That’s what I always say! The problem is that you have to study a lot to learn proper dungeon engineering, and higher stats just make studying easier. Dungeon engineers also have the problem of being pretty limited in what they can do when not in dungeons, and nurturing one is pretty damn expensive. If you have a talented engineer, why not just convince him to be a formation master instead, as the required competencies overlap? At least, that is what all those damn fools think, not realizing being a dungeon master is the greatest.”

“Their loss, I guess,” Casper said, shrugging.

“True that.”

Casper felt a bit better after talking to Minaga, and the rest of his party members also looked at him differently, their wariness replaced with relief and recognition.

Azal even spoke through their telepathic link, “For this labyrinth, you should take the lead. Good call on getting the Unique Lifeform on our side.”

Yeah, that hadn’t really been a plan, more just him being curious. But if he had permission…

“Say, you mentioned other groups when you talked earlier... Would you happen to know if others from my home planet also did your labyrinth?”

“A few, yeah.”

“How about the Chosen of the Malefic Viper?” Casper asked curiously. Jake had to have come through already with their head start, right?

“Casper, rather than answer that, let me ask you something: Do you respect my work and the work of all dungeon engineers who try and create proper labyrinths?”

“I would say so?” Casper answered, unsure why Minaga had even asked that. “Labyrinths are a pretty standard design form of dungeons, and this one is greatly designed and far more complex than I can even imagine. So, yeah, I do respect it, and dungeon engineers in general.”

“Well…” Minaga said, his voice full of exasperation. “Let’s just say some people can’t appreciate good craftsmanship.”

Nevermore City had calmed down for a while after the influx of pinnacle geniuses that seemed to arrive one after another petered out. All of the major factions had sent in their bids for the peak of the Leaderboards, hoping to claim the spot. The longer one waited, the harder it was, after all.

One just had to hold the record for a single second to get the associated reward. Of course, one also had to pass a certain threshold of minimum points to even get the reward in the first place, but all of these top parties would reach that threshold. That meant they were truly competing with one another, and any record set by a group would make it harder to set a new one. As expected of a Leaderboard.

However, one day, more than two weeks after everyone believed all the top parties had already entered, a new one appeared. To see the Dao Sect send a group vying for the top spot had already been a massive surprise to most information brokers, but it paled in comparison to this group. Because this group was not a faction… It was five individuals who all had one thing in common. One trait that made them all uniquely outstanding.

The first member was a more than three-meter-tall, muscular, hunched-over, cyclops-looking creature with an entirely black eye. Pitch-black chains hung from its body, rattling as it walked, yet these chains did not hit the ground; they simply phased through it like they didn’t truly exist. Its skin was entirely gray, and though many would likely confuse it for an undead creature, it didn’t give off any death-affinity energy. In fact, it barely gave off any energy, period. Even its aura was barely detectable, but those who could feel it were instantly put on edge.

A second creature was simply a tattered cloak floating through the air, its hood an endless pit of nothingness. There were no limbs to speak of, and the entire ghost-like creature—it was distinctly not undead—looked like it barely existed in the physical plane. Save for a few moments where an arm seemed to glimmer into existence floating beside it, holding a staff of some kind, it displayed no movements as it floated through the air together with the cyclops and the three other people in the auspicious party.

The third was at least recognizable as a member of a known race of the multiverse. Or at least, she had been one at some point. She looked like an elf of some kind, but not one anyone could quite place. Her skin was entirely white, to an almost frightening level, with black lines running through her in a pattern that acted like a mental attack whenever one laid eyes on it. Luckily, she wore a robe covering her body, but a few weaker D-grades did puke simply upon seeing her hand briefly. She had no hair, but her head was covered in odd, silky threads that extended toward the sky while dancing in an eerie pattern. Most of her face was obscured, as she wore a blindfold over her eyes, and her pale lips made her look almost like a walking frozen corpse. Ultimately, the only real reason people guessed she had once been an elf was her ears. As with the prior two, she could not be properly Identified. Nor could the next group member.

This fourth individual was a humanoid-looking creature, but not one anyone could quite place. Partly because the head—the only thing visible—seemed to be in constant flux. The head was far larger than any regular creature’s and had four faces on it, each looking in a different direction. All of these faces shifted at every second, from female to male, elf to human, sometimes even adopting non-humanoid-looking races. The rest of the body was covered in a black robe, but one could faintly see the rustling of more than two arms beneath, and for a brief second, a long metallic limb showed from beneath the robe.

These four all gave off the presence of otherworldly creatures, and none could be correctly Identified. It was as though none of them truly belonged in the world, which partly made sense due to what they all had in common:

They were all touched and blessed by Void Gods. They were beings corrupted by the void. Creatures that had stared too deep into something mortals should stay far away from, and now found themselves forever changed by the experience. Yet they had survived, proving they were extraordinary just through that feat alone. It was common knowledge that those who delved into the powers of the void would be forever warped… yet…

Somehow, the fifth member of this party was the one that stood out the most. Walking in the center of all these monstrous-looking creatures was a completely ordinary-looking human. He could even be Identified as such. He wore glasses, as he seemed to be reading something on the object he was holding, and his carefree demeanor made it clear he was entirely unbothered by the creatures surrounding him. His eyes—usually the most obvious sign of corruption—were normal, and he did not seem to hide anything under his clothes. Clothes that also did not fit the theme of black robes, as he had on pants with far too many pockets for someone with a spatial storage, along with a coat and apron and work boots. The only extraordinary piece of equipment he was his glasses.

His normal appearance almost made him the most eerie of the group. Especially since he walked in the middle, indicating he was either the leader or the most prominent member of the party. Or maybe it had no meaning, as these were creatures of the void… and trying to understand the void was the Path of the mad.

This group entered Nevermore without making any stops, uncaring about the many observers. Yet none dared approach them, fearing they could antagonize one of them.

Void Gods had no factions. They had no headquarters, no domains, no areas they controlled, or even buildings they owned. It was simply impossible for them to. Yet none questioned their power, for the Void Gods were known and feared. Every single Void God was a being at the pinnacle—a creature that not even Primordials would dare call themselves superior to.

Those touched by the void were few and far between, and seeing five gathered in one spot was already extraordinary… much less five individuals all blessed by Void Gods. This meant they had likely interacted with the void by laying eyes on their Patrons without averting their gazes. A truly foolish endeavor, where one could only expect madness or death to follow. Yet these people had managed to retain their egos.

One thing was for sure… The top factions had just gotten themselves another party to compete with. This party being “late” was no comfort to them, either, because if there was one type of magic that could break a scenario and allow a party to advance fast, it was magic with its Origin in the void.

Chapter 34

For the Family

Teleportation was no doubt the preferred method of long-distance travel in the multiverse. It did have some problems that made it less than ideal as an exploratory tool, like requiring a teleportation circle at both the target location and where you teleported from. One needed to know where one wanted to go in order to teleport somewhere, after all.

If one did not use a magic circle, teleportation became significantly more dangerous, costly, and overall less effective. However, there were instances where one did not want teleportation circles placed in an area.

First of all, many important places were protected by magical barriers. These barriers also protected some teleportation, and while it was possible to allow a “backdoor” of sorts in the barrier, this was, needless to say, a major security flaw. A powerful space mage could often “hack” themselves into a teleportation network and, if there was a backdoor of any kind, exploit that to teleport straight into an area that should otherwise be protected.

That was why most factions only established these teleportation networks inside of the barriers. This was a good method for single planets or even solar systems, but it became heavily flawed if one wanted to connect two distant planets. A single barrier capable of encompassing two different planets in their own solar systems would rarely be worth it.

Due to this, many Waypoints had been established throughout the different universes. These were planets not protected within any borders, filled with teleportation circles allowing one to travel all across an entire universe within weeks if one jumped repeatedly.

The problem ultimately arose when one had to travel from a Waypoint to within a closed teleportation network, because there were some closed teleportation networks, with numerous solar systems—sometimes even galaxies—all protected by one powerful defense system. These were the large areas controlled by major factions, and each faction would often only have a handful at most in each universe.

However, even among these closed systems, some places stood out: the heartlands of each faction. Primordial-1 and a huge area surrounding it was recognized as the heartlands of the Holy Church, and it was an area no god not part of the Holy Church could easily enter—not even other Primordials or those with equivalent strength.

Another well-known example was the Risen and the place known as the Ghostlands. The Altmar Empire had its Capital Cluster, as they called it, with most peak factions having something similar. But there were two heartlands more protected than any others in the entire multiverse. Which was stronger, no one knew, but all knew it was a tie between these two:

The Automata Legion and the Endless Empire.

These two factions stood at the apex when it came to defending their heartlands. This was for obvious reasons, as both had members they could absolutely not risk losing, and the way their societies and Paths worked just lent themselves to making sure they had incredibly safe home bases.

But… one could naturally not just teleport into these heartlands. One had to travel the final distance from the Waypoint to within the barrier themselves, and for security reasons, these Waypoints were always a good distance from the heartlands. Clearing that last stretch was usually not a problem… but only if no one interfered. Because if anyone did, things could get rough.

This was the exact challenge Vesperia found herself facing. She had appeared on the final Waypoint Planet before they would have to manually travel the rest of the way, but barely a second after she had appeared there… the world turned white. Dozens of figures teleported all around her to form a barrier, making sure she was safe as the entire planet below her exploded.

Vesperia barely saw them. A massive, floating mothership and armies of Automata gods all descended upon her, ready to strike the moment she appeared on this Waypoint Planet. The only good thing was that there had been eleven total Waypoint Planets to pick between, meaning the Automata Legion had to be at all of them.

Meanwhile, the Endless Empire only had to show up at one.

The entire cosmos was set ablaze as the Automata Legion attacked. Vesperia was shielded within a pod as four True Royals took flight and escorted her toward the planet; teleportation was not possible due to the interference of the Automata Legion. In the distance, she saw endless flashes of light as war raged. It was lucky that the Waypoint Planets around the Endless Empire were all artificially created and far separated from any others… for if not, entire galaxies could have been snuffed out of existence that day. Vesperia had known this could happen but was powerless to do anything. All she could do was trust her sisters.

Ultimately, Vesperia tuned out all the disturbances all around her and entered meditation, knowing that the best she could do was remain calm. Approximately seven hours later, she felt herself being teleported and opened her eyes to find herself surrounded by divine beings—her sisters, the other True Royals, among them.

It was only later that she came to learn the details of the battle. More than six thousand gods of the Automata Legion had been slain, though they all knew it had little consequence besides the material cost of their bodies, as one never truly killed an Automata god just by destroying its vessel. No, the true victory lay in successfully escorting Vesperia safely into the heartlands of the Endless Empire. That they had already managed to destroy the mothership was a boon, but the Endless Empire had lost a Godqueen in return. An acceptable loss, in their eyes.

The Automata Legion had known their chances of success were low, but they had tried anyway. The Endless Empire had shown up with nearly all True Royals. Being so close to their heartlands, they’d gladly shown up in force, which had resulted in the Endless Empire coming out on top big time, even if one did not include Vesperia in the equation.

In the end, it had been a relatively low-risk, high-reward strike from the Automata Legion.

Safely back in her homeland, Vesperia felt relief and a powerful sense of belonging. She was greeted by all of her sisters, their happiness obvious at finally seeing her return home, even if she did sense some faint hesitation from some of them. They celebrated for a time while waiting for more arrivals, which wound up joining them just a week later.

Gods of the Vespernat Lineage had all felt the moment a True Royal had appeared. Once the news spread that she had safely returned to the Endless Empire, these powerful Hive Queens did not hesitate. Gods of all ranks, including Godqueens, entered the heartlands of the Endless Empire to greet the True Royal and swear their loyalty. There was no hesitation in their actions, no second-guessing. It was in their nature to recognize Vesperia, even if she was only C-grade.

After that, Vesperia still had one more important thing to do before her true work began.

Vesperia was escorted by the Odonstrom Hive Queen down into the deepest parts of the Great Planet known as Primordial-8. Some also called it the Great Hive Planet, but its official designation was still Primordial-8, following the same naming convention as every other Great Planet in the First Universe.

“Are you certain you find yourself ready?” the Odonstrom True Royal asked.

“Yes, there is no cause for concern,” she answered without hesitation. “I already feel the call and their desire.”

“Very well. I shall not question you then, Sister.” The Odonstrom Hive Queen smiled, looking relieved.

“I still detect hints of doubt in your demeanor, Sister,” Vesperia said to the far older god. “From some of the others, too. How come?”

“It is hopefully of little concern, but it is perhaps still pertinent to bring up. Even with your assurances, there is still some doubt about you due to the matters of your birth. Your circumstances are unique, and some fear that you may not truly hold the same allegiances as the Vesperia of old.” The Odonstrom True Royal sighed. “I know this doubt should be dispelled—”

“I don’t think it should,” Vesperia cut her off. “I am not entirely the same as other True Royals or the old Vesperia. But what changes I have experienced are not negative, or even ones I find a need to hide. My allegiances also still lie with my sire along with the Empire; I believe I have made this quite clear. Is this an issue for the council? Or do you not believe it proper I receive the Lineage Treasures?”

The other True Royal sighed. “Perhaps… perhaps not. But even if there is some doubt, there is none about your identity as a True Royal, and thus you can naturally claim your birthright.”

“Thank you.” Vesperia nodded as they continued without exchanging words. They were heading to the innermost armory of the Endless Empire, where the treasures of her Lineage resided. Items that only the True Royals of the corresponding Lineage could make use of. In her case, Vesperia already knew what awaited her:

The Vespernat Royal Diadem and the Vespernat Hive Core.

The diadem would increase the effectiveness of all her abilities by a non-insignificant amount, especially when it came to leading her hive and controlling her subjects. It was also a massive, nearly inexhaustible energy source and a treasure granted directly by the system in the First Era. The Vespernat Hive Core was a powerful treasure she could absorb to expand her inner world significantly while also making the energy within far more potent. The diadem had been a treasure used by the original Vesperia, while the Hive Core had come from the body of the dead Vesperia. These two would not make her much more powerful as a warrior, but would assist her tremendously in rebuilding the Vespernat Lineage.

As a monster, Vesperia could not use normal equipment, but these treasures still worked for her. Throughout the eras, they had also both been nurtured by the Endless Empire. This had not only been done out of faint hope a Vespernat True Royal would appear, either. As long as they kept the Records of the Vespernat Lineage alive, there was hope that a new True Royal would be born through a miracle. It did prove to have done nothing, as the miracle had been her Sire, Jake, even if some of the other True Royals remained skeptical.

Vesperia knew what many of them hoped for.

They hoped that with time, Vesperia would “come to her senses” and disregard where she came from. That she would truly embrace her fate as a member of the Endless Empire… and only the Endless Empire. She also knew why.

The Endless Empire was not allied with any Primordials, as they did not believe any of them could be trusted. The twelve Primordials had been the first gods, and they had an… odd relationship with one another. They often fought and opposed one another, but never had there been a deadly conflict between them. Even when Sanguine and the vampires had arisen, with several Primordials coming for the first vampire, the Malefic Viper had not interfered despite his close relationship with Sanguine. He’d stayed out of it and watched Sanguine fall, not fighting his fellow Primordials.

Vesperia knew that Jake was not the one they had a problem with. It was the being behind him. He was the Chosen of the Malefic Viper, after all, and did anyone truly believe he was indeed making his own decisions? That the Malefic One was not the one pulling the strings?

No, none believed such a preposterous thing to be possible. Vesperia also knew trying to convince them otherwise would be useless, and she didn’t want to try even if she thought she could. She did recognize she was biased on the matter, and her opinion thus held less sway, so she would hold her truth to herself.

Because no matter what people thought… Vesperia had felt the Records of her Sire. Felt his will and that which dwelt within. Perhaps the Malefic One could manipulate her Sire, even fool him into doing things against his own interest… but she did not believe even a Primordial could ever control him.

Some monsters could simply never be tamed.

“We have arrived,” the Odonstrom Hive Queen said.

The two of them found themselves standing before a large, crystal structure with items suspended within. The diadem and the Hive Core. Vesperia felt them both pulsing with power, and the other True Royal looked at her with worry.

“They have been empowered through the ages… Neither is to be taken lightly. The Vespernat Diadem especially. The energy had been overwhelming to even the S-grade Vesperia back in the First Era, and alas, you still only find yourself in C-grade.”

“I shall be fine—of that, I assure you,” Vesperia said, nodding as she walked forward. The two artifacts reacted to her mere presence, and with a thought, the crystals that weaker gods could not even scratch willingly shattered. The full auras of the artifacts were released as they flew toward Vesperia.

She opened her arms and welcomed them both. The diadem landed on her head, and she felt the massive influx of energy as the Hive Core melted into her chest. She felt the overwhelming power coursing through her body, and Records impacted her soul as she stood with her eyes closed.

Vesperia had to endure the Records… but one had to remember she had been connected to a presence that surpassed any other she had ever felt, and compared to that, all else just paled. There was still a lot of energy to tame, but she only took four hours before she opened her eyes once more, the golden jewels on the diadem lighting up and her inner world expanding.

“That… You truly surpassed my expectations, Sister,” the Odonstrom Hive Queen said with genuine happiness. “I believed it would have taken you far longer… Even if you are far from making full use of both treasures, the mere fact you successfully bound them is cause for celebration.”

“We talked earlier about how the circumstances of my birth may impact me negatively… but did the council ever consider that it was just the opposite?” Vesperia questioned her fellow True Royal while deep in thought.

“What do you mean?” her sister asked.

Vesperia’s next words were simply too foreign for her to consider. “That my sire’s involvement in my birth is naught but a boon,” said, smiling.

She did know her words could be viewed as potentially blasphemous; after all, how could the Origin of a True Royal possibly be improved? Vesperia also knew that these words were not ones her Sire hoped she would speak.

It would no doubt only fan the flames of desire the Endless Empire held to have him join the Grand Hive proper and discard his involvement with any Primordials.

A thought Vesperia did have to admit she found appealing, no matter how impossible she knew it was.

For just as some monsters could never be tamed, some became restless if anyone attempted to tie them down.

She did not believe a restless Sire would do the Endless Empire any good.

“Well, that went terribly.” Caleb sighed as he leaned against the broken wall of the castle, his armor entirely burnt away, leaving him nearly naked. He luckily had an extra pair of trousers, for if not, he indeed would have been.

“We were careless,” Matteo—his second-in-command—agreed.

“Yeah.” Caleb nodded. “Good job on keeping the damn Demon Lord still while we dealt with the two Tower Demons.”

Matteo smiled lightly but did not say anything. In the fight, Matteo had managed to trap the Demon Lord in a labyrinth of auditory illusions through his piano playing and use of dark magic for over two minutes, allowing the rest of the party to kill the Tower Demons. Hence, Caleb saying he had done a damn good job.

The problem was that they had not done a good job overall. They had decided to go for only empowering two of the artifacts using the Secret Scrolls, moving to kill one of the Tower Demons while deactivating the Heart of the Demon Lord. However, that plan had gone south.

“I am glad we didn’t bring Nadia,” Matteo muttered.

“Yeah,” Caleb said as he stared from afar at where the Demon Lord had teleported away after they failed to stop him. Nearby, he saw his two remaining party members walking over… and the ashes of the one who hadn’t made it still scattering as the wind swept by, spurred on by the entire castle having exploded after the Tower Demons died.

Caleb and Matteo were the only ones from the Court of Shadows in the party, as, quite frankly, full parties with only their members tended to suck. The three others had consisted of two of Jake’s potential party members from the ceremony and one outside recruit poached by the Court.

The one who’d died had been one of the people wanting to join Jake. She had been a caster that failed to move fast enough when the Demon Lord powered up. The sword had been sent flying towards her while she was distracted, resulting in her body being pierced, her entire form destroyed in mere seconds. As a wood mage, she had been weak to fire from the beginning, and in the end, they had failed to protect her.

“Judge,” the princess from the Altmar Empire—their healer—spoke as she walked over with the final member, a large beastkin warrior with a shield and a mace. Their tank.

The princess looked unsure as Caleb shook his head. “I shall inform her family. Are you willing to stay with the party even after this?”

It took the elf a few seconds to nod. “Ilieasia made a mistake, failing to even use her escape talisman… Let us just hope we get a good replacement.”

A cold response, but one Caleb had expected. He knew the princess was there, in part, to stay close to him to get to Jake, and Caleb could live with that. Finding a healer like the Altmar princess for their party would be incredibly difficult under normal circumstances, so he welcomed making use of his big brother’s… fame? Notoriety?

He wasn’t sure, and it ultimately didn’t matter. Caleb was in Nevermore to get stronger to keep his family safe, and he would not hesitate if making a harsh decision could help him and his own in the long term.

“Let us hope so, indeed,” Caleb said, sighing as he looked onward. “Now, let’s move on and recruit a replacement on the city floor. If not, I will send a request to the Court.”

Caleb also hoped they could relax a bit on the city floor. Maybe even meet some friends?

Chapter 35

Work Ethic

“Good, now adjust the energy output… slowly… Good, now do not forge—ah, you remembered, good. Alright… watch the outer circle… Do not let the resonance fade. You need to maintain the equilibrium until a perfect balance is struck. Keep it up now… Good, good… And the final part… Perfect!” Grand Elder Duskleaf ended his commentary in a proud voice as he inspected the magical formation.

Meira was covered in sweat, exhausted yet proud as she looked at her creation.

The large formation stretched out in front of her, lighting up with intense mana from the nine catalysts acting as batteries. In the center of it, energy gathered, and a small hole had already been pre-dug.

“Now for the seed to be planted,” Duskleaf said happily.

Meira smiled and took out the tree seed from a lockbox she had left off to the side. It was a silverish seed, and she was excited to see it grow. She used mana to levitate it into the air and guide it into the hole, then proceeded to fill the hole with some special soil from afar, her teacher standing encouragingly beside her. Finally, she took out a watering can, flew up above the formation, and watered the entire thing. The formation responded to the magical water and pulsed with power, fully activating to begin feeding the seed energy.

She smiled. “It’s done.” Then she heard the sound of a notification as she gained a level, making her even more excited. One step closer to C-grade.

“Indeed, it is,” Duskleaf said, nodding proudly. “The Silverpine Astral Tree should be able to reach at least ancient rarity with this formation, so it is something to be proud of.”

Meira smiled a bit and shook her head. “I am sure Teacher could do far better when he was my level.”

“Master used to slap me in the back of my head for failing to produce a single epic-rarity plant while in D-grade,” the old god chuckled.

“That’s…” Meira said, fidgeting with her hands. She knew that her teacher had repeatedly said he wasn’t that good at lower grades, but… she had a hard time seeing it. Because today, no one would dispute he was one of the premier alchemists in the entire multiverse. How could he possibly have struggled to produce products at epic rarity?

Seeing her doubt, Teacher shook his head. “I told you already… Talent is a bonus, not a requirement, and that is only in cases where the talent does not become a handicap. The most important thing in the multiverse is work ethic. Nothing else matters if you do not have a good work ethic.”

It was something Meira had heard many times before. She understood it from a logical perspective, but it was still hard to imagine. Could one really become a god just by working hard?

Growing up, everyone around her had worked hard in the mines, day in and day out. They had toiled away endlessly to survive… but she did know why that didn’t count. One still had to challenge themselves. Something her teacher could help her do.

“But you still need to know what to work on,” he continued, elaborating on her own thoughts. “If you decide to just replicate formations at or below your skill level over and over again, you will get nowhere. No, you need to constantly improve and challenge yourself. Without Master, I would have never even made it to C-grade. He was the one who guided me and gave me challenges, and whenever he felt I was stagnating, he gave me a push in the right direction. A guiding hand that made sure I would always face new challenges and be forced to improve. And I knew that he would have abandoned me without a second thought if I fell into complacency, for he did that with so many others who studied under him.”

“I understand, Teacher,” Meira said with a nod. She did not know if Grand Elder Duskleaf would also abandon her if he believed she was stagnating, and she did not intend to find out.

With Lord Thayne’s true identity as the Chosen of the Malefic One revealed to all, Teacher had finally taken her as an official disciple and even given her a Divine Blessing. He had gone so far as to allude to him not having a Chosen himself, hinting at her potentially getting her Blessing upgraded if she proved herself worthy. Meira couldn’t even think about becoming a Chosen, as she was already overwhelmed by her current Blessing and elevated status.

No, no, she had something far less impactful she wanted to accomplish. Her own goal, separate from Lord Thayne and even her teacher.

She wanted to free her clan.

Meira knew that to do this, she would have to borrow the status of her teacher, but she also wanted to go there with her head held high. The most powerful people in the clan were C-grades, and she wanted to go there at C-grade too.

Her mother and siblings were still at the old clan, based on what Izil had told her, and while some would call it an infantile dream, Meira really wanted to be the one to go and “save” them. She wanted to bring them to the Order or perhaps even claim the entire clan as her own to protect it. Something she likely could do right now… but she did not want to go before C-grade.

Meira wanted C-grade to be her “turning point,” so to speak. Even if she was no longer a slave, her profession and class both bore marks of her being one. Both made it clear she was still a servant. If all went well… then none of her evolutions would even hint at it.

She wanted to show up before her family, proud of who she had become and not just her status as the student of the Grand Elder.

It was a small goal, in the grand scheme of things… but it was perhaps the first goal she had set entirely for herself.

Her first goal of many, hopefully.

Sandy was sleepy, so Sandy slept a lot.

Sandy was sleepy because they had eaten too much and had a stomachache.

Sandy had not moved from within the Order of the Malefic Viper since the ceremony.

Sandy would begin to feel better after a few days, only to eat again and get another stomachache.

Sandy was caught in a cruel loop of consumption due to all the evil people having given Sandy too much stuff to eat during the ceremony.

Sandy was totally okay with the current situation they found themselves in.

So… having a regular day job had kind of sucked before the system. At least, most people seemed to think so. Not Jake, though. In fact, he had very much liked having one.

It had given him some kind of structure to his life. Wake up, shower, go to work, do the work, go to the gym, drive home, and relax until he had to sleep to get up for work the next day. This constant flow of everyday life had helped keep Jake together during the nightmarish years before the system.

He still recalled those days as… bad. It was only now, after a few years had passed, that Jake could truly understand how much life had sucked for him back then. How boring and meaningless the entire world had felt. Work had, ironically enough, allowed him to have something to focus on and get through the days until, finally, the initiation arrived, and color returned to his world.

One thing had stayed, though. Jake still liked to work on stuff, which was probably part of the reason he was good at alchemy. He still needed to always try and keep himself busy, and sitting still just never really worked for him. Jake would begin to feel restless if he did nothing for too long, so even when he was on “holiday” and visited his parents and Caleb, he still did some alchemy and helped train Caleb’s shadow assassins here and there.

Minaga’s city floor gave him some flashbacks to those calmer periods of his life, both before and after the integration. Life was incredibly simple here on the city floor, and the days blended together as the months passed. Jake just did alchemy day in and day out. Every “break” he took consisted of going to one of the arenas and getting some points there.

Speaking of the arenas, as Minaga had said, one could fight there once a day versus monsters. One could also fight other people, but it didn’t reward anything. Being able to bet Minaga Coins on duels would have been far too easy to exploit.

Anyway, the daily arena challenge was quite simple. One would enter and be teleported into the middle of the arena, where a timer of one hour would begin. Monsters would then enter the arena, and as long as you killed all that were alive, more would come. This meant that someone more powerful would manage to kill far more monsters than anyone else. It also had to be mentioned that the arena was for individuals only.

After the hour was up, you would be rewarded with Minaga Coins based on the monsters you killed. Overall, Jake only saw this arena as some good exercise, and it helped him practice finishing off foes faster. Sylphie and the Fallen King naturally went to this arena every day, and it had become their primary source of income. Both of them also sold stuff from within Nevermore to get more coins, as they were the slowest when it came to accumulating them.

Just as the Fallen King had complained, it did seem harder for monsters to obtain coins compared to those with professions. The two of them could still do other stuff besides the arena, but it gave little compared to just crafting. There were different facilities in the city that one could work for by assisting natives with all sorts of tasks. The Fallen King had found one that asked for help with soul-related rituals and gave decent coins, while Sylphie helped craft natural treasures using her weird green wind. Jake had no idea how all that worked, but he let them do their thing to earn coins as best they could.

Dina was a bit of an odd one out in their party. She did not have a profession, only her dryad race and Druid class, but that did not make her any less of a crafter. It was only on this floor that Jake learned Dina had an amazing technique to make what were effectively genetically modified plants. She would communicate with herbs to accomplish this, and through this, she created many different plants that Jake had never seen or heard of before.

Even if she used plants she’d already had before entering Nevermore, she could then sell these crossbreeds. However, she and Jake quickly discovered that if they used materials they had gathered inside Nevermore for crafting, the Brokers would buy their products for even more.

Speaking of the Brokers… Jake had no idea why they bought stuff for what they did. These Brokers were all cloak-wearing humanoid creatures that dwelled within many near-identical shops spread throughout the city. These Brokers could be spoken to and negotiated with, and Jake did see some people get away with more Minaga Coins than he would expect by virtue of good negotiation, so merchants did seem to have one advantage.

It had to be mentioned that skills did not really work that well, though. Illusion magic or any kind of mental magic was also not an option, as these Brokers had one tiny little detail that made it unfeasible for a C-grade to influence them:

They were all A-grades.

Why were they all A-grades? Well, it was likely to avoid people manipulating them with skills… so Jake guessed it made sense. Luckily for Jake, he’d never planned on manipulating them; he just sold his alchemical creations. Someone who could still kind of “manipulate” them was the final member of Jake’s party… because the old man had taken the coin lead by quite a margin through selling paintings. It turned out that creations with purely subjective values, such as works of art, were far easier to bullshit a high price for.

Jake was not jealous. Totally not. That the old man was only seven thousand coins off seemed totally fair. That Jake, who had also worked his butt off, was still thirty thousand short was not at all something to complain about.

Current Minaga Coins: 184,190/214,000

From the time they had entered Minaga’s city floor till now, about thirteen months had passed, so they certainly weren’t gonna break the record that had been mentioned to them. This meant they had spent well over two years within Nevermore so far, with nearly half the time spent on this city floor. Jake surely would’ve preferred to do without… but the time was not entirely wasted.

Because it turned out that just grinding out alchemy products every day was quite good when it came to raking in levels.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 211 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 224 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 215 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 221 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Over this period, Jake had gained 14 profession levels, which, if he had to say so himself, was pretty damn decent. The others had also grown over this time, and honestly, this floor did give Jake and the Sword Saint a good excuse to work on their professions while Dina leveled up her race quite a few times.

He had seen the levels slow down as more time passed, and he knew he would soon not get much more experience from just crafting, but that was honestly fine. Once he had enough Minaga Coins for his own toll, Jake had a date with a certain puzzle box he had received during his Chosen-reveal ceremony.

Overall, he thought things were going well.

However… one thing had left a sour taste in Jake’s mouth. Ell’Hakan had appeared on the Minaga City Floor four and a half months after Jake and his party made it there—they’d been well ahead despite entering at nearly the same time—and the current Leaderboard had not been updated, meaning Jake had been ahead of him on points, too. That had been sweet, but that taste of sweetness only made what happened next leave a far sourer taste.

The record to pass the Minaga City Floor had been broken.

When Ell’Hakan had appeared on the floor, he had not sought out Jake. He had not sought out anyone. Based on reports, he had simply listened to the rules explained by someone on the floor allied with him, nodded, and brought his entire party to one of the Brokers.

An hour after entering the Broker’s store, he had left it, and he and his entire party had headed straight for the toll booth. They’d all paid their toll and moved on to the thirty-sixth floor right then and there, leaving before barely anyone knew they were there. Not even Jake had heard they had arrived until after the fact.

Seventy-nine minutes. That was how long it had taken Ell’Hakan to pass the city floor.

Jake had cursed how the hell that was possible, only for Minaga to pop in, full of schadenfreude.

“Would you look at that… A dirty cheater complaining about another dirty cheater? So what if he found a loophole using his Bloodline? Do you think that should be banned? I could totally ban it from here on out, because, you know, it’s not like there are five more floors of my labyrinth, right? Surely, you would not consider using your bullshit Bloodline on these floors, right? That would be super hypocritical, wouldn’t it?”

As much as Jake wanted to punch the four-eyed dungeon master, he could only grit his teeth and curse internally as he swore to make up for the lost time by utterly demolishing the remaining labyrinth. Ell’Hakan had taken far longer doing the prior labyrinth floors, so he hoped to catch up.

When it came to how Ell’Hakan had cheated, Minaga didn’t say, but he did drop one hint.

“The Brokers ultimately decide what they buy something for… so if they, for some reason, think it is a good idea to buy objects for hundreds of thousands of Minaga Coins, then what can you do? Well, I could do something, but if I stop one Bloodline-powered exploit, I would have to stop all of them.”

Jake once more did not want to argue that point, as he still felt like his Bloodline was a better cheat than Ell’Hakan’s. In fact, he refused to acknowledge that any other Bloodlines could ever be superior overall. Sure, Dina’s was better in a plant-filled environment, and Ell’Hakan’s was better on a fucking city floor, but Jake would reign supreme in the vast majority of situations.

Besides, Ell’Hakan not sticking around wasn’t exactly a bad thing, as it meant Jake didn’t have to bother even thinking about the guy. Instead, he could turn his attention to all the other familiar faces who had begun to arrive on the city floor, some of whom he had already made contact with.

In fact, considering how long it took an average party to gather all the Minaga Coins, Jake had a feeling they had quite a reunion on their hands.

Chapter 36

Earthly Reunion

“Ialready told them to go fuck themselves,” the short-haired woman said with a shrug. “Turns out that when the big boss is backing you, everyone else also just backs down. Funny how that works.”

“My interpretation is that you just like to create chaos and political uproar,” Jake said, grinning.

“Who gives a shit?” Carmen said, clearly not caring much.

“Well, not me in particular.” Jake shrugged as he looked at the pugilist that had come by to visit. This was not her first time coming by, either, as she had barged in—or at least tried to, only to be stopped by a system-made barrier—the day she arrived on the city floor.

Through his sphere, he also saw others slowly making their way over to their chosen meeting spot, with the next to arrive likely being the Sword Saint.

“Davian is still being a bitch, complaining about people talking.” Carmen sighed, clearly annoyed as she watched Jake casually mixing some stuff into the cauldron. She herself was also fidgeting with some weird stone figurine in her hand.

“Shouldn’t the talk have died down by now? What are they even saying at this point?” In truth, Jake didn’t care overly much about what people were saying.

“It’s quite romantic, actually,” an old man said as he appeared in the doorway. “A real Romeo and Juliet tale. Two souls from opposite sides of a conflict, their love seeking to overcome even the will of the gods. I am sure books of such a forbidden love shall be written.”

“Hey, old man, wanna test how strong those bones of yours are?” Carmen shot back as she turned to him. “The ones in your face in particular.”

“No, I am quite confident my feeble old bones are not fit to match the fist of a Runemaiden,” the Sword Saint said, chuckling. “And would it lighten your mood to know this rumor is not exclusive to you two?”

“Oh?” Jake said, confused. He had to admit he was not up to date on the latest gossip, but considering the old man nearly had enough Minaga Coins for his toll, he seemed to have some more time.

“An even more unbelievable and romantic tale,” the Sword Saint said as he went over and took a seat. “Imagine the scene. Two lovers, even before the initiation, but in the final moments before the universe changes, one of them sadly perishes… only for the system to arrive and allow them to return to life. Both are thrust into their own tutorials, neither aware of how the other is doing or even that they live… but the moment they arrive back on the same planet, they find themselves part of warring factions, with one now even a Risen.”

“Wait,” Jake said, but the Sword Saint raised a hand.

“Could you imagine the pain these two poor souls must feel?” the old man continued, spinning quite the tale. “To finally be reunited, only to discover their love is forbidden? Even so, it refuses to fade, no matter how they try… and when they once more encounter each other within Nevermore, free from the oppression and influence of their factions, love blossoms stronger than ever before.”

“You can’t be serious, right?” Jake questioned, knowing who he was talking about.

Smiling, the old man pulled out a painting from his spatial storage. Jake looked at it for one moment, then nearly choked and momentarily lost control of his mana.

The painting depicted two people Jake knew quite well. One was an extremely handsome man with loose robes and deep blue eyes. He had a white rose in his hand, which he held out in a romantic gesture while staring intensely into the eyes of the person across from him—a pale man with hesitation in his eyes, looking shy as he held a black robe behind his back, his clothes also halfway undressed for some reason.

Who else could the painting depict but Jacob and Casper? Highly stylized versions of them, anyway.

“You seriously painted that?” Carmen asked in disbelief.

“Naturally,” the Sword Saint said, nodding proudly.

She nodded back. “It’s pretty good.”

“Seriously?” Jake raised an eyebrow.

“What?” Carmen shrugged. “I may be a brute, but I can appreciate good art when I see it.”

“It’s practically fanart,” Jake protested, pointing at the painting as he turned to look at its painter. “And why the hell did you even paint that to begin with? Too much free time?”

“For the Minaga Coins, of course,” the old man answered, flashing a large smile. “Recently, paintings on this topic have been trendy, and the Brokers gladly buy them for high prices, especially as the demand is high while the supply is low. Being a first mover in the market has already been a big advantage.”

“How bloody bored are people?” Jake had a damn hard time understanding. “I would ask if people also wrote fanfiction, but from your smirk, I am just going to assume the answer is yes… How the hell did that rumor even begin?”

“A very good question,” the Sword Saint said, nodding. “It would have had to be someone from Earth to know about their relationship before the system. Additionally, they must have started this rumor and helped perpetuate it for some tangible gain, would they not?”

“Are you for real?” Jake said, his mouth open as Carmen giggled.

“I gotta admit, old man, you are far more entertaining than I first gave you credit for,” she said, still looking at the painting.

“Pretty sure you even painting that qualifies as blasphemy,” Jake said. “Also, aren’t the Risen and Holy Church pissed? Oh, and why the hell did none of them mention this is going on?”

“When did you last talk to either of them?” the old man asked.

“About… two weeks ago, I would say?” Jake said.

“Well, that answers it, then. These rumors started only ten or so days ago and have been spreading like wildfire since, with the prices still spiking. They should reach a zenith within the month, and hopefully, I should be able to collect the final coins by then. Or at least get very close.”

“You think that painting can fetch that much?” Carmen asked.

“Of course not.” The old man shook his head. “I have a collection that I happened to coincidentally pre-prepare.”

“You know what?” Jake said. “We should change the topic, as the two main characters of your head-canon are nearly here.” Although he really just didn’t wanna discuss the topic any further, Casper and Jacob would indeed arrive within the minute. Considering the two were not walking together when they reached the hotel, Jake did find it suspicious that they’d arrived within thirty seconds of each other.

Maybe there was something to those rumors after all… Not.

Jake heard them talking in the hallway as approached. Quite loudly, too.

“I swear, if I ever find the guy who spread this bullshit…” Casper spoke outside. “And you said you tried to kill the rumor?”

“That I did, and there was some effect for a while, but not much,” Jacob said, his voice full of hopelessness. “At this point, I fear that denial will only strengthen the delusions of those who have chosen to believe the rumor.”

“Lyra is pissed, just in case you were wondering,” Casper kept complaining.

Jake looked at the old man as he lifted a finger to his lips and shushed, getting a muted giggle out of Carmen. She enjoyed this far too much. When he saw them enter, however, he also couldn’t help himself.

“The loverboys arrive,” Jake announced loudly as they walked in together. “Coming from a date?”

“Very funny.” Casper stared daggers as he also saw Carmen. “Shouldn’t throw stones when you live in a greenhouse. Aren’t there also rumors about you two?”

“It’s stones in a glass house,” Jacob said, sighing. “And at least there is some partial truth to that rumor, right?”

“See, now you make me want to punch both of you in the face.” Carmen smiled as she looked at Jacob. “You especially, Augur of Cons.”

“The Holy Church is not a con,” Jacob said while shaking his head.

“Sure, and the Primordial Church is not a cult of fanatics…” Carmen snorted. “Let’s not beat around the bush; the Holy Church is a fucking meatgrinder of souls to fuel the Holyland. Nothing less, nothing more.”

“Now, let’s not get all political here,” the Sword Saint said.

Yeah… Carmen did not like Jacob. Jake couldn’t really blame her, either. Had Jake not known Jacob before the system, he too would’ve been far less inclined to engage with the Augur.

“Besides, more people are coming,” Jake commented as he saw two others approach. Caleb would naturally participate in their little meeting, and he had even brought along Maria, who Jake hadn’t met up with before. He did know she had arrived on the floor, having gone to the ceremony at the Order and all, but that didn’t mean he expected her to participate.

One could say many things about Minaga’s city floor—few of them kind—but it was certain that it functioned as a nice gathering spot of geniuses. The record set by Jake’s party had even been broken about eight months back by a group from the United Tribes, led by a beast that reminded Jake of the Great White Stag.

Caleb and Maria soon joined them, and they all greeted each other. The two of them had faced the Demon Lord empowered by only one artifact, earning some mockery, while everyone else present had done it with all three on full power. Jake was kind of amazed the Holy Church had done it, considering Jacob was not a fighter, but he had shared that it was perfectly doable with Bertram able to revive. Having a guy who could use ultra-powerful items that would blow him up after use was quite an advantage. Jake still remembered that Holy Sword during the fight with the Monarch of Blood.

It was good to finally catch up with everyone, though for most it hadn’t been that long. Jacob did feel a bit out of place at times, but he took the constant jabs at the Church with grace, recognizing the faction was problematic.

A lot of blasphemy was definitely going on—that was for sure.

On a side note, this get-together consisted solely of pre-integration Earthlings. Sylphie and the Fallen King would not join them, partly because they were busy gathering more Minaga Coins to catch up, and partly because they wouldn’t fit in. Matteo had also rejected the invitation due to not fitting in, while Bertram just wanted to focus on gathering Minaga Coins.

The last person preparing to arrive was someone who didn’t care about failing to fit in, and someone Jake had not at all expected to actually bother. It was the healer that had mysteriously disappeared from Earth only to reappear at Nevermore with the Dao Sect. He had arrived with a party that was not only hailed as real contenders for the top spot, but had even broken the record of the group from the United Tribes, making them the current record-holders.

He was naturally talking about Eron, the last person invited. Arnold would have been, but he had yet to reach the city floor. Jake only heard about that group from scouts placed by the Court of Shadows, and the weird void party apparently stopped on every single city floor for quite a while and engaged with the Challenge Dungeons there before moving on. An odd strategy, but the entire theme of Arnold’s party was being weird as fuck, so it tracked.

Jake kept an eye on Eron through his sphere as he walked towards the large hotel room they had booked. He looked the same as before and did not wear much equipment, based on what Jake could see. The moment he entered the hallway leading to the room, Jake felt something he had not felt for a while bubble up from deep inside of him. He frowned as he suddenly began to feel… hungry. Famished.

When Eron appeared in the doorway, Jake had to restrain himself, as he nearly instinctively jumped the healer. Jacob went to greet Eron, but Jake remained seated as he clenched his fists, suppressing himself.

Fuck… Jake cursed the curse as he took a deep breath and forced down the feeling. He knew where it was coming from, too. As the wielder of a cursed weapon—one he had even tethered to his soul—it was natural to be influenced by it… but this was a first. Because looking at Eron, he felt an overwhelming sense of gluttony.

Eternal Hunger could smell the feast before it, and it wanted to dine.

“Are you okay?” Caleb asked Jake as everyone turned to look at him.

“Yeah…” Jake said with a sigh, returning his senses to reality.

Eron stood not far from him and smiled as he stretched out a hand.

Jake controlled himself enough to extend a hand and shake it as Eron raised an eyebrow and nodded. “Your control of the curse is… impressive.”

“Curse?” Casper practically jumped. “Oh, fucking hell—you are still walking around with that?”

“It’s a great weapon, just a bit hungry at times,” Jake said in his own defense, having properly reined in Eternal Hunger.

The curse was still lurking, but Jake was no longer filled with the same sense of starvation. Now it was just a slight buzz telling him to pounce, and that a wellspring of vital energy stood before him, reaching levels he could not even properly understand. Jake did wonder… if Eron had addressed his weakness to soul attacks, was he truly invincible unless some utterly overwhelming force appeared? Because as things were now... Jake got the feeling he wouldn't be able to do much to Eron, and he wondered if anyone else at their level could. Shit, he reckoned that the overpowered healer could have potentially soloed the Demon Lord at full power alone. It would have taken a damn long time, but it should be possible. This feeling did make him uncomfortable, but he knew Eron could not truly be invincible.

There must be a poison I can make, Jake told himself as Casper spoke once more.

“It’s a fucking Sin curse; the longer you keep it with you, the more it will embed itself in your soul until it one day becomes a part of you so significant you can no longer cut it out without severely hurting your Path permanently,” Casper explained, trying to be helpful. “As your resident curse expert, I would bloody know.”

“Well…” Jake shrugged as he took out Eternal Hunger.

Casper looked at it for one second before facepalming. “Fucking lunatic.”

“I shall take that as a compliment.” Jake smiled as he put the weapon away and turned his attention back to Eron. “I did not expect you to show up.”

“Why not?” Eron asked with a raised eyebrow and a smile.

“You disappeared from Earth without anyone knowing what happened, only to show up here with the Dao Sect, a notoriously reclusive faction. A faction I know is big on cutting out your prior life and dedicating your entire being to your Path.”

“I must admit I also find it… odd,” Jacob commented. “They are isolationists by default.”

“The Holy Church itself has a similar reputation,” Eron said, “yet you, Augur, find yourself in the company of a Runemaiden of Valhal, a Judge from the Court of Shadows, a mercenary in the service of Gwyndyr, the notorious Chosen of the Malefic Viper, a Transcendent blessed by Aeon, and finally, a student of the Dao Sect. Why is that, Augur?”

Jacob narrowed his eyes. “We are in Nevermore… and I have been given certain freedoms due to my position and what they expect of me.”

“Then perhaps I find myself in a similar situation,” Eron said with a nod, not sharing further.

“People will still talk,” Jacob pointed out.

“If mere words can sway one’s Path, then you have far to go.” Eron shook his head. “The opinions of others are of no consequence. Missing a meeting with all of my fellow Earthlings would only be a cause for regret.”

“Some of us do have to consider the impact our actions have on others,” Caleb put in. “Not everyone can act carefree.”

Jacob nodded at that. “True. The reason I am here is that out of everyone, I have the easiest time explaining my actions. I am an Augur, and my Path is to help others find their Paths. For me to talk to anyone and everyone is expected, and many believe I am meeting you all to try and bring you onto a Path aligned with the Holy Church.”

“Hey, I have a better reason,” Jake protested. “I don’t really care.”

“Perfect argument,” the Sword Saint said, chuckling.

Maria shrugged. “If anyone asks, I’m just a mercenary who was hired to be here.”

“And I am here because this was simply where my Path took me.” Eron finally smiled as he took a seat before turning to look at Jake. “Now, pray tell, how is our dear small planet doing these days, World Leader?”

Chapter 37

Agree to Disagree

“Earth?” Jake said to Eron. “Pretty sure it’s still there. It was the last time I checked. Speaking of, how did you even leave the 93rd Universe? The Dao Sect does not strike me as the kind of faction to have blessed beasts capable of setting up a formation capable of teleporting anyone to another universe.”

“It was not beasts, no,” Eron said. “I was invited by a temple that had prepared a teleportation circle for them to leave.”

“A temple?” Jake looked at Jacob and Caleb. “Was there a faction capable of constructing a cross-universe teleportation circle we didn’t know about?”

“I never heard of it,” Caleb said while shaking his head, with Jacob also looking unsure.

“You said it yourself; the Dao Sect likes its isolation,” Eron explained. “Earth is far bigger than any of us had time to truly comprehend, so is it truly that odd that some would have been hidden from sight? They never claimed a Pylon or engaged with anything system-related. They simply stayed at the old temple they had always lived in and, with guidance from the Dao Sect, constructed a way for them to join the faction properly.”

“I have been wondering, how is this Dao Sect related to those following ways of life similar to their beliefs before the system?” the Sword Saint asked.

“As I am sure you all know, Records bleed through to a new universe even before the integration,” Eron gladly continued. “It often ends up slightly warped due to the change in natural laws from an integrated and a pre-integration universe, but the influence is still stark. We see this with many religions and the Holy Church, but also with places like Valhal and entities such as Yggdrasil being known names even before the system integrated us. For the Dao Sect to also be present is only to be expected.”

“Huh,” Carmen said. “Not gonna lie… I never even bothered thinking about it. But I guess it does make sense that the Holy Church inspired those annoying fucks that go around knocking on people’s doors at all hours of the day, wanting you to join some shitty cult.”

“Records of Valhal created ripples that gave birth to pillaging rapists that raided the innocent all across the globe,” Jacob shot back.

“While the Holy Church taught us the goodness of burning women at the stake,” Carmen said, scoffing.

“Hey, they never changed that mindset,” Casper chimed in, throwing Jacob a glance. “They still want to purge everything that doesn’t fit their mold.”

“That… I can’t argue against.” Jacob sighed. “The attitude towards what the Church calls corrupted enlightened is not something I am a fan of.”

“Also, I never said Valhal were the good guys,” Carmen said. “Let’s not kid ourselves; all our factions fucking suck. Well, maybe not the Dao Sect, as I don’t know anything about them, but look at the rest of us. Evil snake god cult, assassin cult, death cult, ‘holy’ cult, fighting cult, mercenary cult… Actually, I guess the old man is the only one not part of any damn cult. Aeon doesn’t have a cult, right?”

“No cult, as far as I am aware,” the Sword Saint said, chuckling.

“But they do have fanatic fans of his watches,” Jake pointed out. “You know, the kind to buy an expensive watch and then somehow make that watch their entire personality.”

“So, still kind of a cult,” Carmen said with a nod.

“Touche.” The old man shook his head, taking the joke in stride.

“It is also a bit rude to call the Order of the Malefic Viper an evil snake god cult,” Jake protested in jest. “It’s an order, not a cult.”

“The least orderly order I know of,” Jacob cut in. “There is little control and support embedded in the organization’s structure. Perhaps it is good for the powerful, but the weak see none of this so-called order.”

“While the Holy Church only sees control of everyone.” Jake shook his head.

“Not entirely,” Jacob said. “Look at me. I am here right now, and if anyone in this room was part of the Church, you too would have immense freedom. Just not absolute freedom. There would still be consequences, expectations, and responsibilities, but is that really so big of a sacrifice? That you feel slightly inconvenienced at times to bring peace to a trillion living souls who were less fortunate than you? To them, your freedom becomes their fear, while the Church’s control becomes their safety.

“Is the Church perfect? No, far from it, but the multiverse is a wholly flawed place. There is no such thing as perfection, just making the best of a given situation, and I believe the Church will bring the most good for the largest number of people. Even if it does mean that sometimes sacrifices have to be made… Sacrifices nobody at the Church likes to make, but they still see the necessity of making. I wish it was not so, but the multiverse does not allow it to be otherwise, partly because of the uncontrolled freedom and selfishness of others.”

“Wow, you really are here to try and recruit us, huh?” Carmen raised an eyebrow. “It may just be me, but I would rather struggle for myself than be a comfortable slave.”

Jacob shook his head. “They are not slaves, and you have the privilege of being who you are. We all do. You can’t expect everyone to be like us or expect them to turn their entire lives into one long struggle.”

“Nor can you expect me to struggle to make them comfortable.”

“We are getting very political again,” the Sword Saint cut in once more. “But do let me offer some words from someone who has spent his entire life training and managing a large organization… It is hard. You can’t make everyone happy all the time, and in the end, it is rare that anyone can say what the right choice is when a hard decision is made. The same is true for the factions we belong to. They are all flawed in their own ways, and we can argue from now till we get kicked out of Nevermore and never agree. Ultimately, we belong to factions or have backers that fit who we are as individuals, and isn’t that as close as we can get to finding our perfect personal factions?”

Jacob and Carmen seemed to listen to the old man, nodding tentatively and letting the topic drop.

Jake just shrugged. “Or, if it isn’t perfect… just get strong enough to change it. Make it your own version of perfect. The Holy Church does what the Holy Church does because that is what the Holy Mother and the Holy Pantheon want. Reach a level where you can stand beside them and actually change shit if you want to make things better. It may take a while, but shit, if you’re aiming for godhood, you literally have forever.”

“You speak of godhood so casually.” Jacob shook his head. “Statistically speaking, the chances of any one of us even reaching S-grade is incredibly low, much less godhood. While it may be your dream and goal, I don’t believe it is healthy to anchor the changes you wish to bring about on the assumption you will ascend to divinity.”

“Sounds like the words of a pussy with no self-confidence,” Carmen said, scoffing.

“Or a realist with a clear head and no delusions,” Jacob shot back.

“To even reach for godhood is to not only delude yourself into grandeur, but to truly embrace that delusion… enough to one day make it into reality through your own actions,” Eron finally chimed in after being satisfied just listening for a while.

“Jacob, I do believe you misunderstand some things,” the Sword Saint said, shaking his head. “To many of us, godhood is not truly a goal, just an inevitable consequence of us walking our Paths. Either we will become gods walking this Path, or we will die with no regrets, having lived true to ourselves. At least, that is how I feel.”

“Then what is your goal?” Jacob asked the old man.

He smiled. “To live up to the name I have come to embrace. To truly make myself worthy of the title of Sword Saint.”

“And what will you do with all the power you accumulate through that pursuit?”

“That… doesn’t matter. Not truly. I do not gain power to use that power for anything in particular. I gain power to overcome my own self. To reach further and beat myself over and over again. I do not dwell on the why; I simply focus on the how. I have an innate desire to improve… to change. Not changing would be denying who I am. Getting stronger is not something you have to question. It simply happens, as that is the natural course of things.”

Jake listened in and nodded to himself. He saw Carmen do the same. This reminded Jake of one of the conversations he’d had with Villy about how important internal motivation was. To have that innate drive to progress, no matter what. Thinking about why you wanted to get stronger was a waste of time, in Jake’s mind.

“I guess we will just have to agree to disagree.” Jacob sighed. “I just don’t see the meaning in having power if you have nothing you want to accomplish with it.”

No one else commented on the matter after that, and the topic once more changed. Eron finally got to ask some questions about Earth, and it became clear he truly had no idea what was going on. He had only heard that Jake had become World Leader and found the notion amusing. The guy was also surprised when the Sword Saint explained the council they had established.

It also became obvious Jacob did know everything that was going on, proving that the Holy Church likely still had a lot of people on Earth yet to be weeded out. Spies left behind to keep an eye on things, or devout individuals who’d failed to evacuate in time and now hoped to make themselves useful for the Church. Yeah, Jake really didn’t like the Church either.

Catching up with everyone was nice, even if some people were a bit withheld when it came to giving information. Jacob and Eron didn’t share that much of what they had been up to, only giving snippets here and there. Casper, on the other hand, gladly told them all about how they were growing New Yalsten. The realm was also still attached to that meteor just flying through space towards who-knows-where. Not even Casper was sure exactly where they were going, but it sounded like they had some kind of target destination.

Jake already knew what Maria and Caleb had been up to, but they still shared a bit more, especially about their parties and how Nevermore had been so far.

The restrictions on sharing information about Nevermore only applied to people who had not passed a floor yet, so they could all discuss their journey through the mega-dungeon as much as they liked.

Jake found it interesting to hear how everyone had done the different floors so far. It was also good to hear that they unanimously despised that one horrible water floor, with Maria especially complaining about how shit it had been. Being a fire archer… Yeah, Jake totally got her.

When they reached the topic of Minaga’s Labyrinth, they naturally couldn’t avoid the topic of the dungeon master… and this was where Jake learned they’d truly had different experiences with Minaga.

“I believe he is an element primarily made to cause confusion and add a challenge to this part of Nevermore,” Jacob said. “I am not entirely sure why it was judged necessary for him to be here… but I am certain there is a good reason. Also, he is clearly not just some C-grade Unique Lifeform.”

“Minaga is just a dungeon master excited about his dungeon, and he is actively gathering feedback from those doing it,” Casper said. “I can’t see any problems with that.” He shrugged and continued, “Being excited about your own creation is not a crime, and the handiwork is honestly mind-boggling. I do also agree he is not a C-grade, and he is definitely a god or very close to godhood. If not, making the dungeon we have seen so far would be impossible. Overall, I would say he is pretty damn great.”

“Minaga is quite the figure indeed,” Eron said while nodding, not really saying more, though his subtle smile made it clear he knew more about the Unique Lifeform than he let on.

“Pretty sure the blue bastard has the ability to deal soul damage just by constantly talking,” Maria complained. “To make matters worse, my party leader decided to not engage with him at all, meaning he is just talking to us and not with us. Which results in him mainly throwing jabs and mocking all our failures.”

“For some reason, he kept referring to Matteo and me as the sneaky boys throughout the first three floors while also repeatedly alluding to me at least being better than a certain family member of mine,” Caleb said, more confused than anything. “He even went on a whole rant about how nice it was that being a cheater wasn’t a hereditary trait.”

“An interesting character that I must admit I do find amusing at times, though I do believe that is primarily because of a certain hunter on our team who has some good banter with the Unique Lifeform,” the Sword Saint shared with a chuckle.

“I think the live fight commentary was pretty good,” Carmen said, smiling. “He even managed to mimic the sound of those echoey microphones. It reminds me of when I used to do boxing, and it was especially fun versus the Demon Lord. We had a damn good brawl, the two of us.”

“Not gonna lie… I think Minaga just wants to be entertained.” Jake shrugged. “Trying to find logic in why he does what he does sounds like a waste of time. Also, live fight commentary?”

“Yep,” Carmen said. “It was pretty funny, and it honestly helped hype me up. Does that count as assistance? Also, only I could hear it. Nobody else in my party noticed a thing. He definitely did seem willing to slightly bend the rules if it would create a more entertaining scenario.”

Remembering when Minaga had begun collapsing an entire floor to push them onwards, Jake smiled. “Definitely does seem that way. Though there is also a sense of… balance to how he does things. Despite someone ‘cheating,’ he does not directly interfere to stop that person or punish them. Shit, just look at Ell’Hakan cheesing this entire city floor.”

“True… I guess that is slightly commendable, if infuriating,” Maria—one of Minaga’s biggest critics—agreed.

“Not sure I can entirely agree,” Jacob said, shaking his head. “The mist in the labyrinth makes sense to prevent groups from just blitzing through, but I find it downright malicious that divination isn’t just hampered, but turned downright detrimental. I had to actively fight following my skills and instinct during the entire labyrinth to avoid hurting my teammates.”

Casper chuckled. “I can’t lie… Divination purposefully leading you down the wrong Path is just funny. Let me tell you, dealing with fucking seers and Augurs like you is the most infuriating shit when you are trying to make a dungeon with any kind of exploration or mystery. I can only praise fucking over classes like yours for once. You shouldn’t complain too much, either. The skills were useful on that damn harem floor, right?”

Jacob still didn’t seem to agree, but he kept his mouth shut once he realized he was outnumbered. No one else in present company liked divination.

“Speaking of the harem floor, you should really share your stories from there,” Minaga chimed in, standing upside-down on the ceiling. “Quite a few hijinks went on while on that floor!”

“What in the actual fuck!?” Maria screamed as she saw him, with Jacob also jumping back and Caleb halfway standing. The rest of them stayed seated, including Jake.

“The same joke of suddenly appearing mid-conversation again?” he said, looking up at Minaga. “Sooo original.”

Chapter 38

A Truly Delusional Goal

Jake received varied reactions upon joking with Minaga. Casper smirked slightly, Carmen gave the Unique Lifeform a friendly wave, Caleb looked a bit worried, Maria was still not entirely over the guy just popping into the room, and Jacob looked more confused than anything. Eron and the Sword Saint both looked relaxed, with Eron bowing his head slightly, making Jake surer than ever that the guy knew something they didn’t about Minaga.

“A good joke begets repetition,” Minaga answered, still standing on the ceiling. “Plus, it works every time, so why not keep doing it? Just because you are never surprised doesn’t mean others can’t enjoy the experience.”

Throwing the startled people in the room a glance, Jake smirked. “They sure look to be enjoying your presence.”

“Who doesn’t feel happiness at my presence? Look at me; I am always in my own presence, and that has turned me into a very joyful and positive person.” Minaga stopped sticking to the ceiling and did a flip before landing on the floor. “For the record, Casper and Jake are both correct when it comes to their assessments of me. I monitor how people do my labyrinth to find places I can improve, but also to get a feeling for the general power level of the generation. It’s good research and valuable data.

“As for engaging with you while doing it… well, that is purely for entertainment purposes, of course! To add a unique flair of me to the experience, making my part of Nevermore truly stand out.”

“Does it not hurt the competitive integrity of Nevermore that you so openly interfere and engage with the individuals doing the dungeon?” Jacob asked, looking to have gathered some courage with all of them present. “Especially as you take a subjective disposition toward each party, either becoming a helpful or detrimental force?” He still did look pretty damn nervous just asking those questions.

“Eh, nothing is ever perfect,” Minaga said, waving him off. “With how varied the multiverse is, creating a truly balanced playing field is utterly impossible, and adding myself and my mostly meaningless commentary is such a small factor it isn’t worth mentioning. I have said it before, but if my talking and commenting are enough to throw you off your game and make you fail, then you have bigger problems. In other words, stop being so damn punctilious with how you think a dungeon is supposed to be run. The multiverse isn’t fair, and neither is Nevermore. What it does give is mostly equal opportunities, and so do I.”

“How is it mostly equal when some Paths are downright handicapped while others are assisted?” Jacob argued.

“How is it mostly equal when someone with a Bloodline or a Transcendent can walk in and ignore ninety percent of the challenges?” Minaga pointed out as he threw Jake a glance.

“How is it fair when some are not only immune but can use the fire energy of the Demon Lord to empower themselves?” he continued as he pointed at Maria.

“When others are borderline invincible, no enemy capable of breaking through their sheer level of durability or seemingly infinite health pool?” he went on, referring to both Carmen and Eron.

“Or… when someone is able to continuously resurrect a party member of theirs, allowing that party member to repeatedly burn their very life away to release suicide attacks over and over again?” he finished, looking straight at Jacob.

“My point is that you can cry about equality or fairness from now till the end of the multiverse, and you will sound like an idiot all the way.” Minaga smirked. “So embrace the unfairness and overcome it. That is how you become strong. I should know, seeing as I am a Unique Lifeform. I was born only being awesome and managed to overcome that fate to become amazingly awesome.”

“I, for one, commend assisting dungeon engineers,” Casper said, raising his hand.

Minaga smiled confidently at Jacob. “See, I have the crowd on my side.”

The Augur seemed to consider the Unique Lifeform’s words. Then he just sighed and nodded. “Very well… It is ultimately your creation.”

“Exactly. But if you do have any grievances, you can file a written complaint after you have completed Nevermore, and I will be sure to read it. I am not saying I will do anything, but I do read every written complaint we get.”

“How many written complaints do you even get a year?” Jake questioned.

“Well, we don’t really count them by the year… but at least one every million years or so,” Minaga said, nodding. “People just can’t be arsed to go through proper procedures to submit them, you know?”

“Pray tell, what are these totally reasonable procedures?” Jake smirked.

“Well, first of all, you need a written letter, right?”

“Right.” Jake nodded.

“And you need to go to Nevermore,” Minaga continued.

“Reasonable.”

“Exactly. Anyway, once at Nevermore, you just have to take the final step of handing the letter to the Wyrmgod or myself. See? Super simple.”

“Definitely simple and easy.” Jake grinned. “I am sure you two meet with anyone who comes by.”

“Of course we do! Sheez, what do you take us for? We meet with all gods that come by within the very reasonable waiting time of a single second to a few eras, based on how much we like the god that showed up.” Minaga capped his words off with a resolute nod.

“You just said again that you are actually a god,” Jake pointed out.

“That, I never did.”

“No, I am pretty sure you just implied it very heavily.”

“Circumstantial evidence is not solid proof of anything, and I deny all such accusations. It’s all hearsay!”

“Not hearsay when you were the one who said it,” Casper jumped in.

“Casper, I thought we were on the same team here,” Minaga muttered, looking all sad.

“You’re right,” Casper said, nodding and smiling before looking at Jake. “He is clearly not a god, and if you keep making such unfounded accusations, we will file an official complaint with the Order of the Malefic Viper based on your conduct.”

“Very well—I shall retract my slander immediately,” Jake said, going along with the joke as he stood up and bowed. “I apologize on behalf of my client—myself—and wish to settle this matter amicably.”

“Apology accepted; I am glad we could reach a settlement.” Minaga smiled wide, clearly having fun. Still smiling, he looked around the room. “Anyway, are there more questions? If not, then we must get to the juicy bits…”

“You mean…” Jake began as the Unique Lifeform grinned.

“Time to discuss the wonderful harem floor!”

“Oh, the thirty-fourth floor?” Jacob began. “That one was quite interesting, and we were—”

“Fucking boring is what you were,” Minaga said, disappointed. “You just made friends with everything that wasn’t a demon or the Prime Consort, and that was it. I am not saying that wasn’t allowed, just that it was thoroughly uninspired.”

Jacob smirked and lifted his hands defensively, not offended at all.

“Oh,” Caleb sighed. “I guess ours was also pretty uneventful.”

“You assassinated everyone and left the floor before anyone even knew you were there,” Minaga said. “You didn’t even exchange a single word with any living being outside of that first demon. It was pretty damn good to see the sneaky boys strike like daggers from the dark.”

Caleb smirked. “Well, then, glad you liked it.”

Annoyed, Carmen said, “Why the hell did we not do that? That would have been way better than trying to make friends with all those fuckers…”

“You punched the first Mistress you met because she tried to flirt with you,” Minaga said with a deadpan face.

“I thought she tried to attack me.”

“She tried to hug you.”

“Which can be considered an attack.” Carmen smirked. “But, hey, things ended well, didn’t they?”

With a light mood, they all shared their various experiences of the floor, with Carmen naturally going first. They had made the Second Mistress into the new Prime Consort and gained access to all the Secret Scrolls through that. Maria’s team turned out to have a demon on it, and through some proper subterfuge and powerful illusion magic from this demon, they’d managed to convince the Prime Consort that the demon would be a better candidate for the next Demon Lord…

Only for him to end up in the same situation Jake had experienced: Poisoned with the intent to throw him into a ritual. The difference was that while Jake had resisted the poison, this demon hadn’t, and the guy had been damn close to dying. Luckily, they’d managed to save him in time and kill the Prime Summoner. All of the Mistresses and even the Guard Captain had witnessed the Prime Summoner try to sacrifice him, and the group had managed to spin a tale where they had taken down the corrupt Prime Consort who wanted to replace the Demon Lord. From there, they’d been welcomed into the Demon Lord’s castle as heroes.

Casper had a pretty normal experience. They had worked with natives from earlier floors and made some allies and enemies on the thirty-fourth, initiated a vote, and started an internal conflict that ended up creating enough chaos for them to get the Secret Scrolls and move on before a new Prime Consort was even elected.

When they finally got to Jake and his party… Minaga had a hard time holding himself back as the Sword Saint gladly narrated their tale. The Unique Lifeform jumped into the conversation to confirm all the stupid stuff that had happened and even praised the Sword Saint for properly understanding the assignment when the floor was called a harem. They also all had a good laugh when Minaga took over and narrated Jake’s “flirting” with the Prime Consort. Jake had to threaten Minaga to stop him from sharing a recording of the entire scene, much to the disappointment of everyone present, especially Carmen and Caleb.

They continued to share some funny anecdotes before the attention turned to the last person in the room. Eron had been pretty silent, and the Sword Saint finally asked him directly, “How did you and your party take on that floor?”

Eron just smiled lightly as he looked at Minaga. The Unique Lifeform seemed powerless, sighing before speaking, “Well… the rules of the floor said you could not kill the innocents there… but… I guess the concept of death can have many interpretations.”

“We did not kill a single entity on that floor,” Eron said, smiling.

“Technically not”—Minaga shook his head—“but is there truly that big of a difference between what you did and just killing them?”

“Yes, there is,” Eron said, not a trace of doubt in his voice, “for they still live. Their sparks still burn… and do not try to convince me that the original, dull flames of their souls had any more meaning than what they do now. They were aimless vessels from the beginning.”

Minaga didn’t really say more, but he seemed to have lost some of his enthusiasm. “What a bummer. Anyway, my objective here is done, and I guess I should leave you all alone again. See you all soon, and I hope you continue to enjoy your time in my little city!”

With that, he was just gone. Seeing as the Unique Lifeform had left, the others also soon began taking their leave, with Jacob heading out first. The Sword Saint followed soon after, and the others trickled out one by one until two remained: Jake and Eron.

Jake knew that was no coincidence. He felt the gaze of Minaga still on them, but he threw a brief look toward the ceiling as he frowned, making the god back off. He seemed to understand Jake was about to say something he did not want to spread anywhere, and he respected that.

“I take it the gazes of all those curious are now dispelled,” Eron said in a relaxed tone.

“Why did you come here?” Jake asked as he nodded to confirm. “You were less than interested in the actual meeting, and I don’t believe you came just to learn about Earth.”

“I do care about my home planet, and I am glad to see it doing well,” Eron spoke as he leaned forward and looked at the floor for a bit. “But you are correct. My primary reason for attending was not to learn of Earth or those we share a home planet with. I came to seek you out, and I would’ve preferred that it happened under less suspicious circumstances than a one-on-one meeting.”

“Why?” Jake questioned.

Eron smiled. “You talked about goals for gaining power earlier… but none asked me.”

“Neither did you volunteer anything.”

“True, indeed… for my goal would perhaps be seen as more delusional than those of others,” the other Bloodline Patriarch said. “Have you read through the journal I gave you during the Treasure Hunt?”

“A bit of it, yeah.” Jake nodded. He had to admit, most of it was just mumbo-jumbo, but some insights had led to significant improvements in his health potions.

“Have you shared it with anyone else?”

Jake shook his head. “No.” Eron had given it to Jake, and sharing would have been pretty rude, as it clearly contained personal insights.

“I see,” the healer said with a tinge of regret. “Perhaps that is for the best, though I would have been curious what the Malefic One thought of my insights.”

“I can ask him when we next speak.” Jake shrugged.

“I do believe that would be for the best, but do also take this,” Eron said as he took out another journal. This one was even bigger than the other one, and after Jake accepted it and flipped through a few pages, he frowned.

“What even is this? This isn’t just soul magic… but….”

“No,” Eron said, nodding. “No, it is not.”

“What the hell…”

Jake kept flipping through, trying to get an understanding of what the hell Eron was researching. The more he skimmed, the more perplexed he became.

“Every living being has a spark… Even your Risen friend has one, though it is no longer a true flame. Yet it burns nevertheless. The problem lies in exactly this. My Bloodline allows me to see a spark—a representation of the vessel that holds the vital energy of all entities—but with some practice, I came to see more than just the vital energy. I could get glances at the soul, and only then did I understand why it was a spark. Because for there to be sparks… something has to burn.”

Eron looked deep in thought as he continued, “I saw a god after learning more of my powers, and the sparks of gods are truly different. Not just in intensity and power, but on a purely qualitative level. They are far different from what any grade evolution could possibly lead to, which made me question… What is this fundamental difference?” Eron went over and flipped to a page in the large journal.

Jake stared at the drawn diagram there for a second as his eyes opened wide. “You’re serious?”

“I am… and to do it, I acknowledge I may need all the help I can get, Harbinger of Primeval Origins,” Eron said with a deep, knowing smile. “Perhaps this ability of yours will be key, for we will need things not within the purview of the system.”

“This is beyond delusional… but…” Jake frowned more and more.

Eron truly did have a goal that was beyond what Jake had expected… What most expected, no less. While Jake and the Sword Saint wanted to reach the apex of power through their Paths, Eron did not. His mind had been far more singular from the beginning, and he had just one goal:

“I want to protect life… to never see that spark extinguish. To see them capable of forever growing. I realized one enemy is more dangerous than any other to all but the gods. That is when I understood the fundamental difference between all other grades and godhood. We are mortals… they are immortal. Their sparks burn eternally, their Truesouls producing an infinite amount of fuel.” Eron took a step back and smiled widely with an almost fanatical look. “I want to conquer the greatest enemy of all life in the multiverse… of all souls. I want to heal and cure the one ailment none but the gods can recover from, no matter how strong.”

“Time…” Jake muttered.

Eron’s goal was indeed that of a fucking lunatic…

He wanted to create a cure for mortality… or, at the very least, become able to heal away the march of time itself.

Chapter 39

Newcomers To Earth

Holstred looked at the blue sky above as he felt the sunlight on his skin. The planet he now found himself on was a bit cooler than the one he had been born on, but not by a large degree. Upon being informed they had been “gifted” to the owner of another world, he had feared that the environment would be unfriendly, but the climate was nice. Even those still in lower grades were comfortable.

Sighing, he turned to the woman who had just walked up beside him. Despite their situation, he failed to resist a small smile. “How is everyone settling in?”

“Some better than others… The teleportation took a toll on those in lower grades, but the healers said that they just need time to recover,” she answered as she took his hand and put it on her slightly bulging stomach. “We will be fine, okay?”

Holstred sighed again as he looked at his pregnant wife. “I know.”

He felt her stomach before grasping her hand and squeezing it as they both looked at the sun together, and he couldn’t help but remember better times. Times before they’d become slaves… A time before they had been given away to a powerful religious figure on another planet. At first, Holstred had actually hoped that leaving their home planet and the strained environment there could turn their fates for the better, but… now he doubted that.

Learning that their new owner was someone known as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper had not meant anything to Holstred initially, as he hadn’t known of this Malefic Viper. Only later had he learned they would be under the rule of what was essentially the divine prophet of a god with a less-than-stellar reputation… and that this Chosen was from an order of poison alchemists. Learning that had sent a shiver down Holstred’s spine.

I just hope my people can survive.

The world he and his family had come from hadn’t been a paradise either, but… it had been home. Their homeworld had been filled with strife for hundreds of years before the system even arrived, as war had been a constant thing between three races in never-ending conflict. The human empire Holstred had been a part of had long been considered the weakest compared to the dwarves and the Nirax, a scalekin race. However, neither faction had dared attack the human lands due to the fear of the other empire taking advantage of the opening. That was how a balance had been reached for centuries… until it was broken by the system initiation.

Holstred had been known as the Knight Commander in the lands of man—a grand title gifted due to Holstred’s strength even before the initiation, and with the arrival of the system, he had continued to prove his excellence. He had done well in the tutorial, gained a lot of levels, and returned to their home ready to fight for his empire… but things had gone downhill from the very beginning.

Their emperor had died in the tutorial, and nobody had had any idea who would take charge. Individuals who had gotten powerful began to cause trouble as dozens of minor factions sprang up, vying for control, and all the old nobles rebelled with the intent to take charge. They’d all seen the arrival of the system as their opportunity to become the new rulers of the empire, not even considering how that was only exacerbating the ongoing chaos.

They were fools who had never lived on the frontlines. Never known what a precarious state their empire had long been in. Unaware that should they show the slightest weakness, others sat ready to pounce.

So when the Nirax attacked, the expected had happened. They hadn’t been ready. Yet they’d fought back, Holstred on the frontlines from the very first day. Even if the empire hadn’t been ready, he had. War had raged for nearly two years, with intermittent system events and World Congresses that didn’t end in bloodshed due solely to the rules of the system. If not for the rules, that entire event would have been a slaughter, and with the rules, it had just turned into a shouting match that further fueled the hatred between the races.

Eventually, the nobles had gotten their internal issues resolved, and a temporary emperor had been selected. A fool of a man who had then entered an alliance with the dwarves to fight back against the Nirax. Things had finally seemed to be turning for the better, but Holstred had known it was all a mirage. The nobles did not see that the dwarves just used humanity as a meat shield to fight the Nirax for them while sending their own elites into dungeons or to fight monsters. They grew their armies as humans, and Nirax died on the battlefield. By the time they did realize this… it was too late.

As expected, the dwarves had turned on the human empire the second the Nirax were no longer a threat. What followed had not even been a proper fight.

The human armies had fallen, their top general slain, and in only a day, Holstred had gone from a war hero to the commanding officer of a broken army. He had made the difficult decision to surrender, hoping they could avoid a massacre. They had… but the cost was high.

Despite being in early C-grade, Holstred had been made to sign a slave contract. What he did not know was that in the background, the dwarves had joined a divine faction from the wider multiverse and taken in their teachings while expanding. The dwarves had long been an ambitious race, and they were showing that now by wanting to go beyond their planet.

Now, with the war over, Holstred had hoped things would calm down. However, the dwarves faced challenges from within, for despite being the victors, many still sought the total destruction of the humans and the Nirax. The enmity was simply too deep… their hatred too ingrained.

In the final battle, the entire Nirax army was annihilated, the majority of the population wiped out, with the remaining survivors thrown into ghettos and camps. Humanity had been slightly better off, but their lives were far from good. Yet many internal factions within the dwarven empire still wanted them wiped off the face of the planet.

Many had been killed during this period. Dwarves were the superior race, and some had enjoyed taking strolls in the slums, acting however they wanted toward both the humans and Nirax. Executions on the street had been normal, and people getting dragged off to scout dangerous areas commonplace. Everyone, even the dwarves, had known this was not sustainable.

That was when a dwarf had offered an alternative to genocide… Sell off the surviving humans and Nirax as slaves to other factions across the 93rd Universe. He’d quickly gotten support from the merchant families, and with the help of the divine faction, they’d begun selling off slaves. Humanity and the Nirax had been split into segments and sold off, with Holstred being placed “in charge” of this segment. Nearly a million people, ranging from F to D-grade, with only Holstred and a fallen noble—a former duke, now a Viscount, according to the system—in C-grade.

“I should head back,” his wife said after a while. Holstred still looked worried as she gave him a hug. “We will survive, alright? I believe in you; we all do,” she whispered into his ear as she gave him a peck on the cheek and then pulled back. “See you later, alright?”

Holstred nodded and stayed there, waiting. He would have joined her, but he had been called here.

Still staring at the warm sun, Holstred felt another woman approach. It was the one with the scarred face… Lillian was her name, he believed. He had only seen her once, when they’d first arrived on the planet. She’d handled their initial welcome.

“Holstred?” she asked, looking down at an odd, flat, metallic object with glowing glass.

“That is I, ma’am,” he said, bowing.

After being brought to Earth only two days ago, they’d been put in temporary residences. In all honesty, the accommodations were better than the broken capital he had come from. The fact that they hadn’t been treated too badly yet was a bit of comfort. That their new owner and many of the people in charge were also humans helped ease his worry slightly, too. Though, to be fair, every segment of slaves that had been brought to this planet was treated well, regardless of race.

Even so, he did not hold much hope. They had no incentive to treat their new slaves badly right now, but neither did they have any incentive to treat them overly well. Initially treating your slaves well was also a common strategy for many noble families back in the old empire, as that ensured they worked well for longer, hoping that through hard work, the good days could return. Back then, Holstred had seen them as naive… Now, he questioned if they’d simply never had a better choice.

“Follow me, please,” Lillian said, only briefly looking up from her odd magical device. “Miranda is ready to see you.”

Holstred bowed and followed. Miranda… the one the Chosen had put in charge of his planet. At least, that was what he’d been told before even arriving on this planet and by the woman walking ahead of him during the welcome. Outside of her identity as the current leader of the planet, she was also a direct disciple of the Verdant Witches—gods that made the divine beings the dwarven empire served pale in comparison.

It is time to learn of our fate, Holstred told himself, trying to stay stoic. He knew what this Order of the Malefic Viper often did with slaves, and he hoped his people could avoid that. All he could hope to do was appeal to the woman’s humanity, though he doubted it would work. She was a witch, after all—a Path not known for mercy or kindness.

“Just inside,” Lillian said after showing him the way to a large tent with several magical formations around it. Holstred once more bowed, knowing not to speak out of turn lest he offend her.

Entering the tent, he saw the woman in question sitting at a table with several stacks of paper in front of her. She seemed busy but instantly noticed when he entered and looked up.

“Ah, there you are,” the witch said. “Holstred of the Silver Knights, was it?”

He knelt before her. “I was once known as such, yes. How may I serve my new mistress?” In a situation like this, he did feel lucky that his father had made him learn etiquette and that he had practiced meeting the imperial family of old. He also knew that showing full subserviency would serve him best… At least, he hoped so.

“No need for the courtesy,” his new mistress said, looking like she was already tired of his way of acting. “Please get up and take a seat.”

“I apologize if I caused any offense,” Holstred tried again, but she once more waved dismissively.

“Please sit. Then we can talk properly, alright?”

“Yes,” Holstred said, biting his tongue just as he was about to call her mistress again. He went and sat in the chair directly opposite her, which he did find slightly inappropriate. It appeared he had much to learn about this planet’s culture, and he truly feared he had offended her.

“So, I have read some basic information about where you came from, but my understanding is that you and the people with you are remnants of a fallen empire that lost a war. Is that correct?”

“It is as you say,” he confirmed.

She nodded. “Alright. We already sent some healers to talk to people and make sure they are handling everything okay, especially the children. While we are all far more resilient both physically and mentally than before the system, it is still better to find and treat cases of trauma early on rather than delay. We also interviewed a few people from the same planet as you, and they all spoke highly of you, Knight Commander. You at least seem to have earned their respect and led them well during this time of strife, and I hope you will continue to do that, as the coming time may continue to be tumultuous.”

“I shall do my utmost in whatever task we are given…” Holstred said, not sure what he should say. The first part about the children was also… Was it to make sure they would be more productive? Did they need them to be clear-minded for some specific purpose?

“You aren’t given any tasks, per se, but you are given choice,” their mistress said as she cleared away some of the papers and looked him in the eye. “What do you want to happen here on Earth? What kind of future do you hope for? Answer honestly, and don’t just say something to placate me. I have heard plenty try to do that already today.”

Holstred was taken aback for a moment, not sure what to say. But he did detect honesty in her voice, and he believed it unwise to lie. So he took a risk. Gritting his teeth, he answered truthfully, “I wish to ensure our survival. And… perhaps one day… freedom.”

It was truly a gamble to tell your new mistress you wanted to get out of serving her.

“Be a bit more ambitious,” the witch said with a smile, leaning back.

Holstred shook his head. “I… I am unsure. I do not think I can speak for everyone, only my own selfish desires.”

“What are these selfish desires?”

“To rebuild some of what was lost… and find a new home for myself, my family, and all I hold dear,” Holstred managed to say.

The witch raised a brow. “And do you believe those who follow you want that too?”

“Yes.”

“All very doable,” the woman said, nodding with a smile. “All I will ask of you is to draw up a plan for how you want to make this happen and ensure you have enough personnel to act autonomously. Considering the size of your group, I hope you have enough internally. If not, we may have to discuss bringing in others to make sure everything runs smoothly. If there are any competent people you believe could facilitate the transition, please bring them to our next meeting. We have people on our side handling surveying and finding a proper spot you can settle in.”

Holstred was confused as he watched his mistress going over some papers.

She noticed his confusion and looked back at him, seeming to stumble upon a realization. “Ah, I totally forgot to mention it. Lord Thayne—the Chosen of the Malefic Viper—is not a fan of slavery, so we will be nullifying all of your slave contracts once we are done organizing everything. Ah, but let me fix yours right away. Where was yours again…? Ah, here it is.”

His mistress took out a black book he had signed the slave contract in… and a second later, she was no longer his mistress.

Holstred stared in utter confusion as she smiled. “Congratulations. As of this moment, you are free. But do take this and remember to read it over. Not being a slave doesn’t mean you are free from the law, after all.”

His former mistress handed him a small folder reading “Welcome to Earth: Starter Guide,” and he had barely gotten it in his hand when Lillian entered again.

“Take Holstred here back to his group and go find me… What was her name again?… that elven lady we talked about earlier,” Miranda said as she looked once more at Holstred. “It was a pleasure meeting you, and I hope things work out well for everyone. Please spread the word to those under your influence. In a week, we will fetch you again, so have the plans ready for then, alright? We have high expectations for you, and don’t worry—once things calm down, we will look into expanding the political structure of the planet to involve you all.”

“I…” Holstred said, trying to control himself. He questioned so many things. Was this all a bad joke played on them? He did not understand… but if it was real…

“Tha… Thank you.” He bowed, this time with true sincerity.

“You have nothing to thank me for. I am just doing what I should.” Miranda smiled radiantly as Holstred was led outside and back toward the small city of tents and temporary housing his old empire now occupied.

On the way, it finally hit him. He stopped mid-walk. The slave mark on his soul left by the contract… He felt for it… and it was truly gone. Looking down at his hands, he saw them shaking. Taking a deep breath, he clenched them… but it didn’t help, and for the first time, his stoic demeanor broke.

I’m… We’re free?

Holstred had spent the last many months of his life fighting to accept his status as a slave… fighting for his family and all he cared about. Hoping that even if he lived as a slave, perhaps his unborn child would one day be free.

Only to be freed the moment his life as a slave was meant to truly begin. He just stared ahead as tears slowly welled up in his eyes, the realization finally sinking in fully.

We’re free…

Chapter 40

Fun Times Ahead

Jake was left alone in the meeting room, pondering his conversation with that absolute madman Eron.

Some rules of the system were known to be absolute… and the line between mortality and immortality was one of them. It was a fundamental law for a reason, and one that had never been broken in the history of the multiverse, as far as Jake knew. At least… as far as he knew before his meeting with Eron. Because the other Bloodline Patriarch had shared that, a long time ago, one individual had broken this rule.

One immortal mortal, if you may.

Jake had wanted to ask more, but Eron had refused and asked Jake to question the Malefic Viper instead. No matter how much he’d pressed, the healer had been utterly unwilling to share more.

Shortly after that, Eron had departed, leaving Jake to reflect. After a time, he’d wondered… was it truly a good goal? Was giving immortality to everyone even a good thing?

People dying was, as cruel as it sounded, necessary. Most enlightened beings never even reached D-grade during their lives, but even so, a single human could live hundreds of years. In that time, it was pretty common to have dozens of children. If all these children also grew up to have dozens, even a planet like Earth would be utterly overpopulated in just a few centuries.

Even now, wars and such were customary on low-level planets to cull populations. Yet even with these measures, age was likely the primary killer for most beings in the multiverse. Many individuals in high grades reached points in their lives where they believed that further evolution was not an option, and they thus chose to settle down and create families or nurture their factions. Not to mention the many people who never cared about battle to begin with, but only focused on their professions. If these people who never fought lived forever… Jake wasn’t even sure the system would allow it.

There was also the problem of Eron—to put it nicely—not giving a flying fuck about other people or who they were as individuals, nor what was good for the multiverse as a whole. All he cared about was them not dying. Not once did he consider that the “gift” he wanted to give the multiverse could be a curse to some.

Immortality was not necessarily a good thing. It took a certain mindset to handle, and Villy had mentioned that this mentality was rare but a fundamental requirement for attaining godhood. What would happen to someone becoming immortal that did not have the mindset for it? Insanity? Would they ultimately end their own lives?

There were many thoughts in his head, but Jake did recognize they were likely useless for two reasons.

First, the chances of Eron achieving this goal were minuscule. He wanted to do something countless others had tried before, and while he did have his Bloodline, would that truly be enough? Even if he got help from others with Bloodlines and Transcendents, Jake refused to believe others hadn’t tried that before in the trillions of years the multiverse had existed. Even if Eron succeeded, Jake doubted it would be anytime soon, in which case it would be a future-Jake problem.

Second, Jake knew the system still did have some restrictions that not even Bloodlines or Transcendents could overcome. The most obvious one was that everything used something—a law of exchange, so to speak. Not necessarily an equivalent exchange, but few things were free. That was why the Sword Saint could not just instantly have created a Transcendent that turned him into a god then and there. He had to instead pay with levels for the power he gained. Jake’s own infusion of Records related to Primeval Origins was similar, as the system had restricted him in how often he could do it without fundamentally harming himself. It likely knew that a Jake capable of mass-producing pinnacle-level creatures would be too imbalanced.

So, what would be the price of granting someone else immortality? Sacrificing other lives? No, it could not be that simple. Jake thought for a good while and concluded that it was likely the system would never even allow Eron to create a method to make everyone immortal… but if it was just healing the impact of time? To—using his metaphor—refuel the Truesouls of others, giving them more years of life?

That… could be possible. With help, of course. Eron would need assistance from many people, but there would be just as many opposing it, Jake reckoned. As with Sanguine, anyone breaking the power balance established by the gods would find themselves facing much opposition. Jake had faced this with his special ability, too. One could just look at the Automata Legion, which was less than keen on him at the moment.

Ultimately, Jake didn’t want to rule out the mad healer’s goal. Even if Eron’s goal was utterly delusional, he was not the only one Jake knew who had such far-fetched dreams. The healer actually reminded Jake a bit of Arnold and his goal of fully comprehending the entire multiverse and the system through the power of math. It was so utterly outrageous Jake could only respect it. They both had goals that weren’t just “get strong,” but still required them to reach such high levels of power before they would become feasible that, by the time they succeeded, they would be approaching the pinnacle either way. To them, power was just the means to an end—the end being so far out of sight it wasn’t a demerit whatsoever.

Shaking his head, Jake tried to dispel the thought as much as he could. Worrying right now was useless when the possibility of Eron’s dream even becoming a reality was so low. For now, he would shelve even thinking about it and instead discuss it with Villy after he was done with Nevermore. That sounded like what Eron hoped he would do anyway.

Jake smiled a bit to himself, reflecting on all the people from Earth he had just met up with. They all had their own goals and aspirations, some grander than others. The person he was most worried about was Caleb… He was his little brother, after all. He had not shared it with the group, but Jake knew his goal was quite simple: He wanted to protect his family. That in itself was a good goal to have, but it was rarely—if ever—a Path that led one to the pinnacle.

Umbra had likely known this, too, which was part of the reason he’d gotten the Legacy of Tenlucis. The Path of Tenlucis was essentially about forcing someone to keep progressing or die from the pressure of the dark heavens crushing you to death. It would force Caleb to keep going even when he wanted to sit still, and while it was selfish of him, that gave Jake some relief.

Jacob was even worse off than Caleb, Jake recognized, but he didn’t feel the same sense of worry. One was his little brother, and the other was just his old boss and friend from work. It was his own problem if he didn’t have the right mentality to go all the way. If he wanted to get on a Path to godhood, he had to find it himself.

Feeling done with reflecting on the group, Jake left the hotel room and headed towards one of the many alchemy labs to get some proper crafting done and rake in those last Minaga Coins, which would let them finally move on and explore the rest of Minaga’s Labyrinth.

Time passed as Jake continued grinding out alchemical creations to afford his Minaga Coin toll. He ended up being a lot slower than the Sword Saint, who finished only a week after their meeting by dumping his entire “art” collection on the Brokers.

It still took Jake nearly three months to finish, as his speed had slowed down a bit. He did not rush as much, and even mixed in some experimentation here and there. Dina finished collecting her Coins shortly afterwards, yet they would have to wait a little while for Sylphie and the Fallen King no matter what. It also didn’t help with motivation that his leveling speed felt significantly slower, though he did manage to rake in two more levels.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 225 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 226 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 222 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

And, as mentioned, he was good on Minaga Coins.

Current Minaga Coins: 214,390/214,000

Now Jake just had to figure out what the hell his plans were as the others also got ready. As things were, he saw a few options.

The first was to continue grinding alchemy while focusing more on experimentation. This one was slightly problematic in the sense that Jake would still feel some diminishing return due to him having just churned out stuff for over one and a half years. He also didn’t know what kind of foes he would face on later floors, so even if he wanted to research a new kind of poison, he had no idea what he should focus on.

A second option was to try some of the Challenge Dungeons. The Sword Saint had considered this, but Dina had discouraged them both. According to Nature’s Attendant, it was best to focus on all the Challenge Dungeons as late as possible to get as powerful as one could. At least for some of them. The problem was that you didn’t know what kind of Challenge Dungeon you would find yourself in before entering, and as with Nevermore’s general rule of information-limiting, people couldn’t share what they knew of the Challenge Dungeons either. Dina had also mentioned that these Challenge Dungeons often had a very set “theme” and progressively got more difficult, making one go further on average if they were attempted later. The final nail in the coffin was that some of them had limited attempts, and entering and leaving again counted as one attempt. Jake had chosen to take this advice and wait.

The third option was to use the charge of Path of the Heretic-Chosen he had gained when he reached level 220 in his profession. When he had initially gained the charge, Jake had considered using it, but in the end, he had delayed. His problem with the skill right now wasn’t that he didn’t know what to use it on… it was that he had too many things to use it on. One had to remember that the charge had gone from only working on his “of the Malefic Viper” skills to now working on a shitload of things.

“Focusing on any core skill, event, or entity related to the Malefic Viper’s Legacy will allow you to peer into the True Records of the past as you journey through time, space, and reality to experience history firsthand.”

What was it called again? Decision paralysis? Choice overload? Jake wasn’t sure, but whatever the hell it was called, Jake felt like he had so many choices it was difficult to make one. The problem was made worse by the fact that he felt he could now choose any of the nine Legacy skills, as the requirement of adequate understanding was also gone.

But… he could also focus on the First Sage, as he was incredibly curious about that guy. Shit, Jake even considered checking out the other Primordials if he could. He had already seen Valdemar in one vision and gained a lot from it, so should he see a vision with him again? Maybe someone else? Eversmile, perhaps?

There were also events, though that one was a bit harder, as Jake was not clear on that many interesting events. Not much was known about the First Era before the point at which the different Primordials rose to godhood. Jake also felt that there were some things he could not see. As an example, he poked the skill to see if it would show him the moment the Malefic Viper gained his Transcendence or when he ascended to godhood, but both of those were no good. Whether it was because they were not “related to the Malefic Viper’s Legacy” or because the system had restricted the skill in some way, Jake didn’t know.

Ultimately, Jake just couldn’t choose. He kind of wanted to focus on a skill to try and upgrade it, but without the requirement for him to understand it, how would he even know it could help him? No, he wanted to wait and use it when he felt like he truly needed it, and that time just wasn’t right now.

That left Jake with the fourth option, his original idea for what he would do when he was done collecting Minaga Coins. It still seemed like the most attractive choice.

He was gonna play with his puzzle box.

[Puzzle Box of the Seeker (Divine)] – A puzzle box created by the god known as the Seeker. This box is filled with a total of ten thousand levels of mana puzzles of ever-increasing difficulty. Fully unlocking the box will reveal an item sealed within. Soulbinds to anyone who beats the first level. Levels completed: (1/10,000).

This was probably Jake’s favorite gift from the entire Chosen ceremony. Sure, all the other items had been nice, and Jake had used quite a few of them during this crafting session—such as the items gifted by the Risen—but this one still stood out.

He had loved the practice cauldron Villy had given him back during the intermittent period between the tutorial ending and his arrival on Earth, and this one gave off similar vibes. This was not quite the same, as it didn’t focus on just alchemy but was more about general mana control.

Mana control was very much like practicing with any weapon or tool, and from the very first time Jake had interacted with Villy, the god had emphasized the importance of improving his control. Getting better at mana control improved your alchemy skills and your abilities as a mage or ritualist… Anything that required mana, really. Usually, one just practiced using mana for practical things or while using all skills, but puzzles like this weren’t that rare either. Jake had even done one during the Treasure Hunt when he first met Reika.

This puzzle box was, needless to say, on an entirely different level than anything he had ever done before. The first level had been incredibly easy, as it was just a method to Soulbind the item, but when he took out the box and infused energy into it this time, his consciousness sank into the box, and he instantly realized things would not continue to be that easy.

Jake had also had his mind transported to this place when he initially bound it to himself, and back then, he had just seen a few squiggly lines that didn’t properly align with each other, requiring simple fixes.

However, this time he found himself surrounded by broken lines of pure mana, tangled messes, and mana in pure disarray. Jake looked at the absolute mess in front of him and couldn’t help but smile. If this was still only level two… man, did he have a lot of fun ahead of him.

Chapter 41

Finally Done

Jake analyzed the structure and noticed several errors in it. The structure in question looked like a large, square building, at least twenty stories tall and made of pure mana. It was hardened and reminiscent of Jake’s stable arcane mana, but it was indeed just pure mana formed into a shape and then compressed and strengthened through formations.

His job was to bring the structural integrity up to a certain level, but to do that, he had to address flaws embedded within the structure. Not just on the outside, either. This meant he had to “drill” holes and infuse mana to fix what was wrong before he could cover everything up again… all while making sure his actions didn’t cause a collapse.

Since several formations also covered the building, he had to avoid those too. How long it took him, Jake didn’t know, but he quickly found flaw after flaw, and in many cases, he had to make up new methods on the spot to fix a particular problem. His preferred method was to strengthen the mana using hardened, braided mana strings that almost functioned as rebar.

Due to its nature as a mana puzzle, Jake couldn’t use his arcane affinity, but he could infuse some concepts from it. It reached a level where the normal mana was nearly identical to his arcane mana, though there were still some stark differences, such as the sheer gap in durability between the two and the far more physical nature of his stable arcane mana. While a powerful enough disruptive mana wave could make the “solid” structure in front of him collapse, it wouldn’t be able to do the same to his arcane mana.

After an undetermined amount of time, Jake nodded. Everything seemed good. With a thought, a prompt appeared before him.

Submit Completion?

This was something else Jake had learned. The puzzle box was programmed to respond to things he did and worked a lot like a computer program, even able to summon system prompts while his consciousness was immersed within it. In some ways, entering a box was a lot like entering his Soulspace.

Jake confirmed his submitted completion. Suddenly, pressure washed over the mental landscape, feeling similar to a manifold increase in gravity. Jake himself was utterly unaffected, as he had been turned completely intangible, also making him unable to interfere with the test.

The building held firm, but then a powerful wind of pure mana came in from the side… which was when Jake saw he had slightly damaged one of the formations around the ninth floor. A part of the wall crumbled, and the wind invaded the structure, ravaging through it. Within seconds, the entire mana structure collapsed and dispersed into nothingness.

Level failed. Retry?

I’ll get it this time!

Yeah, this wasn’t his first attempt…

Retrying, the building reappeared, but it was not exactly identical. The difficulty level was the same, but the test itself was different. The formations were similar but placed in different locations, the flaws were altered, and the building itself had slightly changed, this time featuring twenty-one stories.

This was naturally done so one couldn’t just try the same level over and over again until they completed it. It was a test of skill, after all, not pure trial and error.

This time around, Jake fixed everything he could find and made sure to strengthen certain sections of the building he feared weren’t strong enough to handle the stress. After double-checking everything, he once more got the system prompt.

Submit Completion?

Like last time, he approved, and the pressure reappeared. This time the building held, and even when the disruptive mana wind swept through, none of the formations were dismantled. The entire stress test went on for about two minutes before everything stopped, and then he got another prompt.

Level 54 completed. Proceed to level 55?

Jake said yes and appeared on the next level. This one was a massive, hanging bridge of mana, and Jake’s analysis made him instantly aware that this task involved ensuring the bridge could stably bear a certain weight for at least one year in a sped-up stress test. However, he did not get far, for within his Sphere of Perception, he saw something he’d hoped would not happen…

The Sword Saint was walking towards his room… which could only mean one thing: Sylphie and the Fallen King were done collecting their damn coins. The Golden Mark left by the King tended to expire after a few weeks, which was why the old man had to go get him in person.

It was with mixed feelings that he emerged from the box. He looked down at the precious object for a moment and smiled.

[Puzzle Box of the Seeker (Divine)] – A puzzle box created by the god known as the Seeker. This box is filled with a total of ten thousand levels of mana puzzles of ever-increasing difficulty. Fully unlocking the box will reveal an item sealed within. Soulbinds to anyone who beats the first level. Levels completed: (54/10000).

After giving the best puzzle box in the world a hug, he put it away and stood up. Checking the time, he saw he hadn’t moved from the floor in about a month, so he stretched a bit and went towards the door, ready to open it the second the old man knocked.

The bastard never knocked, instead standing outside for a moment before saying, “Jake, I know you know I am here.”

“Can you knock anyway?” Jake asked.

“No.”

“Please?”

The old man sighed as he reached out, but just before he could knock, Jake opened the door while grinning. “You were totally surprised, right?” Jake joked.

“Truly,” he said, shaking his head. “I assume you know why I am here?”

“Sylphie finally got enough Minaga Coins?”

“Precisely,” the Sword Saint said, nodding as Jake walked out and began following the old man out of the hotel. “And she is not happy about being the last one to complete her coin gathering. She has not complained as much as the Fallen King, though.”

“Not gonna lie… it’s about bloody time,” Jake said. “Did Carmen and her party manage to get ahead of us?”

“She did. They left just a week ago.”

“Fuck me,” Jake grumbled.

“Disappointed she did not say goodbye?” the Sword Saint teased.

“Nah, we already talked about limiting our interactions in this period leading up to her leaving, and with Jacob and Casper also heading out, we had fewer excuses to meet. Her going to say goodbye would have been weird from an outsider’s perspective.” Jake shrugged. It wasn’t like she hadn’t come by quite a few times during their shared time on the floor. “Just hoped we would at least beat them.”

Jake did also regret not having a proper bout with Carmen in the arena. Both of them had wanted a duel, but sadly there was no way to have private fights. With how durable Carmen was, Jake would likely have been forced to go all-out, and he wanted to hide some of his abilities if he could. Especially skills like Eternal Shadow, which were incredibly effective when used without the opponent being aware of them. Jake not using his full power would also be disrespectful to Carmen. So, in the end, they’d agreed to postpone their duel.

“The scientist from Haven also reached the floor. Are you going to go greet him before we leave?”

“Arnold? Nah, he is a big boy; he can handle himself.” Jake shrugged. “Besides, I reckon he would have reached out to me if he wanted anything. He isn’t the type to just wait around.”

“How about your brother or Maria?” the Sword Saint asked.

“Already did before my last practice session, as I quite frankly expected us to have already moved on by now,” Jake said, shaking his head.

“I see.” The old man nodded, not saying more as they kept walking.

It was a bit annoying, but Jake and company had ended up taking just over two years doing Minaga’s city floor. Sylphie had been the big limiter in how fast they could pass the floor, as the deck was honestly stacked against her.

She was the highest-leveled of them all, which meant she had the biggest toll to pay, but she also had the problem of her marketable skills being limited. She couldn’t craft anything, and when it came to tasks she could assist with, she was equally limited, as many of these tasks required knowledge or skill in certain disciplines.

Sylphie was simply too young to have ever learned anything complex, and all her powers came from instinct and her powerful innate knowledge as a beast. Sadly for her, none of this innate knowledge helped her anywhere outside of the arena.

Jake and the others did help her as much as possible. She sold items they had obtained within Nevermore and reached the cap for how many coins she could earn every single month, but that only did so much.

The two of them quickly walked together to the toll booth, where they met up with the three others. Sylphie was indeed a grumpy bird, with the Fallen King looking more than a little impatient to finally get a move on. Dina looked fine and gave them a small wave when she saw them approaching.

“About time you arrived,” the Fallen King said when they made it over.

“Well, excuse me for adding another five minutes to this city floor. When was it you got done collecting your coins, again?” Jake smiled teasingly.

“Let’s just proceed,” the Unique Lifeform said, really seeming to be in a hurry.

Jake proceeded to activate the toll booth together with the Sword Saint, allowing them to walk through the gate leading to the next floor. The moment he paid, Jake got a system prompt that he had honestly forgotten was even a thing.

Bonus Objective Completed: Pay the Toll to leave the city floor without ever leaving Nevermore. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

“Five hundred points, huh?” Jake said with a small smirk.

“Yeah, not a lot… but it is something, isn’t it?” Dina answered, trying to be positive.

The Fallen King scoffed. “An amount so low it is almost insulting. This entire floor has just been a useless waste of time.”

Jake shook his head. “Could have been more productive for sure, but I won’t call it a total waste of time.”

True, it had been pretty damn inefficient when it came to gathering Nevermore Points, but that didn’t mean it had been a waste of time. They had all stayed in contact during this time, and based on the slow increase in the number of opponents the Fallen King and Sylphie had killed in the arena every day, the two of them had clearly improved. The many tasks Brokers gave also required the person to gradually get better.

Jake and the Sword Saint had also naturally progressed their professions quite a bit, with Jake even improving his mana control with his puzzle box. The Sword Saint hadn’t sat still either, instead choosing to continue painting even when he didn’t need it for Minaga Coins, as he’d wanted to rack up some more profession levels. In his words, it was rare he had calm periods like this to just relax and paint, and his diminishing returns seemed milder than Jake’s for some reason.

“Perhaps not a total waste, but can you truthfully say you wouldn’t have preferred to do without?” the Fallen King countered.

“Well, if you put it like that…”

“Ree!” Sylphie joined in on the complaining.

“Who is delaying our progress now?” the Sword Saint butted in as he motioned for them all to proceed. “The thirty-sixth floor awaits.”

The old man was right, so they stopped dragging things out and moved through the barrier blocking the entrance to the next floor. Through this barrier was just another gateway, and without further ado, they all activated it and were teleported away.

They appeared within a vaguely familiar room. It gave Jake the same vibes as the usual “welcome” room they had first seen on the thirty-first floor, but it all seemed a bit more… highbrow? The oldish-looking temple walls had been replaced with pristine marble, and overall, it just looked more well-kept.

“About time you arrived here. That took quite a while, huh?” Their dear dungeon master’s voice echoed as he appeared on the central platform, though there were no fireworks or big displays.

“And whose fault is that?” Jake instantly countered.

“Not mine, if that is what you are insinuating,” Minaga said. “You can’t blame me for you being slow.”

“You designed the rules of the city floor.”

“That I did, but doesn’t that just mean you are even more at fault? Because me being wrong couldn’t be the case, hence why it must be entirely on you. Definitely.” Minaga nodded confidently to himself.

“Fine, we suck. Happy?” Jake sighed. “Now, what’s the plan from here?”

“Five more floors of my labyrinth,” the Unique Lifeform answered.

“Huh… don’t you think it is kind of beginning to overstay its welcome?”

“Hey, I tried to mix it up!” Minaga said, seeming offended. “These next four floors—with a special surprise on floor forty—are all of an identical design with only slight changes, but they offer something interesting nearly no other dungeon floor does: true choice!”

“But it is still a labyrinth?” Jake asked.

“Yes, there are still labyrinthian features.”

“So…”

“Yes, you will be able to utterly cheat and spoil all sense of exploration, ruining much of the fun of the floor… but not as much as on some of the others,” Minaga answered, looking like he had entirely given up on trying to stop Jake from cheating.

Jake smiled. “Nice. Just wanted to make sure.”

“Now, as with prior floors, I will once more need you to make a difficult choice—better known as a difficulty choice,” Minaga said, very proud of his wordplay.

“Do we have the same options as on prior floors?” the Sword Saint asked.

“Yep… and can I just assume you will choose the Archmage difficulty? Anything else wouldn’t really make any sense.”

“Naturally,” the King answered.

“Great, great,” the dungeon master said, nodding. “Now, I do know you suffered a bit during my wonderful city floor and aren’t all that happy, so let me give you a tiny little tip to cheer you all up. This is not the only time on this floor that you will have the choice of taking an easier or harder path… and if you want the best ending, don’t ever take the easy route. Always strive for the highest difficulty.”

Jake smiled again. “Duly noted.”

“Now, with all that over, I hope you enjoy this floor and those to come! I will add one more thing… I kind of learned that characterization is not my strong suit, so that is very limited in these next few floors…” Minaga looked a tad embarrassed at that.

“Probably for the best,” Jake said, nodding as he teased the totally-not-a-god. “Not only because the ‘people’ were bloody horrible imitations of real sapient creatures, but because it makes life harder for assholes who are good at manipulating them. A pleasant surprise to see you can learn from your mistakes.”

“I will just choose to interpret those very hurtful words as you venting the last of your anger towards the city floor,” Minaga said with a smile, unbothered.

Jake nodded again. “Totally was.”

Minaga kept smiling and offered an exaggerated bow. “In either case, I believe I have taken up enough of your time… Without further ado, let us continue Minaga’s Labyrinth!”

With those words, the Unique Lifeform disappeared, and the giant, glowing gate at the far end of the room began opening. Out came the mist that restricted all senses and movement, and Jake did not hesitate to close his eyes and send out a Pulse of Perception just as the system message for the floor also popped up.

Welcome to the thirty-sixth floor of Nevermore: Minaga’s Labyrinth (Part 6)

Main objective: Reach the end of the Labyrinth.

Bonus objectives: Complete the floor while selecting and completing the room with the highest difficulty rating at least three times (0/3).

Current progress: Highest-difficulty room completed (0/3), end reached (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 28,973

Jake read over the description. Coupled with his mental map from Pulse of Perception, he did have to admit… this part of the labyrinth was kind of different.

Chapter 42

Predictable Choice

Alabyrinth was a labyrinth—no big way to really change that. Minaga hadn’t tried, either, as they once more found themselves walking through winding hallways of mist, following after Jake, who had a nice mental map in his head. The difference this time around was that there was a “correct” way right off the bat, with no rooms or anything to look for.

Instead, they just had to pass through a pretty big labyrinth to reach a gate at the end, but based on how long it would take to reach the gate, this could not be the entire floor. They also had at least three rooms to clear with difficulty ratings attached. The only challenge on this floor so far was the occasional trap, which they could have some fun with. Some of these varied traps were even placed on the fastest path to the finish.

Some were good-old spike traps, some released mana bolts from the walls, and a few even summoned enemies they had to fight. The fights and traps were all made quite a lot harder to deal with by the mist, but they still easily managed and moved forward quickly—or as quickly as one could with the mist limiting their movement speed.

“This is quite similar to what we have done before,” the Sword Saint said, voicing his thoughts.

“Ree!” Sylphie complained as she flew alongside them.

Jake shrugged. “Yeah, pretty damn similar, but we will reach the gate in just a bit, so maybe something will change then.”

Soon, they did indeed reach the first gate. It had taken them nearly two and a half hours to get there due to the traps while taking the fastest route, so he guessed this floor would be quite a pain for parties without what was essentially maphack.

A few minutes later, they turned the final corner and saw the gate before them. This gate was rather different from those prior. On the other side of it, Jake saw an empty void, and on either side were two large runes—four total—that all lit up. Jake scanned them and quickly got the gist of it.

1. Puzzle (Easy)

2. Combat (Medium)

3. Crafting (Easy)

4. Random (Easy)

“We get to choose the challenge room type and the difficulty,” Jake noted as he looked over the four options.

“Not much choice when one considers the bonus objective,” the Fallen King said.

“True.” Jake nodded. “Now, how do we pick…”

It took minimal figuring out before they discovered that three of them just had to infuse energy or touch one of the marks at once. They naturally activated the second option to do a little combat.

Once they activated it, the entire gate began to glow, and as Jake released another pulse, he saw a massive room appear on the other side. It extended even beyond his Pulse of Perception, meaning it had to be at least three hundred kilometers long. He could see that it had a width of around two hundred kilometers, though.

When the gate opened, they walked through the usual fog gate, and Jake felt the pleasant wind hit him. They were in a mountainous environment, and when Jake looked ahead, he saw a pterodactyl-looking creature flying through the air. He naturally used Identify… only to find a disappointing level.

[Windborne Shrieker – lvl 239]

Moreover, he did not feel like it was a strong variant at all. Down in the deep valleys below, dinosaurs wandered around, and while he was still trying to figure out where all the enemies were, they got a system message.

Room Objective: Clear the room to unlock the teleporter.

841/841 enemies remaining.

“That seems simple,” Dina said, nodding.

Jake nodded back. “Yeah, I am surprised there is not some twist… I just think we have to kill everything here.”

“It does seem as such… Thus, we should get started immediately,” the Fallen King said as he extended his hand towards the Shrieker Jake had Identified.

It abruptly stopped in mid-air many kilometers away when the King squeezed his clawed hand. The Shrieker struggled as the King lifted his other hand and made a tearing motion. In the distance, a wing was ripped off the creature. It continued to struggle, but the Fallen King’s hands finally glowed golden as he crushed them together. In turn, the Shrieker in the distance was crushed and fell to the ground, broken.

840/841 enemies remaining.

“City floor wasn’t entirely a waste of time, now, was it?” Jake smirked as he pulled out his bow.

“Meager improvements do not make up for time wasted,” the Fallen King shot back as he began looking for his next target.

Jake smiled and nodded as he looked toward the sky. “Considering we have to kill everything here… I guess finding all of the opponents is meant to be part of the challenge, too.”

“Probably,” the Sword Saint agreed.

“In that case…” Jake grinned and released another pulse, and as it rippled out, he focused. Whenever it passed a creature, Jake made sure to note it by activating Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter, placing hundreds of marks within one second. With his high Perception, marking this many was no problem at all.

Using the Golden Mark, Jake shared the location of every single marked target with the party.

Dina looked at him and asked, “Are you sure about all these locations?”

Jake smiled. “Yep.”

“Okay.” She nodded as she took out her staff and slammed it into the ground, releasing a pulse of nature mana.

Jake just shook his head and took to the skies as the Sword Saint, Fallen King, and Sylphie also set out. He flew towards the far end of the room to mark all of the opponents, with the Sword Saint taking the left side of the room. Behind him, a giant tornado emerged on the left, rain clouds gathering on the right. Yet before any of these had time to do much, death arrived from below. The environment itself turned against the many dinosaurs in the valley below as Dina’s attack arrived, doing quite a number on the local wildlife. Many died in mere seconds.

814/841 enemies remaining.

Seeing the others having fun, Jake also began to release death from above. Being inside the room, Jake could see the end and estimated the entire place was around four hundred kilometers in length. That meant his pulse soon allowed him to scan it all. Once he had marked all the dinosaurs present, Jake set up shop by summoning a platform of arcane mana beneath himself. It was as sturdy as arcane mana could be after his mana practice, and with a proper foothold that could handle the explosions he was about to release, Jake began to act out his dream of being a living Arcane Powershot turret.

He started with all the flyers before on to those on the ground. Towards the entrance, a scar of destruction made its way towards him, wind, rain, vines, and explosions of force magic tearing up the land. Before long, they were done slaughtering the far-too-easy room, with Jake finishing off the last few dinosaurs while the rest of the party made it over to where Jake was.

Room completed. Teleporter activated.

Once they had all flown to Jake, they quickly used the teleporter inside a cave filled with what looked like temple ruins near the far end of the room. Entering it and teleporting onwards, Jake saw the bonus objective update just as they disappeared from the room.

Current progress: Highest-difficulty room completed (1/3)

They once more appeared at the start of a labyrinth with three paths to pick from.

“That was too easy… Do we need to make our way through another labyrinth before the next challenge room?” the King asked, slightly impatient.

“Seems like it,” Jake answered after sending out a Pulse of Perception, “though this one does have a shorter path. More traps, but it will still be faster.”

The Sword Saint smiled, unbothered. “Lead the way.”

Jake and company made their way through this labyrinth within only two hours. It was a bit annoying, but the one positive thing Jake could say was that it at least gave them time to properly regenerate their resources before the next challenge room. Not that they were in trouble when it came to enduring long battles; they always had potions if things went south.

Arriving at the next gate, they were once more met with four options.

1. Puzzle (Medium)

2. Collection (Medium)

3. Combat (Easy)

4. Random (Easy)

And this one was actually a choice. Both the Puzzle and the Collection one were of equal difficulty, based on what Jake could see, though he did want to make sure that was indeed the case.

“Say, Minaga, when several options have the same difficulty rating, can we just pick ourselves?” Jake asked, prompting a visit from the dungeon designer.

“Right on!” Minaga answered gladly. “I did tell you there would be actual decision-making on these floors, didn’t I? You can select whichever one you believe fits your party the best, as long as they are all of the highest difficulty rating available. I do want to also add that I am not actually deciding which ones get the high difficulties here. I made it all pseudo-random to make every experience slightly different. Ah, for reference, you will be able to find this kind of floor with the same design even in other grades. It is quite popular, if I may say so myself.”

“Several grades, huh?” Jake said, nodding. “Man, that must have been hard. Almost like it takes a godly level of power to design something like that.”

“I did say they were pseudo-random, but that doesn’t mean I don’t have a backdoor where I can decide to make every single room the worst… Say, how about we decide to make every single challenge room from here on out take place underwater?”

“You wouldn’t,” Jake said without a shred of fear. “I do not believe your integrity and professionalism will allow you to have water levels within your labyrinth.”

“I… You’re right,” Minaga surrendered. “There are lines that simply shouldn’t be crossed, and that threat was in poor taste. From the bottom of my heart, I apologize. Though I will add that I can still change the rooms to something else that you will also hate.”´

“And I am forever grateful that you will not do that.” Jake smiled. “Thanks for answering, and I hope you continue to have a great day.”

“Good to know we reached an understanding. Enjoy the floor!”

“We will.” Jake smiled again before turning to the party. “We should pick the Collection one. My gut is telling me that will be incredibly easy and cheeseable.”

“Oh, come on!”

Alas, his complaint was too late. They had all activated the Collection room, and the door opened to reveal another large, albeit slightly smaller room than the last. This environment looked like a large underground cave, but luckily there were no mushrooms anywhere. There was plenty of moss, though, and it grew in odd patterns, leaving natural formations all over the place and the air full of mana.

Room Objective: Collect all the Hidden Tokens.

32/32 Hidden Tokens remaining.

Their objective was to find all the hidden tokens throughout the large cave. These tokens were all hidden inside natural formations, below the ground, or inside walls, with some even floating within odd green clouds that permeated the air.

Anyway, a few Pulse of Perceptions and a Dina who kindly asked the moss to lend a hand later, and they teleported to the next labyrinth.

Current progress: Highest-difficulty room completed (2/3)

“I do hope the difficulty increases,” the Sword Saint said as they began walking through yet another labyrinth. “After the Demon Lord, this seems far too straightforward and easy.”

“Ree!” Sylphie also complained, saying that the later opponents in the arena on the city floor had been harder and a lot more fun.

“Variance is welcome when it comes to the rooms, but in order for the variance to hold meaning, there has to be an element of challenge to the variance,” the Fallen King joined in. “If not, it is simply going through the motions.”

“Well…” Dina said as she fidgeted with one of the flowers growing from her hair. “I think it’s okay. The Demon Lord was a big outlier in difficulty, and if this floor didn’t start easy, it wouldn’t have space to get harder later on. We are pretty good at these rooms, too, and I do think there is fun to be found in seeing how fast we can go.”

“See, that is a good mentality to have!” Minaga swooped in to agree.

“Oh, so you do like it when we speedrun the floors and cheese them?” Jake shot back with a grin.

“Anyway, please continue,” Minaga said, backing off as fast as he had come.

Jake shook his head, and the party kept up their high speed through yet another labyrinth before they arrived at their third gate and choice of the day.

1. Traps (Medium)

2. Crafting (Medium)

3. Combat (Medium)

4. Random (Easy)

This one had the most interesting choice so far. They didn’t want to waste too much time discussing, though, and ended up just going with the combat option since the Fallen King and Sylphie both heavily advocated for it. Jake had a strong feeling they just really wanted to kill stuff and blow off steam after the city floor. Hopefully, they would calm down shortly.

This combat room also proved itself easy, though it was slightly harder than the first one they had done, despite both being medium difficulty. After clearing it, Jake had to confess he had kind of expected the floor to be over. They’d even completed the bonus objective.

Bonus Objective Completed: Complete three rooms of the highest difficulty. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

However, despite the objective being completed, they found themselves facing yet another labyrinth. Jake frowned, wondering how many they had to do. The others had the same question.

“Is it possible this is part of the labyrinth?” the Sword Saint theorized. “That we can’t just pick the fastest path every time? Also, is it possible there was more than one exit in any of the prior labyrinths?”

Jake considered for a bit and used another pulse. Ultimately, he went with his gut and shook his head. “No… No, I think we just have to keep going, and that there are just more than three.”

“How many do you think there are?” Dina questioned.

“Hm,” Jake said, thinking. Then a lightbulb went off in his head, and he spoke with certainty. “There are six rooms total we need to clear.”

“Okay, how in the cursed name of evil Demon Lord Gubrothas did you cheat yourself into figuring that out? Seriously, how utterly overpowered is that Bloodline of yours to—”

“It’s the thirty-sixth floor,” Jake interrupted. “Thirty and six. Hence, six rooms having thirty-six total would honestly be too much. Shit, there are probably seven rooms on the next floor.”

Silence followed for several seconds as the Sword Saint just smiled, and Dina did all she could to suppress a giggle.

“Am I… Am I that predictable?” Minaga asked, questioning his entire existence.

“A better question is if I am indeed just incredibly smart,” Jake joked back.

“Considering that is an impossibility…” Minaga roasted him, “I… Did the rest of you also figure it out?”

“I hadn’t really thought about it,” Dina answered.

“Ree,” Sylphie said, also not really caring.

The King stayed silent as expected, but the Sword Saint kept smiling and said, “Such an idea never even crossed my mind. I had considered there was some hint in prior words you spoke, a clue in the number of difficulties and how all the options got harder with time. Alas, all in vain, as it seems I merely do not have a mind comparable to you two.”

“I am pretty sure he just insulted us both,” Minaga said.

Jake nodded. “Same, man.”

The old man just kept smiling as he motioned forward. “Should we not get going? We have three more rooms next, do we not?”

He spoke the last part while looking up toward the ceiling of the labyrinth.

“You know, I am beginning to hate your party more and more…”

“Nah, he loves us,” Jake joked with the Sword Saint.

“You know, I am definitely filing a complaint with both Vilas and Aeon after this.”

Jake kept smiling as they walked, holding himself back from pointing out how referring to two Primordials using their names was definitely the behavior of someone who wasn’t a god. Definitely.

Chapter 43

Cruel Trap Room

After the fun bantering with Minaga, they arrived at room number four, and finally, the difficulty seemed to have increased. At least… it said this would be hard.

1. Traps (Hard)

2. Collection (Medium)

3. Combat (Medium)

4. Random (Hard)

As they were still following Minaga’s advice of never picking anything that wasn’t of the highest difficulty, the only choice was between Random and Traps. Jake considered for a second, but his gut didn’t really tell him one was better than the other. Maybe because both would be easy for him.

“Let us just pick Traps,” the Fallen King said as he scanned the options. “The Hunter will likely be able to trivialize any challenge and allow us to pass through quickly.”

“I guess.” Jake shrugged as he turned to the others.

He did kind of want to pick the Random one just to see if there was some fun category they had yet to even see, but alas, the other three agreed to just go with Traps. Well, Sylphie didn’t particularly care, but she did seem like she wanted to get through these floors fast after the city-floor delay, so she just went with whatever she thought was fastest… which was typically just agreeing with everyone else.

“Let’s do that, then,” Jake said, nodding as he infused energy into the particular rune.

He was soon joined by the four others. The rune lit up as the door in front of them began opening, revealing the room that had just been generated. Jake released a Pulse of Perception and noted that the place was only around ten kilometers long and less than five meters in height and width, which made the place incredibly small for a challenge room. However, he also soon realized why it was so small.

The entire place was utterly packed with stuff. What appeared before them was a massive obstacle course with a web of challenges. The walls looked to be made of some kind of metal, and large panels stood here and there, forcing whoever tried to go through into small openings reminiscent of doorways.

Jake looked around for a while and quickly spotted one more thing of note. The mist was not entirely gone in this trap room. A small amount of it remained, but its properties seemed slightly different. It did not obstruct sight anymore, but Jake did feel that the movement-restricting effect mostly remained, meaning things like teleporting through were out of the question.

“Odd,” Jake said. “I don’t feel any real danger…”

Dina looked at the room a bit before taking out a seed. She tossed it in the air, and before it landed, a vine soldier had grown from it. The one-meter-tall creature began walking into the area with the traps, and the moment it walked just five meters ahead of them, a barrier sprang up, separating the vine soldier from Jake and the others.

It paused slightly, but Dina urged it to keep walking. It did so, and just a few meters later, it activated a formerly invisible formation on the floor, resulting in an explosion of mana spears shooting up from the ground. The vine soldier was hit, but the spears only left small tears in its body… and then it disappeared.

Only to reappear right beside Dina, the barrier in front of them also fading in the process.

“I believe we may have underestimated these trap rooms,” the Sword Saint said.

“Ree!” Sylphie said, wanting to give it a go.

Jake saw no reason to deny her, so the hawk shot forward and turned into wind. She got several hundred meters into the room while successfully avoiding all the traps until, suddenly, a section of the wall shot out like a piston, hitting the living gust of wind that was Sylphie. The glowing formation at the end of the piston glowed with some kind of energy, and in the very next second, living wind joined them back behind the barrier.

Sylphie turned back into her physical form and screeched in annoyance. But she did learn something.

The piston had managed to do a very small amount of damage to Sylphie, and that had caused her to teleport away. The prior traps she’d avoided had failed to do any damage even if they had partly hit her, making Sylphie—being the smart bird she was—conclude that someone would only be teleported back upon taking damage.

“So, who wants to go next?” the Sword Saint asked.

Jake was about to volunteer when Dina stepped up. “I can test if it is indeed about taking damage.”

“That sounds like a good idea,” the old man said, smiling as he motioned for her to give it a shot.

As Dina walked forward and passed that invisible threshold, the barrier popped up again, confirming that only one person could attempt the room at a time. Dina walked forward while taking out her staff and touching her chest with her one free hand, which glowed with dense life energy. Bobo, her living armor, began to grow as her body was covered, and tapping herself with the staff infused Bobo with even more energy. Vines sprang up from all over, creating a cocoon of defensive plants.

Then she jumped forward and pointed her staff, shooting out a vine that gripped one of the panels meant to block one’s progress. She used this vine to drag herself further into the room, the vines below her functioning as dozens of small legs.

Nearly instantly, she triggered a bunch of traps. Spears shot out from the walls and hit the amalgamation of vines, but they failed to do much. Even as a few vines were cut off or exploded, Dina remained untouched behind all her defenses.

When she reached the piston, her vines took most of the blow, and she ended up using the vines almost as springs to help her pounce. She launched herself forward with help from the momentum, and within only a few minutes, she reached the midway point. So far, the only true challenge for her seemed to be the small openings she sometimes had to get through, forcing her to shrink her form momentarily before expanding it again.

“Does not seem hard,” the Fallen King said as he walked over and poked the barrier blocking them in, making sure it was indeed utterly impenetrable.

“Let’s see,” the Sword Saint said patiently.

When Dina pressed on into the second part, the traps got harder. At one point, the walls on both sides grew spikes and slammed together, but Dina managed to avoid being crushed by raising her staff to stop both walls at once. The damn staff didn’t even bend from the impact, and after she infused some energy, it grew in length and pushed back both walls, allowing her to pass safely.

More traps followed. Explosions of mana, spears shooting out, pitfalls, acid getting blasted from the walls, crescent energy waves, and of course, the trap room itself moving physically while trying to stop her. However, nothing could penetrate the dryad druid’s defenses. Even when the Fallen King pointed out a blast of soul energy, Bobo somehow managed to absorb it instead of Dina, which did look a bit funny, as, for a fraction of a second, Jake felt like Bobo had been teleported away—only to somehow instantly return to Dina.

In the end, Dina managed to make it to the other side without suffering any injuries. The second she stepped on a small platform at the far end of the room, the barrier in front of Jake and the others faded away.

“Okay, yeah, it is about taking damage,” Dina explained through their telepathic link. “When Bobo took some damage, the room tried to teleport him, but because he is bound to me, he was instantly brought back again. So good defenses do work here.”

“I believe the real way it was meant to be done is memorizing the safe path… There were places you could go without activating anything,” the Sword Saint sent through the Golden Mark.

“That appears to be an unnecessary waste of time,” the Fallen King said, scoffing. Without waiting further, he floated forwards straight into the trap room. His passive barrier was already active, and with a wave of his hand, it turned golden. Then he casually flew on at a relaxed pace.

Traps activated all around him, yet nothing managed to do anything to the barrier, and in a time only slightly slower than Dina’s—only because he clearly didn’t rush—the Fallen King made it to the other side safely. His defenses were simply too overpowered.

“Now, who is next?” the Fallen King questioned cockily.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched as she flew up in the air, gladly taking on the challenge after perching atop a glowing green branch that appeared behind her feet. Jake felt her confidence and cheered her on as he observed her.

She seemed to levitate on the branch and wiggle in a cute-looking way, like a cat ready to pounce. What was less cute was how her body began to glow with green energy, the wind picking up around Jake and the Sword Saint. Power accumulated in their surroundings as Sylphie lowered herself a bit and opened her wings. Jake barely saw the familiar Green Shield appear around her body before the entire entrance area of the trap room exploded.

Like a bullet from a railgun, Sylphie blasted through hundreds of traps, narrowly navigating amid all the small gaps to make it through the room. Even with the mist limiting her movements, she flew with insane speed. All the spears, pistons, and moving walls—really, any trap that took even a moment to activate—were simply too slow and only fired off in her wake. What did hit her, the Green Shield managed to stop. This resulted in Sylphie safely making it to the other side in record time.

“Ree! Ree!” she bragged over the Golden Mark, sounding incredibly proud.

Jake sent a mental thumbs-up, having honestly expected Sylphie to have trouble with this room due to her attempt to get through by transforming her body into wind. Luckily, that wasn’t an issue. That just left Jake and the Sword Saint.

“You can go first,” Jake said, motioning to the old man.

The Sword Saint hesitated for a moment before nodding. On guard, he entered the room, and with light steps, he began making his way through. A water barrier surrounded him as he slowly proceeded, trying not to activate traps as he went. Sometimes he did activate one, but before the attacks could hit him, he either dodged or released a counterattack.

However, less than a kilometer in, he failed to dodge a mana spear that penetrated the water barrier and left a small cut around his ankle. Instantly, the Sword Saint found himself teleported right back to Jake.

“I shall wait patiently,” Jake said, smiling teasingly.

The old man just sighed and went again.

This happened fourteen more times, and with every try he got further. In the last two attempts, he used his boosting skill to make his defenses better and speed faster, resulting in him finally passing the full room, albeit somewhat worse for wear. It had ended up taking the Sword Saint a touch over an hour to finish the room, which, in retrospect, wasn’t that bad. It just felt like a long time due to how fast the others had done it.

“Now we only wait for the Hunter,” the Fallen King spoke through the Golden Mark. “I hope you do not disappoint us.”

“That would certainly be embarrassing after watching my many attempts,” the Sword Saint concurred.

“I am sure he has a plan,” Dina said, trying to be diplomatic.

“Ree!” Sylphie’s suggestion was to just smack every trap with his cauldron.

Jake didn’t really think that was necessary as he walked into the trap room and smiled. “Be there in a jiffy.”

What followed was a nice, casual stroll. Whenever he got close to one of the traps, he saw the formation and quickly stepped around the lines that would activate it. Occasionally, he did activate one, yet he easily dodged whatever was shot at him. Towards the end, he purposefully walked in a nearly straight line, evading everything the trap room could throw at him. All in all, it was a nice experience, and Jake soon rejoined the others.

“Showoff,” the Sword Saint said, chuckling as Jake walked through the final barrier.

He hadn’t used a single skill during his little stroll, and had only summoned a couple of stable arcane barriers here and there to block stuff he felt too lazy to dodge. Oh, and he’d caught one mana spear mid-air after infusing his gauntlet with energy. That one had indeed been only to show off.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked, questioning why he didn’t use the cauldron.

“A meager trap room like this isn’t worthy of facing my ultimate weapon,” Jake answered in a haughty voice.

“Ree,” Sylphie answered in full understanding.

“You know… I… No, I can’t say that,” Minaga’s voice echoed. “Sharing information like that is against the rules.”

Jake and company were already mid-teleport when he spoke, and they appeared before yet another labyrinth. He saw Dina was about to inquire, but he nudged her slightly, and she seemed to understand by staying silent.

“Truly… Truly, can I say it?”

All five of them continued to ignore him, following Jake to enter the labyrinth.

“Alas… it seems no one can hear me, so perhaps it is safe to disclose…”

Their team cohesion was truly on point, as none of them reacted to a single word the Unique Lifeform said.

“Well, if no one is listening, I guess I can just talk out loud a bit. That trap room was quite well designed, if I may say so myself. It was made so people who are incredibly durable can’t just walk through, allowing it to counter certain individuals and force them to actually think for a second. It is also interesting to think about how that trap room was partly based on one of the Challenge Dungeons available here in Nevermore, although that one is quite a bit different. Thinking about it further, that Challenge Dungeon would surely be easy for someone who can just casually walk through and easily dodge every single thing here. Ah, it is truly good that no one is listening, because I am definitely not allowed to disclose that. Also, while I am here talking to myself, I can’t help but ponder one of the funniest things going on right now in one of the other instances of floor thirty-seven. I couldn’t possibly have predicted that a trap room made not to damage, but to teleport people back would completely and utterly screw over some of the people who manage to find methods that make them borderline invincible in their current grades by seemingly giving them infinite health points. Yeah, definitely couldn’t have predicted that.”

Jake and the others casually walked as they listened to the Unique Lifeform sharing information that Jake was pretty sure you couldn’t share according to the rules of Nevermore. Not that he complained. He also instantly put together who Minaga was talking about towards the end of his monologue.

“Could you guys imagine if Eron had to do that trap room that we just did?” Jake joked with the others.

“Odd… I just had this weird thought that some trap rooms are harder than others…”

Jake grinned. “Or maybe one even harder.”

“The schadenfreude is palpable,” the Sword Saint said, chuckling as he shook his head.

“Hey, that’s what he gets for being faster than us on that damn city floor,” Jake shot back.

“Ree…” Sylphie whined softly.

Jake plucked the bird out of the air and patted her head as he walked, holding her in a hug. “It isn’t your fault the evil creature who designed the city doesn’t like awesome hawks like you.”

“None of my design decisions are ever targeting individuals.”

“He is just jealous,” Jake said, comforting her further.

“I am definitely never jealous.”

“Yeah, a super-jealous guy for sure,” Jake went on, with Sylphie now cheering up a bit. Still, Jake couldn’t help but imagine Eron in one of those trap rooms.

Man, do I wish I could see that. He is definitely not having a good time.

Eron was not having a good time. He appeared back at the beginning of the trap room, unsure how many times he had tried so far. Frustration was obvious on his face as he simply tried again. He memorized the route he’d taken the last time and managed to get five meters further on the next attempt, taking him to a bit over the twelve-kilometer mark. Only three more to go.

His party members were meditating at the end of the trap room, having all completed it. All they were waiting for was him.

He kept going, again and again. All methods had been tried. Even if he purposefully did damage to himself in the trap room, the teleportation would activate, making him unable to use his original plan of just blowing up his body and slowly advancing to the end.

As more days passed, he inched ever closer. Every attempt was identical until the end, where he added just a few more meters every time while making sure he didn’t trigger a single trap. His stats were simply not high enough to allow him to dodge anything. Finally, after who knows how long, he passed through the final barrier and completed the room.

His party members awakened, looked at him, and nodded as they prepared to move on. A tacit agreement was reached of never selecting trap rooms ever again. They would gladly pick the Random option over one.

Eron truly hoped to forever put the experience behind him. To never think about it again, and for no one else to ever—

“Man, that’s a great new record!” Minaga said. “Ninety-seven days to pass one trap room? Okay, not actually sure it’s a record, but damn, am I saving the recording anyway! Gonna be fun to rewatch. Maybe I should invite some friends over for a watch party?”

Alas, fate could be cruel.

Chapter 45

Minaga's Labyrinth True Ending

Minaga had been pretty honest from the get-go when he talked about the floors after his city floor. They had indeed just been the same setup over and over again, with ever-increasing difficulty. The difficulty actually reached a level where Jake and the others had to get serious, especially in the final room of each floor, where at least one of the hardest options was hard-coded to always include a boss. At least, Jake assumed it was hard-coded, as it was like that every time, and Minaga never denied that was the case.

One minor change was that all the labyrinths seemed shorter, containing both standard shortcuts and traps you could activate to progress faster. This included a few instances of walls that could be opened as well as illusory walls; the latter was Jake’s favorite, as he hadn’t noticed the first one he saw in his sphere was even meant to be illusory before he laid eyes on it.

This was the only reason Jake and company could keep their clear times of both floor thirty-eight and thirty-nine below a full day, though it did get damn close on floor thirty-nine. Having to do nine rooms total was a bit taxing; no two ways about it.

Jake also had to admit that they had gotten fortunate, though. Not lucky enough for him to think that Minaga was actively helping them, but lucky enough for him to feel lucky. More than half of the rooms had been combat rooms, and with a few bosses and collection rooms mixed in, they had just enough time. They were further helped along by liberally consuming potions between rooms so they never had to slow down. They also restricted all chatter with Minaga to the labyrinths, where their speed was limited by the floor rules.

Anyway… with their success also came more experience than Jake had expected.

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 220 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 223 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 221 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

Jake would undoubtedly say that two levels in two days was damn good. It was definitely faster than alchemy could ever be unless he got epiphanies related to upgrading skills. The others had also all gained plenty.

Anyway, after the floors, they found themselves standing inside the in-between floor before it was time for the fortieth floor. They were not in a hurry, as they all definitely needed to be back in peak condition. Jake felt that the final floor would not be easy. Upon seeing them all relaxing, Minaga swooped in to echo that sentiment.

“Remember to rest up well before the final floor of my labyrinth, alright? It’s gonna be quite an experience and will truly test you. The Demon Lord boss will look like a cakewalk in comparison; I can promise you that! Okay, maybe not a cakewalk, but definitely a far easier kind of walk than the walk you are about to walk into.”

Jake smiled. “You know, I have quite a good idea of what we will face.”

“Well, don’t spoil it for the others even if you do!” Minaga argued.

“Pretty sure they figured it out too.”

“In that case, let’s all act like none of you know, so please act surprised when you see the final challenge, alright?”

Jake threw a glance at his party members, and after getting a few shrugs, he agreed. “Sure, pal, you can have that.”

“Thanks, and see you soon! Who knows… maybe sooner than you think!”

Yeah, Minaga himself is definitely the final boss, Jake thought, smiling to himself. He knew he’d be lying if he said he wasn’t looking forward to it. The Minaga that had appeared in all of the welcome rooms had been a level 275 Unique Lifeform, and if he was as powerful as the Fallen King would be at level 275… Jake was definitely not confident in winning alone.

Even with his party, it would be incredibly rough. Also, despite them all knowing they would face Minaga, they did have the problem of not knowing what he could actually do. Sure, he had teleported around a bunch with help from the dungeon, but he had shown none of his actual powers. The only clue was that he was some kind of mage, given the name of the different difficulties and his whole demeanor and clothes. Also, being a dungeon master and mage just tended to go together, with Casper being an outlier.

As part of Jake’s preparations, he also finally distributed the last 2400 stat points from his Altmar Signet that he hadn’t yet placed anywhere. Looking at his stat caps, he could get roughly 800 more Strength and 1100 Agility from the ring. That left him with 500 stat points left to place, and after a bit of consideration, he put them into Endurance. Having more Endurance would allow him to better withstand his boosting skill and even keep it active for longer. Besides, if he changed his mind later, he could just redistribute the stat points.

Checking out the ring, he nodded.

[Altmar Signet of Supremacy (Legendary)] – A ring presented by the Altmar Empire to the Chosen of the Malefic Viper. This ring is made of an unknown but extremely energy-dense metal, with an unknown gem of immense power embedded in it. This ring was originally based on the Trial Signet design but has been further refined and improved to make a fitting gift for a Chosen. The first time the wielder equips the ring, they will be able to distribute the signet’s energy into whatever stats they desire. Distributing any of the stat points will make the ring Soulbound. A brief recharge period is required between each redistribution of stat points. Stat points cannot be redistributed during combat. Enchantments: +2500 Perception, +900 Strength, +1100 Agility, +500 Endurance.

Requirements: Soulbound.

With all preparations done, Jake and company continued forward without delay. The others had also consumed elixirs to make sure they had all the stat boosts they could, and besides some potential improvements in equipment, they had no more optimization to do. They were already in formation as they entered the fortieth floor, ready as could be and at the peak of their game when the room appeared before them. With their entry also came the expected floor introduction.

Welcome to the fortieth floor of Nevermore: The Grand Finale of Minaga’s Labyrinth

Main objective: Defeat the final boss.

Bonus objectives: N/A

Current progress: Final boss (0/1)

Note: It’s the finale!

Current Nevermore Points: 42,973

Jake read it over along with everyone else. However, they did not have much time, as an aura appeared in the middle of the large, cathedral-like building they found themselves in. The temperature of the place increased as flames gathered, revealing the outline of an all-too-familiar figure.

[Demon Lord – lvl 275]

“You gotta be kidding me,” Jake whispered under his breath as the Demon Lord fully manifested, a spear appearing in his hand.

“I have been waiting for you!” the demon said as it pointed the spear at them. “Behold, I, the long-lost twin of Demon Lord Gubrothas, shall be your deaths! My name is Demon Lord Gobruthas, and today I will avenge my—”

He didn’t get further before, suddenly, the entire cathedral was enveloped in blue energy. The room exploded as a massive white pillar crashed through the roof, crushing the Demon Lord into paste. Everything shook as the pillar kept drilling into the ground, squashing the Demon Lord further. On top of it, Jake saw the expected figure he had already presumed to be the boss.

It was naturally Minaga himself.

[Minaga – lvl 275]

Jake saw him, and then… then the lights came. Strobe lights began blinking throughout the hall as thousands of openings appeared on the pillar and walls of the room, all shooting out colorful lights in all shades of the rainbow. The walls of the cathedral also began extending outwards and shuffling around, expanding the battle arena significantly.

The light show continued for several seconds before a massive spotlight appeared, illuminating Minaga atop the pillar as he spread out his arms.

“WELCOME, WELCOME, WELCOME! TO THE GRAND FINALE!”

With his words, a system message appeared in front of them all.

Event unlocked: True Ending

You have completed all the prerequisites and proven yourself worthy to face the true final boss of Minaga’s Labyrinth: its creator. Take heed, for this challenge surpasses all those you have faced prior.

Note: Due to the difficulty level of the challenge, any individual that takes lethal damage will be teleported out of the boss room instead of dying. Should all party members be defeated, the event will be failed and cannot be reattempted.

New Bonus Objective gained: Do not allow a single party member to be defeated during the battle.

Jake scanned the message and frowned, yelling at the Unique Lifeform before he could continue his introduction show, “No death here?”

“Not unless you kill yourselves, no. Actually, let’s just get all that out of the way… Let me say it like this… Concessions were required before the Wyrmgod and system would accept having a challenge of this caliber placed on the fortieth floor of the C-grade portion of Nevermore. Not a minor concession, either. In order for balance to be reached, the system implemented the condition that you can’t die, only be defeated. In other words, if you are to take fatal damage from me, you won’t actually die but be teleported to jail! And if you all get jailed, you will fail and be sent back to the in-between room, and things will look quite a bit different when you reenter.”

Jake nodded at Minaga repeating the information. “So, as the system message said.”

“Exactly,” Minaga said, smiling. “Now, can I continue without you ruining my groove?”

“Be my guest.” Jake bowed, giving the Unique Lifeform space.

“Thank you. Now, where was I… Oh, right!” Minaga cleared his throat as he continued with his scripted speech. “You, brave challengers, find yourselves at the final challenge of Minaga’s Labyrinth! What else could it be but the opportunity to face the peak of dungeoneering itself? Me! The creator of the greatest labyrinth ever!”

“Oh, my lord, I cannot believe the final boss is actually Minaga himself!” Jake exclaimed loudly.

“We were thoroughly bamboozled and all taken by surprise,” the Sword Saint echoed in a dry voice.

“Yeah, a big reveal,” Dina said while nodding along, giggling a bit.

“Ree!” Sylphie screeched, trying to act surprised too. Only the Fallen King wasn’t a good sport about the entire thing.

“Ha ha! Naturally, you had no way of seeing such a twist coming! This will be the ultimate challenge of my labyrinth, and should you come out victorious, you will be generously rewarded! Should you fail, you will have to do another challenge that will still give pretty decent rewards, but way worse than if you’d defeated me!”

The five of them nodded as they observed the Unique Lifeform. Jake scanned him as well as he could, trying to get a good read… and one thing was indeed certain: Minaga was far more powerful than any opponent he had ever faced before, bar none. To make matters worse… the Unique Lifeform knew them. He had observed them throughout the dungeon, and Jake would not put it past Minaga to use that against them.

“Don’t let your guard down for even a second,” Jake warned his party. “And don’t hesitate to use boosting skills.”

A second passed as the final vestiges of the light show died down. The fight was about to start.

“So, challengers… are you ready to face Minaga?” He smiled, looking tauntingly down at them with raised eyebrows.

Jake smirked, pulled out his bow, and jumped to the side. The Fallen King and Sword Saint moved forward as Dina stayed in place, while Sylphie shot into the air.

“I shall take that as a yes,” the Unique Lifeform said as he lifted one hand and grinned from ear to ear. He snapped his fingers, and his body exploded with energy, his voice still echoing throughout the entire hall. “Cue my boss theme.”

The deep sound of bass rumbled the room as music began playing from who-knows-where. Jake and the others didn’t take their time to enjoy it, though.

Following his own advice, Arcane Awakening activated at 30% right off the bat as he nocked an arrow and took aim at the Unique Lifeform that had yet to move. Yet just as he released his arrow, a massive floor tile flipped over right in front of him, blocking him and making his own arrow explode right in his face.

Then the more than twenty-meter-wide tile flew towards Jake, forcing him to dodge away as more of the floor rose to try and block him in. Busy dodging, he could only get a few glances at the Sword Saint closing in on Minaga, his boosting skill also active.

Minaga’s pillar exploded the very next second, roots erupting from all over it and flying towards the Unique Lifeform. He jumped in response, meeting the Sword Saint in melee while summoning a staff in each hand.

The Sword Saint kept diving in and slashing, forcing Minaga to block his blows. Yet just as the old man was about to pull back, Minaga moved in closer, and it looked almost like his staff became stuck to the Sword Saint’s sword as he swept it upwards.

All the old man could do was be dragged along with the staff as he was tossed above Minaga… right into the path of a diving Sylphie, who had to divert her course. To make things worse, Minaga lifted his second staff and pointed it at where Sylphie was dodging, shooting out a torrent of flames that forced her even further away.

Then, in an almost dancing motion, he pivoted out of the way of a blast of force shot by the Fallen King. Simultaneously, more than a dozen magic circles appeared around him. Stopping his pivoting, he pointed with a finger gun towards the Fallen King.

“Bang.”

All the magic circles exploded simultaneously, releasing giant ice spears that flew toward the other Unique Lifeform. Reacting quickly, the Fallen King summoned a golden wall in front of himself, but the ice spears proved more powerful than he had expected, making the barrier crack and forcing him to retreat just before it shattered.

Jake, who had finally managed to get free of the shuffling floor tiles, released a barrage of destructive arcane arrows at Minaga, who was falling to the ground. This made him raise his hand and summon a metal wall of pure energy right in front of himself.

“Oopsie,” Minaga said when a root spear nearly hit him in the foot as he landed on the floor. He managed to dodge it just as two overlapping crescent waves of water and wind cut towards him, forcing him to once again summon a defensive barrier. This one was molten metal, releasing a huge amount of steam when the attacks hit it.

“All-elemental magic… perhaps more than just elemental magic,” Dina said through their Golden Mark.

“Advice?” Jake said.

“Be prepared for any kind of attack.”

Jake sighed as the steam began to gather above Minaga, who stood there with a lifted staff. The orb of dense energy grew above him while he infused even more energy into it.

“Come on—you can do better than this! In fact, I know you can.”

Jake and the others had time to properly get in position to strike again as Minaga just stood there with a giant grin on his face. Then he shrugged.

“Fine. If you won’t attack…”

Cracks formed all over the orb above him, releasing intense energy.

“… then I will.”

Chapter 46

Big Spells!

The very next second, the orb of steam above Minaga exploded, bathing the entire room in dense white fog. This steam shared some concepts with the labyrinth’s mist, meaning that within a second, he had severely limited the sense of everyone. Well, everyone except Jake, that is. With his Mark of the Avaricious Hunter and Perception, he was pretty much unaffected, considering the size of the room.

“Dina, left, fire,” Jake warned her.

She responded just in time by turning and manifesting a wooden shield right as a staff slammed into it, exploding in a huge inferno that blasted her backward. As she slid across the ground, Bobo managed to help shake off the last of the damage, dozens of tendrils of wood extending from her body.

Minaga was about to strike again when a stable arcane arrow pierced the mist, hitting him in the shoulder and penetrating his robe.

“Man, how bloody high is your Perception stat?” Minaga questioned as he telekinetically pulled the arrow out just before it exploded, once more making it clear he knew what Jake and company were capable of. Except he seemed to have underestimated Jake’s Perception.

Jake also had a bit of a theory as he shot another arrow. Minaga reacted somewhat slowly but managed to block it with a barrier he’d summoned with one staff. Meanwhile, he pointed the other toward Dina, who was about to cast some magic of her own.

“Dina, dodge to the left.”

Without hesitation, she stopped casting and jumped to the left, just in time to avoid a beam of light that burned a tunnel through the mist. Minaga seemed surprised she’d reacted in time, but was even more surprised when two arrows flew around his barrier, hitting him in the shoulder and arm.

Both were once more pulled out telekinetically in an instant, but Jake had confirmed his theory. The mist is also limiting his Perception somewhat…

Minaga was less affected than anyone else, though. Even Jake was hit harder by the mist; he just managed to overcome it through sheer stat points. To continue his testing, Jake loosed another arrow, this one of the destructive variety. It was blown up in mid-air halfway to the target when Minaga shot a small beam of light at it.

Another flew right behind it and forced Minaga to sidestep. The Unique Lifeform looked slightly annoyed at Jake interrupting him. Due to Jake’s distraction, he had lost his chance to deal damage to Dina before the Fallen King, Sword Saint, and Sylphie could reenter the fight.

A massive tornado gathered as Sylphie addressed the dense steam that hampered everyone except Jake. The tornado lifted all the steam just as the Sword Saint and Fallen King got close to where Jake told them Minaga was standing, the old man attacking with a more cautious approach this time around.

From behind, the Fallen King summoned a massive ball on a golden chain that he swung from the side, timed to arrive at the same moment as the Sword Saint’s attack.

Minaga saw the attacks coming and smiled as he sank into the floor, dodging both attacks.

Jake’s eyes opened wide.

“Dina, behi—”

It was too late. The Unique Lifeform popped up right behind Dina, who was decidedly not ready to respond. In one hand, he held a ball of fire, and in the other, an orb of frost, both giving off intense energy. He brought them together in a double-palmed strike only a meter behind her. The moment the fire and ice met, Jake’s danger sense exploded, and he instinctively used Gaze of the Apex Hunter on Minaga to try and delay him.

It only managed to freeze him for a minuscule moment, but it was enough for Dina’s guardian to counterattack, shooting out hundreds of roots to meet the mixed fire-and-ice attack.

With what happened next, Jake was incredibly glad he had given Dina a chance to defend herself.

A massive explosion of white energy blasted a section of the room apart. Dina was sent flying, her entire form encased in a mix of flames and ice. She smashed into the other side of the massive room as Minaga stood still for a moment.

“Good response from both of you.”

He did not have time to say more before the Sword Saint closed in, and this time Minaga did not pop into the ground. The floor itself erupted from the Fallen King telekinetically lifting it with enough force to shatter the tiles.

Minaga seemed unbothered, but the old man was intent on being a threat. Water surrounded his blade as he did an upwards slash, and Minaga moved to block again, only to find himself feinted when the sword abruptly shifted direction. The Unique Lifeform was ready and had already moved to block the sword… only for the blade to vibrate and seemingly rewind in time for but a moment. Having thrown off all timing, the Sword Saint slashed the surprised Minaga across his stomach just as he jumped backward.

“Also a good one!” Minaga smiled as a faint trickle of blue blood dripped from his stomach, with only a light cut left there. Jake had already had his suspicions, but the Sword Saint had confirmed it.

“His body is more durable than expected…” the Sword Saint said just as he charged in again. “Dina, are you okay?”

While the Sword Saint engaged Minaga, Jake offered ranged support with the Fallen King. The two of them worked together to ensure the old man was not instantly overwhelmed.

“I’m fine… but Bobo is hurt badly,” Dina communicated through their telepathic link as she dislodged herself from the wall. Her robe was torn, and the wooden armor usually covering her body was broken in several places from a mix of frost and flames. “I will need some time to heal him.”

“Let’s hope he can’t do that frost-fire attack again,” Jake answered as he kept shooting arrows. Talking and fighting at the same time was not particularly hard with a C-grade mind.

Sylphie had managed to thoroughly dispel all the steam, and she now prepared an attack from above, even if she still had to keep the tornado active. The Fallen King was also cooking while Jake and the Sword Saint fought Minaga, who was not particularly pressured. Jake did notice that he did not do any magic after the big attack he had sent Dina flying with, though.

Even so, actually damaging Minaga was an uphill battle. It was good that he didn’t seem to have any healing spells, yet he slowly began to push back the Sword Saint. Jake’s fellow human was simply too out of his league when it came to sheer stat disparity. Luckily, they only had to hold on for so long.

The Fallen King was done with his preparations. Both his claws shone with golden light, and his golden crown flashed with energy. A golden veil fell over where Minaga stood. With a look of surprise on his face, he was pressed into the ground, everything around him seeming to vibrate. He slightly buckled as all the tiles around him cracked, and a dent in the floor formed in the area the golden veil affected.

This magic was an extension of what the Fallen King had practiced during his time on the city floor. Usually, he was always the direct source of all his force magic, resulting in it often functioning more as direct ranged attacks rather than what it truly was: an advanced form of telekinesis.

Now, he was capable of not only shooting it out from his body, but also striking from even more angles.

With Minaga temporarily suppressed, the Sword Saint and Jake made their moves. The old man pointed his blade and used his erosion stab while Jake released an Arcane Powershot.

“You’re pretty good, too!” Minaga grinned as his eyes began to glow. The golden veil of energy started lifting off him just as the Sword Saint and Jake’s attacks arrived.

With the pressure slightly lessened, Minaga managed to point his staff and meet the stab head-on, resulting in the Sword Saint being sent flying back from the sheer feedback of his sword hitting metal. As for Jake, he hit himself in the chest with his other hand, blasting himself backward and out of the golden veil.

“Nice tr—”

A green pillar of highly condensed wind energy descended from above, drilling down in a constant stream. Sylphie had hidden within her own giant tornado, successfully proving it was a superior method of stealth. Minaga hadn’t even noticed her preparing her attack. Mentioning the fact that the steam was mixed into the tornado, helping to hide her, was not necessary. Not at all.

Rock from the already-shattered tiles flew everywhere as the constant stream of wind energy continued, bearing down on Minaga. Jake did not sit idly by; he already had an arrow nocked as the others also prepared themselves to strike the moment Sylphie’s attack was completed.

They got their chance sooner than expected.

From the floor, a massive amount of rock speared up and blocked off the wind long enough for Minaga to jump out of the attack. Just as he did this, three ranged attacks arrived at once, but he clearly had all his magic back: He summoned a thick metal shield, borrowing the momentum from the attacks to retreat slightly.

“Gotta admit, I did forget about the bird for a moment there. Big mistake.” Minaga’s voice echoed through the hall as he landed safely on his feet. The attack from Sylphie had frayed his robe and left him in just his pants. His upper body was covered in small cuts here and there from the slashing winds, with a few small holes on his arms and the cut from the Sword Saint being the only other outward injuries.

With a wave of his hand, Minaga manifested a new pair of identical robes. Above, Sylphie was annoyed at him for escaping her attack—a descending barrage of wind blades—but Minaga just casually swept his staff across the air. A brown magic circle appeared, radiating with earth mana.

It didn’t fire right away, as Minaga had to first dodge a Splitting Arrow from Jake, but before anyone else could make a move, he grabbed one of his staves with both hands and held it like a baseball bat.

“Batter up!”

Minaga swung the staff hard and hit the magical circle. The moment he did, a more than ten-meter-wide rock flew out, leaving a trail of fire behind it like it was a meteor.

Sylphie’s wind blades all hit the meteor, but they failed to have any impact, forcing her to dodge out of the way. At least, she tried to. Below, Minaga pointed his staff at the meteor. It began to pulse, and even from the ground, Jake felt the gravitational pull from the large boulder.

The bird tried to get away, but the pull was too powerful. Sylphie summoned her Green Shield and flapped her wings as best she could, and at the very end, she managed to get mostly out of the way. Emphasis on mostly. The side of the meteor still hit her, sending her tumbling as her green shield exploded into wisps of green energy. She had wisely not tried to turn herself into wind; Jake could only begin to predict the effects that would have had.

She got away with only a damaged wing and a few burns. Minaga stared up at her, clearly a tad disappointed by his attack failing to do anything of note. Seeing the power of the attack, Jake also formed a prediction as he shot several arrows at the Unique Lifeform.

Minaga reacted by dodging and hitting away one of his arrows using his staff, and even when the Sword Saint attacked, he did not use any magic at all. This allowed the Fallen King to swoop in from the side, having realized the same thing as Jake. Minaga, seemingly unable to use magic, tried to block the Golden Claw using one of his staves, but the sheer scale of the attack still left several gashes up his arm.

Exactly five seconds after he used his meteor attack, Minaga slammed one of his staves into the floor, making it erupt in a sea of sharp spikes that forced the Sword Saint and Fallen King back. The arrow flying for him, he also barely blocked using a small metal plate that appeared in front of his face for a brief moment.

“Five seconds,” the Fallen King and Jake sent through the telepathic link at nearly the same time. Jake allowed the Unique Lifeform to elaborate by explaining, “Every time he does a major spell or combination magic, he cannot use any magic for five seconds. That is our time to strike.”

Jake nodded, as that was his conclusion too. It did also make sense… because if Minaga could spam out spells like what he’d used on Dina, they wouldn’t have a good time. Shit, even when he didn’t do combination magic, they were pressured.

Minaga went on the offensive with his magic up and running, electricity crackling around him. Lightning bolts were sent flying towards the Sword Saint, yet the old man summoned a wave of water to absorb it.

With a palm, he shot off a giant fireball toward the Fallen King, making the Unique Lifeform block the other Unique Lifeform. He was about to also shoot something towards Sylphie when the ground below him rumbled. He quickly stomped as the ground shook and a small earthquake vibrated the entire hall, but even if he tried to stop it, a powerful vine full of life energy still shot up from the ground. Just as it did so, it grew thorns and wrapped around his arm.

Minaga loosed a wind blade to try and cut it off, but before he could, the vine ripped itself back into the ground. The thorns dug into the arm and cut through flesh. Blood flew into the air, making the Unique Lifeform cringe.

“Okay, that actually hurt.”

The attacker had naturally been Dina, who had managed to stabilize herself and rejoin the fight. She had laid low and waited for a chance to strike, and given the torn-up arm, Jake would say it was definitely worth it.

With her back in the fight, the fight was equal for a while, allowing them to repeatedly trade blows. Minaga did take a few hits here and there, but his tricky spellcasting also caught them by surprise occasionally, resulting in far worse wounds. Luckily for them, they now had a healer back in the fight.

After a solid few minutes where a balance was reached, the Unique Lifeform retreated slightly, lifted both staves, and smashed them into the ground. A massive wave of pure force magic pushed Jake and the others back while also disjointing any projectiles.

With the space disrupted by his shockwave, Minaga raised his hand and began to gather sand, then released an intense flame that embraced the sand. Within a second, all of the sand had turned into an odd orb of glass with hundreds of flat surfaces all across it, making it look like a hollow disco ball, which—

Jake’s eyes opened wide.

“Defenses, now!”

His warning came just in time. Minaga pointed a finger gun at the glass orb, and a beam of light shot out, entering the disco ball and emerging as condensed lasers aimed at each of them individually. Every single of them reacted and summoned their own defenses, with Jake standing behind a stable arcane barrier. However… even behind the barrier, he saw the laser slowly burning through it, and from what he could see, the Sword Saint and Dina were struggling. Several layers of their barriers had already melted.

Minaga pointed the ray of light into the ball and grinned. Then the rays of light hitting them all disappeared. Minaga just stood there, shooting light up into a ball that was slowly growing brighter and brighter.

“Let’s take this spell for a spin!”

Using his other hand, Minaga telekinetically lifted the ball and set it spinning, turning the entire room into a deadly laser-rave in an instant.

Chapter 47

Many Minagas, Handle it! (Yes, I have made this reference before, sue me)

Thousands of lasers the width of a pencil spun around the room, cutting through it with intense speed and power. Every single person in Jake’s party summoned their best defenses or tried to dodge. Sylphie even turned her entire body into wind to resist most of the damage.

The Fallen King intensified the energy in his shield as best he could, and Dina jumped back as walls of roots continuously rose in front of her to try and block the attack, sacrificing layer after layer. The Sword Saint summoned several veils of water along with an odd painting that radiated intense energy. They all did their best to block or lessen the damage of the attack.

All except for one.

The moment before Minaga unleashed his attack, Jake rushed forward, stepping down and teleporting. Despite the shockwave slightly destabilizing space, he got more than halfway to the Unique Lifeform before the laser show began.

Because there was one place the attack didn’t hit: right below itself. Right where Minaga stood.

Jake sprinted as the lasers arrived, more than a dozen beams sweeping in from the side. Despite this, Jake did not slow down in the slightest. Both katars appeared in his hands just as the first beam hit, but Jake was ready.

Using Eternal Hunger’s edge, he reflected the first ray of light. The beam moved so fast he had to use the Blackpoint Blade as a bridge to make it flash past him. At the same time, Jake dove in between two beams and used every small spot he could fit through. Briefly, he met the eyes of Minaga, who just stared at him.

He kept staring as Jake dodged hundreds of beams within a second, finally arriving in the safe zone right below the disco ball.

“That is some bullcrap right the—”

Jake kept going with his momentum and slammed both katars into the chest of Minaga, who was still casting the spell. He penetrated halfway to the hilt with both weapons before the light show stopped, and then his danger sense exploded. He jumped back, not even having the time to try and pull out his weapons.

A beam shot down right where Jake had just stood. He pivoted around it, slamming a dark green, glowing palm into the Unique Lifeform’s side while the beam of light burned a hole dozens of meters into the ground. Minaga seemed to have had enough: The sound of the disco ball shattering sounded out, and thousands of razor-thin shards of glass descended upon Jake, forcing him to properly retreat.

Jumping back, he failed to fully dodge his own Blackpoint Blade, which Minaga had sent telekinetically flying after him, leaving a cut on his cheek. Eternal Hunger had already been recalled as Jake made his retreat.

Jake wasn’t even sure how prematurely he had interrupted the large spell, but he was sure as hell happy he had. Seeing as Minaga was not following up with more spells, Jake assumed he couldn’t, so he pulled out his bow and began pelting the Unique Lifeform while checking in on his teammates.

Sylphie had managed to come out of it mostly unscathed, but she had consumed a lot of energy from thousands of beams of light sweeping through her elemental form. Dina had also come out okay, though she too had consumed a lot of mana by repeatedly summoning her root walls, with Bobo only barely managing to block what did get through. She’d still received a nasty cut right above one of her eyes, but she was quickly healing it.

The Sword Saint was surprisingly unscathed as he stood behind a large painting. The painting itself had been utterly burned to a crisp and pierced in places, and the Sword Saint’s expression suggested losing that particular painting was not a pleasant experience. From the telepathic mark, he also made it clear that was a limited-use skill with high energy consumption.

Finally, there was the Fallen King, who—to put it nicely—looked like shit. The constant barrage of lasers had managed to get through his barrier, leaving hundreds of burn marks crisscrossing his entire body. The only untouched parts were the mask and the ivory hands and feet, which were too naturally tough to be affected.

Despite clearly being damaged, the Fallen King did not seem affected, nor did he hesitate to make a move to at least get some revenge. Golden energy gathered in both of his hands as he unleashed a large, golden beam carrying energy of the soul-damaging variant.

Dina and the Sword Saint also engaged as Sylphie dove down, a whirlwind of slicing winds surrounding her. The next few seconds resulted in Minaga getting dozens of minor injuries as four people went HAM on him during his period of weakness, while Dina focused on healing everyone.

Five seconds after the spell stopped, magic from Minaga reappeared. A tornado of fire erupted from his body, throwing away the Sword Saint, and his hand shot out a howling blast of snow and ice, launching Dina toward the back of the room. Jake managed to dodge both of these and navigate a stable arrow around the magic, striking Minaga in the chest. A blast of force hit the exact same spot as Jake’s arrow, making it pierce even deeper than before. With a mental command from Jake, it exploded, bathing Minaga in destructive arcane energies.

Jake’s eyes opened wide as he was forced to summon a stable arcane barrier against the gust of wind sweeping towards him. It only managed to lift Jake off the floor and send him skittering back, but the Fallen King was less lucky. A spike of metal flew out from Minaga, piercing him in the chest and blasting him back until he hit a wall. Said wall then began to fold as if wanting to crush him, but the Fallen King released an omnidirectional shockwave, freeing himself.

Minaga attacking Jake and the Fallen King once more gave Sylphie and the Sword Saint an opening, and they both struck. By now, they had begun to get a far better read on Minaga’s abilities as well as his overreliance on hand motions to cast. As they found more and more small openings, the wounds on Minaga accumulated a bit at a time. Whatever damage Jake and the others took was swiftly handled by Dina, who focused primarily on healing and landing the occasional strike if she saw a good opening.

After Jake landed a solid Powershot a few minutes later, making Minaga reel back with a bloody chest, he suddenly stopped mid-movement and grinned. His body was full of wounds, but he seemed unbothered. “Oh, damn. I hit seventy percent health! Do you all know what that means? That’s right—it’s time for phase two!”

Jake got a bad feeling as he heard this. He wanted to shoot another arrow at Minaga, but he suddenly felt space warping around him as Minaga took out an odd orb and raised it. At the same time, his body began to warp, too.

As they all watched, more Minagas appeared. Five versions of himself looked to almost walk out of the original as the orb above him exploded, and Jake’s vision momentarily went dark.

He found himself transported to another arena, standing alone in front of a clone of Minaga.

“Ha ha! After spending nearly half of my remaining health points, I have successfully split you up, and on your lonesome, you shall face this clone holding an undefined percentage of my true power! Only after you have defeated it can you enter the arenas of your party members and assist them in killing their respective clones. After you have slain all of the clones, you may return to the main boss room once more and face me in a final phase!”

Jake stared at the clone and got a feel for its power. It was a lot weaker, but not weak by any means. What’s more, if they were all facing their own versions… Jake wasn’t sure how all the others would do—especially Dina, who’d had to consume a lot of energy thus far.

“What, no banter?” Minaga said, sounding disappointed.

Without hesitation, Jake charged. If he could only help the others after he was done here, it meant he had no intentions of delaying. Mid-charge, his speed increased as Arcane Awakening activated at the offensive 50%. His reason for entering melee rather than staying at range was simple… He was pretty sure Minaga was way better than him at ranged combat.

He did not believe Minaga was better at dodging in a melee brawl.

Minaga grinned at Jake’s charge as both staves appeared. One of them sent a flamethrower toward him, but Jake quickly jumped to the side and, with another jump, continued his charge. With a swipe of the other staff, a barricade of rock spears shot out of the ground. Jake vaulted over them before they had even fully emerged.

Dozens of orbs appeared all around Minaga as beams of light shot out, but Jake expertly dodged them all and stepped down one final time, teleporting right in front of the Unique Lifeform. A staff flew down towards his head, but Jake had already slipped by it and landed a solid jab at Minaga’s chest. This time, the weapon penetrated far deeper than on the real version, leaving a solid wound.

Metal chains shot out from one of the staves, but Jake fired a shockwave of arcane mana and blasted them away before he managed to land another cut. Minaga retaliated fast by unleashing an explosion of fire, making Jake jump back. Mid-jump, he pulled out his bow and fired a single arrow in an instant, taking the Unique Lifeform by surprise to leave a nice hole in his chest.

Landing, Jake teleported into melee again. Minaga was already preparing to launch a ranged attack. He successfully interrupted Minaga by stabbing his arm, continuing his relentless assault. Jake had no plans of letting up as he continued his all-out aggression, never allowing Minaga to cast a major spell—assuming he even could in this split form. This required him to make some sacrifices, as his Scales of the Malefic Viper had to handle quite the brunt of magic attacks Jake chose to endure or only partly dodge to avoid disengaging for too long.

Minaga eventually began adapting, becoming more defensive and summoning metal barriers to defend himself while attempting to get some distance. Jake tried to stay close, but a powerful mix of earth shards and wind magic made it difficult as, momentarily, the fight shifted to ranged combat.

Momentarily.

Through the use of Eternal Shadow, Jake managed to avoid a large spike of lava and once more close the distance.

Jake had time on his side, as the poison was slowly accumulating within Minaga, but he was also on a tight timeline. He had a nagging feeling that he was on a timer… As for whether this timer was due to his party members being in danger or some unknown factor, he had no way of knowing.

Either way, the best course of action would be a swift victory, no matter the scenario.

Elsewhere, Jake’s other party members faced their respective clones. Sylphie’s room was a glorious battle of two domains of magic fighting one another. A bird and Unique Lifeform flew within, trying to find chances to strike at one another. Both sides consumed vast amounts of resources, with no clear winner in sight.

The Fallen King fought Minaga straight on, the other Unique Lifeform meeting him with a similar mindset. In the end, they were both Unique Lifeforms. A natural compulsion to compete was ingrained in both of them, even if Minaga was, by all rights, far more powerful, both in this form of himself within the dungeon and his true, likely divine version outside.

Other Unique Lifeforms were simply the closest they could ever get to kin, and this left them with a need to prove themselves superior. It was the same as with the Ashen Devourer. As such, their fight was fierce. Both parties went all-out from the get-go, trying to prove themselves the better Unique Lifeform.

Dina took a far more calculated approach. She communicated her strategy through the Golden Mark, and it was instantly approved. Rather than fighting Minaga, she went entirely on the defensive, not even trying to attack unless it was to interrupt something she found too dangerous to block, avoid, or heal through. She was strong, yes, but in a one-versus-one, she was likely the weakest in their party overall. Her offensive prowess was simply not that impressive.

This left Jake’s final party member… the Sword Saint.

Miyamoto listened to Minaga finish his speech as he prepared himself. The Unique Lifeform stood in front of him, seemingly just waiting for his opponent to make a move… but the Sword Saint had something bothering him.

“You’re holding yourself back, aren’t you?” he asked Minaga.

“What makes you ask that?” Minaga asked with a smile and a raised eyebrow.

“Your movements are, at times, almost intentionally stilted when you swing the staff. As if you are purposefully making sure you do not pass a certain self-imposed threshold of technique. I have done so before when practicing with others.”

“Man, you are crazy good at fighting for a C-grade, you know that?” The Unique Lifeform shook his head.

“I shall take that as a compliment,” the Sword Saint said, bowing.

“It was, so you should! Anyway, yeah, you are right, but it is what it is. Or do you not want it to be what it is?”

“This may be inappropriate of me to ask, but…” The Sword Saint sighed. “Would you allow me to experience your guidance?”

“You want me to not hold back as much?”

“Yes, as impertinent as that may be,” the Sword Saint said, nodding. He knew he was being selfish in his request. They were there to beat the fight, and here he was, asking instead for guidance. While the others were trying to win quickly, he was just talking. No… he was asking for his fight to be made harder.

Minaga looked at him for a second before just smiling. “You know what? Fine, I can bend the rules a bit. From here on out, this clone will not use any magic, but I shall raise my technique level proportionately to make up for it.”

“I thank you,” the Sword Saint said, bowing again. “I will also not—”

“No, you do everything you can to win. Trust me—you will need it. Also, I am changing your victory condition. Rather than defeat me, the other four clones just have to be destroyed.”

The Sword Saint knew not to argue, so he just nodded.

Minaga looked at him and grinned as he waved his hand, a sword appearing in front of him and floating. It looked like a weak, common-rarity steel sword that you could buy in bulk for cheap, and the Sword Saint did not feel anything special about it. What’s more… it was blunt. Not a shred of an edge present.

“Well, then. Prepare yourself. The lesson is about to begin, and you have only one task.”

Reaching out, he grasped the sword, and the moment he did, Miyamoto jumped backward on instinct as his eyes opened wide.

“Survive.”

Miyamoto desperately took a defensive stance, feeling like a child standing before his sword instructor for the very first time. Fear mixed with excitement as he prepared for a duel with someone of skill incomparably superior to his own.

Chapter 48

Solo Battles

Blood flew into the air as Jake managed to slice the neck of Minaga, making him stumble back. His one arm already hung limply at his side as he tried to retaliate with the other using a blast of fire, but Jake dodged under it and stabbed Minaga in the arm.

A final eruption of power sent Jake stumbling back amid a rain of lightning bolts, making his entire body tingle from the impact and his scales crackle with energy. Minaga himself looked spent as he stood there, leaning on his staff.

Jake pulled out his bow, showing no mercy by firing an Arcane Powershot into Minaga that sent him flying into a wall with another hole in his chest. Activating his Arcane Charge from the Mark, he made Minaga flash with arcane energy and groan.

Still embedded halfway into a wall, he looked at Jake. “Heh… good fight. I at least had fun. You are also the first one to win, so take pride in that! Good luck with the rest of our battle.” Minaga smiled. “See you soon.”

With those words, Minaga’s clone turned into wisps of energy that moved and created three portals, each with the figure of one of his party members above it. The one not showing was the Sword Saint’s, and Jake knew why, as the old man had informed them of his special “lesson” with the Unique Lifeform. After he had informed them of that, there had been radio silence, but considering they had not gotten any notifications about failing the bonus objective, he should still be fighting.

Jake felt happy, but he was not really proud of being the first one to finish his fight. In fact, it was completely expected. The clone he fought was weaker than the real Minaga by a great deal, but it was still level 275, which meant his Big Game Hunter skill remained active and as powerful as before, and all of his skills that allowed him to do more damage to higher-level foes still worked. He was truly the best in fights like this.

Focusing on where to go next, he looked through the portals and quickly reached out using the Golden Mark. “Done with my clone. Where should I head next? Anyone need help badly?”

They had not communicated much, as they were all busy with their own respective fights, so Jake didn’t know the situation in the other rooms.

“Ree!” Sylphie complained through the link, clearly not happy with how things were going on her end.

“I can hold on for a while longer,” Dina said.

“Leave me be,” the Fallen King said dismissively, sounding almost offended by Jake even daring to ask if he needed help with handling the other Unique Lifeform.

No answer from the Sword Saint. Not that it mattered, as helping him was not an option.

Jake didn’t delay. He jumped through the portal with the figure of Sylphie above it, and the moment he arrived on the other side, he was buffeted by powerful winds as he got a lay of the land.

If Jake’s fight had been a focused fight with emphasis on micro-strategy that led to little impact on their surroundings, Sylphie’s fight was the exact opposite. The entire room was thoroughly torn up all around him as magic on a massive scale ravaged it. With no party members to watch out for, Sylphie let loose and became a living whirlwind of destructive winds, filling nearly half of the room.

Minaga had clearly responded in kind. Massive magic circles floated around him, throwing out large-scale spells as if mana wasn’t even a resource to him. Giant, freezing tornadoes met Sylphie’s winds and canceled each other out, both parties trying to land smaller and more deadly attacks whenever an opportunity presented itself. That usually took the form of Sylphie occasionally attempting a fly-by, with Minaga sometimes finding an opening to land a beam of light or a highly condensed ice shard or metal spike.

A sort of balance had been reached, and Jake truly had no idea who would win if it continued. He had no interest in finding out, either.

Sylphie and Minaga crashed within the tornado as their domains overlapped, and Sylphie’s charge was met with Minaga striking out with a palm of whirling flames. A giant inferno exploded from their impact, yet the fire was rapidly dispersed by the powerful winds. Just as Minaga prepared to strike again, he suddenly cursed.

“Well, shi—”

A fully charged Arcane Powershot hit him in the side, blasting his barrier apart and sending him reeling back with blood trickling down his side. A stable arcane arrow had deeply penetrated his shoulder, and he did not have time to pull it out before Jake made it explode.

Sylphie quickly followed up by unleashing a giant blade of wind, sending the Unique Lifeform tumbling back even further. Minaga stabilized and went on the offensive, but facing two opponents was much more difficult.

He seemed to know this, too, as he tried to be ultra-offensive, knowing that if he didn’t, he would fail to accomplish anything. Rather than dodge, Minaga tanked several attacks as dozens of magical circles popped into the air around Sylphie. She tried to get away, but a few of the circles lit up, sealing the area. The rest of the circles began glowing with increasing intensity, and even when an arrow pierced Minaga’s chest and sent him flying, he didn’t lower his hands, but instead finished the spell.

All of the magic circles shattered at once, releasing pulses of dark energy that washed over Sylphie. A screech echoed throughout the hall, making Jake worried. He moved to make sure Minaga could do nothing more, repeatedly blasting the Unique Lifeform back while Sylphie got her bearings.

The explosions of dark magic had not hit just her, but all of the wind that was connected to her. Her body seemed to give off black smoke that had invaded, almost like a poison consuming her from within. Jake did not register it as poison, but he knew it was damn close.

Minaga had a hard time dealing with Jake alone due to how injured he was, and when an enraged Sylphie rejoined the fight, things got even worse for him. Coupled with what injuries he had taken from Sylphie during their one-versus-one fight, Jake and his bird niece managed to finish off the Unique Lifeform within the next few minutes.

“Two down—and with the old swordsman doing his thing, two to go! Do hurry, though!” Minaga’s body faded into wisps of energy, spawning two portals. As they were still forming, Sylphie flew over and landed beside Jake.

“Ree,” Sylphie said, sounding sad as she took out a small bottle from her vest and ate it.

That dark mana spell had severely damaged her mana pool, forcing her to drink a mana potion. She was also a tad low on other resources from Minaga’s magic and her long fight, but she sounded confident, if disappointed, in how hard of a time she’d had.

Jake calmed her down, and after telepathically confirming that the Fallen King still refused help, the two of them headed to Dina’s arena.

What met Jake and Sylphie upon entering was a raging inferno, making it clear which school of magic Minaga had chosen to deal with Dina. It seemed to be working pretty well, too, based on how much ash was spread everywhere. It was as if an entire forest had been burned down throughout their fight.

Dina was flying around the room, repeatedly defending herself, while Minaga chased after her, released fireballs, blasted out flamethrowers, and summoned what looked like living creatures of pure fire to pursue her. Dina kept calling up green barriers or vines to defend herself, even if they got burned down in seconds.

Yet even while clearly on the back foot, Dina looked nearly untouched. Her defense against the constant barrage of spells was nearly perfect, and even when Minaga mixed it up and used things other than fire, she was ready and responded appropriately.

Jake and Sylphie entering the arena naturally changed the situation quite a bit. Quite a bit, in this instance, meaning this Minaga clone was utterly screwed as the three of them teamed up. With Dina helping out the two of them, they could be far more offensively-minded. Knowing one had a healer on their side did wonders for one’s self-confidence, and in this case, it even allowed Sylphie to get healed up a good deal.

Minaga did give it a good shot, but the clone was just too weak compared to the real thing and didn’t have the same powerful composite magic. Or maybe he did, and Minaga just chose not to use it. Hearing that the Sword Saint would fight Minaga in a “special way” just confirmed something Jake and the others already knew… The Unique Lifeform was not serious.

Which made sense… because if he was a god—which he one hundred percent was—they wouldn’t stand a chance at all, even if his stats were heavily reduced. Just through sheer experience and skill, they would have been fucked. That he held himself back to a certain threshold was only to be expected, and that the old man had convinced Minaga to slightly let go of these self-imposed restrictions was indeed risky as fuck. Not that Jake could blame him. The Sword Saint had a hard time finding people around his own level of power skilled enough in pure technique to fight him.

After fighting Dina’s clone for around five minutes, it too bowed out and summoned a final portal, which they promptly headed through. What met them was an even more intense sight than what Jake had seen in the prior two rooms.

The Fallen King stood on one side, his body covered in wounds. Several sections had huge swaths of his bark-like skin ripped off, and one of his legs looked halfway cut through. On the other side was a Minaga who had lost both an arm and a leg, with his entire body truly reflecting the intense fight. He even lacked two of his four eyes, claw marks bleeding across his face.

“Do not interfere,” the Fallen King ordered in their heads just as they appeared.

“Arrogant as always.” The Minaga clone smiled. “I say always, even if I don’t really know you, as honestly, all of us Unique Lifeforms are the same, aren’t we? All arrogance. With actual power to back it up, mind you.”

Scoffing, the Fallen King’s body exploded in golden light as he summoned two golden hammers on chains. He swung one as Minaga jumped using his one leg, dodging it. The second hammer descended from above, but Minaga flung himself out of the way using telekinesis and pointed his staff at the King, shooting out a highly condensed beam of light.

It hit the King’s barrier, making him float to the side as fast as he could. When the bubble was burned through, the beam barely missed him, allowing the Unique Lifeform to counter once more. Both hammers swung wildly as the two wisps in the King’s eyes began to glow.

Both hammers shone brighter than before and briefly sped up, allowing the Fallen King to hit Minaga. His attempt to block flung him across the room. Jake thought it hadn’t done much, but he frowned when he got a better feel for that golden glow.

Soul magic.

Jake saw Minaga get to his feet, but he had clearly taken a lot of damage. That hammer had not just hit Minaga’s physical body; it had directly impacted his Soulshape, rocking it and damaging it. Jake could already imagine the headache one would get if hit directly.

Nevertheless, Minaga was not down for the count yet. A magical circle appeared below him and accelerated him forward, sending him flying towards the King as he infused mana into his staff. It began to grow thicker and longer as the King tried to stop the other Unique Lifeform.

Minaga chose to take the golden blast of force directly to the face, sending blood flying everywhere. Simultaneously, he swung hard, hitting the Fallen King in the side faster than he could react. The barrier broke, and the Fallen King folded like a lawn chair around the large staff before getting blasted into the wall at the far end of the room.

Dina looked worried and was about to make a move, but Jake held out a hand and stopped her. A second later, a dense golden beam erupted from the broken wall, hitting the now kneeling Minaga who was missing half of his face. He didn’t move, but the moment the beam stopped, the Unique Lifeform fell forwards, dead.

“Wow, good job—you killed one of five clones all alone!” Minaga’s voice echoed through the hall. “Truly proud of you, fellow Unique Lifeform!”

Out of the broken wall he had been thrown into walked the Fallen King, his right arm utterly broken and his midsection full of injuries. Yet he gave off an indomitable aura and a strong sense of pride. With Minaga’s body dissolving, Dina no longer held back. She took out her staff and fired off green lightning that began slowly mending the King’s broken body.

Soon enough, a portal appeared, this one bigger than any of those prior. On the other side, Jake could see Minaga sitting with his legs crossed atop a raised platform, energy revolving around him.

“You good to go?” he asked the Fallen King, who floated over next to him. He saw the golden lines pulsing through his body, making it clear his boosting skill was active at either full power, or close to it.

“I shall do fine,” the Fallen King said dismissively.

Jake threw Dina a glance.

“The body of the Fallen King is just a vessel… Unless it is utterly destroyed, he will be fine,” she explained.

Kind of already knew that, Jake thought, shrugging as he led the others through the portal. This also meant the Sword Saint had succeeded. If not, they would have gotten a notification, so he had to be fine. Well, not necessarily fine, but at least not lethally injured.

Upon arriving on the other side, the four of them appeared standing below the newly raised platform Minaga was sitting on. An orb of energy floated above him, nearly ten meters in diameter and radiating intense power.

Right after they arrived, another portal appeared beside them. Jake looked over as what at first looked like a bloodied rag fell out. However, on second inspection, he saw it was the Sword Saint. The old man landed hard, looking like he could barely stand, then fell to his knees.

The reason he looked like a rag was all the blood and tattered clothes. His body was marred with more wounds than Jake could count, nearly no part of him untouched. Even as he knelt there, blood slowly dripped from his body, making it clear many of the cuts were incredibly fresh.

Jake stared at the old man with wide eyes. “What the hell happened to you in there?”

The Sword Saint looked at the ground and smiled slightly as Dina focused intensely on healing him. The countless wounds on his body slowly started to close. Even so, it was clear he had taken significant damage, and he was in horrible shape, especially considering his boosting skill was going at full power.

Yet he smiled to himself.

“I survived a tough lesson,” the old man spoke, seeming to recall what he had just experienced with an expression of fondness.

Chapter 49

A Difficult Lesson

The Sword Saint had found himself in a lesson with quite the difficulty.

To face a superior foe was nothing new to him. Throughout his life before the system, he had fought many people superior to himself while growing better and better. Oftentimes, he’d also met those who simply had a stronger physique, making their speed and power higher than his own. Even so, he had risen to become one of the most talented swordsmen in the entire world, even before the system. With his many years of continued practice, even as his body deteriorated, he was perhaps the most skilled.

After the system’s arrival, he hadn’t faced a single individual around his own level who he would recognize as superior when it came to pure technique. Everyone he found capable of beating him gained their superiority not through sheer skill, but by some other advantage. Jake had an instinctive style that surpassed all sense of logic and technique, as one example.

No, the only person that the Sword Saint had fought around his own level, with a degree of technique even approaching his own, had been Ell’Hakan. He’d still been behind, even if he had proved himself a formidable fighter. The fact that he’d used a trident did contribute, too, as the Sword Saint hadn’t fought people who used those often.

Alas, the point was that the Sword Saint found it difficult to encounter opponents who could match his skill level. Fighting people of equal or superior skill was the best way to improve, so he felt like the lack of proper foes held him back. He did firmly believe that once he spent more time in the wider multiverse, he would meet many who matched or surpassed him, but for now, he felt starved.

That was when Minaga appeared.

When the Sword Saint asked Minaga to duel him using at least some of his true skill, he had expected it to be with his staff, as that was what Miyamoto had seen the Unique Lifeform display hints of overwhelming skill with. To see him pull out a sword was a welcome surprise, but he did quickly come to realize he had made one mistake.

He had either overestimated his own skill level significantly… or underestimated Minaga’s.

The Unique Lifeform stepped forward as the first move. Shifting back slightly, the Sword Saint tried to get a read on his opponent. Minaga took another step, entering the range of Miyamoto and offering him the chance to try and land a light attack.

Blood sprayed as the Sword Saint jumped back, a light cut on his arm from the blunt blade. It had moved faster than expected, yet didn’t seem any swifter than his own sword.

“Good try, but too obvious,” Minaga said, smiling. “So try again.”

Not wanting to back down, the Sword Saint moved in again, this time not holding back as his Rainblade activated. Water revolved around his blade, and several raindrops shot out toward the Unique Lifeform. Without Minaga even moving, the raindrops were cut into pieces mid-air, and the Sword Saint missed, stumbling forward.

He then jumped back as a sword swept up, leaving a light cut on his chest.

“Keep coming.”

Following the encouragement, the Sword Saint did just that. He used several of the attacks in his arsenal, but no matter what he did, it proved useless. Miyamoto felt like an utter novice. A child fighting against a true master.

And he only felt euphoria from that sensation.

“You have already progressed somewhat,” Minaga explained, blocking dozens of blows while flaying the Sword Saint’s robes through counterattacks. “The concept of the blade is embedded within your water, allowing it to cut and act like an extension of your weapon… but it is only that. An extension. Your concept itself still needs work. Most will come with time, but just as much shall be from practice. I noticed on the prior floors that your focus recently has heavily shifted to improving other aspects of your powers. Rain and time magic are all well and good, but don’t lose sight of the blade.

“Here, let me show you…”

Miyamoto swung with all his power when Minaga seemed defenseless. He did not even use his blade but instead swept his hand up, moving to catch the sword. The sharp edge of the Sword Saint’s blade hit the palm of the Unique Lifeform. The Sword Saint stared in confusion as Minaga’s flesh remained uncut. In fact, he held the ancestral blade like a blunt metal stick.

“The strongest blade is not forged from the greatest materials in the multiverse or sharpened to perfection,” Minaga said in a calm tone. “The strongest blade is the one wielded by the strongest swordsman. Sharpness is a concept like any other, and it depends on your will as much as any physical prowess or whatever weapon you may possess. You will still need the whole… but as you are now, I need nothing more than my intent to render your cuts useless. Before a fire mage, fire shall do little harm. In the same vein, a master swordsman should never find himself cut by a lesser blade. In other words, to me, it doesn’t matter if you wield a sword or a blunt object. With your current power, you simply cannot cut my flesh.”

Miyamoto tried to retrieve his sword, but the Unique Lifeform had it thoroughly grasped in his hands. Rather than struggle, the Sword Saint did something else. He dove forward as he chopped, a faint layer of water surrounding his hand.

Minaga moved his sword to block it and smiled. “Man, having a good student is great,” he said, kicking the Sword Saint away before throwing his ancestral sword back to him.

Catching it, Miyamoto barely managed to block in time as Minaga attacked.

“As I just said, anything can be a blade as long as it has the faintest level of sharpness.” The Sword Saint listened to Minaga’s words, his body suffering more cuts all the while. “Water is a great tool to make blades, as you have no doubt already realized. But you need to seek deeper. Consider all the whys you can find. The Path you walk is one of enlightenment through practice and learning, same as me. Don’t look at those around you as ones to imitate, and at most, only observe them for inspiration. Only Dina walks a kind of Path similar to yours, after all. Jake, Sylphie, and that other darn Unique Lifeform all walk Paths following their instincts, which means teaching them can be downright detrimental, as that could bring them further from their instinctual comprehension. To them, actually understanding something isn’t overly critical. They only need the how; the why is an afterthought to comprehend after the fact. You, on the other hand, do well with a teacher, as you get stronger from the why… Am I just rambling here? Do you understand what I am trying to say?”

“I believe I do,” the Sword Saint answered as he retreated, Minaga giving him a light reprieve to respond. “I am to truly ponder the concept of sharpness… No, of all those related to my Path. I am to honestly try and understand them. But I believe I am already doing this. My sword is already central to my Path; all other concepts are only there to assist my blade.”

Minaga laughed as he moved in, and Miyamoto once more tried to desperately block. He managed to resist a few unpredictable slices, but he still found himself bloodied.

“When did I ever say you were doing anything wrong!?” Minaga laughed, pressing on as the Sword Saint tried to adapt. “Did I ever say you were straying from your Path?”

Miyamoto was confused, which made him briefly lose focus and suffer a nasty cut to his shoulder. He tried to counterattack but was pushed back when Minaga landed a palm strike on his chest, leaving more than fifty small, crisscrossed cuts from the light attack.

“I believed you were pointing out flaws,” the Sword Saint said as he stabilized himself, questioning whether he failed to comprehend the words of the master swordsman before him.

“I was.” Minaga smiled as he raised his sword before continuing his relentless assault. “You have three massive flaws compared to me.

“The first is experience,” the Unique Lifeform said as he allowed the Sword Saint to attack over and over without countering, gladly just blocking everything. “The number of foes you have encountered that could truly match you is limited. This will improve with time, but you would do well practicing with someone of high skill when you can. Not necessarily skill equal to your own, just someone close enough. Superior would be best, of course, but that can be hard to find.”

Their “fight” continued with the Sword Saint now on the defensive, using everything he had to avoid any lethal blows, his boosting skill already active at full power just so he could hang on.

“The second is time. You may think it is the same as experience, but… Actually, no, you probably don’t think that, as I assume you know the difference. You strike me as a smart fellow, after all. Anyway, this one is the most obvious. You need time to practice what you already know. Time to meditate. Time to ponder. Time to simply grow in power and have your horizon expanded. Experience and time do go hand in hand, as experience is simply one good way to spend your time.” Minaga sent the Sword Saint flying, nearly severing an arm.

“Third is your biggest flaw compared to me by a large margin, but sadly, I cannot help you in this area,” the Unique Lifeform said in a far more serious tone. He even stopped attacking for a second as he sighed. “The third is… handsomeness. No matter how many times you evolve, you simply cannot even begin to approach the perfection that is Minaga.”

Miyamoto stared for a few seconds before he smirked to himself, feeling a singe of pain from his cut-open cheek. “As much as it saddens me, that is simply something I will have to live with.”

“Damn shame, damn shame…” Minaga shook his head. “Anyway, let’s continue our fun. I am sure you have already realized what this lesson is about by now, right?”

The Sword Saint nodded, yet Minaga still explained, “That’s right—it’s experience. That will be my method of teaching. Observe, feel with your body, and study me as you try to survive. Learn what you can without finding yourself crumbling, but do know that you are on a timer. The lesson will end when either your party succeeds in killing my four other clones, or your body fails you. Whichever comes first. Now, let us speak with naught but our swords.”

These were the final words Minaga spoke before he attacked again, and the Sword Saint met his teacher. Everything he did was foiled, but he kept fighting as the minutes passed. He was pushed back repeatedly. Minaga did not let up, barely giving him time to breathe, yet the Sword Saint also began to notice something else. The Unique Lifeform intentionally used certain repeated rhythms in his swordsmanship. One would think getting a read for this rhythm would make it easier for the Sword Saint, but he soon came to realize this insight was a necessity, not a way to get an advantage…

Because Minaga kept heightening the difficulty. Whenever the Sword Saint thought he saw an opening or reached an adequate understanding of his opponent, the pattern slightly changed, forcing him to dance to Minaga’s tune once more, and all he could do was try and keep up.

No matter how much he felt like he had improved, the wounds kept coming. Miyamoto barely found a brief opening to consume a health potion to battle the blood loss, as his body was shredded nearly beyond recognition.

This kept going as the minutes passed.

Suddenly, Minaga changed his movements and attacked in a far more aggressive manner.

The Sword Saint moved his blade carefully, trying to block the other sword, but it seemed to move in an ever-changing pattern. Just as Miyamoto thought he was about to block it, it seemed to disappear, only to reappear and leave a cut on his chest. He knew better than to try and counterattack, but even as he attempted to dodge, he failed.

He could only stare with wide eyes as the flat side of the blade struck him in the stomach, sending him tumbling backward and sliding to leave a trail of blood across the tiled floor. Trying to get up, he felt his legs failing momentarily.

I cannot delay.

There was no choice anymore. Deep inside, he knew that a mere Glimpse of Spring would do nothing in this situation. It was unfortunate, but he would rather unleash his full Transcendence than fail the bonus objective. Miyamoto also believed the backlash this time should not be as bad as it had been during the Treasure Hunt.

With determination, the Sword Saint slowly stood and sighed. “I call—”

“Aaand the others have killed the fourth clone,” the final Minaga clone interrupted, stopping mid-movement. “Well, that was a bummer and a bit faster than expected. Oh, well. What can you do about it? I guess I could have made the clones stronger, true, but I digress.”

Shaking his head, the Unique Lifeform threw a glance at the old swordsman standing there, frozen a dozen meters away. “I guess you win. Congratulations! Man, I teach a damn good lesson, if I may say so myself. I should become a multiversally renowned teacher! Actually, on second thought, that sounds miserable. Yeah, I am just going to stick to impromptu lessons like this.”

Miyamoto could only stare as his wounds suddenly began aching. He reflected on his own state and compared it to the creature before him. The Minaga clone stood relaxed and with his simple, blunt sword in hand, not a single thread on his robes touched by a blade.

The Sword Saint—if he could even call himself that—looked quite the opposite. Every part of his body was covered in small cuts, thousands in total, that marred him from head to toe. More blood than a human body could possibly contain coated the room from his wounds.

One would think he would feel humiliated. Miyamoto had been utterly dominated from the very beginning. There were no two ways about it. Hundreds of times, Minaga could have killed him, but every time he’d been spared.

Miyamoto could only feel grateful as he bowed deeply, despite the intense pain it invited. “I thank you for this lesson.”

“You bloody well should! Nearly no one gets an opportunity like this. Now get out of here and see if you can beat the final phase!”

With those words, the Minaga clone exploded, and the Sword Saint was enveloped by a portal. He dropped back into the boss room, surrounded by his four party members.

Jake studied the smiling old man and his expression of reminiscence. While Dina quickly healed him, Jake shook his head and turned his gaze towards the meditating Minaga, who still had his eyes closed. Whether he was giving them time or preparing something, Jake didn’t know, but he welcomed the brief pause anyhow.

And brief it was, as only a few seconds later, Minaga opened his eyes.

“You have passed the second phase, I see! And all of you even remain in the fight, proving none of you are pathetic dead weights.” Minaga sounded oddly offensive for no reason. Slowly standing up, he lifted his hand and pointed at the giant orb of energy floating above him. Jake’s danger sense stayed silent even as Minaga’s finger began glowing. “For this achievement, I will award you the opportunity to face my final form... me, in a way cooler environment with more magic and stuff!”

With those words, the orb above him exploded in a massive shockwave, bathing them all in light. The entire boss room was obliterated, blinding even Jake as Minaga’s voice echoed.

“Cue the final theme!”

The music changed, yet Jake still had no idea where the hell it was coming from.

Chapter 50

Third Phase!

Jake’s eyes slowly adjusted as he sent out a Pulse of Perception, trying to get a read on what exactly Minaga had done when he exploded the giant orb. What met him was a mental image he had not seen coming.

The entire room, outside of the now mostly bare floor, was gone, with even the tiles having disintegrated from the odd shockwave. The walls and ceiling had been blasted apart, leaving large platforms floating all around them in empty space.

Indeed, that was all Jake saw beyond the central platform and the many floating pieces of debris: empty space. The environmental mana had also changed significantly, feeling far emptier. Hollow. Nearly all of the affinities were gone, leaving them only with pure mana.

As his eyes slowly adjusted, he noticed how much darker it had gotten. When they finished adjusting, he finally got a good understanding of what had happened.

Jake and company found themselves floating on a large stone platform in the middle of space, the surrounding stars giving off little light. The only physical objects other than the large stone platform were the broken parts of the walls and ceiling that had survived the giant orb’s explosion, now floating all around them, suspended in space due to gravity’s shift.

The orb had been made solely to blow up the room without affecting Jake and the others. It was just a fancy way to introduce the arena where the final phase would take place.

As for Minaga himself, he was floating on a small platform right in front of them, both staves ready.

“Let us have this final fight amongst the stars! Come, challengers, and face me in my most powerful state! Okay, my most powerful state within the C-grade portion of Nevermore, anyway. Wait, also outside of that special lesson with the old swordsman. Ignore those. This is my most powerful state nevertheless!”

As they stared up at the Unique Lifeform, Jake had a premonition.

“He is going to use more… complicated forms of magic now,” Jake sent through the Golden Mark, warning the others. “At least space magic, but probably also other kinds.”

None of them seemed surprised, as there had to be something different about this final phase. Jake experienced an odd mix of emotions: He wanted to see what Minaga was now capable of, but he also wanted to win.

Jake smiled as he looked tauntingly at Minaga, getting a grin in response.

“Now, let us begin!”

Minaga’s words became the starting shot. Jake’s body began to glow with power, his aura heightening, and he instantly understood there was more to this phase than just more complicated magic.

The Unique Lifeform had finally used his own boosting skill.

Jake instantly retreated. The Sword Saint did the same, followed by Dina as she healed him. The Fallen King, despite being damaged, dove forward. Considering his boosting skill was fully active from the get-go, he seemed keen to get into the action. Sylphie followed suit by circling around their foe, waiting for an opening.

Smiling, Minaga stomped his foot. The platform below him cracked as he kicked off it, all of the stone catching fire and shooting towards the Fallen King. He blocked it with a barrier in front of him, but Minaga had already released another attack before the King had time to react. This one struck from above, completely avoiding the summoned barrier. Dozens of ice shards fell upon the Unique Lifeform.

Minaga was about to do more when an Arcane Powershot struck him, forcing him to retreat slightly. Jake did not let up, shooting and making full use of the wide-open space. He had already found his way to some of the debris, using it as a foothold while shooting.

“You really are the biggest threat… or maybe just the most annoying,” Minaga said, praising Jake. At least, he saw it as praise.

The Unique Lifeform spread out his arms, and Jake suddenly felt that the stars above shone brighter than a moment prior. He jumped when he felt a sense of danger, and just in time. A beam descended from above, obliterating where he had just been standing.

Using a hand motion, Minaga made the stars above shift. Jake was still staring as what looked like a bull formed via Minaga’s drawn lines, and the entire figure began to glow. Sylphie tried to stop Minaga, but he teleported—meaning space magic was now also on the table—and appeared too far away for any of them to interfere.

Up above, the constellation flashed one final time before moving. For a brief moment, Jake felt like the constellation was connected to a higher concept—one far beyond anything in a C-grade dungeon. It was gone as fast as it came, but Jake had used Identity on the constellation on instinct… and he was not sure if he regretted that decision.

[Eldenstar Bull Monarch – lvl ????]

He saw this Identify result only for a brief second. Then it suddenly changed, and even his system log was no longer the same.

[Sign of the Bull – lvl 260]

The beast broke out of the stars above and descended upon them. Its body was made up entirely of stars, giving it an ethereal appearance. The power it radiated was also not to be underestimated, especially if one considered it some kind of summon.

This beast flew straight down at Sylphie, space seeming to warp around it. Minaga also quickly began moving again as he pointed his staff towards Jake. Stepping down, Jake teleported away just in time. All the debris around him flew toward where he had just stood, forming a solid ball of stone. Gravity magic?

Jake also had to dodge this solid ball when Minaga threw it at him. High above the platform, Sylphie had engaged this Sign of the Bull monster. The beast used some kind of astral magic to warp space and make small stars appear, which it then exploded to dispel Sylphie’s wind. Sylphie did not want to see herself outdone, though, as she began to tear into the creature of stars. It seemed very effective, too, as the winds alone seemed to almost destabilize the constellation’s form.

Why or how it was so effective, Jake didn’t know… but then again, Sylphie’s Sylphian Winds were weird.

Back with Minaga, the Fallen King had shrugged off the ice shards and engaged again. Golden blasts lit up the darkness of space, blocking out the lights of the stars as Minaga summoned a dense barrier to block. The golden waves rolled over it as Minaga lifted his hand.

Space shook as one of the staves appeared. The staff shone and warped reality around it, itself warping in turn as it took on the appearance of a spear and lightning bolts flew from its form. A golden hammer soon descended, but Minaga had already teleported once more, appearing above the middle of the platform. He floated and grasped his staff, ready to throw it.

“Dodging this one is heavily recommended.”

He was looking straight at Jake, but he was ready. So was the Fallen King. Problem was… there was no sense of danger. Jake’s intuition screamed, and he reacted.

“Dina, watch out!”

Minaga twisted his body mid-throw, the spear of lightning flying past Jake and the King—straight for Dina, who had retreated with the Sword Saint to heal him.

Jake’s warning allowed her to respond just in time, and she acted without hesitation. Her form exploded in green light as a projection of a grand tree appeared above her, Dina herself standing within its trunk. It shielded both her and the Sword Saint when the spear hit the translucent projection of the tree, only slightly embedding itself before the lightning was absorbed.

“So you have learned a bit from that old tree!” Minaga grinned.

Dina had also changed as she cast this spell, her small antlers growing and clothes shifting. She had entered her most powerful form, putting them on even more of a timer.

The Sword Saint stood beside her, looking apologetic. However, he did seem to be in way better shape than when they’d first entered the room. The blast of intense life energy was no doubt also doing him good.

Dina seemed less than happy with being forced to activate her form change. She pointed her staff at Minaga’s, which was stuck in the bark of the projected tree. Roots shot up and coiled around it, dragging it into the ground and effectively sealing it away.

“Now that is just petty.” Minaga shook his head and flew to the side to avoid a golden blast and a Splitting Arrow.

At least, he thought he had avoided the attacks. They flew straight past him and hit the Sign of the Bull that Sylphie was fighting, blasting it back and allowing Sylphie to land a solid blow of her own. Minaga saw this and cursed to himself a bit. He began flying upwards to help the beast, but Jake and the Fallen King had resumed their attacks, forcing him to respond.

He dodged all the attacks by flying through the air and deflected a few arrows with his staff. Exactly three seconds after he had thrown the lightning spear, he teleported away when Jake and the Fallen King managed to pincer him.

“Three seconds between the big spells and more magic,” Jake said, sharing his thoughts with the group. “Or it may be a trick… Either way, it could be an opportunity.”

With his magic back, Minaga went on the offensive. The Fallen King and Jake found themselves heavily pressured while Sylphie slowly took the lead above. Meanwhile, the Sword Saint and Dina prepared themselves to rejoin the fight. The projected tree was still there, and Dina had briefly shared through the Golden Mark that she could not move or do any long-range magic with the skill active.

A projected tree that didn’t allow you to move? Very thematic. From the looks of it, Minaga knew this was the case, too, as he went after the Fallen King hard. The Unique Lifeform had already been damaged after the second phase, and now he was even worse off. Dina’s quick healing simply wasn’t enough, and with how much stronger Minaga was now, Jake could not turn the tide.

Ice and rock shards cut into the Fallen King as he retreated and summoned a barrier, only for a burning ray of condensed light to descend from above and burn into his shoulder. A third follow-up attack sent a plane of pure space magic barreling into him, blasting him into the stone platform below and creating a small crater.

Before the Fallen King could get up, the stone around him warped, creating a small mound to temporarily seal him in.

Minaga raised his hands and gathered energy. Jake instantly recognized the signs of a big spell being cast, and he tried to help with Gaze and a Powershot, but it only delayed Minaga slightly; he simply tanked the arrow, accepting the wound in exchange for potentially finishing off one of his opponents.

Jake felt the Fallen King’s intention to try and land his final trump card through the Golden Mark. Yet just as he was about to, another figure rejoined the fight.

Thrown by a massive vine and surrounded by dense life magic, the Sword Saint flew straight for Minaga. Jake saw the light gathering far up in the sky, the faint projection of a moon appearing just as overcast skies blocked out its light.

The old man turned younger for a moment as he appeared right in front of the Unique Lifeform and drew his blade.

“Glimpse of Spring: Stormcut.”

Space momentarily shattered, melting the barrier of spatial magic summoned by Minaga like butter. A large crescent wave spanned the horizon as blood spewed into the air, and the aura of the moon above faded away.

Minaga was sent stumbling back with a massive wound running from his shoulder to his hip—the kind that would have had guts spilling out of a lesser being. Minaga swiftly responded by dragging a burning hand across his own chest, cauterizing the wound.

“Man, that one was a lot stronger than what you used against the Demon Lord… Why did I agree to give you a lesson, again?” Minaga teleported away from Jake’s attempt to follow up. Jake was totally fine with that, as he knew one of the Sword Saint’s weaknesses with the Glimpse of Spring was that he could not move immediately after using it. At least, not very well.

“Good cut, though,” Minaga said, grinning. “Does make me wonder… Why is it only a glimpse?”

The Sword Saint still looked tired, regardless of healing, yet he smiled. “Perhaps you will find out.”

“Making me all excited here,” the Unique Lifeform said, laughing in between dodging attacks from Jake.

Down below on the platform, Dina’s skill that had left her rooted—pun intended—expired, and she rushed over to the Fallen King, who had managed to break out of his tomb of stone. She instantly went to work with her healing, and the Unique Lifeform took out one of his golden soul pellet-things that he used as improved potions.

In the sky, Sylphie was swiftly gaining the upper hand, her Sylphian Winds seemingly countering the constellation beast quite nicely. Once she was done, she would rejoin the fight against Minaga, and with the Fallen King and Dina also there, Jake saw their chances as good.

The only negative was that time wasn’t on their side. Everyone besides Jake and Sylphie had their boosting skills going at full power now, and while Minaga also had one active, Jake suspected he would outlast them. It was also only a matter of time before Jake and Sylphie had to go all-out.

They all knew this, which was why they moved in unison to strike at Minaga while they could. The four of them pressured the Unique Lifeform, and Jake had to admit the old man surprised him.

If the Sword Saint had one major weakness, Jake would say it was his defensive profile. He’d used that weird painting once, but in most cases, he could only use his sword or weak water barriers to block attacks. That was still the case… but his way of doing it now felt different.

Minaga shot off turbulent waves of unstable space, making reality crack in their wake, but the Sword Saint some-fucking-how managed to slice through them, dispersing their magic. He even cut a blast of wind apart, making it scatter harmlessly around him. Whatever the hell had happened during that “lesson” of his had made him come out… sharper? Like the power of every cut had become stronger in some odd way.

Soon enough, the constellation beast was slain by Sylphie, at which point she dove down and joined the assault. Defensively, Minaga proved a lot better in this final phase, as he liberally teleported around and used spatial barriers, but he was still only one being against five. When it was just two or even three of them, Minaga had the upper hand, but by now, they knew not to get separated and always covered each other.

Minaga slowly took on wounds, while Jake and company managed to come out mostly okay if one didn’t consider their stamina and mana draining fast. Dina, in her transformed state, was a wellspring of life, healing them passively while offering purely defensive assistance to ensure no one took a bad hit.

The Sword Saint even covered the stars above with a cloud that made rain fall upon the battlefield at all times. Things weren’t looking good for Minaga as he was repeatedly pushed back.

The brawl continued until the Sword Saint broke a space barrier and allowed Jake to land a well-charged Arcane Powershot, sending the Unique Lifeform barreling back.

As Sylphie flew in to follow up, Jake saw Minaga smile.

“Sylphie, get ba—”

It was too late. Minaga turned towards Sylphie, a black cube appearing in his hand. The hawk tried to avoid it, but he threw the cube like a baseball, and despite Sylphie’s wind blade and Green Shield, she was hit. The moment before the cube struck her, it expanded to swallow Sylphie. The cube then continued in its thrown trajectory, the hawk nowhere to be seen.

“One down,” Minaga said, smiling as he pushed his hands together. “And do you know what time it is?” While Jake communicated with Sylphie, who seemed trapped within some odd space, Minaga spoke again. “It’s labyrinth time!”

With those words, dozens of black cubes of shifting space appeared all around him, flying toward Jake and the others at unprecedented speed. They were all ready… until the cubes suddenly began teleporting. The Fallen King was not fast enough; a cube appeared right in front of him, swallowing him.

The Sword Saint dodged two, but a third one came from an odd angle after flying out of a portal behind him, and when he turned and tried to cut it apart, he was simply swallowed along with his sword.

Dina blocked nearly a dozen of the cubes with vines and blasts of life energy until one managed to swallow her, too.

Through Sylphie, they quickly became aware of what these cubes were:

Spatial labyrinths.

Small, self-contained labyrinths you would have to break out of to escape. They were small, but… who knew what Minaga could do with even a minute of no interference? Clearly, it would be best for at least one person not to get trapped.

This brings us to how Jake reacted.

More than a hundred cubes came for him—far more than any of the others—teleporting and shifting as portals appeared to spew them out.

He proceeded to dodge every single cube as they flew past him, continuing into the darkness of space along with the four that contained his party members.

The Unique Lifeform had raised his staff and seemed to be casting something when Jake looked his way mid-dodge. Minaga made eye contact and stopped casting.

“Yeah, good point; I won’t ever get it off. Oh, well. I guess this is also a valid option.” Minaga pulled the staff that Dina had tried to seal out of the ground below, and his other one appeared, too. “Let’s see if you can hold out till the help arrives. Very in character, by the way. Refusing to do my labyrinths even now.”

“Hey, not my fault tha—”

A beam of light shot at Jake, forcing him to dodge as space around him seemed to bend. He blasted himself to the side using mana to avoid having his face blown off.

“Oh, no, you won’t get me monologuing to buy time!”

I wasn’t trying to… Jake thought, longing to defend himself as he desperately tried to dodge. As he realized there was no space to hesitate anymore, his body exploded with power. Arcane Awakening fully activated as he prepared to face off against Minaga in his most powerful form alone.

Chapter 51

An Underhanded Strategy

Jake knew that overcoming Minaga alone in his fully empowered form was not gonna happen. He had won against the clone only due to its weakness compared to the original, but even that had been a pretty hard-fought battle.

Of course, this was assuming Jake actually had to beat the Unique Lifeform to win.

Jake jumped back to disengage as Minaga unleashed a barrage of spells, clearly having decided to try and take Jake down before his teammates had time to return. Given the estimated time it would take to do the labyrinths and the fact that they had been flung into empty space, forcing them to make their way back to the central platform again even after they were out, Jake didn’t wanna bet on them getting there soon.

Retreating further, Jake let Minaga give chase and then dove behind a large piece of debris, making the barrage of fireballs hit that instead. A large boulder flew over next, breaking it apart, but Jake was already long gone. He teleported to another part of the broken wall, where he promptly released a potshot.

His arrow was blocked by a barrier, which was totally okay with him. Any amount of time or energy Minaga spent on defending was time he didn’t use to attack. And damn, did Minaga like to attack. As he waved his hand, more than a dozen magic circles flashed into existence behind him. At the same time, Jake felt space around him constrict as dense spatial barriers formed to his sides, above and behind him. Combination spell.

“You may be fast… but can you dodge this?”

Every single formation pulsed to release a flaming metal spike straight at Jake. He dodged them and was about to taunt Minaga when a second barrage came, followed by another one even faster than the ones prior. The pulses continued, growing faster, and Jake was soon faced with more than sixty machine guns shooting out metal spikes.

Too many, Jake concluded as they kept coming. While he would have loved to see Minaga burn through mana to keep the spell active, he knew that it was only a matter of time before he was hit, forcing him to make a difficult decision.

Have to risk it.

Rather than dodge, Jake charged forward. Minaga seemed pleased but frowned slightly as Jake’s body split into two. The spikes usually focused on one target, but with two, Minaga had to either spread them out more or choose to focus on one. Either case would be advantageous to Jake.

Jake felt pleased with himself as he closed in with his Eternal Shadow ten meters to his side. Yet just as he began to feel this, his danger sense spiked.

Every single formation behind Minaga exploded, each shooting out seven or eight metal spikes like a shotgun. Jake cursed as he tried to dodge and summon a stable arcane barrier. His Eternal Shadow also reacted fast, dodging many attacks, but was eventually hit and dispersed.

Blood flew into the air as three metal spikes hit Jake. One hit his thigh, one his stomach, and one his shoulder, as he had angled himself to take the hits in the side. This was the least amount of damage he could see himself getting out of his pickle with.

Before Minaga could do more, threads of arcane mana flew out of Jake’s hand and wrapped around every metal spike to pull them out, still leaving him with three nasty holes.

“Man, I wanted to say a quip, but the fact that you got out of that combo spell with so few injuries… Yeah, you are definitely a cheat.”

“Says the Unique Lifeform who was born overpowered,” Jake shot back as he pulled out his bow and began shooting arrows alongside his words.

“Says the Bloodline Patriarch,” answered Minaga while he dodged the arrows or deflected them with his staves.

“Still just a human and not some darling of the multiverse,” Jake said as he managed to trick Minaga with a Splitting Arrow, getting a single one of them to hit him in the leg.

“Oh, poor you, being one of the enlightened races with infinite potential and all the Paths in the world open to you,” Minaga said, snorting as he pulled the arrow out on the off chance it had been primed to explode. It hadn’t, but he played it safe.

Jake smirked and retreated while shooting, wanting to get some distance from Minaga before his magic returned. “I guess we are both suffering.”

“We do have it rough, the two of us—that, we agree on. Of course, I have it harder, as I have to live up to my own greatness every day.”

“So humble, too.” Jake smirked again as he used two One Steps to find a nice cluster of debris.

“The humblest there is; in fact, I would argue I am the best at being humble in the entire multiverse,” Minaga joked as the three seconds passed, putting magic back on the menu.

This once again put Jake on the back foot. Survival was the name of the game. He didn’t want to risk another major spell, as even the normal casting was a bloody nightmare to keep up with. Not even Jake was capable of fully dodging everything. The passive barrier from the fully activated Arcane Awakening, coupled with his Scales of the Malefic Viper, did help a bunch with the larger magical attacks, but ultimately, Jake’s lowest stat was still Toughness. He was not built to take hits, but to avoid them.

On the labyrinth front, things were looking… okay? They weren’t overly large, but they would still take time to break out of. Sylphie used her speed to quickly look for an exit, and at least there were no traps or anything. She could also hear the whispers of the wind due to the lack of mist, allowing her to rapidly make progress.

The Sword Saint noted that there was even lighting within the empty, grayish hallways of the labyrinth. It was ultimately just a damn maze you had to find your way out of, and the longer you took, the more fucked your party would become as you floated further and further into the emptiness of space.

Dina further added that the entire place was shrinking slightly with time. This meant that the labyrinth became shorter and faster to do, but Jake also didn’t want to know what would happen if it shrank too much. Getting crushed within a labyrinth cube did not sound like a nice way to go.

As for the Fallen King… well, Jake had a brief exchange with him, and they reached an agreement.

Not dying while also not giving Minaga the chance or space to cast another major spell remained Jake’s main focus as he slowly bought time. Minaga didn’t seem overly stressed about finishing off Jake rapidly, though, and he knew why…

His resources were dropping fast. Arcane Awakening was a massive drain on its own, and coupled with his need to constantly use One Step, summon barriers, and regenerate his Scales, it was obvious he would run out of energy sooner rather than later.

Minaga gave off a vibe that suggested he didn’t believe actually beating Jake could be worth it, so he kept up his constant barrage of spells, either waiting for him to mess up or to run out of stamina or mana. He acted as if everything was going as expected.

Thus, Jake did something Minaga definitely had not seen coming. Lifting his hand to his face, he grasped his mask, pulled it off, and threw it toward the Unique Lifeform. His opponent dodged it, confused, then looked at Jake to discover that the mask had never left his face. Yet an object had clearly just been thrown past him.

“An illusion? No, that—”

A wave of energy erupted behind Minaga as a Golden Claw lit up the horizon, striking him in the back and spraying blood. The Fallen King instantly materialized from the thrown mask, utilizing a property of the mask Jake had never used before. As per the description…

“The Fallen King has anchored his existence to this mask, and as its owner, you are the master, allowing you to summon the Fallen King to your location at any time.”

Jake viewed summoning the Fallen King as kind of rude, and it went against the agreement they had… but in this case, Jake gladly used it for their collective gain. With permission from the Fallen King, of course. What’s more, this was something Minaga definitely couldn’t predict, as Jake had never done it before.

“Summoned? Wait…”

Minaga found himself with the Fallen King on one side and Jake on the other, and both let loose. The Unique Lifeform struggled in that bad position and had to play defensively for a while, taking several wounds as he attempted to stabilize. Jake and the Fallen King were not gonna let that happen; they both went all-out. Pulling out an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter and rapidly charging Arcane Powershot, Jake released a devastating attack while the Fallen King summoned a massive, golden hammer that descended like judgment from the heavens.

Combined with surprise and confusion, it was enough for Minaga to use his very first defensive combination spell. After putting his hands together, a giant metal sphere appeared all around him, and a field of swirling darkness soon appeared to consume it. This left him standing with a semi-transparent barrier that both the golden hammer and arrow failed to even impact. Both attacks simply sank into the darkness, never to be seen again.

As for Minaga… well, he seemed far more interested in what had just happened with the Fallen King than the actual fight. He looked extremely curious and confused as he slowly floated down to the large central platform.

“This doesn’t make any sense… That kind of summoning must mean… Huh, you are bound to him? Oh, I get it. He killed you, and in order to survive, you chose to bind whatever vestiges of your soul remained to the Records that would be transferred to the item you would drop, which you knew would be your mask. Naturally, leaving you utterly broken in the process. This was only made possible since you were the boss of a tutorial, meaning the Records transference for the kill was increased. Of course, there would be no way for you to actually ever recover from that state, as that would require powers capable of restoring a Truesoul and lost Records. Unless the system decided to lend a hand, which I assume it did due to how perfect your resurrection was. Well, perfect besides you now being bound to Jake here, which, by the way, is also utterly insane.” Overall, Minaga’s rant hit the nail on the head. When he pointed at Jake and prepared to continue, however, Jake had a thought.

Using the Golden Mark, he quickly spread his idea while Minaga continued. When the dark defensive sphere disappeared, none of them attacked. He and the King watched Minaga walk around the large central platform.

“Why insane, you might ask? Say, Jake, do you have any idea what it means for him to store his soul within the mask, which is, in turn, bound to you? It means he stored the entire concept behind his existence within you. Within your Records. Yet you weren’t affected negatively in the least, which means your own Records were not only equal but superior to a Unique Lifeform’s, allowing you to utterly overpower him. Especially considering this bond remains after his resurrection. If I had to wager a guess, you probably even hold influence over his life and death… Man, you really are utterly broken. Both of you, but in different ways. Man, I can see why Vilas made you his Chosen; you seem to have been a monster even in the tutorial… no doubt due to that Bloodline of yours.”

Minaga just kept talking as he looked deep in thought. “What’s more, for a Unique Lifeform to willingly submit in such a fashion… No, is it even submission? Some kind of mutual understanding? Man, this is peculiar.”

“An understanding was reached; that is correct,” the Fallen King answered. “One of mutual respect between two opponents. I did what I had to in order to survive. Nothing more, nothing less.”

“Oh, yeah, and your way of doing so was pretty damn impressive and probably bound to your Unique skill in some fashion,” Minaga said in a pondering tone. “It isn’t something one can just do, after all. Most wouldn’t try, either. Recovering itself was truly an impossibility, and I find it amazing that Jake even bothered bringing you back to life. The system doesn’t like to give out items allowing someone to circumvent one of its rules, so it couldn’t have been easy.”

“It did happen due to a system event,” Jake confirmed.

“I reckoned so… Was it a direct request of the system? It sometimes likes to fulfill wishes, so to speak. Or perhaps it was an item of some kind? If you don’t wanna answer, that is perfectly fine.”

“I guess it isn’t that big of a secret,” Jake said, trying to look like he was thinking for a few seconds. Finally, he sighed. “It was an item.”

“One-time use?” Minaga questioned curiously.

Jake looked at the Fallen King, who had now caught on. He also seemed to consider for a moment before saying, “You may answer…”

“Very well.” Jake nodded and resigned himself to confirmation. “It was one-time use, and I spent quite a staggering amount of Credits on it.”

“Wait, someone was selling it? During a system event?” Minaga seemed even more intrigued.

“Ah, I apologize. It was during a system event where the system auctioned off items directly as part of a reward for doing another event well.” Jake sighed loudly. “I was definitely surprised when the system manifested itself physically like that just to sell items…”

“Oh, manifestations like that do happen, though they are very rare. Well, they are not rare for you as new initiates of the new universe, but for the rest of us, they are few and far between.”

“Truly? Have you encountered the system before in a physical form?” Jake asked, looking surprised.

“Of course I have. Duh!” Minaga laughed.

“Really? Under what circumstances?”

“Heh, well, I probably shouldn’t, but if you insist, I guess I can—wait!” Minaga yelled in realization as he felt what had just happened.

At once, all three labyrinth cubes flying through space broke open as Dina, the Sword Saint, and Sylphie coordinated their exits. They had surmised that Minaga would likely know the moment someone got out… so they had all waited right at the exit to emerge as one while Jake deployed a truly underhanded strategy.

“That’s right!” Jake smiled in triumph as the three auras approached, flying at full speed back toward the platform. “I successfully got you monologuing!”

“You… You scoundrel! This is unethical! How dare you use my own extreme curiosity, vanity, and desire to hear my own voice against me!”

“A perfectly executed strategy.” Jake grinned. He and the King had gotten some distance from the Unique Lifeform, with Jake standing on the platform below, ready to react to any attacks.

“Damnit! I should have known; it was so obvious that you were just stalling!”

Pulling out both staves, Minaga released a shockwave of energy towards Jake and the Fallen King. The Fallen King blocked the blow and was sent flying back for several kilometers, while Jake dodged to remain standing on the central platform.

“Almost as if it was so damn obvious I saw right through it!”

As Jake’s danger sense erupted, he tried to retreat away from the central platform. Just as he did, a massive magic circle appeared all across it to release an enormous shockwave. In the empty space all around the platform formed what looked like millions of planes of glass reshuffling themselves. They created a barrier around the central platform…but it was not the usual kind of barrier.

It was another fucking labyrinth. One that everyone, including the Fallen King, was now outside of, trapping only two people inside. What’s more, Jake could not resummon the Fallen King. What’s even more, far above, the constellations shifted, the stars seeming to resonate with the magic circle on the platform. It was only a matter of time before more of those Sign Beasts would appear.

Minaga stood on the platform, smiling as he looked at Jake. “Guess it’s still just the two of us, eh?”

Jake looked at the Unique Lifeform and noticed the formation was still glowing along with the above constellation. The spell was active… A large combination spell…

Without hesitation, Jake pulled out his bow and loosed an arrow. Minaga dodged as Jake released another, this one blocked by his staff. Jake kept shooting, while Minaga retreated for a bit before changing his strategy and charging at Jake with a staff in each hand.

Jake’s theory was confirmed, and he was ready.

Beating Minaga with magic? No fucking shot.

Without?

Well… it was time to find out.

Chapter 52

"Of course there is one."

Jake maintained distance as he continuously retreated and took potshots at Minaga, who had no way of fighting at long range without his magic. At the same time, Jake heard from the Fallen King that the entire labyrinth Minaga had summoned seemed spatially expanded, making it a nightmare to get through. He did try to blast walls apart, and while he had some success, it appeared slower than simply rushing through as fast as possible. Jake did want to simply summon him again, but doing so was a huge strain on the Fallen King. Doing it once was fine, but more than that could have less-than-desirable consequences. So he fought alone.

Minaga handled Jake’s barrage of arrows extremely well, but he still couldn’t block everything. Jake had gotten good at shooting tricky arrows that curved to hit where the Unique Lifeform moved to dodge or looped around the staff raised to block it. His opponent was obviously also aware of this, as he stopped chasing and stood still while looking at Jake with raised eyebrows.

“Heh, while I can’t do normal magic right now… you do realize you are standing on the magic circle, right?” Minaga grinned as the ground below him began to glow, and the entire formation shifted.

When Jake stepped down, it felt like the entire world had become heavier, at least when it came to using One Step. Space had been constricted, he realized. What’s more, Minaga seemed to have slightly shrunken the arena, giving Jake less and less space to work with.

Minaga once more gave chase, yet Jake was no longer able to teleport, making it significantly harder to get proper distance. Three times, Jake barely avoided getting caught, and the fourth one forced him to switch away from his bow. Both katars appeared as the nature of the battle changed. Jake dove into melee, dodging under a staff sweep to go for a stab. Minaga was quick and stepped back as he countered, yet Jake countered the counter, slamming the staff into the ground.

He managed to land a quick stab on the Unique Lifeform’s arm but took an elbow strike in return, making him stumble back. Gritting his teeth, Jake re-engaged again, pushing the Unique Lifeform even more aggressively than before. His strikes were vicious, and Minaga found himself being slowly pushed back by Jake’s ferocity.

Several minor wounds were exchanged, but neither combatant could land any meaningful hits. Jake kept pressing, picking up speed as his katars struck dozens of times a second, putting Minaga more and more on the defensive.

“I do find it odd you are so focused on the bow… Not gonna lie—you strike me as more talented as a melee fighter,” Minaga said, trying and failing to hit Jake with his staff. With his second staff, he did manage to force Jake to disengage for a brief moment. Both of them jumped back, giving Minaga more space to talk.

“It’s like you’ve spent far more time training your melee capabilities than your skill with a bow. Don’t get me wrong—you are mean with a bow, too, but you don’t exude the same kind of pressure as you do right now. This is like having a wild beast going crazy at you, yet without the usual downsides of such a bestial fighting strategy due to your ridiculous reaction times and pure instinct.” As Minaga landed on the platform more than fifty meters away, Jake was already charging over. Preparing for the attack, Minaga continued, “I could see you walking the Path without having ever encountered the bow… perhaps for the better. Or not. Who is to tell?”

Jake kept sprinting, not commenting on anything Minaga said. He knew there was some truth to Minaga’s words, but he didn’t have the time or desire to think about things like that in the middle of a fight like this.

“Also… you seem to be misunderstanding one thing. While it is true that I cannot use any magic right now… ” Minaga lifted his staff above his head, where it began glowing with power. His aura spiked for a moment before he finished, “This isn’t classified as magic.”

Reacting to his danger sense, Jake leaped to the side just as Minaga smashed the staff down. The entire area he had just occupied exploded from the sheer force of the Unique Lifeform’s swing. As his eyes landed on Minaga, the glow from his boosting skill seemed to change. Minaga smiled, leaned forward, and stepped down.

The ground erupted beneath his step, sending him flying straight toward Jake. Without hesitation, Jake bent his back to dodge a staff sweeping right over where his head had just been, a shockwave of pure force emanating in its wake. The other staff descended from above an instant later, and Jake barely managed to slip by it.

He was still hit, however, when the ground once more erupted from the sheer power of the blow. As he flew through the air, he took out his bow and fired a single shot into Minaga’s back, much to his opponent’s annoyance. He also had a good idea why Minaga had suddenly gotten stronger.

Pure stamina manipulation, Jake concluded while blasting himself to the side using arcane mana to avoid landing on the ground again, as Minaga had already charged towards his estimated landing location. He changed course for Jake mid-charge, resulting in the two of them clashing once more, with Jake now purely on the defensive.

Minaga had gotten stronger. Faster. Yet Jake did not surrender or even try to disengage. He welcomed the pressure, pushing himself further than before. He practically felt his own veins burning from Arcane Awakening as he did all he could to keep up with the Unique Lifeform.

His mind was fully focused as he dodged. He read the flow of the fight, felt the power surging through his own body. He knew he needed to do something. Wrest back some level of control. Land a big hit. But he didn’t have the tools to do so. He knew he lacked a skill for a situation like this, and Descending Dark Arcane Fang just wouldn’t cut it. The skill was difficult to use, as he had to actively circumvent many of the skill’s functions—such requiring a downward thrust. That meant a longer activation time and less overall power.

But… if the skill wouldn’t cut it… Jake would just have to make it into one that could. The current Descending Dark Arcane Fang was fundamentally flawed. It relied on dark mana—an affinity he didn’t really use for anything anymore, and had replaced with curse energy when it came to Eternal Hunger. The entire method of delivering the blow was also flawed, as doing a downward thrust with a katar was awkward at best and impossible at worst.

So he rebuilt it from the bottom, taking inspiration from other skills and what changes he had already made to the skill after he began using katars. There was nothing truly new… He just had to combine everything.

Existing changes to Descending Fang. Inspiration from his curse energy. From his fight with sim-Jake. From the power of the Blackpoint Blade. His own arcane mana. From everything he had done to better his melee skills.

Eternal Hunger slowly pulsed with energy as a dark mist surrounded the blade, but a faint layer of arcane energy covered it just as it appeared. Meanwhile, Jake only dodged and used the Blackpoint Blade as he prepared. Minaga didn’t seem to have noticed anything, or at least he acted like he hadn’t. The exchanges continued until Jake saw his opportunity when Minaga tried a slightly wider-than-usual swing.

Using Gaze of the Apex Hunter, he threw off Minaga’s flow for a fraction of a second. Long enough for him to dodge a blow and gain ample space to launch his attack.

Jake stomped down, making the ground beneath him crack as he thrust Eternal Hunger forward. Minaga had not been ready when the katar hit him in the side, Eternal Hunger glowing with a deep purple aura as the cursed arcane energy flooded into his body. Minaga’s eyes shot open as the blade penetrated nearly all the way to the edge; he swung at Jake hard, missing but launching himself away as Jake got a system notification.

[Descending Dark Arcane Fang (Rare)] – A fang that strikes from the darkness, clamping down with the fury of your arcane. Infuse your blade with a mixture of dark and arcane mana as you do a downward strike, significantly increasing damage done and penetrative power. Dark mana makes the wound harder to heal and drains energy until dispelled. Arcane mana creates a powerful coating and extends the edge while increasing all its basic capabilities. Damage improved further if the weapon is benefitting from Twin Fang Style. Adds a bonus to the effect of Agility, Strength, and Intelligence when using Descending Dark Arcane Fang.

-->

[Piercing Cursed Arcane Fang (Epic)] – A fang born from darkness, now having embraced the power of curses, kept in control by the Hunter’s arcane mana. Infuse your weapon with a mixture of curse energy and arcane energy as you perform a thrusting strike, significantly increasing penetrative power and damage done. The curse energy will linger in any created wounds, the effect dependent on the nature of the curse energy applied. Arcane mana creates a powerful coating and extends the edge while keeping the curse energy contained. Significantly more powerful when used with Eternal Hunger. Damage improved further if the weapon is benefitting from Fang of Man. Adds a bonus to the effect of Agility, Strength, and Intelligence when using Piercing Cursed Arcane Fang.

Jake briefly glanced at the notification as Minaga landed a dozen or so meters away, a nasty wound glowing with an eerie light in his side. What’s more, Jake felt a brief burst of revitalization as Eternal Hunger fed on the energies of the Unique Lifeform.

He also took this brief chance to chug down a stamina potion, seeing as he was below 15%, and it would soon become a major problem. Keeping up with the Unique Lifeform was not easy at all.

Minaga took a solid second to address the wound. Jake felt him flood it with vital energy, rapidly eliminating the curse energy. Jake used the moment to properly observe his foe.

Despite his high-energy attitude and unbothered demeanor, Minaga looked like a mess by now. His entire body was covered in wounds and dozens of arrow holes—not to mention the deep claw mark all across his back or the frightening cauterized wound across his chest. Moreover, poison had repeatedly built up within the Unique Lifeform. His soul was also partly damaged from the King’s attacks, and Jake wouldn’t be surprised if a few seeds from Dina had managed to take root inside of him.

All in all… Jake felt that Minaga did not have that long left. He was on his last legs for sure.

“I said it… Way nastier as a melee fighter,” Minaga spoke, not moving to attack again. Jake knew why.

Another aura entered the arena; the Fallen King had finally broken through. Sylphie was close behind, and Dina and the Sword Saint were quickly making their way through the labyrinth, likely to arrive within the next half a minute. Minaga seemed to realize fighting the King and Jake without his magic wasn’t a good idea. He looked at them both and sighed.

“Oh, well…,” Minaga said, his voice echoing all around them. “I guess it’s soon time for the grand finale… Just a bit more… and there we go. I am now down to only 10% health.” Minaga lifted his hand, and a barrier appeared around him.

Jake had no confidence in breaking it, even if he really wanted to try. He had a very bad feeling that the fight wasn’t as over as he had just begun to believe.

The formation below him on the platform stopped glowing, and the entire labyrinth disappeared in an instant. Dina, the Sword Saint, and Sylphie appeared in the middle of nothing and quickly worked to get their bearings, and then their party began regrouping. Dina went straight for Jake and hit him with a green bolt of lightning, sending a wave of pure life energy through him. It was probably needed… His health pool was not looking good. Fighting Minaga alone for so long was not healthy—not to mention the constant drain on his health from Arcane Awakening.

Jake and the others kept looking on as Minaga smiled. “Remember when I called the third phase the final one? Yeah, well, what good boss doesn’t have a secret hidden phase, only activated if certain conditions are met!?”

Of course there is one, Jake thought just as he noticed something. The constellations above were still glowing.

They were never to summon more beasts… That entire thing was just misdirection.

The realization came just as Minaga spread out his hands, and the entire cosmos lit up. The stars above shone brighter than ever before, all the constellations releasing beams of light that descended upon Minaga to grow his aura.

“Hidden final phase: Cosmic Minaga!”

An explosion of bright light blinded them all for a brief moment, and then the Unique Lifeform was revealed. His entire body was glowing, the constellations covering his body like tattoos. His form emanated a staggering amount of power. Upon feeling Minaga’s aura, Jake knew that this ability was similar to his own Arcane Awakening, in that it overflowed the body with far more energy than it could handle. Even now, Minaga’s wounds worsened by the second… The problem was what he could do until he ran out of power.

“Finish him quickly!” Jake practically yelled through the Golden Mark as he pulled out his bow.

The others reacted instantly, too. Attacks flew out from all over as Minaga looked at them. Lifting his hand, he released a shockwave that blasted them all back… but Jake felt there was more in it.

A faint layer of dust had been included with the blast and was now floating in space. Jake didn’t even have to warn the others; they all reacted defensively as every single speck of dust exploded. While they were still reeling back, beams of light shot down like falling stars.

Followed by actual meteors.

None of them held anything back as the cosmos lit up from their own respective magics. Minaga seemed to only grow more and more powerful with every passing second, his aura growing… and making the final threat clear.

“We need to kill him now, or I fear he will detonate!” Dina warned through the Golden Mark.

Their attacks flew at Minaga with this knowledge in mind. Jake landed several arrows as the Unique Lifeform simply stood there, blocking the hits or tanking them with his body while the sky itself seemed fall upon them. Pillars of light flashed down, forcing them to dodge or be struck with attacks even the Fallen King could barely handle—not to mention the constant meteor shower.

As the situation was turning desperate, the Sword Saint proposed a solution. “I can use my Transcendence fully… However, tha—”

“Don’t—not yet.” Jake looked at Minaga and steeled himself. “I got one more trick ready… If that doesn’t work, feel free. However, I will need a moment to land a hit…”

“Simply give the word,” the Fallen King said.

“I will do my best,” Dina added.

Jake nodded to himself and prepared a final trump card he had readied for this fight against Minaga. Another kind of attack he had never used before, as it relied on something he seriously doubted the Unique Lifeform could predict.

With no hesitation, Jake took out five poison bottles and threw their contents into his mouth. Then he charged Minaga, his party ready behind him.

Chapter 53

A Grand Achievement

Jake charged forward to the updated rhythm of Minaga’s boss theme. It had once more shifted in this so-called final hidden phase, and the stars also seemed to pulse with the beat. The number of attacks descending from above was staggering, and only Jake had a chance to even approach the Unique Lifeform without having to take several hits on the way.

Vaulting over a meteor, Jake got closer yet didn’t dare use One Step due to how warped space was; the meteors clearly had some kind of strong gravitational pull. Minaga raised a hand and released a large beam toward Jake, forcing him to dodge the energy as well as a meteor headed straight for his new position. Before it had a chance to hit, a crescent wave of water cut it apart, allowing Jake to keep going without slowing down too much.

Jake focused on what was inside of his mouth as he got closer. He was swishing the liquid around, letting it burn his throat while it mixed and created a truly unstable amalgamation. Necrotic Poison… Hemotoxin… Sleeping Night Toxin… Ethsoul Toxin… and finally, his best Neurotoxin. All of it haphazardly tossed together and combined inside his mouth.

He knew this mix wouldn’t actually work. It would be impossible for him to turn it into something useful… unless he had help. A way to combine it using powers far beyond what he was capable of. So Jake pulled out the final item.

[Vision’s Venom of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – A single droplet of pure, concentrated energy and Records related to the Malefic Viper. Significantly increases the potency of any toxin it is mixed with. Using this venom during the creation of any alchemical toxin increases the chance of activating Malefic Viper’s Poison, empowering the final product with the Records of the Malefic Viper. If used by the Chosen himself, the activation of Malefic Viper’s Poison is ensured if the created item is applicable.

It was a gift from the much-hated statue Felix had crafted, but Jake could not deny the item’s power. He quickly pulled out the single drop and threw it into his mouth, then used Concoct Poison on the amalgamation.

Right as he did so… something descended. A power far surpassing anything else momentarily appeared within the arena, and the aura of what was inside Jake’s mouth changed. It became something that should not exist, but through the power of that single drop, it did. Right as he knew it had worked, Jake encased all the liquid in stable arcane mana and created an orb.

[Malefic Viper’s Poison] has been activated! The transcendent power of the Malefic Viper has forcefully increased the rarity of your creation to Ancient, increasing all effects substantially.

*You have successfully crafted [Volatile Malefic Soulbane Poison (Ancient)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

Moving to only around a hundred meters from Minaga, Jake sent his ready signal through the Golden Mark. Even if the poison was currently being held together by the power of Malefic Viper’s Poison, it would soon break apart.

Reacting to the signal, Sylphie made her entrance as a light green breeze. She accelerated Jake further and caused several meteors to change trajectory and miss him. In the very next moment, a green bullet descended with unprecedented speed, heading straight for Minaga. Her Green Shield was active as she barrelled through dozens of meteors, her body burning with energy. Minaga looked up at the bird as she met the barrier protecting his body.

A massive explosion sent a green burst of wind flying everywhere, blasting Sylphie back. Her body was destroyed as she tumbled through space, forcing her to transform into wind. She was heavily injured, but she had accomplished her goal as she flew back toward Dina and the others.

The barrier protecting Minaga was filled with cracks, and large streams of water shot through the cosmos as a voice echoed, “Glimpse of Spring: Erosion.”

The Sword Saint’s stream of water impacted the barrier, stabbing through every single obstacle in the way and disintegrating everything it touched. He could not move in closer, but his Transcendence-empowered Erosion Stab still managed to finally break the barrier. It shattered like glass, making Minaga stumble back and even leaving another nasty wound on his chest.

While he was without defenses, Dina and the Fallen King made their move. Vines sprang up from three places on Minaga’s very own body, rapidly spreading and attempting to restrain him. At the same time, a golden aura descended upon the entire battlefield as the King unleashed a powerful suppressive force. Minaga froze, unable to move, and Jake closed in while feeling hairline fractures spreading across the mask from the Fallen King exerting himself.

Despite everything, Minaga was not entirely hopeless. He made eye contact with Jake as powerful pressure descended from the stars. A deep rumble went through the arena, and every single star shot a concentrated light beam straight toward Jake. His only direction for dodging was backward… but that was never going to happen.

He kept going as the beams arrived, maintaining eye contact with Minaga. Time slowed down from Moment of the Primal Hunter activating, and Jake used that slowed-down time to cross the final distance while placing the orb of stable arcane mana in his hand, also holding Eternal Hunger as he appeared right in front of Minaga.

Time resumed just as Jake unleashed every shred of his Hunting Momentum in a full-force forward stab. Piercing Fang empowered the strike further as he aimed for Minaga’s stomach, and the Unique Lifeform was not able to react in time. The orb with the Malefic Soulbane Poison was firmly grasped in his hand as it pierced Minaga’s stomach, allowing him to embed his entire hand before the Unique Lifeform had any chance to respond.

Without hesitation, Jake used his other katar to sever the hand inside Minaga. Simultaneously, Dina’s vines wrapped around his body and pulled him backward out of another barrage of light beams.

Minaga stared as Jake flew away before looking down at the hole in his stomach. Jake reached out with his hand, which began to glow with the familiar dark green light of Touch of the Malefic Viper. He then pushed the unstable amalgamation over the edge. The stable arcane energy keeping it trapped also disappeared with a mental command, and the poison was unleashed.

“Well, shi—”

The Unique Lifeform erupted in a dark green aura as the poison shot through his body, making his entire form distort as if his Soulshape was trying to escape its physical confines. His appearance warped for a second, reality seemed to flash, and the stars above blinked with uneven light as the constellation tattoos on Minaga’s body broke apart one after another.

As his Soulshape shattered, his left arm rotted into black dust within a second, followed by one of his legs, while the rest of his body convulsed.

Suddenly, he stopped contorting. He seemed to have a final moment of clarity before grinning widely. One last time, he stared straight at Jake and the others with a taunting look while showing off his usual goofy smile.

“You should know by now… I always go out with a bang!”

With those words, Minaga went supernova. Jake’s eyes opened wide as he crossed his arms and summoned an arcane barrier. The shockwave reached him first, making the entire barrier crack, and the blast itself followed soon after.

Jake saw nothing but pure white light as the barrier broke, and the scales covering his body crackled and broke… until suddenly, the pressure was gone. A faint green color instead appeared, and Jake was dragged all the way back to his party by Bobo. Meanwhile, Dina stood holding her staff high, her entire body glowing with green light as a massive projection of a tree covered all five of them.

The supernova washed over the tree, the projected bark burning and peeling away as the Sword Saint and Fallen King tried to help by summoning two barriers. Jake also quickly joined them, and even Sylphie tried to help. Heat began to enter the protective zone within the tree trunk just as the blast subsided and the cosmos became still.

*You have slain [Minaga – lvl 275] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Right as the notification came, the projection of the tree faded, and as Dina’s transformed state disappeared, she fell over to the side. The Sword Saint was quick to catch her, but Jake still stared at where Minaga had been.

There was nothing left but a few broken pieces of rock from the central platform floating through space. Even most of the stars were gone or dimmed to a level where one could barely see them. Jake finally allowed himself to calm down when his intuition told him the danger was over, and he let his own Arcane Awakening fade, causing weakness to flood his body.

Turning to his party, it quickly became clear they were all in a horrid state. The Sword Saint looked utterly haggard, having used his Glimpse of Spring twice in one fight. Dina was unconscious, so she naturally wasn’t in good condition, and the Fallen King stood with a mask that had quite a few cracks in it, giving off a weaker and far more unstable aura than before. Sylphie was the one who’d come out the best, though her energy reserves were close to zero. As for Jake himself… well, he definitely could’ve been better.

“We won.” Jake smiled to the others just as the entire space shifted, and he felt himself being teleported before appearing within an in-between room surrounded by his four party members.

Being confirmed safe dispelled a lot of the lingering tension from the fight, and Jake felt everyone relax. The Sword Saint quickly took Dina and put her on one of the sofas in the room to relax while Jake dragged himself over to a chair.

“That idea of yours was reckless,” the Sword Saint said as he looked at Jake and nodded. “But it worked, so good job. A better solution than mine, as I feel uncertain I could even have accomplished finishing him that quickly even if I went all-out.”

Jake smiled lightly and leaned back. “Nothing ventured, nothing gained.”

Sylphie had also slowly flown over and landed on Jake’s chest. He now held the tired bird, who seemed more than happy to just snuggle up to him. She had done a good job and deserved some head pats.

Even the Fallen King had taken a seat in one of the chairs as he worked on his unstable aura. Jake knew he had severely overexerted himself with that final attack of his. It had been far more than just an attack to stop Minaga from moving… It had weakened his soul and made it far more susceptible to Jake’s poison.

After they had been sitting there for nearly a minute, they finally got notifications that felt pretty damn delayed. Jake read the first two and was a bit disappointed, but then he remembered the Demon Lord situation and continued, grinning from ear to ear when he saw the third one.

Fortieth floor completed. 400 Nevermore Points earned.

Bonus Objective Completed: Do not allow a single party member to be defeated during the battle (0/5). 1000 Nevermore Points Earned.

Grand Achievement earned: Complete the True Ending event by defeating a fully empowered Minaga in an exemplary manner. 10,000 Nevermore Points earned. Due to completing a Grand Achievement, you will receive a 25% multiplier to all Nevermore Points at the final calculation.

“That is… quite something,” the Sword Saint muttered as he read the notifications.

Jake could only agree as he stared at the Grand Achievement, which he hadn’t even known was a thing. 10,000 Nevermore Points was already a shitload, but the 25% bonus was… massive. It also answered why getting to the top of the Leaderboards was so coveted. Feats like this Grand Achievement were things only the true top elite could ever accomplish, and with how massive the bonus was, Jake reckoned it was pretty much mandatory if you wanted to aim for the top. Making up for a 25% deficit seemed damn near impossible, and it did make him wonder if there were other such multipliers.

“A hard-fought battle rewarding an achievement I doubt many can accomplish… A level 275 Unique Lifeform is no easy foe to defeat,” the Fallen King said, having managed to mostly stabilize, though he did remain quite weakened. It didn’t strike Jake as the kind of weakness that would disappear within a few hours or even days, either.

“Ree,” Sylphie lightly screeched in agreement as she looked up at Jake with begging eyes, making him pat her again and reaffirm how good of a job she had done.

Dina was still down for the count, as she had clearly gone above and beyond by blocking that damn supernova, which Jake did think was kind of overkill.

Using his brief moment of respite, Jake decided to check another important thing. Level-ups. He instantly saw he had gotten one level from the poison, which was honestly fair, given that he had kind of cheated when he made it.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 227 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

As for his reward for killing Minaga… well, Jake couldn’t really complain.

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 222 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 225 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 224 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 226 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Four levels from killing Minaga was a lot, but also not really a lot, considering how much stronger he had been. Had Jake won the fight alone, he reckoned he would have gained at least ten levels. Not that he believed he could have won alone.

Dina stirred soon after Jake was done looking at his levels, her eyes shooting open. She rapidly sat up while looking around, and before any of them could say anything, Bobo seemed to inform her of the situation.

She smiled. “We won.”

“I already said that,” Jake said, smirking in response as he gave her a thumbs-up. “You came in clutch towards the end. Great job.”

Dina just nodded, but before she could say anything… well…

“Man, I sure did a number on you all, huh?” a voice echoed as an all-too-familiar figure popped right into the room with a big smile on his face.

Dina jumped slightly as Jake turned to look at the newcomer who had just popped up, and he instantly noticed this wasn’t the same Minaga as the one they had just fought.

[Minaga – lvl 349]

“Please tell me this isn’t some final-final, super-hidden phase?” Jake said, sighing as he looked at the Unique Lifeform.

“Would you like for it to be?” The Unique Lifeform grinned.

Jake stared for a second and then sighed, doing something he very rarely did: turning down a fight. “Fuck that.”

Minaga shrugged. “To be fair, it wouldn’t be a fight even if you were all in peak condition.”

“True, true.” Jake nodded. “Should we apologize for killing you, by the way?”

“Nah, it’s all good; what’s a bit of murder between friends?” Minaga waved him off. “Nice touch there at the end, by the way.”

“Was that a Touch of the Malefic Viper pun?”

“I can neither confirm nor deny,” the Unique Lifeform said, smiling jokingly before he suddenly turned extremely serious. “By now, I guess some of you have guessed why I am here. That’s right—it is related to loot… but…” Minaga seemed incredibly conflicted as he let out a big sigh and sat down. “I must apologize for something. All this time, I have been deceiving you all, and it is only fair I make this confession. You may not believe it… but... I’m actually a god.”

An absolutely shocking revelation.

Chapter 54

Minaga's Big Secret & Rewards

Minaga’s absolutely shocking reveal left them all dumbstruck for a moment.

Jake was the first to act amazed. “I cannot believe that the dungeon master who refers to Primordials by their names, created an entire section of Nevermore, displayed skills above anything a mortal possible could while sparring the Sword Saint, and has acted like a semi-divine being this whole time was actually a god,” he said with utter befuddlement. “Where were the signs!?”

“I know, I know, and I do feel genuinely apologetic that I had to keep this secret, but I feared it would impact you negatively if you knew from the beginning I was truly a god,” Minaga said, shaking his head.

“Could the fact that you can create different avatars have been a clue?” Jake questioned himself.

“Ah, to be fair, that wasn’t an avatar. In fact, I don’t make avatars.” Minaga waved off the notion. “The entire sentiment of avatar creation just seems so unnecessary when you are Minaga.”

“I do want to ask you what you mean by that, considering it is clearly a leading question, but I would honestly rather wait and see the sweet loot you promised,” Jake said.

Minaga looked slightly disappointed. “Sure you don’t wanna know my big secret? It isn’t actually a secret, mind you, as it’s something everyone who knows about me is aware of, but I still like to call it my big secret for sentimental reasons since it was a big secret once upon a time. Back when I was a mortal, that is. You know, because I am no longer a mortal now. Being a god and all.” He then stared inquisitively at Jake.

“Loot first,” Jake insisted.

“It’s considered customary to be super respectful to gods, you know.”

“And even more customary for loot to drop after you beat a dungeon, but here we are,” Jake masterfully countered.

“Damn loot goblin…” the Unique Lifeform grumbled.

“By the way, why do you keep your voice infused with Willpower even now?”

“Because I am a god, and it makes me appear more dignified, yet intimidating,” he answered. “But seeing as you don’t seem to respect the culture of the multiverse, I guess that sentiment is wasted on you.”

“Sorry, I guess.” Jake shrugged, unbothered.

“Just for that, you will be the last one to get your loot,” Minaga said with an evil grin.

“Wait, that isn’t fa—”

“Nope, I already decided, so get in the back of the line and watch me shower your party in good stuff before you are allowed to get anything,” Minaga said, having grasped victory in their conversation. “Because that’s right… you all get one reward each! Usually, you can’t give out so many items at once, but that is why I made it so the last five floors didn’t give anything to increase the reward given here. And man, did you hit the jackpot, as I got some real good stuff prepared.”

They all nodded along as Minaga decided to turn to the Fallen King first. “I am starting with you, as quite frankly, what you get is the most boring out of everyone. Well, I call it boring, but I doubt you will complain.”

With those words, he pulled out a deep blue glowing orb. The moment it appeared, Jake felt the rush of energy from it and the enormous pressure it seemed to exude on its surroundings. Upon using Identify, he quickly understood what it was.

[Minaga’s Soulcore (Unique)] – The Soulcore of the slain C-grade Unique Lifeform known as Minaga. This Soulcore contains a significant amount of Records related to the Unique Lifeform and has many alchemical uses. Directly consuming the Soulcore will lead to unexpected effects. The Records and energies within are enhanced through unknown means, making the Soulcore even more potent.

It was true that, in Jake’s eyes, the reward didn’t look that special, but based on the Fallen King’s reaction, it was clearly something he wanted very badly. He did look confused, though.

“This item… could only appear if you had truly died… but…” the Fallen King said, yet he nevertheless accepted the orb, not caring about the pride he’d shown earlier when he borderline refused to even talk to Minaga.

“See, I wanted to tell you why creating this item is possible for me, but Jake here refused to let me explain my big secret, so I can’t,” Minaga said with a big sigh as he threw a glance at Jake.

“Fine…” Jake relented.

“Great.” Minaga grinned as he cleared his voice and made his second grand declaration of the day. “I can create clones of myself.”

“Uhm,” Dina said somewhat nervously, “I think most people learn to do that at some point…”

“I don’t think you understand,” Minaga said. “I make actual clones.”

Dina seemed confused, and Jake also wasn’t sure what he was getting at.

“Could you elaborate?” the Sword Saint questioned.

Minaga smiled, very satisfied with having piqued their curiosity. “When people usually create alternative versions of themselves, it is through pouring items into making a puppet, creating an avatar that holds a portion of your full power, or maybe just a projection with no real power besides a bit of mental energy. I do neither. I create a second version of myself… independent from any of the others. In power, soul, existence, and Records.” Minaga smiled again. “The only thing linking us is our minds, as we are all still the same, even if we stand independently. So, yes, the Minaga you killed was truly me. A clone of me, anyway.”

“That is… not a possible skill,” the Fallen King began. “Unless it is your Unique skill, but even so, it seems too powerful. It breaks conventions.”

“You know as well as I that the Unique skills of us Unique Lifeforms go beyond the rules of the multiverse and are pretty much just Transcendent skills that aren’t actually classified as Transcendent skills due to being granted by the system. We are living anomalies, after all. But there is some truth to what you said… It is too powerful, hence its limitations. Only a certain number of Minagas can exist at once, though I can make more if they are lower-leveled clones. Oh, and one other minor detail… I don’t have any skills besides that one.”

“Wait, no skills?” Jake questioned. “What do you mean by that?”

“That my status screen has one skill and that I never got any other. Okay, that is a lie, as I technically have some other skills, but I never had a single skill selection in my life, and everything I do is purely freeform magic. The skills I do have are general-utility stuff everyone else also has… though I never did get Identify, so that one is a bit of a bummer. Took a long time to make my own version without a skill.”

“Then was it one of your created clones we fought just now?” the Sword Saint asked.

“Yep, and you did kill it for real,” Minaga confirmed. “It is no different than if you had truly killed a Unique Lifeform at level 275. Because you did.”

“I see,” the Sword Saint said, nodding. “I presume the knowledge and experience of this clone came from the original body?”

“Another misunderstanding.” Minaga smiled. “There is no original body. In fact, the very first Minaga died only in B-grade. There is no original; there are only many iterations of me out there. There is only Minaga.”

“Huh,” Jake muttered as he frowned. “How exactly does—”

“Nope, we are done talking about that topic now that I got you interested,” Minaga said with an evil smile. “You said you wanted loot first, so I am just obliging.”

He then turned to the dryad in the room before Jake could protest. “Next up is Dina! I must confess that you impressed me a lot, as you even managed to block my Minaga Self-destruct Attack, though it did seem to take quite a toll. Anyway, I thought about it a lot, and your control is truly impeccable. The problem is what you control. Your vines are strong, but I feel like you need more quality over quantity with them, as only the ones summoned directly from your Guardian have any real oomph. While I cannot directly tell you what to do or how to improve, I can give you a little something that could help you. Even if you decide to use your reward for something else, that is all fair, as quite frankly, this little thing will be a huge boost no matter what if you successfully learn from it.” Minaga then took out an odd wooden box.

Dina looked at it for a while before she accepted and opened it. Right as she did, the entire room was filled with a green aura, and Jake felt all of the mana in the room being replaced. Projections of trees appeared everywhere around them, and moss began growing on the furniture from the sheer density and power of the nature mana. Jake Identified the small item within the box before she quickly closed it again.

[Refined Ancestral Branch of the Emerald Forest (Mythical)] – A wooden branch from one of the Ancestral Trees found within the World Wonder known as the Emerald Forest. This forest contains immense power and Records related to the concepts of nature and life, with this branch containing some of the essences of the Emerald Forest. Through unknown means, the branch has been further refined, making the energy within far more manageable to absorb. Unknown alchemical uses.

Jake was taken aback the second he saw the rarity tag, and Dina was also looking at Minaga like he was insane. “This… This is…”

“Right, probably should give an explanation,” Minaga said. “The Emerald Forest is the World Wonder of the Fourth Universe—a giant forest filled with creatures starting at A-grade. Deeper within, you will find beings with the power to rival gods, and in the deepest parts, Godkings don’t even dare set foot. I took that branch pretty far inside of the forest and made some improvements so you can actually use it. It’s a really good thing, and I know that your grandad has spent quite some time within this forest.”

“Can I… Isn’t this too much?” Dina questioned while just staring at the box.

“Nope! It’s just enough. Moving on to my fellow swordsman. Your reward is rather self-explanatory, so here ya go.” Minaga took out a disc and threw it casually to the Sword Saint. Jake used Identify on it mid-air.

[Minaga’s Sword Projection Formation Disc (Mythical)] – A formation created by the Unique Lifeform Minaga himself, infused with his soul and essence. The user can infuse energy into the formation disc to summon a projected arena, including a corporeal clone of Minaga wielding a sword. The formation takes approximately thirty minutes to activate, and any disturbances will interrupt the process. Reabsorbing the formation into the formation disc is instant. The soul within the formation has a limited lifespan and can only be summoned for a total of 1000 hours before permanently dispersing, rendering the Sword Projection Formation useless. The summoned projection will always be the same level as the user.

Requirements: Soulbound.

The Sword Saint looked at the item and smiled before he stood up and bowed. “Thank you for continuing your teachings.”

Minaga waved him off. “Eh, I like good students, and that was the best gift I could get one, as you don’t look like you need any equipment. There really isn’t much to say, as I created it myself, so you know it is damn awesome… though it did take a sacrificial ritual using one of my clones, so that was kind of fun. Anyway, moving on to the little featherball!”

Without waiting, Minaga took out what looked like a flower crown, but on second glance, Jake saw it was more of a nest. It looked incredibly odd, and though a light green wind seemed to surround it, compared to the other items, this one had no fearsome aura.

Using Identify, Jake wasn’t quite sure what to think.

[Dreamy Embrace of the Benevolent Sylph (Mythical)] – An item created by a particularly benevolent Sylph who loved all those who, like her, were loved by the wind. Allows the user to submerge their soul into the dreamy embrace of the nest and enter a small, simulated world created by the item’s creator. While within the simulated world, the user may experience the true winds of this benevolent Sylph, taking inspiration and seeking guidance. However, should the user not be loved by the wind, or the remnant will of the Sylph not take a liking to them, the dream may become a nightmare… and the Sylph less than benevolent.

Requirements: Soulbound.

Sylphie looked at the thing for a bit before jumping out of Jake’s arms and hopping over as Minaga placed the item on the floor. The bird stared down at it inquisitively while Minaga explained, “Now, not gonna lie—this item was part of a series of nine, created by a powerful Sylph before she died as a final gift to the world. However, do not think that in any way makes it less impressive. I do also feel like I need to add that out of those nine, five have been bound and used by others so far, and this resulted in four of those dying from the Sylph within the dream not being a fan. So, yeah, a lot of people think they are cursed, but I got a good feeling the Sylph will be more than happy with you.” Minaga then slightly nudged the nest closer to Sylphie.

The hawk kept looking at it for a moment before screeching and putting it into her little vest’s spatial storage. With the item safely put away, she hopped back to Jake.

“Now you, Jake,” Minaga began. “Sadly, I also have to give you something, and man, you are truly difficult to give anything to. Unlike the Sword Saint here, giving you a practice partner or something akin to that could potentially do more harm than good, not to mention risking Vilas breathing down my neck if I go against any of his intentions. Ah, but you do definitely need to work on your archery. Anyway, that is beside the point.

“I also don’t like to just give equipment, as we all know that stuff becomes useless just as you begin to use it. You really had me wracking my brain, you know, until I remembered a special something. While this doesn’t really help make you stronger, it does assist you in potentially becoming so in the future. Plus, it is something Vilas is fine with you getting, so a big bonus in favor of giving it to you there.”

Minaga took out an odd item. It looked like an urn of sorts and didn’t give off any special aura, but Jake still felt like the item was far from ordinary. Using Identify, he was not sure what to think or say when he saw the description.

Soulflames…

Chapter 55

Cradle

Soulflames were something Jake had pushed to the back of his mind ever since he first learned about them. Primarily because in learning about them, he’d learned how screwed he was if he wanted a Soulflame that fit him, and since replacing one was incredibly difficult, he had just resigned himself to do without for the foreseeable future.

He was aware that having a Soulflame that fit you was strictly better than not having one. However, having a Soulflame not suited for your Path was worse than none at all. The issue with Jake was his arcane affinity. Soulflames were created from freak accidents where mana of a certain affinity gathered in an area and an elemental was about to be born, but for some reason, this process failed and mutated, resulting in a half-born elemental only retaining a bit of spirituality. This effectively made a Soulflame a half-elemental, half-natural treasure.

This meant Jake’s only option if he wanted a Soulflame was to artificially create an environment for one to be born… or wait till he got strong enough to influence huge areas passively with his mere presence and Records, resulting in his arcane affinity appearing naturally throughout the multiverse, thus turning it into a true affinity. Even then, the circumstances in which Jake’s affinity would appear were probably few and far between, so Jake had just assumed he was fucked if he wanted to get lucky and find a Soulflame.

So for Minaga to offer him a treasure related to Soulflames… Jake truly had no idea what to think as he read the description of the item.

[Cradle of Soul’s Kindling (Mythical)] – The Cradle in which a flame may be kindled as it awakens its own spirituality. Nascent Soulflames of hundreds of affinities burn within the internal space of the Cradle, experiencing a cycle of life and death as they struggle and absorb one another while growing in power, waiting for one of them to ascend to the world outside. Only a single Soulflame can truly be born from the Cradle; the item is destroyed upon extraction, with all other Soulflames having become fuel for the chosen one. The Cradle can be infused with energies to sustain and influence the internal world. The internal world of the Cradle cannot be entered by any being with a Truesoul, and any Truesouls born within will immediately find themselves destroyed, their energies further nurturing the Cradle.

Requirements: Soulbound.

“This is…” Jake muttered as he looked at the urn that he guessed was made out of some ceramic material, though it was far from fragile. Jake doubted anyone present, including the peak C-grade Minaga, could even leave a mark on it.

Minaga held it out and Jake tentatively accepted it, not exactly sure what he was dealing with even after reading the description. Not because he didn’t understand, but because it just felt too… good? Convenient? Jake wasn’t sure.

“I noticed you didn’t have a Soulflame, which is honestly pretty odd, considering you are the C-grade Chosen of the Malefic Viper. At least, I thought so at first. The problem with people like you, who are so heavily reliant on the one affinity that cannot be found in the wild, is that no Soulflames can be found either. At least, not before you get a lot stronger and create a special environment to nurture one… or cheat using an item like the Cradle.” Given his judgmental tone, it was clear that the explanation was more for the other four than Jake himself.

“Will I be able to create a Soulflame related to my arcane affinity using this?” Jake questioned. “From what I was told, it usually takes a very long time for one to form…”

“Of course you can form one; that is why I gave it to you. Duh,” Minaga said, sounding almost offended. “After you bind the Cradle, just send in a lot of mana and keep feeding it once in a while to influence the environment within. You are ultimately still relying on pure chance that a Soulflame with your arcane affinity is born and then manages to rise toward the top, but the more time passes, the more attuned the Cradle should become to you. It isn’t a quick and easy guarantee, but it is borderline the best solution you will ever find for a C-grade, and that Cradle is worth more than you can imagine. Not gonna lie—the other stuff I gave out is good, but the Cradle is probably the most valuable if we go by pure resale value, as it is rather unique. Way more unique than the actual unique Soulcore I gave my fellow Unique Lifeform, though I did make up for that by actively empowering that core.”

“Huh.” Jake nodded as he inspected the Cradle. He knew that getting a Soulflame couldn’t be that easy, and it seemed he was right, as even the Cradle had a strong element of luck if he wanted to create an arcane Soulflame. However, it would undoubtedly save him a shitload of time. As Minaga had mentioned, he would have had to set up a special environment to nurture one, which he had planned on doing at some point, but this Cradle made that unnecessary.

“Ah, also, since you can only ever extract one Soulflame from the Cradle, only go for one with good quality, alright?” Almost scoldingly, Minaga added, “It would be a damn waste if you decided to take out an elementary or even low-tier Soulflame.”

Jake nodded along to the words. “Yeah, definitely not gonna accept anything below a pinnacle-tier Soulflame.”

Soulflames ranged in quality, with the categories consisting of elementary, low-tier, mid-tier, high-tier, pinnacle-tier, and Supreme. Elementary were ones that barely passed as Soulflames yet were prime for growth, while Supreme Soulflames were the best that one could get, bar none. The reason Jake wanted at least a pinnacle-tier one was due to the relative ease of raising a pinnacle Soulflame to a Supreme Soulflame. Relative did a lot of heavy lifting in this case, as it was still bloody hard, while raising a Soulflame of an even lower tier would be borderline impossible and more akin to gambling than anything else.

Getting a good Soulflame right off the bat was incredibly important due to their semi-permanent status. A Soulflame Jake got in C-grade would stick with him for the rest of his life and grow with him forever, so if he got a bad one, he would have to either accept mediocrity or spend way more resources than anyone would find reasonable to upgrade the one he had. In either case, Jake sure as hell wasn’t ever going to fuse with a low-level Soulflame. He was way too much of a spoiled Chosen for that.

Naturally, Soulflames were still more complicated than simply being split into these quality tiers, but it was a good estimate. Assessing a Soulflame’s quality was relatively simple, as it was just a question of Records, and Jake knew that one could easily distinguish good and bad Soulflames just using Identity. At least, you could become able to. Jake didn’t know if he currently could, but maybe with Sagacity…

“Hey… is he totally spacing out right now, or is it just me?” Jake vaguely heard Minaga whisper to the Sword Saint while throwing glances his way.

The old man smiled. “He is simply stunned by your generosity.”

Minaga nodded. “That makes total sense. I am stunningly generous.”

“Sorry for actually thinking about my reward in depth,” Jake said, faking offense.

“Oh, sorry, just not used to seeing you think, I guess.” Minaga shrugged. “Glad to see you unlocked that ability.”

“I do wonder about something,” Jake began, doing that thinking thing again to completely change the topic. “Why did you have a cooldown period after each of your combination spell casts? Is it some kind of special application of magic to make it stronger, or do you overload your body or something? I found it odd, especially considering it was the same amount of time every time. Well, there is also one more option for why the cooldown was there, but…”

Minaga grinned. “Last one is correct.”

“Seriously?” Jake sighed. “Well, fuck me.”

“You would have been utterly fucked, indeed,” Minaga said cheerily. “And it was honestly kind of hard to get that five-second timing down every time!”

That’s right… That entire cooldown period had been entirely self-imposed.

Jake could already imagine it… A Minaga repeatedly using combination magic spells without any pause in between, potentially even using more than one at once, would be completely impossible for their party, and perhaps any party. Considering his self-imposed cooldown, it was entirely feasible he’d also slowed down the casting speed, and had likely completely avoided his most potent spells altogether.

It only made sense, considering he was a god. If Minaga had not been doing freeform casting but instead using actual skills, Jake guessed many, if not all, of the combination spells would have been at least ancient or legendary rarity, with the strongest ones approaching mythical. That he would also have actual mythical skill-level magic and even beyond was only to be expected.

“Ultimately, one of the reasons the system doesn’t allow anyone to die on this floor is because of the inherent unfairness of the challenge, not just the expected difficulty,” Minaga explained. “If I decided that I didn’t like someone and went all-out to kill them, or if I was bribed by some faction to kill other young talents, things could get bad real fast. The system put in a preemptive measure to avoid that ever happening.”

Jake slowly nodded. He—and likely most of the others—had already guessed this was the reason for the special rule of no deaths.

“Ah, but I did actually kind of screw up once during the fight,” Minaga said, scratching the back of his head. “That last death explosion was a bit over the top and not really a part of the script… I just thought you’d also cheated, using that weird poison thing on me. That was totally cheating, by the way.”

“Wow,” Jake said. “I am shaken. Shaken, I tell you! How dare you accuse me of cheating when I am the beacon of honesty and fairness in all of my endeavors!”

“I felt the presence of the Malefic Viper from your damn mouth!” Minaga shot back.

“Done through entirely legitimate and normal means!”

“Based on your track record, cheating is normal to you,” Minaga said, refusing to back down.

“Oh, wow, great argument.”

The Sword Saint raised a hand to cut in. “Nothing about me cheating by using my Transcendence?”

“No, that one is okay and not cheating. Maybe if you had fully used it, I would have maybe called you a cheater, but as things are, only this guy with his stupid Bloodline is the cheater.”

“You know,” Jake said, “I never thought you would be a sore loser.”

“We literally just discussed how I, the great Minaga, held myself back to not accidentally squash you into paste, with the system even recognizing I am too awesome to be allowed to kill you,” Minaga said with a deadpan face.

“Excuses, excuses,” Jake said, waving him off.

Minaga glared at Jake but didn’t say anything more before the dryad in the room spoke up. “Excuse me… but did you retrieve this reward yourself, or was it generated by the system?” Dina was looking down at her box with the Branch from this Emerald Forest.

“Great question,” Minaga said, perking up again. “I got everything myself. Well, one of me did. For Nevermore, the system only helps that much, as it is ultimately a created dungeon rather than a natural one, so…”

Casual conversation continued as Minaga stayed and chatted with them for a while, sharing tales of how he had obtained many rewards that he had either already given out or was still saving.

However, in the end, the Unique Lifeform couldn’t stay forever. They had completed Minaga’s Labyrinth, after all, and he was just there to give out loot. All good things had to come to an end, and Minaga appeared kind of sad as he looked at them with melancholy.

“Anyway… ladies and gentlemen, I want you to know that despite our differences when it comes to the definition of cheating, it has been a pleasure having you experience my labyrinth. You are all pretty damn good seeds and have bright futures ahead of you, no matter how infuriating you may be. Either way, I hope you all have a wonderful descent going forward. Who knows? We might even meet again. If not in Nevermore, then the vast world beyond.” Minaga smiled as he stood up, bowed, and threw them all a final snicker. “There are quite a few of me out there, after all.”

With those words, Minaga disappeared in a final flash of light, forever the showman.

Casper hid away and prepared as the two pinnacle beings fought each other, the ground below them utterly torn up from their constant exchange of attacks. Azal the Ghost King fought the third-phase Minaga in a nearly equal duel, though he was slowly losing out. Luckily, Maltrax the beastkin Risen was also there to provide support by occasionally striking from odd angles and making sure Minaga could not launch any major attacks.

Azal was truly a monster in the clash, moving with incredible speed as his large, ghostly blade cut through the darkness of space in an eerie pattern. The blight energy burned on his body, making him look like an avatar of the Blightfather himself, allowing him to even push back Minaga and land blows. He had needed to consume many spirits to reach that state, but it was worth it as long as they won.

The lank abomination and the banshee woman had both been thrown out due to taking lethal damage, leaving only three people left to fight in the final phase. The banshee had been eliminated during the phase where they split up, and the abomination during this third phase, lost to one of Minaga’s major spells after the rest of them had been thrown into mini-labyrinth cubes. Seeing as the banshee had functioned partly as their healer, it wasn’t overly surprising she had been unable to hold on, but the abomination had been a surprise, as he had effectively been their tank.

During the phase where they had been split up, it had been pretty difficult for him, too, forcing Casper to use his Blightform and spend the entire time trying not to die. He’d gone through all of his pre-prepared traps to slow down the Minaga clone long enough for Azal to arrive, and together they’d quickly finished off the clone, with Casper’s traps even managing to do some damage. Azal had wanted to help the banshee first but been too late. Maltrax had handled her phase herself, making it clear she was the second strongest.

Fighting continued between Azal and Minaga, and Casper did all he could to not allow the Minaga to catch him out, as he knew he was the weakest—and Casper did have to admit that the beams from the stars above were quite hard to dodge. Only his link with Lyra helped him stand a chance, as he was effectively two beings in one.

One had to remember that Lyra was not a normal Blightwraith, but one created personally by the Blightfather himself. She was linked to Casper in a bond that made her something akin to a Guardian, yet her own being. Casper had no idea how it all worked… and frankly, he didn’t care.

“Are you ready?” Casper asked Lyra as Minaga unleashed a major spell, making the stars above shimmer and descend in light beams upon Azal, forcing him to pull out a massive shield resembling a skull.

“Let’s show him!” Lyra’s cheerful voice echoed in his mind.

Casper smiled. His weapon was ready, and Lyra had completed her own preparations. Lifting the large wooden stake that resembled a spear, Casper prepared to throw it as his Blightform began to fade. While the ghostly flames that embraced his body moved from him onto the wooden stake, Lyra embedded parts of herself into the weapon, amplifying it further.

Without hesitation, Casper threw. Dark runes of pure curse energy pulsed across the stake as it flew through the air, the greenish blight energy invading it mid-flight and making its cursed runes glow in an eerie light.

“Heh, you really think I didn’t know you were charging up a big one!?” Minaga yelled as he turned, ready to block the stake.

Right as he did, Maltrax let out a ghastly howl. A massive projection appeared above her, depicting a white-and-black wolf howling towards the sky. For a brief moment, a rotting moon appeared, and the entire world seemed to stand still. Minaga couldn’t move for that brief moment, during which the wooden stake flew straight by his staves and pierced his chest.

Before he could do anything more, Azal’s sword slammed into the stake, embedding it further. The blight energy and curse energy burst forth, igniting the Unique Lifeform’s entire being. Cursed runes spread all over his form as Azal took advantage of the curse’s restraining effect. Maltrax also soon joined in on the assault, and not long after, Casper saw Minaga stumble back with all the magic on him fading, and then his aura of life disappeared.

Casper stopped pushing the power of the curse from his hidden position and sighed, utterly spent. Lyra didn’t reply, having passed out from overexertion. Yet he felt like there could have been more to the fight…

“We missed some secret final hidden phase, didn’t we?” Casper questioned as he saw the boss fading away.

“You did,” Minaga’s fading form said. “Wait, now it isn’t a secret hidden phase any mo—”

He disappeared midway through the words as Casper and the others got the kill notification. A moment later, they were teleported to the in-between room, where they reunited with the two party members who had taken lethal blows.

Not long after, they got their notifications from completing the fight, and even if Casper knew it was damn good, he saw that Azal looked slightly disappointed.

Fortieth floor completed. 400 Nevermore Points earned.

Grand Achievement earned: Complete the True Ending event by defeating a fully empowered Minaga. 7500 Nevermore Points earned. Due to completing a Grand Achievement, you will receive a 15% multiplier to all Nevermore Points at the final calculation.

His disappointment was helped by Minaga appearing and handing out loot soon after. Azal got a mythical-rarity natural treasure, while the rest of them got extremely high-quality legendary rewards.

As Casper was admiring his own loot—and mentally getting over the grand revelation that Minaga was actually a god—he couldn’t help but wonder why he had never heard of Minaga before… If he was a god, it just felt weird that his name wasn’t more well-known.

Or… well, Casper could see him being a bit “much,” so… maybe people just didn’t like to talk about him?

Chapter 56

A Viper's Assessment

“Were you nervous?” the dragon god in humanoid form asked as he looked at the black-scaled god sitting across from him. “Your Chosen did look to be in trouble quite a few times there. He was lucky his teammates were able to assure their victory.”

Vilastromoz looked at the Wyrmgod, who clearly enjoyed watching the recording. Yes, recording. A live feed was all well and good, but Jake knew when they were watching using that. With a recording, he would only know one person was looking while remaining unaware of all those who saw the recorded footage. It was a great workaround the Viper had noticed and begun taking advantage of a long time ago.

“If he hadn’t won, I would have been disappointed, though I do question if perhaps the difficulty has spiked more than in previous years,” Vilas wondered.

“Hey, I was being totally fair and equal!” the third person chimed in, sounding incredibly offended at the notion that he had upped the difficulty.

It was naturally Minaga, the creator of the floors. Though this version of him was of the divine variety.

Viper shook his head. “I never said you weren’t fair, just that the difficulty has grown.”

“Maybe a bit,” Minaga admitted. “And, alright, you do have a point that not all challenges are equal, but I have to hold myself back too much for total equality to be possible, and slight variations can happen, you know? Or are you telling me to never have fun and do stuff like my little duel with the swordsman?”

The Viper looked at the Wyrmgod. “Have I complained about anything? Have I proposed any changes?”

“No,” his fellow Primordial said, shaking his head. “You just made an observation.”

Minaga looked between them. “Damn, you old guys teaming up against the poor, unpaid dungeon engineer.”

“Do you wish to be employed?” the Wyrmgod asked with a raised eyebrow. “That could be arranged, with a proper contract in pla—”

“Figure of speech, figure of speech…” Minaga waved him off. “But hey, your Chosen is fun, if extremely infuriating. Though I guess you already know the suffering. That guy is just kind of crazy with that Bloodline of his.”

The Viper just smiled as he looked at the Unique Lifeform, not bothering to comment on how Minaga was the crazy one. Because in the eyes of many, himself included, Minaga was one of the craziest existences in the multiverse.

Minaga was a mistake who’d been born in the middle part of the Third Era. At least Vilastromoz firmly believed he was a mistake, and the system seemed to agree based on no creature like him ever appearing again. Furthermore, the fact that the system had so uniquely limited the abilities of the Unique Lifeform meant that the sheer level of power from that one Unique skill was roughly estimated to be equal or superior to every single skill Minaga would have earned from when he was born in C-grade all the way to godhood. The only skills Minaga ever got were certain “earned” skills that were pretty much required, such as some related to godhood. However, he lacked many basic skills and had things he couldn’t do, including giving Blessings.

However, he was still a Unique Lifeform. Just due to his sheer stats, he’d been able to overwhelm most foes at equal levels from birth, and he’d also been able to create clones of himself since the beginning. About a dozen, from what Vilastromoz had observed, with the number steadily growing as Minaga grew. By now, being a powerful god, the Viper had no idea how many clones he could have in total. However, if one included just the divine-level clones, he estimated it to be in the thousands.

And… this led to why the Malefic Viper believed Minaga was a mistake. The entire concept behind his existence was too much.

Vilastromoz had told Jake that Aeon was perhaps the hardest god in the multiverse to kill, and he still stood by that… but if he had to say who was the hardest to get rid of permanently, he would say Minaga. Minaga himself was strong, yes, but he was not a pinnacle god. At least, Vilastromoz didn’t think so, but it was hard to know how powerful the highest-leveled clone was.

No, the problem was that in order to kill Minaga for good, you had to kill every single clone. One benefit was that if you killed the current highest-leveled clone, then Minaga would have to level up to that stage again, but that was in no way a permanent method to get rid of him.

Killing people with cloning abilities or avatar creation wasn’t a new thing, and Vilastromoz had many tools to do so. Eversmile was an example of someone who rarely cared if people had hidden ways to try and survive, even if they killed their main bodies. He could track down any failsafe, any contingencies, and any avatars left behind. But for Minaga, that wasn’t an option.

Back when Minaga had just entered B-grade with his highest-leveled clone, he’d managed to piss off a god and, through that god, an entire pantheon. A late-tier B-grade had ended up killing the Minaga clone, and they’d thought that was that… until a week later, when a new clone appeared and wreaked havoc until it, too, was killed. A few days later, another clone appeared on a nearby planet and attacked the faction again. This kept happening, with at least one attack every month. A few times, the Minaga clone did come to talk about maybe making peace, but every time he was killed. What exactly the faction believed they would accomplish, not even Vilastromoz in his infinite wisdom knew, but they’d clearly failed, as the “war” continued.

Across four galaxies and nineteen thousand years, more than a million Minagas had been killed. Three gods had hunted down Minaga for over ten thousand of these years, with their biggest accomplishment being a thousand years of peace after they believed they had killed off the final clone… only for a new Minaga to appear, stronger than ever before.

In the end, the gods had capitulated to a mere A-grade mortal and made peace with their heads bowed. An absolutely ludicrous scenario that had only happened due to the stupidest of reasons. The entire conflict had been caused by someone telling Minaga he should bow in the presence of a superior—something the Unique Lifeform had not liked. He’d told the other guy to stick his staff up his behind. They had attacked due to this comment, and… well, the rest was history.

This was also the first time Vilastromoz had heard of Minaga’s existence, as this story had sent the rumor machine of the multiverse into overdrive. Many factions had approached Minaga, curious gods had investigated him, and quite a few had even tried to kill him just to see if they could. Vilastromoz had honestly expected Eversmile to try, but the god had not; in fact, he’d even warned others to perhaps reconsider.

Vilastromoz understood why this warning had been given, as after Minaga became a god, he’d gone on quite a revenge spree. He’d become a menace that ravaged dozens of pantheons for half an era. This was also when he was given quite an interesting moniker: The All-God Legion.

Legion was… fitting, for Minaga was a faction by himself. Fighting a single god was already a nightmare, but they were ultimately limited by only being a single individual, even if they could make armies of avatars and whatnot. The reason the Automata and True Royals were so feared was due to the armies they could spawn and mobilize.

Minaga was that, but as a single creature. Many gods could kill a Minaga… but no god could destroy Minaga. No faction dared make him an enemy, as Minaga had never once in history lost a single conflict. He would be a relentless force of destruction, bearing down on you infinitely, impossible to ever get rid of. Not that many worked with him, as he was also known to be an actively infuriating character that refused to ever do what others told him. Most thus chose to merely ignore his existence entirely, neither antagonizing nor really interacting with him.

The only hope the Viper had seen to ever kill Minaga permanently was making sure he never made it to godhood. Since he made clones, it meant that the age of the Truesoul was equal in all clones, so age would have still been his end if he failed to ascend. Now that he was a god, truly killing him wasn’t something the Viper saw happening. Especially not after he teamed up with the Wyrmgod and picked up dungeon engineering.

Because the Unique Lifeform had one… side effect of his ability. One that was utterly ridiculous from the Viper’s point of view. One of the biggest reasons he firmly believed Minaga was a mistake, even in the eyes of the multiverse: His unique cloning skill had led to a sort of “bug” in the system.

There could only ever be one unique Truesoul of a creature present in the multiverse at once, which meant that one could never bring multiple copies or prior versions of an individual out of a dungeon. However, at the same time, having a prior version of yourself in a dungeon also didn’t have any effects on you.

This turned out to have some seemingly unexpected effects when it came to Minaga. The way Minaga made clones was a bit similar to the Hive Queens using energy to create spawn, or perhaps even what Jake expended to bring out Primeval Origins. That is to say, he spent a form of energy separate from anything else that still had a limited pool.

Here was where the issue arose…

Minagas in dungeons didn’t count towards his maximum number of clones, as they didn’t affect the other clones.

Minagas in dungeons could leave and remain unique, as their Truesouls were different.

Minaga was aware of all his clones in dungeons, and they were aware of every other Minaga.

If Minaga was already at his clone cap, the clone would die upon exiting a dungeon, but if not, it could simply exist from there as normal.

All of this is to say that Minaga had potentially billions of clones hidden in dungeons throughout the multiverse. No, it was certain he had that many just based on Nevermore. Clones hidden in separate dimensions that no one could ever access.

These things combined were why the Malefic Viper felt certain that Minaga was the most difficult being to kill off for good in the entire multiverse. Not for lack of trying, either, as Minaga’s personality had made him quite an infamous figure. However, there was one being who had managed to forge a mutually beneficial relationship with this unique… Unique Lifeform.

“His Bloodline is indeed exemplary,” the Wyrmgod said in a relaxed tone. “I have considered potential methods of limiting the scope of his powers within a given floor, but I find most solutions will have other unintended consequences. Seeing as his skills are mostly based on intuition, there truly are no simple solutions. I would not find myself surprised even if a procedurally generated floor was susceptible to his powers.”

“Exactly!” Minaga said, sounding offended by Jake’s mere existence. “It’s like trying to address a fundamental bug in a system by introducing more advanced systems to work around it, rather than just removing the bug… or ignoring it, I guess.”

“Ignoring it is the solution, indeed.” The Wyrmgod nodded, then seemed to switch his mental attention elsewhere for a second.

“So, Vilas, gotta ask… why the deceit about his Bloodline?” Minaga asked the Viper curiously. “That whole aura-resistance thing is a good lie and all, but we both know that the Bloodline is so all-encompassing it can’t be hidden forever, and… well, why hide a good thing?”

Vilastromoz smiled to himself, fully aware that even if Minaga and the Wyrmgod had a lot more insight into Jake’s Bloodline than nearly anyone else, they still only knew a bit of it. From what he had gathered, they were still unsure whether the Primeval Origins aspects came from the Bloodline, or if the Bloodline was just a catalyst allowing him to use some special item.

This wasn’t even getting into the potential effects the Bloodline had on his own evolutions, resulting in him being a higher form of human, nor the most shocking part of it: including a percentage amplifier to a stat—and one that was even growing with every evolution. Even Jake didn’t understand why that portion mattered as much as it did, and luckily, it was something no one could easily find out unless his dear Chosen spilled the beans himself.

“Minaga, do you remember the many factions who came to you in the early days when they learned of your ability?” the Viper asked Minaga in turn. “The many pantheons who wanted you to join the moment you became a god?”

Minaga shrugged. “Well, yeah, they were pretty annoying, but Jake is already part of your social club, so I can’t see that being a problem.”

“True, they may not try to recruit him outright… but that doesn’t mean they can’t become major pains in the ass,” Vilastromoz said, shaking his head.

Minaga still looked like he didn’t get it, but the Wyrmgod zoned into the conversation again and sighed. “They seek to obtain his Bloodline without having him join them directly: through the act of procreation. Suppose they succeed in getting him sufficiently attached to a member of their faction. In that case, there is also a chance they might eventually recruit him, in which case it would be him voluntarily going over to their side.”

“How is that a pain in the ass?” Minaga questioned further. “Don’t humans like to procreate? Heck, most enlightened races seem to love it based on how they multiply so much, especially those who manage to get even relatively powerful. Based on his meetings with the Runemaiden, it didn’t look like he wasn’t a fan, either.”

“It is not that simple, and not something that should ever be done without plenty of forethought, especially when you have a Bloodline like Jake’s.” The Viper shook his head as he looked at Minaga. “I could try to explain to you the nuances, but I fear they may be lost on a Unique Lifeform that, by definition, will be forever alone. No matter how many clones they can make.”

“Low blow,” Minaga grumbled. “But, fine. I guess you know him better than I do…”

The Viper smiled. “I would sure hope so.”

“So… you taking bets on how long it will take for him to create a Soulflame using the Cradle?” Minaga asked in a cheerful voice, changing the topic.

“I am not doing any bets with you after the bullshit you pulled last time.”

“That was eighty-seven eras ago; you can’t still hold a grudge!” Minaga complained. “Also, that bet wasn’t with me, but with another Minaga, so it isn’t fair to hold me accountable.”

Vilastromoz glared at the Unique Lifeform. “That is the exact excuse you used to not pay up last time.”

“Well…. it was also true then?”

The worst part was, due to how Minaga worked, there wasn’t even any karmic debt to reap or take advantage of, as Minaga had gotten rid of the betting clone in question.

“What if you make a bet with my highest-leveled clone?” Minaga asked with a smile as he pointed a thumb to his own chest. “In other words, me!”

“That isn’t your highest-leveled clone.”

As the Wyrmgod raised an eyebrow, Minaga’s look turned defensive. “It totally is!”

“No, it isn’t,” the Viper insisted.

“It is!” the Minaga clone said as he flared his aura. True, it was far beyond the norm, surpassing Godkings by a wide margin, though not quite matching Snappy’s, but…

“Odd, because Oras mention—”

“Anyway, Jake sure is overpowered, huh?” Minaga smiled, and the Viper just shook his head.

The Wyrmgod also seemed unbothered, knowing that arguing with the Unique Lifeform was an utter waste of time. The Viper did have to consider recent developments, though, some of which were beyond his expectations. Primarily what exactly Minaga would do from here on out.

It was clear Minaga had taken an interest in Jake. More of an interest in him than Vilastromoz had expected, at least. He had even gone so far as to plant a clone of his with the swordsman in a covert way. Whether such developments were a good or a bad thing…

Well, only time would tell. With Minaga, it could truly go either way.

Chapter 57

City Floor Forty

Jake and company spent a touch over two weeks just relaxing in the in-between room, having exerted themselves perhaps a bit too much during the Minaga fight. The fact that they’d just gotten cool new items they wanted to either absorb or experiment with was certainly also a factor.

During this time, the Sword Saint managed to set up the Sword Formation within one of the bedrooms and even had a light spar with the Minaga clone. Testing revealed that only the Sword Saint could use the formation, so that was a bit of a bummer, but probably a necessary limitation for Minaga to even give it out. If not, it could maybe even have been used as a defensive formation, as it quickly became clear the Minaga clone in the formation could pretty much exert whatever force it deemed necessary.

Dina was enamored with her wooden branch and instantly got to work on a formation that would allow her to properly absorb it, though it didn’t seem like that would be a small project. Absorbing any kind of high-value item like that wasn’t something to be done haphazardly, according to her. Jake’s advice of just throwing it into a cauldron while mixing it with a bunch of high-rarity stuff to see the results was not taken seriously.

The King was more relaxed with his gift; he’d eaten the Soulcore of Minaga the moment he got it and promptly begun meditating. The two weeks they waited before continuing was the time it took for the Fallen King to awaken once more. By the time he did, the cracks on the mask were fully healed, but nothing much seemed to have changed. Still, Jake reckoned he’d gotten good gains based on his uncharacteristically jovial mood.

Sylphie was the one who had gained the most precarious treasure, and Jake had to confess he was somewhat nervous about her using it. He had insisted on being present the first time Sylphie infused energy into the nest-like treasure. The bird had just sat in it like a normal nest, and after infusing some energy into it, she’d seemed to get sleepy and doze off.

It had taken nearly five hours before she woke up again, only to yawn, say the dream-projection of the Sylph was super weird but kind of nice, then go back to sleep again. So, yeah, Sylphie was definitely loved by the wind, putting Jake at ease.

Speaking of Jake… with everyone else playing around with their loot, he naturally also got some alone time in with the Cradle of Soul’s Kindling. At first, he had just been infusing some energy into it while—pretty stupidly—testing how durable it was by trying to nick the urn. He couldn’t, and based on all the things he tried, he doubted any C-grade could even leave a mark. That isn’t to say B-grades necessarily could either, as Jake honestly had no idea how durable it was.

Ah, but he was also slightly productive.

Jake discovered that he could not only infuse his energy into the urn, but also look inside. And what he saw was astonishing. The description of the Cradle had talked about a world inside, but Jake had seen that more as either a metaphor or perhaps just a small space much like the inside of Sandy’s stomach.

What he found instead could truly be described as a world. A massive space resided within the Cradle, making it look like a miniature solar system. At first, Jake thought he was looking at a sea of stars, but then he noticed it was actually tens, if not hundreds of thousands of Soulflames burning in space. Some chased each other, some fled, some did nothing, and some simply found themselves consumed by the environment.

Solid walls formed the edges of this space, each made from different materials and featuring entire cave systems within them. Some of the walls were made of rock, others of metal, ice, wood, pure mana, water, lightning, clouds, pure light, pure darkness, and many more. Honestly, the entire place just didn’t make any sense, based on all the rules Jake knew of affinities. Yet it all seemed to be in balance, and on all of these walls and within all of these tunnel systems, Soulflames moved about.

As he observed, Jake noticed what he believed was a Soulflame about to be born. He watched with excitement as the energy gathered, but he was soon left with wide eyes, as the process didn’t stop. The mana kept gathering until a fully formed elemental was just about to appear.

Right then, the entire world of the Cradle seemed to come down on it like heavenly judgment, and the whole elemental dispersed into pure energy once more, never truly being born. Having seen it once, Jake looked for more instances of this, and within less than an hour, he saw hundreds of similar cases. Watching this had answered one of Jake’s biggest questions: The Cradle wasn’t actually doing anything he didn’t already know was possible; it just did what was possible damn well.

A Soulflame’s birth process was the same within the Cradle as in the outside world, except for the environment being more primed than usual, and whenever an elemental was about to be born, it would be instantly killed. That way, the Cradle avoided actual elementals ever appearing, which would be counterproductive. While alchemists loved their Soulflames, elementals loved to consume them even more, as they were pretty much considered top-tier natural treasures.

Anyway, Jake felt a lot better after understanding exactly how the Cradle worked, and he infused plenty of his own arcane mana into it. After he had put in nearly his entire mana pool, he saw a pretty large sphere of it floating in the middle of space, covered by some kind of protective film that staved off other Soulflames while it grew. Jake had a good feeling this orb would continue to grow as he poured in energy, and eventually, his arcane affinity would begin to invade other places in the Cradle beyond this one orb.

From there, the question of whether a good Soulflame would appear with his arcane affinity was still a matter of chance. The purpose of the Cradle was upping this chance and, through the sheer number of birthed Soulflames, creating one that was really good.

This was how two weeks quickly passed, and then it was finally time to head onwards. Truthfully, they weren’t all in peak condition yet, but considering they were heading onto a city floor and assumed the difficulty of floor forty-one to be lower than the Minaga fight, they moved confidently through the gateway.

Congratulations! You have arrived on the eighth City Floor of Nevermore.

All violence outside of the arenas is strictly prohibited on all city floors. Challenge Dungeon(s) can be found in the central square. If Nevermore is left and reentered, you will automatically be taken to the latest city floor unlocked.

You have successfully completed the first portion of Nevermore, permitting entry to the middle floors of the C-grade section. From floor forty-one onwards, all floors will be significantly larger in scope. All basic floor completion bonuses will be increased tenfold to compensate for the increased floor sizes moving forward.

“Did any of you know that Nevermore had portions like this?” Jake questioned after reading the message. He was mainly asking Dina but had phrased it as an open question to be polite.

As expected, everyone shook their head except for Dina, who seemed to be in thought for a moment before answering, “I didn’t know for sure, but I had heard that sections existed… I had expected Minaga’s Labyrinth to be viewed like one of these sections—not that there was any kind of official segregation.” For some reason, she looked a bit apologetic.

“Aight.” Jake nodded. “Well, can’t say I don’t welcome change, as I hoped Nevermore wouldn’t go back to the usual stuff before Minaga’s Labyrinth. Let’s hope the difficulty is also higher on these floors.”

“If they are larger, there may be space for a wider range of difficulty on each floor,” the Sword Saint pitched in.

“Even if that is not the case, simply splitting up to complete the floors faster while facing challenges made for entire parties will naturally result in an increase in difficulty,” the Fallen King also added.

“Ree,” Sylphie said, contributing her own excellent point.

“True, true.” Jake nodded and smiled at the others. “Before we move on…”

He got a few grins all around, as they all knew where they were headed.

Jake and company once more sought out the Leaderboards, curious as to whether they had managed to take the top spot back. Jake had confidence they had, as they had thoroughly cheesed floors thirty-six through thirty-nine, then done as well as anyone could on floor forty.

When they saw the Leaderboards, he could only smile at the current top record.

Average Nevermore Points (Floors 1-40): 12,521

Current Nevermore Points Record (Floors 1-40): 54,373

The top Points Records was the exact score they had, meaning they had indeed reclaimed the top spot once more. The difference was for how long. As mentioned, they had likely been faster than many other parties, and there was a good chance those just hadn’t arrived yet.

Looking at the average, Jake found it so low it was a bit silly, especially considering some people had less than this—it being average and all. Then again, seeing the more than four times higher Points Record that he and his party members held did put things into perspective.

Any party capable of even beating floor forty this early on in the integration and getting on the Leaderboards had to be pretty talented. A regular “elite” party from Earth likely wouldn’t even be able to beat the average, or at least, not yet. They would likely also take far longer than Jake and company. There were many floors before Minaga’s Labyrinth where one could just stay and grind levels for a while if they so desired.

This would also not be done while beating many of the events, skipping a few bonus objectives or limiting achievements. Things like the Demon Lord or Minaga fights were entirely out of the question.

“We reached the top spot again,” Dina said, smiling as she looked at the Leaderboards.

The Sword Saint nodded. “For now.”

“It is no excuse to—”

“Yeah, yeah, no complacency, but keep going hard… You gave that speech the last time.” Jake smiled at the Fallen King.

“Words that should not be forgotten,” the Unique Lifeform still insisted.

Jake couldn’t really argue against that. He studied the Leaderboards while the others chatted, also taking note of how few people were on this floor. Compared to Minaga’s city floor, this one was practically deserted. A few curious people had thrown glances their way, all of them far above their levels. Considering they were scouts from different factions, Jake reckoned they also knew who Jake and the others were and thus left them alone.

As he stood there looking at the Leaderboards, Jake got curious about who else had passed them. Closing his eyes, he released a Pulse of Perception, scanning his surroundings and the people observing them. One of them wore a familiar robe and was located within a large building in the middle of the city with several deserted houses around it.

“Say, wanna go check in with someone who might know a bit more about everything going on?” Jake asked.

“Oh, the Order of the Malefic Viper has someone here?” Dina replied, instantly picking up on what Jake was asking.

He smiled in response. “That, or some creep stole a robe from the Order and is impersonating a member.”

“I see no harm in that,” the Fallen King answered noncommittally.

“May as well,” the Sword Saint said, also nodding.

Thus, Jake led them toward the building with the scout inside. Not that it was needed, as Jake saw the scout making her way over to them the moment he began walking toward the house. A bit before, even, showing she had already decided to make contact.

A few minutes later, a scalekin in a cloak with a familiar imprinted motif jumped down from a roof and landed in front of them, already on her knees. “This one greets the Chosen of the Malefic One and his comrades.”

“Hey, there,” Jake said, nodding as he identified the female scalekin.

[Acidfall Wyvern – lvl 294]

Jake was a tad surprised at seeing a wyvern in humanoid form having taken up the job as scout and informant within Nevermore rather than just practicing themselves. He wasn’t going to ask, thou—

“Why is a wyvern with decent talent wasting their time playing attendant on a city floor like this?” the Fallen King questioned.

Before Jake could even throw the Fallen King a glare, she responded, “I am not competing on any Leaderboards and have no need to hurry. I have only stayed here for a year while nurturing a natural treasure, and will continue my own descent in a few months. Thank you for your concern.” She flashed the kind of smile that wasn’t really a smile.

Jake just threw the Fallen King a glance, then turned his attention back to the attendant from the Order. “Ignoring that annoying interrupting Unique Lifeform, do you know a place where we can discuss privately?”

“Would right here be acceptable?” she asked. “My current base of operations is under a protective circle due to an ongoing experiment.”

“Sure, go ahead.” Jake shrugged and whipped out a set of chairs and a table he totally hadn’t stolen from one of Minaga’s in-between rooms. Totally not. And if he had, then it was the furniture’s own fault for being too comfortable.

After they all took a seat, Jake began questioning the attendant about the event, all the while making sure no outsiders were listening in.

“We don’t know exactly how many parties have passed the True Ending event of Minaga’s Labyrinth, much less how many have done it without suffering any losses, but it is estimated that the number will rise to at least in the dozens over the coming period as more elites make it to floor forty,” the attendant said in a careful tone. “The event is only doable by parties who are competing on the Leaderboards, and even then, it has other requirements we are not entirely certain of.”

“I, too, believe there are other requirements that are purposefully obscured,” the Sword Saint said curtly. “We also need to consider that not all parties manage to have every member make it through the entire fight. In fact, there is often at least one weaker link that is eliminated or just someone who finds themselves ill-equipped for the fight, particularly during the period where each combatant is separated into individual fights. If they are unable to hold on long enough themselves, that is an easy spot to lose a comrade.”

The attendant nodded. “That is true, but we have no good way of determining either case, and we can only make educated guesses on who passed the True Ending event unless they outright state whether they did or not.”

It quickly became clear that while the attendant would happily give out information, she truly didn’t know much, and she wasn’t even overly aware of the other big parties. Jake kept calling her an attendant, but in truth, she was also just doing Nevermore herself. She had been asked to stay on this floor in case anyone from the Order came by with questions, as she could work on her project on any city floor. That was also why she had been hidden when they arrived.

Jake and the others left the city floor soon after, seeing no reason to stay there. A few pulses from Jake also confirmed no one else they knew was there. The lack of reason to stick around was probably also why it was so deserted. Stronger parties especially saw no benefits, as there was an assumption that the following floors would be easier than the Minaga battle or whatever fight they’d had if they didn’t face Minaga himself—an assumption that was probably correct.

Alas, there was only one way to find out. Jake and company continued onwards with the hope that the following floors wouldn’t be too boring.

Who knows… maybe they could even be fun?

Or horrible...

But hopefully fun.

Chapter 59

Karmic Plague

One had to skip back a few weeks to find out why Jake and company had chosen violence.

They had traveled with the Caravan Guard Captain and the caravan for around a week, and had learned a lot more about the world. They had even entered the territories of two factions and traded with small local villages. The caravan they were on transported primarily people, but it also had foodstuffs, herbs, and metals. All in all, everything seemed pretty normal. At least when they were on the road.

Sure, every person other than the Guard Captain didn’t say anything of substance and generally gave off powerful NPC energy. They just made small talk with each other, with the Guard Captain more than happy to only talk to the five of them. Clearly, he didn’t even view the people he traveled with as people worth interacting with.

One thing they did discover was that teleportation circles did not work on the planet. One Step worked as normal, and none of the others noticed anything either, but upon further inspection, Jake did find that the spatial mana in the environment felt slightly distorted. He reckoned it had something to do with the entire “isekai” thing.

Anyway, the truly odd things began to appear when they interacted with the Otherworlders.

Throughout their experience, Jake thought things felt… off. He observed the natives quite a lot, and he even questioned whether they were slaves or something at one point, but the Guard Captain shot that down, saying there weren’t any slaves on the planet as far as he knew, and that the nobles had strictly outlawed any kind of slavery.

Again, this just felt weird for a planet with a medieval style, but it wasn’t something Jake wanted to question. So he and the others just continued their travels.

In the first village they arrived in, not a single person went to meet them. They just ignored the massive caravan with nearly a dozen C-grades and hundreds of D-grades on it. Only when they fully entered the village was there some recognition of their presence beyond a few random stares, including the biggest building in the village opening its doors.

Out walked a large man and a woman, both with eyes that showed intelligence far beyond that of the natives. Jake instantly recognized them as Otherworlders.

“Captain! Good to see you come by!” the large man said as he laughed.

“Oh, my… I see you brought friends?” the woman at his side spoke, looking curiously at Jake and company.

“Yeah, Otherworlders I met on the way here,” the Caravan Guard Captain answered with a light smile. “They just got isekai’d to Tri-World before I arrived.”

“Pretty rare for five people to come together like this, but I guess it happens.” The man shrugged, then greeted Jake and the others. “We are the Village Chiefs of this little place. Welcome to Tri-World; I hope you all enjoy your stay, even if it does take a bit to adapt to the planet.”

Jake nodded while the Sword Saint took charge and responded with courtesies. Jake was too busy using Identify and trying to figure out where this odd feeling of wrongness came from.

[Village Chief – lvl 230]

[Village Chief – lvl 232]

Their levels were a bit higher, but still low. Far too low to be any threats, which made Jake question why the Wyrmgod considered it a good idea to guide them to this place using the caravan. Sure, they could just start blasting, but for now, Jake kept calm.

He looked on as the female Village Chief kept chatting with the Sword Saint and the man walked over to one of the barges.

“So, people on barge three, you should all get down and settle down here,” the male Village Chief said.

Jake looked on with a frown, thinking that was the worst sales pitch ever to make someone move the—

“Oh, that sounds like a wonderful idea,” the elderly man on the barge said with a nod, and every single person there stood up and began jumping off. No one else spoke, but instead just followed the elderly man down onto the ground as the Village Chief yelled for some of the villagers there to carry over and load large pieces of timber onto the barge.

Do they… just follow orders? Jake wondered. And the Village Chief knew, considering he had already planned for that timber to take its place.

Soon after, they bid farewell to the Village Chiefs and headed onward toward their next destination. The Sword Saint questioned the Guard Captain on the way about the odd interaction there, but he didn’t really answer aside from saying that was how things were on Tri-World.

The next village was the same, and by the time they made it to the third, Jake and company were honestly pretty freaked out. Just as they all agreed something was seriously wrong on the planet, they all got a notification.

Bonus objective gained: Discover the true nature of Tri-World’s peculiarity.

It didn’t seem like much, but the fact that it had given them an objective meant it was something worth looking into and not just the natural setting of the floor. The “people” in Minaga’s Labyrinth had also been one hundred percent fake, but that had clearly been done in a semi-joking manner, and been so damn obvious and comical at times. This planet just felt weird. Different. Jake’s intuition told him something far more insidious was going on.

Two weeks and several more villages later, they split up with the Caravan Guard Captain when he told them that they would stay in a small village for a few days due to a delayed shipment of ores. They didn’t really complain, as this was a good excuse to scout out the planet by themselves and head towards one of the major cities marked on the map they had gotten.

Speaking of the map, it had given them an okay understanding of the planet’s geography. The three factions controlled roughly seventy percent of the planet’s landmass, with the rest remaining unclaimed. The unclaimed area simply had too many monsters to make it worth trying to control, or included land with little to no value. Of the seventy percent, thirty-five percent was controlled by the Enlightened Republic, twenty-five by the Beastfolk, and the final ten by the Risen.

Only about five percent of the planet was covered in water, with nothing that could be called oceans. From what they gathered, the most powerful beings on the planet were also only mid-tier C-grades, which should be more than manageable. Of course, it was possible that the people they questioned didn’t know the true peak of power for the planet.

Their party of five continued their exploration for a while, and it was only when separated from the Caravan Guard Captain that they truly understood how fucked up the natives were.

Jake and the Sword Saint had visited a small village by themselves and tried to talk to the people there, and while they had reacted, they’d only ever answered questions and never asked anything themselves. They also answered incredibly truthfully, as if lying wasn’t even a concept to them. Moreover, they discovered one extremely odd thing.

They didn’t seem capable of saying no.

Regrouping, Jake and company sat down to discuss what the hell was up with Tri-World.

“These people… are practically not even alive,” Dina said in a slightly horrified tone. “They are more like puppets than actual people. Calling them slaves wouldn’t even be accurate… I… I don’t know what it is, but something is seriously wrong. Something magical in nature.”

“It is subtle, but I do feel a stark difference between the natives and Otherworlders,” the Fallen King said. “The natives have souls that seem almost incomplete, as if a part is taken out, or perhaps blacked out. Why or how that is, I cannot say, but I do estimate it to be from outside interference. Though it is odd that it affects everyone equally, including children. Perhaps it is a soul curse?”

“This interference seems to have almost conditioned them,” the Sword Saint muttered.

Jake sat deep in thought for a while, thinking, until a lightbulb suddenly went off. “I think I know…. No, I know… I know,” he said with a deep frown.

It was something he had only read about briefly after chatting with Villy about Eversmile and being referred to a book. It was a book that the snake god had described as “very much not common reading material,” even if a lot of what it said wasn’t exactly secret. It was a book about a special kind of karmic magic that was outlawed in the multiverse and that even Eversmile no longer used, despite being the original creator.

It was something called a Karmic Plague. Others also called it a Lineage Curse due to its effects. A Karmic Plague was, as the name implied, a type of karmic magic that spread like a plague once a person was “infected.”

The Lineage Curse name came from the effect this ultimately ended up having. The biggest direct transfer of Records and karma came from parents to children, so if someone infected with a Karmic Plague ever reproduced, the child would inherit the plague. In summary, it would spread from a source to something created.

In fact, it was possible to infect entire planets…

Most types of magic would expire once they ran out of energy, but if someone or something kept feeding the original power source of this magic? Moreover, each infected person became their own power source.

Jake was still explaining this when they all got a notification.

Objective Completed: Discover the true nature of Tri-World’s peculiarity. 400 Nevermore Points Earned.

“I guess that confirms it,” the Sword Saint said, looking at the notifications. “But how was anyone supposed to figure this out?”

“Karmic Plagues—and plague magic in general—have not been used in any official capacity for many eras…” Dina muttered. “And if they are used, they will be hidden. I did know about them, but I never imagined we would encounter one.”

“Ree?” Sylphie also chipped in, usually not the most active in these kinds of discussions. She questioned why anyone would even make this kind of magic.

“I think this variant of a Karmic Plague was originally made in an attempt to create more loyal soldiers,” Dina answered, shaking her head. “But I am not entirely sure. A lot of these things aren’t made with an express purpose, but just to see if the creator could. Also, I don’t think we needed to figure out it was a Karmic Plague, just that it was some kind of soul affliction or karmic affliction.”

“It’s also possible we would encounter some Otherworlder who knew,” the Sword Saint added.

On a side note, Jake did not share the part about Eversmile having originally made it. Nor that Villy had admitted to maybe being an advisor on the project.

Jake was about to speak again when another prompt came up.

Bonus objective gained: Locate the source of the Karmic Plague.

“Well, I guess we know what we are doing, then,” Jake said.

Luckily, they were pretty close to a major city. Not the capital of the Enlightened Republic, but a pretty major city that, according to the map, had around fifty thousand residents. Yeah, populations in this world weren’t overly large, and even the capital only had around a million living there.

Soon after, they arrived at the city, and after only a bit of exploration…

Well…

This was where they would encounter the impetus for Jake ripping apart an entire city, with the others spreading out and annihilating surrounding villages and towns. On the way, they had already discussed that there was likely only one way to “cure” the natives of the Karmic Plague, but they were still not entirely sure.

That changed with one of their first encounters after entering the city.

They had observed from a distance to try and find some more Otherworlders, and soon spotted a man and a woman walking down the street, chatting. Three natives walked toward them: a man, a woman, and a small kid. All five in the encounter were humans.

As the parents and daughter walked down the street, the kid bumped into the leg of the Otherworlder woman. It was obvious that the woman had, on purpose, walked into the kid, and Jake already thought she was an asshole for that… but what followed exceeded his expectations for horribleness.

“How dare you walk into me?” the woman said with a smile, clearly enjoying the scenario she herself had created. “Apologize right now.”

“We are sorry for any inconvenience we have caused the noble, and will do anything to make up for it,” the father said promptly as he bowed, the woman Jake assumed to be his wife following suit.

The noblewoman still looked smug when the man leaned over and whispered something in her ear, making the woman grin even more. “In that case, slap each other and the kid.”

Without any hesitation, the two natives slapped each other hard enough to spill blood before also hitting the kid, making her fall to the ground. The slap was so hard that the skin on her cheeks was ripped up, spewing out blood. Instantly, the girl started crying, yet the noblewoman rolled her eyes.

“Make her shut up right now,” she said in an annoyed tone.

What happened next nearly caused Dina to kill the noblewoman right then and there.

Once more, without even a second of hesitation, the father of the girl walked over and stomped on her head twice, killing her. He then turned to the noblewoman as if waiting for her to approve, with the mother just standing there with empty eyes.

“I… Wow, you didn’t have to kill her, just shut her up,” the noblewoman said, sounding surprised.

“I apologize. Is there anything we can—”

“No, it’s fine.” The noblewoman waved him off before suddenly giggling. “That sure was something.”

“I told you that you need to be more direct with your orders, as they can still interpret your words somewhat, and the immediate nature of your order made him choose the most extreme yet fastest option.” The nobleman laughed before looking at the father, who stood with a bloody boot next to his daughter’s corpse. “Clean your spawn up and get out of here. Oh, and everyone around, stop staring and get a move on.”

The father nodded and began cleaning up as ordered. The mother joined, too, while the nobleman and noblewoman strolled away, all the native onlookers also continuing their day like nothing had happened. No one around had really reacted to the fucked-up event outside of stopping and staring.

Seeing this left all of them in silence until the Fallen King spoke up.

“There is no cure to this kind of soul mutation,” he said, and Jake nodded along. He already knew that.

The problem was that the people were fully one with the plague by now. Fully infected. It wasn’t really something one could fix—at least, not a bunch of C-grades. A plague could be cured, but no fucking way they or any other C-grade could do it, as Jake had never heard of anyone below A-grade ever creating a plague… much less a Karmic Plague. The way the Karmic Plague worked was akin to Jake’s own soul mutation in the form of Anomalous Soul. Rather than giving extra mana, theirs made them unable to reject carrying out anything asked of them or truly questioning anything in general.

“I… Why would the Wyrmgod even create a floor like this?” Dina questioned.

“I don’t know, but I have an idea,” Jake said, sighing.

He did agree it was bloody weird, and he wondered if the Primordial wanted to teach them some lesson or something. Perhaps it was a fucked-up social experiment. At least for the usual party. The thing was, he and Dina knew a bit more about the multiverse than the average Joe.

They had initially speculated that this floor would turn into some political situation where they had to find a faction to support, or maybe even start their own. That was likely still an option if they wanted to just complete the floor and move on… but… no. That would be the “wrong” choice.

This planet was fucked. Something had to seriously change, and if their party was to decide…

Well, Jake’s “idea” of a planetary sacrificial ritual was legitimately back on the menu.

Because while they had originally been unsure of what their objective was on this floor, they knew for sure now. Plagues were outlawed in the multiverse for a reason, but that didn’t mean some didn’t still create them. And the course of action once one encountered a plague was pretty damn clear.

The way to get rid of a plague was to remove the source. That wouldn’t help those already infected, as they would still be able to spread it, even if the plague would begin to slowly weaken with the source gone.

Even if this floor seemed open-ended, Jake knew there was only one “right” decision, and he didn’t doubt it would be the one that gave the most points, seeing as the Wyrmgod had been one of the people involved in outlawing the creation of plagues. Ultimately, even if they removed the source of the Karmic Plague, for those already infected, there was only one reasonable cure…

Extermination.

Chapter 60

The Only Cure

Jake had never been a big fan of killing humans—or any humanoid beings, for that matter—yet he also wasn’t directly averse to it. It was more that if he had to choose between fighting a giant bear or a human to get levels, he would prefer the bear, even if both had the same level of intelligence.

What he definitely didn’t like and did feel averse to was killing low-level humans. That just felt wrong on a fundamental level… but… Jake did so anyway. The four others did, too. Dina was reluctant; the Sword Saint seemed neutral, like it was just something that had to be done; and the Fallen King and Sylphie honestly didn’t sound like they gave two shits about doing a massacre.

Their reason for this purge of life was an experiment of sorts. A grisly one. They wanted to see the response of the Enlightened Republic and the rest of the world. Hopefully, they could even bait out some of the Otherworlders in charge. Because it was clear that only Otherworlders had anything to say in this world, and that “noble” was just a synonym for Otherworlder.

The killing proceeded smoothly, as the big city didn’t have anyone above level 240, making it a quick and easy location to wipe out. Their group met up once they were done, then proceeded to wait in the area for nearly half a day. Not a single person showed up, making it clear there would be no response, so they moved on toward the capital. Throughout the whole endeavor, the natives didn’t even fight back; they just stood there like mindless drones. Jake had the feeling that if he had just yelled for them to lay down and die, they would have done so without question.

To repeat, the place was fucked up.

Ultimately, one also had to remember that they were in a dungeon, and nothing was truly real. None of the people there had a future, and their only fates were to be challenges on a Nevermore dungeon floor while potentially teaching the people doing the floor some kind of lesson—which, if Jake had to be honest, was probably a very good thing, as he very much wouldn’t like this kind of place to exist in the multiverse outside. Still, he was aware that such a place probably did exist somewhere. He just really hoped to not encounter it.

Flying toward the capital, Dina wasn’t in the best mood. “Will… Will we need to kill everyone there, too?”

“The Karmic Plague is so ingrained within their souls that getting rid of it would mean death,” the Fallen King said. “The choice we stand before is to either leave them to their meaningless lives, or end their existences. I care not either way.”

Dina already seemed to know, but Jake understood she wasn’t happy about it. “We should scout out the place a bit first,” he said. “Maybe even talk to some of the Otherworlders to discover what the hell is going on from people who display some level of independent thought. But I do think that our course of action will ultimately not be a peaceful one. No matter how friendly they are… Well, you already know.”

On a side note, Jake hadn’t bothered speaking to the two nobles he’d seen in the other city after the shit they pulled with the native parents and kid. They had died without even knowing what hit them.

“There is likely some kind of leader there,” the Sword Saint said. “That it is called a republic does strike me as odd, considering that usually indicates some kind of democratic process or elections, which makes no sense considering the state of the natives.”

“It is only the Otherworlders who can decide anything,” Jake said. “It can also be because it is a merged faction of different races, each having a representative, but who knows? It’s just a name. Either way, we will have answers when we get there.”

Two weeks passed before they arrived at the Enlightened Capital, showing the sheer size of the planet. They passed dozens of large settlements on the way, and while they did scout some of them out, it was just the same shit everywhere.

Every single place had one or more Otherworlders in charge of everything, and in many of the small towns, the one Otherworlder lived like a king surrounded by slaves. They talked about it, but ultimately decided not to wipe out these places immediately.

They also saw a lot of the natives and how they lived. For the most part, they seemed normal. They talked with each other and lived their lives, and if not for the fact that they couldn’t really decide things themselves, Jake couldn’t spot any differences. He even saw a party of C-grades hunting down a large beast within a valley, working together and using skills as expected.

The mere fact that they had even reached C-grade was astonishing, considering their shortcomings due to the Karmic Plague. But it did also show why experiments like this were performed. Making someone a slave would always harm their Path and limit any and all potential they had significantly. The Karmic Plague did, too, but in a far less severe manner; plus, it removed any need for contracts and such. It didn’t make it any less fucked up and insidious, but Jake could see how someone who didn’t care about other living beings outside of how useful they could be would perform this kind of experiment.

As the capital appeared in the distance, still a few hundred kilometers away, Jake scouted it out visually by squinting. It was a large settlement with tall walls surrounding it, most of the buildings inside of the walls, but some outside. In the center of the city, a large tower soared higher than anything else, though he did spot a lot of vast, impressive buildings behind the walls, including an official-looking structure with really impressive carvings on the pillars. The place was definitely bigger than any other settlement they had seen, but to confirm and get some information, they made use of the rules of Tri-World, even if it felt wrong.

Rather than entering the capital right away, they sought out a farm outside of the walls and found a man working the fields. At only E-grade, he instantly turned and looked when Jake and the others landed a few meters from him.

“Who is the most powerful person in the Enlightened Capital?” Jake asked, knowing small talk was a waste of time.

“The Lord Protector of the Enlightened Republic,” the man answered with a smile.

“Are they also the most powerful person in the Enlightened Republic?”

“Yes, I believe he is.”

“Where does this Lord Protector live?”

“In the Grand Spire at the center of the capital; you can’t miss it,” the man explained.

“What level is he?” the Sword Saint asked curiously.

“I apologize, sir. I do not know. However, I can go ask others if they know, and if not, go see for myse—”

“No, you can just continue on with your day as if you never even spoke to us,” the Sword Saint interrupted, knowing Jake was also very much done with the “conversation.”

Jake was already looking at the capital wall when Sylphie let out a small screech, the farmer back at work and acting like they didn’t exist.

“Yeah, no way in without being discovered,” Jake told Sylphie, nodding.

A large formation covered the city before them, and based on Jake’s quick scan, it was a dual-purpose defensive and detection formation. The defensive part was not active at all times, but the detection was.

As things were, they didn’t really care about being detected, as they had gone there to talk with the most powerful person present anyway. Entering the city, Jake instantly felt a presence lock on to them, and a male voice echoed out from the spire towering over the capital.

“Newcomers, huh? I guess I can entertain you a bit.”

A small opening appeared in the spire, giving Jake and the others access. Jake had already released a pulse and found a single man waiting for them inside the spatially expanded building. He looked humanoid but had longer ears than normal, making Jake guess he was a half-elf.

Entering the tower through the small portal, Jake and company found themselves in a large, spacious living room with fancy decor. Sitting on a large couch was a middle-aged half-elf, and Jake naturally identified him, finding his level impressive.

[Lord Protector of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 291]

“Not very polite of you to come barging in like this… I take it you five were also the ones who caused a ruckus in the outer regions of the Republic?” the man asked, looking relaxed.

“We were,” Jake answered, having already gone over the game plan with his party before coming. “Hard not to after seeing the disgusting state of the place, and we knew purging them was the only cure.”

“Oh?” The Lord Protector smiled. “You speak as if you know what the cause of this planet’s peculiarity is?”

“We do,” Jake confirmed. “A Karmic Plague.”

“I did get the feeling you five were rather extraordinary the moment I felt you enter the city… You truly have proved me correct. Few have any knowledge of Karmic Plagues.” The Lord Protector then summoned a wine glass and took a drink.

Jake just looked at the man for a while before he sighed.

“I have lived here for more than two thousand years already… Nothing has changed during all this time. For so long, I had no idea why Tri-World was so unique, and I, too, struggled with the thoughts I see you have now. Let me just clarify… There truly is no cure, as you say. But that doesn’t mean killing them is the only choice.”

“Do you know the origin of the Karmic Plague?” Jake asked. “Who caused it? Or… maybe how to get rid of it?” He knew the last one wasn’t very likely unless there was some dungeon fuckery going on, which was one of the reasons they wanted to check out a major faction.

“Hah,” the middle-aged man said, shaking his head. “There are some theories, most of which stem from one person. A couple of centuries ago, an Otherworlder arrived who wasn’t a fan of how things were run and created her own faction. She was the very same one who informed us all that a Karmic Plague was the cause of Tri-World’s peculiar nature. She was insistent that the Karmic Plague placed upon Tri-World could be stopped as long as we sought out the core of the planet. That we should unite and create an expedition down there, risking our own lives fighting monsters all the way down on some vain hope that we could change the status quo.”

“Was she right?” Dina asked. “That the key to getting rid of the Karmic Plague lies at the planet’s core?”

“Who knows?” The Lord Protector shrugged. “And who cares? Tri-World isn’t broken. No, this place has its perks and downsides both, but overall I would say the benefits outweigh the negatives.”

“Could you elaborate?” the Sword Saint asked diplomatically.

“The Karmic Plague has resulted in the populace indeed just being drones, but they still retain proper Truesouls and whatnot, making them prime subjects for experimentation. It also doesn’t mean they are less competent—at least, not by much—and finding new assistants isn’t too difficult. As for downsides… well, it can get a bit lonely here. The natives are not exactly interesting conversational partners, and trying to settle down for a family is out of the question. The Karmic Plague means that even if two Otherworlders reproduce, the child will also be fully affected.”

“So it is the planet that is the source,” Dina said with certainty as she nodded thoughtfully.

“We will have to confirm that,” Jake said, sighing before turning back to the half-elf. “I am curious… You didn’t mention being stuck here and the forced teleportation that brings the Otherworlders here as a downside?”

“True, that is a problem for some.” The Lord Protector smiled. “At least, it used to be. Having been stuck here for a while, we figured out a method to leave the same way we came in. Of course, things aren’t that simple, and I am one of the only ones who knows the spell…”

The Lord Protector continued with what Jake felt pretty damn sure was a practiced speech, if not something scripted by the system, as he explained what they would have to do in order to pass the floor.

Bonus Objective Gained: Retrieve ten Beastcores from the mysterious space beasts. Then use them to create a portal, allowing you to travel to the next floor and any Otherworlder to leave Tri-World. WARNING: This will complete floor forty-one and forfeit any additional rewards.

The Bonus Objective that appeared very clearly outlined all they had to do, and Jake and company quickly understood that the other factions likely had similar objectives available. In fact, this was probably the way to speedrun the floor if you just wanted to pass it quickly. Of course… it wasn’t that simple with the plague.

“What happened to the woman who wanted to cure this world of the Karmic Plague?” Jake asked.

“Well, what do you think happened? We got rid of that damn witch. Things aren’t perfect here, but we make them work and use Tri-World’s nature to our advantage. I myself have had quite good progress while living here, and so have many others. Even if you want to leave, I would at least advise sticking around a while.” The Lord Protector smiled. “There are many things you can enjoy here not available elsewhere. You know, have some fun.”

Jake nodded slowly and looked at his party members. He especially looked at the Fallen King, who had been busy scanning the Lord Protector all this time. The Unique Lifeform made it clear one of their suspicions was confirmed as Jake looked at the Lord Protector.

“Do you know why it is called a Karmic Plague?” Jake questioned.

“Due to it spreading through karma. At least, that is how that witch explained it. That is also why we Otherworlders are unaffected, as we are not connected to the planet like the natives. Such is its design, which makes sense if you want it to create subservient citizens while maintaining a powerful ruling class.” The Lord Protector shook his head. “Why the trivia?”

“It does spread through karma, indeed.” Jake nodded. “But did you know it was a failed experiment? That it was too hard to control for anyone lacking enough experience in both poisons and karma to handle? Too complicated. Too prone to freak mutations as it went through being after being. So, do you truly think you can escape from it? Whatever caused the Karmic Plague to take hold on this planet was the same thing that brought you here… because it needed you. You don’t see, and you don’t feel it, but you are a carrier. As long as any strain of the plague remains, there is no way to fully address it.”

The Lord Protector stared at Jake with confusion for a while before scoffing. “What an absolutely ridiculous notion. I will have you know that I researched the effects of the Karmic Plague for over a thousand years before I even knew what it was called. It directly affects the soul’s perception of choice and critical thinking. The mere fact that I am able to call your accusation that we Otherworlders are affected ridiculous should be proof enough it doesn’t work on us.”

Jake just sighed as he looked at the man. “You say that you researched the Karmic Plague for so long… How many natives did you kill during this time?”

“I don’t keep count, but probably only a few thousand. I didn’t research it all the time.”

Dina looked angry, but Jake raised a hand before she could say anything. “By the way, I can’t see your level… What level are you?”

“291,” he said proudly. “Which makes me one of the most powerful people on this planet, in case you were wondering.”

“Curious,” Jake said. “Why would you just answer that?”

“Why would I have any need to not answer such a simple question?”

“Why would you?” Jake pressed.

“I saw no reason not to,” the Lord Protector kept arguing.

Jake sighed as he threw the Fallen King a glance. The Unique Lifeform confirmed what he already knew.

“Then tell me how to destroy the Karmic Plague,” Jake said. “Tell me the method that witch had made up.”

“Hmph… She thought that as long as the core was addressed, it would be possible to… to…” The Lord Protector’s words trailed off as he suddenly frowned deeply. “Do you truly seek to get rid of the Karmic Plague?”

“Yes,” Jake merely answered.

“Can’t you just simply leave? I gave you a path. One you and any other Otherworlder who wishes to leave Tri-World can make use of. With the portal I can make, you would be able to go home and act like you never came here.”

“I think we both know that isn’t going to happen,” Jake said with a sigh, already knowing what was about to happen based on the nature of the Karmic Plague. “The Karmic Plague must not be allowed to spread, so would you help us destroy it?”

“I would…. Wouldn’t…. I…” The Lord Protector looked confused for a moment before suddenly sneering.

Bonus Objective failed: The Lord Protector has turned hostile.

“I will not allow you to disturb the balance of Tri-World!” the man yelled as he stood up, the entire space imploding as he collapsed the spatially expanded room in a fit of rage.

Chapter 61

To Raze a Republic

Jake was pushed back by a wave of dense space mana, but he quickly stabilized himself. The entire tower had erupted, sending stones to the ground below from the Lord Protector’s implosion of the expanded space.

The Lord Protector had an oddly empty, yet enraged, look in his eyes. His body was burning with power as a sword appeared in his hand. Still, he seemed to hesitate, as if the gravity of his situation only hit him now that he had actually gone and attacked. His mind was clearly still a mess, and he genuinely looked confused, as if unsure why he’d had such an emotional outburst.

“Alright… it is confirmed now,” Jake communicated through their mark. “The Otherworlders are quite heavily affected, too, though the effect is slightly different. I guess this settles it.”

Rather than making them lose all ability to question anything, it just made them… what was the word?… accepting of the status quo. They didn’t see the need to say no. Like with the natives, it was an insidious kind of magic. The kind Jake really hated to think about even existing.

Karmic Plagues didn’t always look like this… In fact, most plagues in general didn’t. Most just killed people or made them weaker; the Karmic part was only related to how something would spread. A plague could be anything, and this Karmic Plague on Tri-World was just of the mental-magic variant. It fucked up your head.

He remembered all the way back when he had fought the Minotaur Mindchief in E-grade. He could still recall the slimy feeling the mental magic of the Minotaur had given him. He remembered feeling like he was the friend of the Minotaur, questioning himself about why they were even fighting. This Karmic Plague was like that, except people never snapped back to reality.

Mental magic did have its weaknesses; it had limited energy and wouldn’t work forever. If you made someone think they were your friend, that illusion of the mind would pretty quickly begin to unravel even if you kept applying the magic. The target would build resistance, and the illusion would break, making long-term mind control not really a thing… unless it was something like this Karmic Plague.

The natives had been infected from their birth. What made it worse was that the source of the mental magic was not viewed as coming from another entity. It was coming from your own soul, as if they had tried to influence themselves. The closest comparison Jake had was being possessed by Eternal Hunger. That curse also wouldn’t just wear off. Of course, with Jake, the effect wouldn’t be permanent, as he would just be sealed away in his own Soulspace and eventually break out to regain control, but there were plenty of instances where people fell to curses or the like in the history of the multiverse, never breaking out and changing their entire being permanently.

These Otherworlders were in a similar state to someone possessed by a curse. They could potentially be cured. Potentially being a strong word here. Jake guessed that someone at least at A-grade had made this strain of Karmic Plague. Probably even higher. That is to say, he had no way of curing people already infected. Considering they were in a dungeon, there was no way to bring them out and have them inspected by someone able to find a cure, either. Well, the right way would be to bring that powerful person to the planet, but that obviously wasn’t an option here.

Moreover… the Karmic Plague made them heavily resistant to anything that would “hurt” the plague. Another potential nasty-as-fuck trait of a Karmic Curse. The ones infected felt protective of it. Happy they had it. Close to it, like family, and any mention of a “cure” was like telling them to kill their best friend. The ones infected didn’t even notice this unless directly put in a scenario where they had to choose whether they wanted to be cured. Which was what Jake had done with the Lord Protector to confirm.

That entire thing about a teleportation gate to leave the planet was also just bait. Jake reckoned they could even have been punished with a point penalty if they made it, considering it broke one of the few multiversally approved laws in existence, dictating the isolation of any plague-infested areas.

“We all know our objectives, then?” the Sword Saint asked.

“Yes,” Dina said with determination. “Sylphie and I shall head towards the marked spot on the map where the fourth faction once resided.”

“Ree,” Sylphie confirmed.

The Fallen King merely made a noise, and the Sword Saint sent a mental nod. Without any further warning, the swordsman took off in one direction and the Fallen King in another, each headed towards one of the other two factions on Tri-World. Sylphie and Dina hesitated for a moment upon staring at the enraged, yet conflicted, space mage calling himself a Lord Protector.

“He is mine,” Jake said aloud.

Sylphie didn’t need any more prompting before she took off, Dina following after.

The Lord Protector seemed very surprised as he looked at Jake. “Do you truly believe you can defeat the entire Enlightened Republic alone? There is still time to reconsider… Fighting like this is useless. We are both Otherworlders. If you want to end the Karmic Plague, doesn’t that mean you would also have to end yourself? You, too, are infected now that you have set foot on Tri-World.”

Jake just shook his head. “It takes more than fifty years before it begins to infect people. That is the incubation period where it slowly builds up, and as long as you leave within that time, you are good.”

After discovering the nature of the Karmic Plague, Jake had noticed that all five of them had indeed been infected. At least, kind of. It was so nonexistent that Jake hadn’t even noticed before doing a thorough scan of his body. He had then promptly removed it using Palate of the Malefic Viper, which was also why he knew of the fifty-year incubation period. That fifty years was also the maximum time you could be in Nevermore while at C-grade certainly wasn’t a coincidence.

“I… Even so,” the Lord Protector tried, “Tri-World is fine as it is. Why… Why do you need to ruin it? Why not just accept that life is good here? With time, you will come to understand that—”

Jake sighed loudly, not seeing any sense in talking. It was just the plague talking. If Jake had to guess, then the isekai function was likely there to make up for population decline while also introducing people who knew about the wider multiverse and could potentially leave at some point, thus spreading the Karmic Plague further. Just as a planet could infect people, so too could people infect a planet if there were enough of them… Over time, a single individual could end up dooming an entire planet.

Pulling out his bow, Jake looked the Lord Protector in the eye. “You either kill me here and chase after my party members, or we will end the Tri-World as you know it.”

The Lord Protector’s face turned cold, the conversation truly over. “Then you must die.”

An edge of highly condensed space mana coated the edge of the Lord Protector of the Enlightened Republic’s sword. There was no hesitation in his movements as he slashed at Jake, releasing a massive crescent wave that cut through the air and made everything vibrate.

As Jake watched the more than a kilometer-wide blade heading toward him, he sprouted wings and flew backwards while firing an arrow at the space mage. A barrier blocked it instantly, but Jake easily dodged the large opening strike. A few more attacks followed, only confirming Jake’s first thoughts. Through only that first attack, he had gotten a good idea of what he was dealing with. It wasn’t simply overconfidence that had made Jake choose to face this Lord Protector alone.

He’s a fucking houseplant.

He was someone who had leveled not through fighting, but by sitting indoors and doing his own experiments. His moves were big and flashy, not at all efficient, made more to look cool than actually be useful. Sure, those kinds of attacks would still work against other people who sucked at fighting, or people far weaker than him… but Jake was neither of those.

A dozen slashes went past Jake as he released a barrage of arrows that curved around the space mage. The Lord Protector struggled to erect barriers that could block them all, yet he failed to stop an Arcane Powershot that blasted his passive barrier apart. He tumbled back through several buildings before he hit the ground, structures collapsing upon him.

Jake did not let up. He continued with a barrage of arrows as the entire capital city of the Enlightened Republic rapidly became aware they were under attack. Many presences appeared all over the city, and figures began rising into the air.

Jake glanced around and spotted four individuals of note, all of them Otherworlders.

[General of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 271]

[Elf-King of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 266]

[Human-Queen of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 268]

[Dwarf-King of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 264]

“How dare you declare war against the Enlightened Republic!” the elf among them yelled. “For this transgression, you will—”

Jake spun around, an arrow already nocked and ready to go. His perception of time slowed as he pulled back the string and Gaze of the Apex Hunter activated, freezing the elven king and all the figures surrounding him. His Arcane Powershot struck the Elf-King right in the chest, blasting him back in an explosion of energy. Jake gave chase using a string of One Steps, creating distance from the other new arrivals and the Lord Protector, who was already emerging from the rubble.

The Elf-King ended up landing on the outskirts of the capital, leaving a giant crater. Yet before he could even properly stand up, Jake was upon him. An arrow slammed down from above, hitting the unprepared nobleman’s head and blasting it straight off.

*You have slain [Elf-King of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 266] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Weak, Jake semi-complained as he turned to the other figures of interest. They had all given chase but stopped the moment they saw the Elf-King die. Looking at them, Jake scoffed.

“To arms, soldiers of the Enlightened Republic!” the General proclaimed loudly, and hundreds of small groups began floating into the air. They were all C-grade, but most of them were low-tier… and none of them were impressive.

These squads all yelled as the General released some group buff. Jake knew there were several Otherworlders mixed into these squads just from a cursory glance. In fact, it seemed like all the “leaders” of these groups were Otherworlders.

While the many large groups flew toward Jake at unimpressive speed, he looked their way and opened his mouth while infusing his voice with Willpower. “All soldiers, kill the closest Otherworlder.”

It took a second for them all to process what he had said. Some of them were faster than others. The Otherworlders mixed in were taken by surprise, attacked by the ones right next to them despite screaming for them to stop—a command the natives promptly obeyed.

More orders were barked at them, but before they had any time to even turn toward Jake, he yelled again, “Kill any Otherworlder that is not me.”

Once more, they attacked, and once more, they were told to stop. The entire situation was funny if you didn’t think too long about it. This repeated several times, with the natives in the Enlightened Republic only becoming a source of chaos.

The Lord Protector, who had reemerged, clearly realized this. Looking on with anger, he screamed, “Anyone part of the army—kill yourselves.”

What followed was just that. An eerie sight played out as thousands began falling out of the sky, their eyes glazed over and their own souls extinguished. There had not been a single moment of hesitation, no trace of doubt or questioning. No survival instinct.

Jake only felt reaffirmed in what they were doing as he looked at the Lord Protector with killing intent. His job was to wipe out the powerful people in the Enlightened Republic, and he planned on doing just that. They had also clearly realized that it was either him or them. The Lord Protector and General attacked while the remaining King and Queen began using some kind of magic. Neither seemed like a threat, and the Lord Protector seemed too annoying to kill quickly, so he went for the General. He was a dwarf wearing heavy armor, and while that did make him durable, it also made him slow.

When space mana warped in Jake’s surroundings, he knew the Lord Protector was trying to trap him, but he had seen better before. Compared to Minaga, the Lord Protector was an amateur, and Jake easily used One Step to break through and continue toward his target while releasing several potshots.

The General responded by taking out a large axe to block, his body burning with some red energy. Jake didn’t particularly care much about what he did, as the dwarf wasn’t even good enough to block all of the arrows he shot, taking hits to the shoulder and arm. Worse still, Jake felt something he rarely felt from his opponent when fighting these days.

Fear.

An emotion far too easily exploitable.

Unleashing Pride of the Malefic Viper, Jake attacked the psyche of the dwarf, making him temporarily hesitate and allowing him to close in. He entered melee due to the three others fighting him and how they all sucked at using magic offensively. They had no confidence in not hitting their comrade, and if they still tried… well, dwarf-shields were totally viable.

While everyone hesitated, Jake managed to attack. Eternal Hunger struck the dwarf in the chest with Penetrating Fang, blowing apart the aesthetically pleasing but not very functional armor of the General.

Blood spewed out from his strike, and the General’s eyes widened as he used his other katar to stab through the opening in the dwarf’s helmet. Pulling out Eternal Hunger, he got ready to strike again by preparing another Penetrating Fang.

Before Jake could finish off the General, his danger sense warned him of an incoming attack. A fast one. He barely managed to twist his body as an arrow flew by him, the wind warping and cutting in its wake, leaving several tears in his armor. It was some evolved form of Powershot, no doubt.

Turning his gaze, he spotted a figure a few dozen kilometers away, standing outside of the city borders: An elven woman wearing a cloak and holding a bow, already halfway through nocking another arrow.

[Ranger Commander of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 278]

Jake also felt something else from her. He had become quite attuned to the Karmic Plague after learning about it, and Sense Poison was constantly detecting it. Yet when he looked at the elven Ranger Commander, he didn’t feel any trace of the plague at all. No… it felt like what he’d sensed within himself and his party members. Still in incubation.

Still savable, Jake concluded. Another curveball by the Wyrmgod, no doubt.

Jake looked her way to make eye contact, then projected his voice. “Stand down. You are new on Tri-World, I can feel it, and the Karmic Plague has yet to fully take root. You do not need to—”

He had to stop talking when another arrow was fired. Jake dodged as a massive pillar of pure space mana descended upon him, slamming him into the ground. With a groan, Jake dug himself out of the pillar’s newly created pit just as a rain of arrows fell on him.

“Relax, for fuck’s sake!” Jake yelled very diplomatically while using One Step to get away. Keeping an eye on the Lord Protector and dodging another attack, he tried one more time. “Do you get what is going on with this planet? The Karmic Plague is—”

“I fucking know, you self-righteous piece of shit,” the Ranger Commander yelled back. “And while these pathetic natives aren’t as good as the slaves I used to have, they are sure as fuck better than not having any slaves at all. Now shut the fuck up and die already.”

He realized he had misunderstood. Rather than a moral curveball… perhaps the Ranger Commander was instead a lesson that some people just sucked.

Jake sighed loudly as he looked toward the sky and the second massive pillar of space mana gathering. “Well, okay, then.”

When the pillar of space mana struck down, Jake pulled out his bow and let loose, Arcane Awakening fully activating. His body exploded with energy. He was confident he had drawn out all the powerful people of note. Now, it was just cleanup time.

An arrow of arcane mana shot upwards, and the entire pillar of space mana exploded like a tower of glass. The purple-colored fragments from Jake’s arcane mana went flying everywhere as the shards fell upon the broken capital. He was finally getting serious.

Chapter 62

An Inspirational Experience

“There was much debate whether we should include this example of a Karmic Plague within the dungeon, but ultimately we agreed it would be for the best,” the Wyrmgod explained to the Viper as they observed the slaughter going on in the Enlightened Republic. “Many mortals don’t even know about them these days, so this can serve as… What did you call it? A public service?”

“Yeah, definitely a good idea to teach the masses. I can attest to how horrible those things are.” Minaga shuddered. “I lost quite a few clones to plagues throughout the ages. I insisted we got the most insidious kind while also allowing it to serve as a nice mental screening of anyone who does the floor.”

“You are still doing all that, huh?” the Malefic Viper said. “I take it Umbra continues to pay well?”

“We can’t reveal privileged information about what we do with the data of Nevermore attendees,” Minaga said, waving him off with a smile.

The Viper shook his head, not bothering to argue. Combat information was usually difficult to come by, and it was a bit of an open secret that you could obtain some intel and potential recordings from Nevermore if you were in good enough standing and had the funds. Two criteria the Court of Shadows easily met.

“Oh?” the Wyrmgod said after a few hours of silence. He turned his gaze to Minaga. “Another flawless completion of floor forty?”

“I don’t wanna talk about it,” Minaga grumbled.

“Ah… I see… Quite a group, indeed.” Throwing a glance at the Viper, the Wyrmgod noted, “One of them appears to be from the same planet as your Chosen, too.”

Between Minaga looking annoyed and the timing of it all, Vilastromoz had a very good idea of what party it was. He also understood Minaga’s annoyance… for those who had embraced the powers of the void were truly annoying.

The Wyrmgod waved his hand, and another screen appeared, showing some clips from the battle. An impressive showing, if Vilas said so himself. Beings who were blessed by Void Gods were always interesting and powerful creatures—at least, those that managed to stay sapient. This party was definite proof of that.

A corrupted elf that could heal by removing the very concept of the person having even taken damage. A cyclops with chains that appeared unbreakable, managing to seal away even Minaga’s magic for several seconds at a time while landing incredibly powerful physical blows.

The corrupted shapeshifter, with its many faces in flux, was also incredibly unique, somehow seeming to contain far more souls than a single being. All bound together by the void into one Truesoul, which allowed it to fill its vessel anchored to reality with one soul at a time, effectively changing stats and likely even skills, making it an incredibly versatile creature.

When it came to the Void Shade—the most “normal” creature in the group—this one was still quite a specimen. An incredibly powerful caster and assassin both, able to merge into the gap between space itself. This was the kind of creature that came to be when something truly became stuck between a state of life and death, and through that, embraced the emptiness of the void. Void Shades were creatures that would cease to be if they ever lost their Blessings, which was why they were regular agents of the Void Gods.

Finally, there was the human scientist. All of the others were beings made for combat and personal survival. Apex creatures of slaughter and destruction that could strike fear into nearly any being around their own level. This human was quite the opposite. His body was weaker than any of the others, not even reaching the level of other low-tiers of similar levels. In fact, when it came to any combat situation, he seemed relatively useless. He was a craftsman and a creator, but such skills would not save someone when in a direct confrontation. His mind would not save him from a descending blade.

Yet one had to remember… he was blessed by Oras. Not all Void Gods were equal, and the reason the others seemed to view him as their leader was precisely due to the one who blessed him. Oras the All-Seeing, Oras the Eyes of the Void. Out of all the Void Gods, he had the strongest connection to the world outside of the void due to his gaze being able to pierce the veil separating the void and reality, making him an incredibly respected figure. For someone recognized by Oras, excellence was the baseline, and the human did not disappoint.

The moment he appeared on the fortieth floor and the fight was about to begin, the Viper saw what the human planned to do. Vilas could only flash a small smile as the scientist summoned a golem before his entire body flashed out of existence.

Vilastromoz saw it clearly. His soul became one with the machine in a fashion that reminded the Viper of how the automata gods operated. His soul was primed to be hidden within a pre-prepared core of the golem, while the human himself resided elsewhere—within the nothingness of the void.

His weak body was entirely hidden, and the only way to force him out was to destroy the core of the golem, which had a design reminiscent of the Altmar golem. To make matters more extreme, when Minaga was about to finish his speech, two more golems appeared. The Malefic Viper saw they were all linked through one mind controlling all three at once like puppets, and when the fight truly began, he did not doubt more mechanical constructions would appear.

What’s more… this link the human had created was extended. It did not just link together the scientist’s machines but all of his party members, allowing them to nearly operate as one being, independent yet guided. There even appeared to be some level of resource sharing with his party members. When the fight began, Minaga was instantly pressed, and while the party did face trouble… they ended up doing the entire event more cleanly than Jake and his group had, if only by a little. It was also significantly less flashy, which wasn’t surprising, considering void magic wasn’t exactly synonymous with colorful.

“Impressive,” the Malefic Viper said upon seeing the recording. “Definitely contenders for some of the top ten spots. I guess quite a few figures are.”

“In the end, it shall come down to the Challenge Dungeons for the very peak… As always,” the Wyrmgod said.

The Viper had great confidence Jake would do well with those.

“So… to talk about something more fun, do you think Jake will do a planetary sacrificial ritual?” Minaga asked with genuine curiosity, clearly also more than happy to change the subject away from the void-touched. Again, understandable. Based on the clips of the fight, it had been an infuriating experience for the Unique Lifeform.

“Perhaps, perhaps not,” Vilastromoz said with a smile, enjoying seeing Minaga not having his curiosity satisfied.

“Manually slaying every single infected being is not feasible unless they want to spend the next many years on floor forty-one,” the Wyrmgod chimed in. “I do reckon that a planetary sacrificial ritual is on the table if your Chosen is well-practiced in the art, though it depends how they wish to approach the end of the floor. I believe we will have to see if they want to make use of the other methods provided by the floor. They are very much open to creative solutions.”

“Are you insinuating my labyrinth didn’t have a lot of creative solutions?” Minaga questioned.

“Yes, naturally, it was very limited,” the Wyrmgod said. “Your desire for control over scenarios and the inability of the system to offer assistance through skills make any and all floors you create inherently limited. Moreover, you made a labyrinth. Labyrinths having too many creative solutions at once would be bad design.”

“Wow, just calling me out like that in front of our mutual friend,” Minaga grumbled. “Look at Jake; he is a way better friend. He knows about the Viper’s relationship with this little plague thing, right?”

“He does, indeed,” the Viper said, nodding. The books he had given Jake were very much restricted knowledge, after all, and had things in them that only a few gods were even aware of.

“And yet he hasn’t shared it with everyone… How nice of him,” Minaga said, shaking his head as he turned his attention back to the screen showing what was going on in Jake’s dungeon instance of Tri-World.

Vilastromoz smiled wryly. Yeah, that was pretty nice of Jake, as it would be problematic if that knowledge spread too much. In hindsight, he maybe shouldn’t have given Jake access to restricted knowledge so freely, but… eh, it was probably fine.

Jake had definitely also figured out by now that the Karmic Plague seen on Tri-World was a strain originally created by Eversmile as part of an experiment… and that the Malefic Viper had been a consultant on that project, with Eversmile cashing in a favor to make him help.

But who could blame him for asking the Viper? Who was a better consultant than the original creator of plagues?

Jake wasn’t sure how to feel when he stood far up in the sky and looked at the ruins beneath him. Not a single other living being was anywhere in sight, and every powerful person in the Enlightened Republic was dead. Most hadn’t even been a threat… but this was a purge. Be they Lord Protectors, military personnel, or random squad leaders, all had been wiped out. Even the citizens who had survived becoming collateral damage were gone.

Is this my first time doing a full-on massacre like this? he questioned himself.

Sure, there had been the Deepdwellers in the dungeon near Haven and probably a few other instances of Jake killing a lot of creatures of the same race in a limited area, but destroying an entire capital city like this still felt different.

What’s more… it had been so effortless, to a disturbing degree.

He sighed as he condensed an orb of destructive arcane mana and sent it flying downward to clean away the rubble, preparing for what he’d have to do later. The second it hit the ground, it created a massive explosion that consumed most of the city remnants below him. It then continued to expand, its destructive arcane energies annihilating anything it got close to, creating a massive crater.

It was an odd feeling he rarely reflected on, but being able to casually create an orb of mana with more destructive potential than a nuclear bomb was just something he and other C-grades around his level could do. Jake rarely, if ever, did so, because there was truly no need for it under normal circumstances. Large-scale attacks were a waste of energy and often far less potent, as the intensity of the energy that hit your enemy would be wasted on just destroying the environment. Yet he had to remember that he could. Sure, an attack like the orb he’d just made wouldn’t even injure anyone he considered worth fighting, even if he hit them point-blank, but if he wanted to wipe out a lot of weaker people… it was incredibly effective.

For a long time, Jake had wondered exactly how the Malefic Viper had managed to wipe out all life on a planet while still in C-grade, but he now understood why. Given a lack of foes capable of challenging you, it was just a matter of spending enough time on the task.

Jake tried to shake the thought out of his head as he turned to his notifications and saw the expected flood. Hundreds of thousands. The majority, he really didn’t wanna see, so he filtered out all but three.

*You have slain [Lord Protector of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 291] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*You have slain [General of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 271] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*You have slain [Ranger Commander of the Enlightened Republic – lvl 278] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 226 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 227 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 227 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Jake read them through while flying a good distance away from the capital, away from all the destruction, and looked for a nice place to take a breather. He soon came across a forest, where he promptly landed and found a clearing to relax in. After a quick pulse to confirm there were no threats, Jake sat down and deactivated his Arcane Awakening, feeling the wave of weakness wash over him.

The fight with the Lord Protector and Ranger Commander hadn’t been incredibly difficult, but it also hadn’t been overly easy. Both had been a lot higher in level than him, and their pure stats were nothing to scoff at. The power of their attacks had been more than enough to severely threaten him, but it was clear they’d had severely limited experience fighting life-and-death battles with people of nearly equal power.

Had they actually known how to fight properly, Jake would have had a far harder time and probably just fought them all with the party, but… they had sucked. Well, the Ranger Commander had actually been kind of okay, and Jake had gotten some inspiration from some of her skills, which also made him realize something else.

He seriously hadn’t fought a lot of archers, had he? Were archers rare in the multiverse or something? He had faced so damn many with other weapons—even the bloody space mage using a sword—which had helped him with his melee skills and learning from the fights, but, yeah, not really any archers.

As he sat there thinking to himself, he also quickly checked in with his four party members to see how things were going on their ends. To the surprise of no one, they were all just traveling to their destinations with weeks, if not months to go before they would arrive. The planet was ultimately pretty damn huge, and they had to travel from deep within the Enlightened Republic. Well, former Enlightened Republic.

That left him with some time to recover fully, ponder a bit on archery stuff, and look through the capital for anything of value. Maybe even clues about the Karmic Plague. He didn’t want to get his hopes up, but it was his plan for now. The Sword Saint would handle the Risen while the Fallen King took on the beastfolk, with Sylphie and Dina going to where the fourth faction had once been located.

The territory of the witch’s faction was marked on the map, making them all certain that the place held some meaning or clues to handling the Karmic Plague. Jake didn’t believe that wiping out the entire population manually was the go-to method for this floor, nor did he believe that a sacrificial ritual was the only way to go. No, the floor had to have some methods built in.

Sitting in meditation, Jake further pondered on potential solutions to the floor before switching to replaying the fight with the Ranger Commander in his head. That she was the last of his kill notifications was no coincidence, as Jake had fought her longer than necessary in order to bait out all of her skills.

Jake was the kind of person who didn’t learn much about combat from reading books or being taught, but instead did best with some live demonstrations. The only other archer he had really ever seen fighting was Maria, but her Path was far too intertwined with using fire magic in everything to help Jake much.

The Ranger Commander had been a lot more standard. She’d used wind magic—probably the most common form of magic to combine with archery—but otherwise just stuck to the basics. Both of them had Splitting Arrow skills and variants of Powershot, but the elf had also had some interesting skills he didn’t.

One of them was a skill he had seen but skipped. It allowed her to blast herself all over the place by amplifying the energy that pushed her back after every shot, which turned out to be quite a nice way of dodging when combined with wind magic. She also had bouncing arrows that could redirect themselves mid-air, which was another skill Jake had skipped, but he felt pretty confident he could somehow bake that functionality into his archery skill with time.

But the skill she had used that interested Jake the most wasn’t really one of her “flashy” attacks. It was the use of normal arrows. Jake reckoned it was her archery skill, but every single arrow she’d fired had spun around with impressive speed and appeared to have small whirlwinds around them, increasing their stability in flight, and wind mana also seemed to increase its penetrative power. He noticed that the wind magic would strike first before the physical arrow would make contact, which got him thinking.

However, only after seeing her big finisher had he truly gotten an idea.

Jake knew that her method wasn’t the way for him, considering he didn’t really do wind magic, but the idea of packing mana around it was interesting. All of Jake’s other attempts at infusing an arrow with magic had been difficult due to the arrows often being poisoned, but also due to the arrows already being arcane arrows.

So, seeing as Jake had some time, he began working on an idea he had. Honestly, he had been thinking about this for a while and had worked on the idea some time ago. Seeing that Ranger Commander had convinced him to try and bring it to fruition. He aimed to improve a skill that he should probably have improved a long time ago:

Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter.

Chapter 63

An Upgrade with Layers

Jake still remembered the day he’d gotten the skill. It was the signature skill of his first proper class and had been damn awesome when he initially got it. He got a bit nostalgic when he remembered bombarding that massive Storm Elemental atop the cloud continent with Hawkie. The orb from that kill had even helped give birth to Sylphie. To say that the skill had been important would be an understatement… which was why it was just a shame to see the sorry state it was in these days.

[Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter (Rare)] - The signature skill of the Ambitious Hunter. An arrow to strike down a fated foe in a single shot. Grants the skill to summon a powerful arrow designed to strike down a specific foe. The Hunter must envision his foe and, with great focus, channel all of his desire to slay it to summon the arrow. The arrow summoned deals significantly greater damage to the envisioned target while ineffective on anything else. Damage increased further based on level disparity. Adds a small bonus to the effects of Agility, Strength, and Perception when using Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter.

Yeah, looking at it now, the fact that he hadn’t upgraded it yet was just downright shameful. Even at rare after the downgrade from the evolution, the skill was still pretty powerful, but it also had some severe drawbacks. First of all, it only worked against the designated target, and while he didn’t think he could or necessarily even wanted to get rid of this level of specialization, it did suck that it was also ineffective against barriers or someone just throwing a big rock at it. He had gotten around the barrier problem by always shooting it with Arcane Powershot, sticking the destructive arcane energy to the arrow to break the barrier before the arrow could physically strike it, but that wasn’t exactly optimal.

This was naturally only the start of the improvements he made.

He meditated as he pondered on the issue and began to form a proper plan in his head. After about a day and a few potions, Jake was back in peak condition, and sadly had to delay his arrow-improvement plans a little bit. Before he could focus his attention solely on upgrading the skill, he had to be done with his other obligations, which included looting. That way, he could work on the skill without feeling guilty. Thus, he began to scour the ruined capital of the Enlightened Republic for anything he or his party members could potentially use.

Jake was pretty sure there would be some worthwhile items, considering his Pulse of Perception revealed several hidden underground chambers throughout the formerly large city. He even found people within some of them, all acting like the city above them hadn’t just been razed to the ground a day earlier. Having to begin somewhere, he started out with these occupied chambers. He quickly discovered all of them were quite nicely sealed and blocked out pretty much everything going on above ground, including sound.

Within half a day, he’d gone through all of them. He’d found only natives within every single one—besides one that had served as a bunker for Otherworlders to seek refuge. There’d been eleven of them in there, and, well, their fates didn’t really have to be described. Neither did the fates of the natives, many of whom had been down there as experimental subjects. Subjects who, based on the journals and recordings he stumbled upon, were often tortured and involved in fucked-up experiments, yet never had any reactions. They didn’t even need to keep them trapped, as they just followed the order of not leaving without permission.

None of these rooms with what was effectively just a bunch of slaves interested him, and the records on how they had experimented on the natives there, even less so. Turning his attention to the other rooms without people in them, he finally found an interesting one directly below where the Lord Protector’s spire had been. It was pretty obvious in hindsight, and once he broke in, he found a large archive. Looking through it briefly, he quickly noticed a small safe with magical locks placed on it.

After a bit of tinkering, he thanked his beloved puzzle box for the practice before he unraveled the locks and opened the safe. Within, he found just a single journal named Dark Witch. As he took out the journal and began flipping through the pages, he quickly got a good idea of what he was dealing with.

The Dark Witch was apparently the official name they had decided on for the former leader of the fourth faction. Probably because she used dark magic, based on the descriptions in the book, but also because she aimed to spread “corruption and chaos” throughout Tri-World, and thus had to be purged.

Most of the content of the journal was just boring history about the fourth faction and how a bunch of Otherworlders who also wanted to get rid of the Karmic Plague had gathered there. The truly interesting part came toward the end, after an excessively self-gratifying section about how awesome the Lord Protector had been during this entire conflict.

“Defeating the Dark Witch proved a strenuous task, but with the unification of those who saw her corrupted ideology, we managed to end her evil reign and burned the capital of her fledgling faction to the ground. However, even if we defeated her, ending her life proved difficult. Even so, we firmly believe that the fight left her crippled, as she fled underground. May the monsters down there consume her, so she can at least give something back to the now renamed Tri-World. Note: Do keep the area under observation, especially the entrance to the cavern system she fled into.

Update: Recent data suggests the witch still lives even a decade after the fall of her faction. Designate area as a no-go zone.

Update two: The influence of the witch has spread more than we hoped. Diving into the cavern system is an option, but too risky. Erecting countermeasures using other means is heavily advised. I will bring it up at the next summit.

Update three: Countermeasures successfully deployed. We decided to enter the cave system and discovered what she was trying to do, but we managed to stop her by sealing away a treasure of corruption she had brought with her when she arrived on Tri-World. Unless the three Living Seals are destroyed, that damn witch shall never be able to ruin Tri-World.”

Jake was about to contact his party when a notification suddenly appeared.

Bonus Objective Gained: Find and deactivate the three Living Seals to unseal the “treasure of corruption” brought to Tri-World by the Dark Witch. Warning: Doing this will make it impossible to escape Tri-World with the assistance of the three major factions.

Current Progress: Living Seals (1/3)

Well, it turned out the system wanted to tell them before he could. Moreover, they had apparently already unlocked one of the Living Seals. Jake was unsure what exactly a Living Seal was, but the journal provided a few more snippets of information. Living Seals were honestly pretty self-explanatory, as they were seals rooted within living beings. The journal even included the fact that the Elf-King, of all people, had been the Living Seal from the Enlightened Empire, with the two other Living Seals placed within individuals from the two other factions.

“An unexpected but welcome bonus,” the Fallen King communicated through the Golden Mark after Jake was done explaining the rest of the content in the journal.

“Considering we already planned on purging the entire power structure of these factions, this extra objective is indeed of little consequence and only benefits us,” the Sword Saint agreed.

“So, she was indeed still alive and is called the Dark Witch,” Dina said. “Did you find more information on her, and do you think she will prove hostile or amicable when we make contact?” Since she and Sylphie were heading toward the Dark Witch, this information was obviously quite a lot more pertinent for the two of them than the two guys.

“Hard to say,” Jake honestly answered. “It has been more than two hundred years since they defeated her, and chances are the Karmic Plague has quite the hold on her now. I think it is more likely that this treasure was left behind before she was fully infected by the plague, with her maybe being a boss guarding it or something. Either way, proceed with caution. If the Dark Witch was strong enough to require all the factions to work together, then she is likely the most powerful opponent on the floor.”

“We shall keep that in mind,” Dina assured him. “And, to clarify, you remain confident in meeting up with us on short notice if required?”

“As long as Sylphie stays with you, yes.”

“Ree!”

“Yep, take good care of Dina for the rest of us,” Jake said, chuckling to himself. The other four continued talking a bit, primarily out of boredom, as they were all just traveling. Not exactly the most entertaining pastime.

Jake, on the other hand, did a final scan of the ruined capital city before flying back to the forest, where he could finally get back to what was truly important: improving Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. Something it would hopefully not be called much longer.

He had already mentally gone over many of the downsides of the skill, but for now, he didn’t actually bother trying to address any of those directly. No, instead, he wanted to focus solely on adding onto the basic properties of the skill while ridding it of the negative aspects that would prevent his new arrow idea from working.

Without further delay, he got started, and he began with the most straightforward improvement. Jake was an arcane hunter, through and through, yet his Ambitious Arrow didn’t have a hint of arcane energy to it. That was definitely something he wanted to touch upon and improve. However, he didn’t just want to do it in a basic way, but in a way that would assist him in what he wanted to do later.

There were also some other aspects he wanted to improve upon right away for his idea to even work, and one of those was the rule stating that the arrow couldn’t hit anything that wasn’t the target. He didn’t need it to be an arrow that would hit everyone equally, but just the option for it to still harm targets it wasn’t specifically made for. Even if it was just a packet of harmful energy that dealt pretty shit damage, it would still be enough, as all he needed was the conceptual change.

In the forest, Jake looked around for any beasts and quickly found a few D-grades lurking about. They were good enough, and Jake got practicing. He started experimenting by summoning arrow after arrow, focusing on them while moving towards the improvements he wanted. This also quickly revealed another of the “bad” things about the skill now only being rare: It was too cheap. When he first got it, the skill had taken a lot out of him, but that was no longer the case. That he also just needed to up all the specs of the skill was a given.

His practice continued uninterrupted for five more days, during which he moved from choosing different targets to constantly summoning arrows for the same D-grade—a goat of some kind—while feeling for slight changes. On the third day, he managed to create an arrow that he then promptly used to kill a D-grade other than his initial target, proving that the strict requirement for only working on the targeted foe was gone. The only reason it had taken so long was that he wanted to ensure the skill wouldn’t lose any efficiency in the process, and luckily it hadn’t. In fact, it had gained slightly more overall power from other minor improvements he had added.

Towards the eve of day five, Jake was done.

He held out his hand, and an arrow appeared. Its design was that of a simple bolt that looked straight off a small ballista, with runic carvings covering the shaft. This was all pretty standard, and one only truly saw the changes when looking at the arrowhead. It was slightly larger than normal and had the hue of Jake’s arcane mana. If one looked really closely, one could see what looked like small lightning bolts bouncing within the arrowhead from the intense infusion of destructive arcane energies. The runes covering the body also now carried slight hints of arcane energy, making the entire arrow slightly more powerful. This was not necessarily due to it growing inherently stronger, but because it better fit his Path.

Jake nodded, satisfied, as he got a notification. For now, he ignored it and shot the arrow toward his designated target. It flew true, and the far lower-leveled monster naturally didn’t stand a chance at dodging. He carefully observed its effect when it hit. The stable arcane energy covering the tip of the arrowhead pierced the goat like a true, physical arrow—something Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter usually didn’t—and then a flood of destructive arcane energy came out. However, rather than simply exploding, it rode the curtails of the true Ambitious Arrow beneath that hit right as the stable arcane barrier shattered.

The arrow sank into the body of the monster as Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter usually did, releasing a flood of pure damage into the goat. Some of the destructive arcane energy snuck its way in, too, directly impacting the soul of the goat along with the inherent energy of the Ambitious Arrow for a substantial increase in overall damage. The goat’s soul was instantly extinguished, and the destructive arcane energy that couldn’t enter through the “hole” created by the Ambitious Arrow continued onward like normal, blasting a hole in the goat’s physical body.

It was complete overkill, but good data. Jake also finally checked his notifications and saw the upgraded skill.

*Skill Upgraded*: [Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter (Rare)] --> [Double-Layered Arrow of the Ambitious Arcane Hunter (Epic)]

The name had gotten super long, to the point of it being kind of dumb, but nevertheless, he read the full description to see what he had changed.

[Double-Layered Arrow of the Ambitious Arcane Hunter (Epic)] – An upgraded version of the signature skill of the Ambitious Hunter. Grants the ability to summon a powerful double-layered arrow to strike down a specific foe. The Hunter must envision his foe and, with great focus, channel his Willpower to slay it into the creation process. The arrowhead will possess two layers, allowing the Hunter to inject destructive arcane energy into a stable arcane layer surrounding the true arrowhead. The summoned arrow deals significantly greater damage to the envisioned target. Damage increased further based on level disparity. Adds a small bonus to the effects of Agility, Strength, Intelligence, and Perception when using Double-Layered Arrow of the Ambitious Arcane Hunter.

So, it now also had arcane energy infused into it, resulting in it scaling with Intelligence. It had also changed the wording when creating the arrow to include Willpower, indicating some scaling with that too. Additionally, the strict target requirement was indeed gone, and it included the description of the layers with destructive arcane energy within.

Jake nodded with satisfaction as he sat down and took a breather. It was a good upgrade, and the only downsides from the upgrade were the increased energy cost and slightly longer time to summon. The upsides were pretty much all the changes to the skill, along with significantly increased damage to all aspects of the skill, even the pure Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter part. Yet perhaps most importantly, the skill was now far more aligned with his Path.

However… Jake wasn’t done with this upgrade session yet.

One of the things he had never liked much about the former or even current skill was his lack of input on how the arrow would end up looking and its overall design. Sure, the skill tried to design the arrow to be better against a specific target, but in all honestly, as long as the end was pointy enough, the actual effect of this system-assisted customization tended to be negligible. What customization the system did assist with was also dependent on his own insights into the target, so who’s to say he couldn’t just do that customization himself? No, he definitely didn’t need that part of the skill… so if he could replace it with him designing the arrow himself, that would be swell.

If he could do this, that meant he could make use of the larger form factor of the arrow compared to his normal arrows. Considering he often conjured an arrow and kept it hidden in his quiver until he needed it, he could even make the creation process more involved. When he first got the skill, Jake had needed to spend well over a minute focusing all he could to make one arrow without being able to do anything else. Now, he could create one pretty fast within his quiver without it affecting him. He was fine with it taking longer for a better effect, and with his C-grade mind and soul, he could easily split his attention between a fairly involved summoning process and fighting.

There was also the downside of him needing a high level of insight into his target for the skill to even activate. He could always summon arrows for humans or other beings that he was already familiar with, but he often faced unique opponents he had never seen before. So unless he wanted to spend a good week stalking his target to analyze it, he was shit out of luck. This was particularly a problem when one factored in how it was pretty much anti-synergy with Stealth Attack that Jake couldn’t make his strongest arrow without first engaging in combat first.

To summarize, the primary thing he wanted out of the skill was more control. Back when he got it, the level of automatization in the skill had been great. He’d only had to focus on a specific target the system ruled he knew enough about, and bam, the arrow would be summoned.

Now he wanted to truly be the master of his own skill. Double-Layered Arrow of the Ambitious Arcane Hunter was a fine upgrade… but it was just the first part of his plan. Because if he had to upgrade it, he wanted to upgrade it properly.

In all honesty, Jake had long wanted to do a lot of things with Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. However, he’d always hesitated. One of the reasons he hadn’t upgraded it before was definitely because he didn’t know which direction he wanted to take. He knew that opening one door would close another, and while just infusing the arrow with arcane energy was an easy solution to instantly upgrade it, Jake wasn’t certain if that was what he wanted. He was pretty confident it would be part of the upgrade, but he feared making his arcane affinity too prominent and creating a skill that no longer made use of the quite frankly awesome innate concepts within the original Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. Now he felt more confident, and he believed he had found a good solution.

Because if he couldn’t decide on which direction to take the skill… why not all of them at once?

Chapter 64

Better Arrow = Better Person

Upgrading skills was indeed something one had to do with a lot of forethought and consideration. Well, that didn’t really count for most Legacy skills, as, ultimately, they all led toward the same Origin, so even if you misstepped once, it was easy to realign. However, for skills that had no set progression path—like Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter—it was easy to fuck up the skill’s future potential.

While it was true that entirely removing a concept from a skill was difficult, what was even more difficult was adding it back again, especially if it was a concept you didn’t truly comprehend. As an example, adding dark mana to something or taking it away again wasn’t overly hard for Jake, but what if he, let’s say, tried to upgrade Big Game Hunter? What if he fucked up and removed the passive ability that directly boosted stats when fighting stronger opponents? If that happened, he would be shit out of luck with a skill that was likely just worse than what he’d had before.

Jake was certain that something like Big Game Hunter relied on some concepts he could eventually learn to manipulate himself—Yip of Yore, for example, somehow manipulated insane concepts to make himself stronger to a ridiculous degree—but for the current Jake, there was no way in hell.

That meant that if he lost that conceptual aspect, he had no way to add it back. That had been Jake’s biggest fear with upgrading Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, as his arcane affinity tended to be somewhat overpowering whenever he applied it to anything. Thus, he had decided to avoid messing with the true core of the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter by adding an arcane layer to keep all influences from other concepts away from it. He would still affect these concepts a little, as not doing so was impossible if he wanted to improve the overall capabilities of the skill, but he did so with a steady hand.

The upgrade to epic rarity had been easy enough, but going beyond that would be quite a challenge. One once more had to remember that this was all Jake working on improving the skill. There was no predefined way to upgrade the skill; he was going purely by feel and what he wanted to do.

Jake didn’t know how much time he would have before he was needed elsewhere, so he got to work right away. He informed the Fallen King that they shouldn’t contact him through the Golden Mark unless it was an emergency or for asking something vital. The Unique Lifeform naturally didn’t argue, as he understood that Jake was working on something important. Hence, he left Jake wholly alone to improve the skill.

Well, he was not entirely alone, as he was surrounded by a bunch of innocent beasts that would become test subjects. There were also a few nearby villages of natives if that became relevant… Jake would have no shame using those as test subjects either, considering they planned on cleansing the planet anyway.

After meditating a bit on the subject, Jake began to draw a mental map of what he wanted to do. The very first thing was deconstructing the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter aspect of his newly upgraded skill. More accurately, he wanted to isolate the concept responsible for the skill dealing more damage to more powerful foes. After that was done, he would work on improving. Jake already knew that one potential direct improvement of the Ambitious concept was the Avaricious one, so that was an obvious contender. The Horizon-Chasing concept from his new class was also an option, as that seemed even higher in tier… but Jake did sometimes know when to limit himself.

The reason he needed to isolate this concept was to make sure he would place it at the very center of the skill. Right now, Jake didn’t need to “place” it anywhere, as the skill had an automatic summoning process, but if his improvements worked as he desired, then he would have to design the entire arrow by himself with minimal system assistance. There would still be some system assistance—if not, it wouldn’t be a skill—but it would be far from an automatic process.

In addition to this Ambitious or Avaricious concept, there was whatever made him deal more damage to foes he was more familiar with. That one was equally confusing and difficult to understand, so he also had to make sure he isolated that. Honestly, he wasn’t sure how much he would touch it; he just hoped to successfully retain the concept with everything else he planned. If things did work out, it would change from being a requirement to something that would allow him to make a better arrow if he knew more about his opponent.

Essentially, these two concepts were ones he would isolate but not really touch apart from trying to give them some overall improvements. Those improvements would likely come naturally from him just infusing more energy into the skill and the system coming in with an assist when the skill upgraded in rarity, but he still had to keep an eye out.

Now, when it came to the arrow itself, well… The idea of a layered arrowhead was useful, and Jake did consider going forward with this same concept but ultimately decided against it. The reason he had even made the Double-Layered arrow upgrade was to confirm that this next part of the plan would work. And it had. Also, if Jake wanted to design and summon the entire arrow from scratch, what could he possibly create it from, if not his own arcane affinity?

If he did this, he would also have more leeway when it came to what he would add with this upgrade. The reason he was so insistent on being able to design the arrow himself in such detail wasn’t just his desire for control, but also what he would add to this creation process. What he would mash into the arrow during its creation.

As for what he wanted to add? Well, this was where his desire to make the arrow go in all directions at once came in.

Jake could have chosen an upgrade path where he would infuse the arrow with a shitload of destructive arcane energy attuned to the inherent concepts in the skill, and he didn’t doubt that would be very powerful. He could also have chosen to instead lean into his poisons… or dark mana. Maybe even curses.

He had considered getting a skill using curse energy, as an example, but it was hard to dedicate a skill solely to that, especially if the skill could only be used in limited circumstances. Of course, skills being hard to use could also lean into making them stronger, Touch of the Malefic Viper being a prime example of a skill that was limited by design in its current grade to optimize power. This wasn’t exactly what Jake wanted, but he’d purposefully added complexity to the skill, making the summoning process longer in exchange for a better—and more customizable—final product.

In fact, part of Jake’s inspiration for the upgrade path he had chosen was finding a way to shore up a potential weakness: What if he faced an opponent he knew was weak to something but didn’t have a good way to deliver the super-effective attack?

Well, that was what he hoped this new skill could become: A way to deliver whatever kind of arrow he thought was suitable for the specific situation he found himself in.

In summary, Jake wanted to create an arrow he would build from scratch.

A core would be created, consisting of stable arcane mana locking in conceptual energy related to the Avaricious, with the arrowhead containing the “better against an enemy I know” concept. Around it would be a second layer of arcane barriers housing energy Jake could choose entirely on his own. Blood from the Malefic Viper, poison mist from Wings of the Malefic Viper, curse energy from Eternal Hunger, destructive arcane mana, dark mana, or even just fire mana or whatever else he decided to toss in there. The point was, he wanted it to be customizable.

It seemed simple enough in principle, but Jake liked to keep it that way. Of course, he knew that in reality, it was far from easy to accomplish what he wanted. So he did the only thing he knew how to do…

Repeatedly trying shit until everything somehow worked out.

Jake wasn’t the kind of guy to sit down with a notebook and sketch out different hypotheses while scratching them off one by one as he slowly found the right solution. He was instead the kind to fail spectacularly while leaning into his absolutely massive Perception stat to spot what was wrong while relying on his intuition to decide his next course of action.

Thus, Jake got started, quickly finding a target and holding out his hand. He fought back as the skill began to activate, trying to get a good read of what exactly was happening when he summoned it. With some effort, a single string of arcane mana formed, followed by a few more that began to create an outline. He then tried to infuse a bit of—

And it broke.

He went again and tried to—

Broke again.

Alright, what if he—

Shards of arcane energy fell all over the ground.

Ah, but—

Energy feedback was a bitch, and now Jake had quite a few burn-like marks across his frayed hand. Luckily, he had two hands!

Okay, a few hours later, he was down to one hand, but in his defense, he had tried something new that could have totally worked. Nothing a potion couldn’t fix!

Given enough time, things were sure to turn out just like he had imagined… right? He should have sufficient time with his party members traveling to their respective destinations, so he just had to keep on keeping on. Sure, it could get a little dangerous at times, but hands could always be regrown, so was it really that dangerous?

Besides, he had confidence. It wouldn’t take that long, right?

A long time later…

Jake held out his hand, and the air just above his palm seemed to shimmer as a film of extremely thin arcane mana appeared, showing the outline of a shaft. Stamina, health points, and mana left his body as this shimmer condensed into barely visible energy within this fine film. Once it had reached a certain threshold, Jake sent out thousands of strings with a mental command. They all wrapped around the arrow like he was weaving something, spinning around what would become the arrow’s body.

A solid purplish shaft was quickly created before Jake turned his attention toward the tip of the would-be arrow. Another fine barrier of arcane mana appeared as Jake focused on the native Tri-Worlder in the distance. An odd energy Jake could not truly describe gathered within the arrowhead, and he summoned a ball of stable arcane mana around it to make sure it couldn’t escape.

Once he felt certain the energy was properly sealed within, faint destructive arcane energies licked across this ball, shearing off parts until, finally, a broadhead tip was formed. Jake nodded, satisfied, and moved on to the next part. Another firm film covered the entire arrow at once as Jake focused.

Pink-purple destructive arcane energy crackled to life within the thin barrier of arcane energy, entirely locked away from the energies sealed in the shaft’s core and arrowhead. As he kept pouring in destructive arcane mana, it became denser and denser; he stopped just before it would explode. He had a lot of experience with the entire thing exploding at this point.

Another web of arcane strings appeared, spinning around the arrow to nicely wrap up and strengthen it. Studying the arrow, he checked for any imperfections yet saw nothing outrageous. He had to constantly focus on all of the different energies and keep them stable throughout this process without letting any of the conceptual power leak out.

So far, so good, Jake told himself.

Jake reached out with his hand and touched what he had just summoned. He was barely able to fit his hand around it. It was more than two and a half meters long and quite thick, with a large broadhead that didn’t look especially sharp, but Jake knew looks could be deceiving. Giving the shaft a good squeeze, he felt its structural integrity, and upon seeing that his hand didn’t get blown up, he nodded in satisfaction.

Now it was down to the final part.

With careful hands—but not too careful, as he wanted to make sure the entire thing wasn’t too unstable—Jake nocked the frankly too-large arrow, the size so stupidly big he had to use some light telekinesis to keep it level. As he stood there with it nocked, he took a deep breath and felt for the final concept he wanted to introduce. One that he hadn’t really thought he would add, but when he had reached this point before, it had just felt right.

Upon focusing, fletchings slowly grew out of the arrow. They were subtle and looked plastic, but Jake knew they were far from simple, as they practically radiated with a familiar energy. It was true that Jake didn’t have confidence in infusing the concept from his class into it… but he still had confidence in using some of the concepts from his archery skill.

Jake did a final once-over on the massive arrow he was barely holding up. This was far from his first time getting to this point, and he took a deep breath as he prepared for the final part of the process.

Here goes nothing.

Focusing all his will, Jake exerted pressure on the arrow from all sides and willed it to condense. A loud crack sounded out as, in an instant, it was smashed from a two-and-a-half-meter-long arrow down to one just a bit over a meter and twenty. Jake stood frozen with bated breath as he carefully observed every part of the arrow.

A few seconds passed, and nothing happened.

Nothing happening was good.

Fuck yeah, Jake thought, grinning. He knew he had succeeded, and a notification confirmed it right after.

*Skill Upgraded*: [Double-Layered Arrow of the Ambitious Arcane Hunter (Epic)] --> [Protean Arrow of Avaricious Horizons (Ancient)]

Smiling, Jake read the notification and was honestly surprised at seeing an all-new word used in the skill name. Protean. That was not one Jake had run into before, but it was one of those words that sounded powerful. As far as he recalled, it was pretty much a synonym for versatile, but probably considered a level higher. It also tended to relate to being the “first” or something… which gave Jake pause. Arcane was not mentioned anywhere in the skill name, so what if that was mixed into that Protean word? Or was he just overthinking things, and it didn’t mention his arcane affinity in the name because it was a less significant building block than the other parts?

He was unsure and exited his thoughts.

Jake looked at the random native in the distance he had designated as his desired target when creating the arrow. He stared for a few seconds before he sighed, shaking his head. Then he lowered his bow and, with a simple mental command, dispelled the arrow. It had been difficult to make, but he knew that with the skill upgraded, it would be far easier the next time. Plus, he found no joy or satisfaction in slaying a random E-grade farmer.

What he did find joy in was reading the description of his new skill.

[Protean Arrow of Avaricious Horizons (Ancient)] – An arrow born not of a single desire, but the urge to create something that could encompass all of them. Grants the skill to design and summon a powerful layered arrow to strike down a targeted foe. The Hunter may envision his foe and channel his Willpower into the creation process. The arrow will possess extra layers, and the Hunter can inject desired energy into these stable arcane layers surrounding the true arrow. The summoned arrow deals significantly greater damage to the envisioned target based on Willpower and familiarity with the target. Damage increased further based on level disparity, Perception, and distance traveled. Due to the Hunter’s powerful connection to the arrow, he can influence its flight path. Stat bonuses are applied depending on the nature of the summoned arrow.

There was a lot to unpack, but all in all, Jake had gotten exactly what he wanted. Plus, there was clearly room for growth. The description mentioned making multiple layers of energies, but Jake was pretty sure he could only shape a single one right now. He’d also kept all the things he wanted and added some nice extra scaling to the arrow with the Horizon concepts. It even mentioned he could influence its flight path, which he hadn’t explicitly aimed to do but was excited to test out.

All in all, this arrow truly was an amalgamation of so many different concepts, and he was all for it.

Seeing as he was done with the upgrade, Jake decided to return to the real world and contact his party members, all of whom he had neglected for… he wasn’t sure how long.

“I am done with the skill upgrade,” Jake communicated through the Golden Mark, quite happy with himself.

“About time,” the Fallen King sent back in a slightly judgmental tone.

“I wasn’t that long… was I?” Jake questioned. He had a tendency to lose track of time when really focusing on stuff like this, but he couldn’t have been that long if his party members had never contacted him during his training, right?

“You should check your notifications,” the Sword Saint sent.

“What? Have you guys managed to… Oh...”

Yeah, alright. Looking at the missed notifications, Jake could see he had mayhap taken a bit longer than expected.